<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grace Bible Institute – Confessing The Faith And The Christian Creeds</title>
    <link>/en/courses/211/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Confessing The Faith And The Christian Creeds on Grace Bible Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 03:18:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/en/courses/211/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第一课 （lesson 1）我相信</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第一课 （lesson 1）我相信
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：2188
Lesson One: I Believe
第一课：我相信
A. In 2 Corinthians (4:13), Paul quotes this Old Testament passage: “I believed; therefore I have spoken” (Ps. 116:10). St. Paul was reminded of these words by what he had recently suffered. Despite the problems that had nearly overwhelmed him, he had experienced yet again the Lord’s mercy and safe deliverance. Once again he had been confirmed in his faith. As a result, he testified of his gratitude to the Lord by confessing the central truth of his faith:
We also believe, and therefore speak, because we know that the one who raised the Lord Jesus from the dead will also raise us with Jesus, and present us with you in his presence. All this is for your benefit, so that the grace which is reaching more and more people may cause thanksgiving to overflow to the glory of God (2 Cor. 4:14-15).
在哥林多后书(4:13)中，保罗引用了旧约中的这句话：“我因信，所以如此说话”(诗篇116:10)。圣徒保罗因为自己当时的遭遇而提到这句话。尽管困境使得保罗几乎不知所措，但是他再次经历了主的怜悯和看顾。他再次在信心上被坚立。由此，他通过对真理的认信做了对主感恩的见证：
我们也信，所以也说话。自己知道那叫主耶稣复活的，也必叫我们与耶稣一同复活，并且叫我们与你们一同站在他面前。凡事都是为你们，好叫恩惠因人多越发加增，感谢格外显多，以致荣耀归于神(哥林多后书4:14-15)。
B. For the most part we write creeds and use them in our worship services to proclaim the goodness of God in Christ. The word creed comes from the Latin credo, the first word in the Apostles’ and the Nicene Creeds. It is usually translated, “I believe.” This Latin word also meant, “I have confidence in; I rely upon.” The word corresponds to the Greek word for “faith” or “trust” (pistis). Faith then is nothing but childlike trust in Christ for the forgiveness of sins, life and salvation. This is the very heart of the Gospel: “For we maintain that a man is justified by faith without the deeds of the law” (Rom 3:28).
我们写信经并在敬拜中使用它们是为了宣告上帝在基督里的美意。信经这个词来自使徒信经和尼西亚信经中的第一个词，拉丁语credo信条。它常被翻译成，“我信”。这个拉丁语单词也有“我对…有信心；我信靠”的意思。这个词与希腊语 (pistis)“信心”或“相信”这个词的意思一致。 信心就是如孩童般相信基督使我们罪得赦免并给我们永生和救恩。这是福音的最关键内容：“所以我们看定了：人称义因着信，不在乎遵行律法”(罗马书3:28)。
C. St. Paul has further demonstrated the very clear connection between our saving faith in the Lord Jesus Christ and our confession of that faith:
If you confess with your mouth, “Jesus is Lord,” and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved. For it is with your heart that you believe and are justified, and it is with your mouth that you confess and are saved (Rom. 10:9-10).
So, the CREED is a confession from the heart of a Christian’s innermost convictions regarding the living God and God’s relationship to him. When a Christian confesses his faith, he is declaring his trust in God. He is also giving God credit for what He has done and still does to save him.
圣徒保罗更详细地说明了我们在主耶稣基督里救恩的信心与认信之间非常明显的联系：
如果你口里认耶稣为主，心里信神叫他从死里复活，就必得救。因为人心里相信，就可以称义；口里承认，就可以得救(罗马书10:9-10)。
因此，信经是基督徒心底对所确信的永活的上帝和上帝与基督徒关系的承认。当一个基督徒认信时，他就宣告了他相信上帝。他也将上帝已经做的与仍然为拯救他而做的事归荣耀与上帝。
D. Homologia (confession) is another important word commonly used in the Greek New Testament. Very early in the life of the New Testament Christian Church, the followers of our Savior confessed that Jesus of Nazareth was the Christ and the Lord (Rom. 10:9), or the Son of God (Matt. 16:16). At the beginning of our Savior’s public ministry, John the Baptist is very careful to make the confession that he is “not the Christ” (John 1:20); on the contrary, St. John, the Apostle, declares that “everyone who believes that Jesus is the Christ is born of God” (1 John 5:1), and that “if anyone acknowledges (confesses) that Jesus is the Son of God, God lives in him, and he in God (1 John 4:15). Today we also call our specific creeds “Confessions.” We say that the Lutheran Book of Concord contains “the Confessions of the Evangelical Lutheran Church.”
Homologia (confession 信仰告白)是另一个在希腊语的新约中常常用到的重要单词。在最早期新约基督徒教会的生活中，我们救主的追随者承认拿撒勒的耶稣就是基督也是主(罗马书10:9)，或者说是上帝的儿子(马太福音16:16)。在我们救主公开传教的初期，施洗约翰对于他自己“不是基督”的陈述非常谨慎(约翰福音1:20)；相反地，圣徒约翰，这位使徒宣告“凡信耶稣是基督的，都是从神而生”(约翰一书5:1)，而且“凡认(confesses承认)耶稣为神儿子的，神就住在他里面，他也住在神里面”(约翰一书4:15)。如今我们也称我们特定的信经为“信仰告白”。我们说路德的协同书包含“福音派路德教会信仰告白”。
E. The confession (homologia) then represents the basic core of the Christian faith. But such confessions soon became far more than a personal declaration of the faith by individual Christians and personal proclamations of the Gospel (Rom. 10:8-10; 2 Cor. 4:5; 2 Tim. 2:8). In an expanded form they were also a standard or norm for the true faith. In this way they were also used to combat false doctrine. One of the earliest instances of this use is found in 1 Cor. 15:3-7 (written by St. Paul about 57 A. D.). For in this letter Paul sets forth in a rather formal way a confession he has received. He does this in order to fight the heretics who were denying the resurrection. Many other short statements of doctrine are found throughout the New Testament. The Letter to the Hebrews frequently alludes to the confession (homologia) to which his readers should hold fast (Heb. 3:1; 4:14; 10:23).
那么信仰告白所代表的就是基督徒信仰的基本核心。但是这样的信仰告白不久就成为远不止是单个基督徒的个人信仰宣告和福音的个人宣言(罗马书10:8-10；哥林多后书4:5；提摩太后书2:8)。从更广的范围来说，他们还作为衡量真信心的标准或准则。因此，他们也被用作与错误教导的斗争。其中最早这样使用的一个例子就是哥林多前书15:3-7(由圣徒保罗写于公元57年前后)。因为在这封信中，保罗以一种相当正式的方式阐明了他所接收的信仰告白。他这样做是为了对抗否认耶稣复活的异端教导。很多其他简短的教义陈述贯穿新约始终。给希伯来人的信中不断向他的读者提到他们应该牢牢抓住的信仰告白 (homologia) (希伯来书3:1；4:14；10:23)。
F. In the Ancient Church, another word came to be employed for a creed or statement of faith, namely, “symbol.” We are not really sure today how this word “symbol” came to designate a creed. The Greek word from which “symbol” is derived meant “to put together,” and then to compare things, to see the relationship, the similarity or dissimilarity. And so the word symbolum, both in its Latin and Greek forms, carried the basic meaning of a sign, or a token (a badge by which one is known), and then a confession or creed which identified one’s beliefs. By the Third Century, “symbol” referred to the questions and answers which were part of the baptism service. These were based on the Trinitarian Formula commanded by our Savior:
All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit, and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you (Matt. 28:18-20).
在早期教会中，有另一个词被用于代表信经或信仰告白，即“symbol标志”。我们现在还不是非常确定“标志”这个词如何被确定为信经的名称。希腊语中“标志”这个词源于“集中”并将不同事物进行比较从而找出彼此之间的关系和异同的意思。因此，symbolum (信经)这个词在拉丁语和希腊语中同时具有的基本意义是记号或象征(众所周知的标记)并且信仰告白或信经代表了一个人的信仰。直到三世纪，“标志”这个词一直指的是洗礼仪式中的问答。这些问答都是基于我们救主所吩咐的三位一体论：
天上地下所有的权柄都赐给我了。所以，你们要去，使万民作我的门徒，奉父、子、圣灵的名给他们施洗。凡我所吩咐你们的，都教训他们遵守(马太福音28:18-20)。
G. Later, “symbol” became the regular title for a declaratory creed (a special term for a creed in which a believer makes a personal statement of faith). The three most important declaratory creeds are the Apostles’, the Nicene and the Athanasian Creeds. These are fixed formulas summarizing the essential articles of the Christian faith, emphasizing especially those doctrines under attack at that time within the church. A “symbol” thus was also a badge, or banner, or confession, which identified the Christian as orthodox over against heretics.
在此之后，“标志”成为宣言信经 (信徒作个人信仰陈述时使用的对信经的特殊术语) 的常规代名词。最重要的三个宣言信经是使徒信经、尼西亚信经和亚大纳西信经。这些是概括了基督徒信仰必要条款的固定表述，他们尤其强调了那时在教会中受到攻击的那些教义。因此，“标志”也是一种代表与异端相对的正统基督徒的标记或标题或信仰告白。
H. Our Savior and His Apostles have given many warnings in the inspired Scriptures that Christians should believe, teach, and confess all things commanded by Christ (Matt. 28:19-20; John 8:31-32). The New Testament further taught that the followers of Christ are to avoid those who believe and teach anything contrary to the Apostolic doctrine they had learned (Rom. 16:17; 2 John 9-10).
我们的救主和他的使徒们已经在神所默示的圣经中告诫基督徒们要相信、教导和承认所有基督所吩咐的事情(马太福音28:19-20；约翰福音8:31-32)。新约中进一步教导基督的追随者要远离那些相信和教导任何与使徒们从基督那里所学到教导相悖的人(罗马书16:17；约翰二书9-10)。
I. The Early Church took these admonitions seriously and did not practice church fellowship with those who denied the Apostolic doctrine. Some leaders in the modern Ecumenical Movement falsely assert that the Ancient Church was essentially one in doctrine and in fellowship. It is equally false that this external unity was based on some vague statement about the Lordship of Jesus, so that various false viewpoints could live peacefully in the church. Because they desired to be faithful to what they had received, the first Christians used baptismal questions and answers, creed and formulas, to determine that a person really believed the true faith.
早期教会慎重地接受了这些告诫并且不与那些否认使徒教义的人进行团契。一些现代教会合一运动的领导者错误地坚称早期教会在教义和团契里合一。这等同于错误地认为外部合一是基于对耶稣主权的含糊陈述，这样各样错误的观点可以在教会中和平共存。因为他们渴望忠实于他们所领受的，最初的基督徒用洗礼的问答、信经和固定表述来判定一个人是否真正相信真道。
J. In the Early Church not everyone was permitted to worship and participate in the celebration of the Lord’s Supper. Those who were uninstructed or had not yet finished instruction were excluded from communion. Others were first examined to find out whether their beliefs were in harmony with what was taught in Scripture. The rule of the Ancient Church was: No participation in the sacred Means of Grace with heretics or schismatics. “The Early Church was never in doubt that unity in doctrine is a prerequisite of alter fellowship. No one who taught false doctrine might receive holy communion in an orthodox congregation: (Elert, p. 109). Basil the Great, Archbishop of Caesarea (c. 330-379), insisted that one who had formerly held heretical opinions must be instructed in the Nicene Creed if he whished to be admitted to an orthodox church and receive its sacraments.
在早期教会中，不是每一个人都被允许敬拜或参与圣餐礼的。那些未受教导的或未接受完教导的人禁止参与圣礼。其他人要首先接受考察从而了解他们的信仰是否与圣经教导一致。早期教会的规定是：不允许异端或分裂教会的人参与神圣的施恩具。“早期教会从不怀疑教义上的合一是改变交通的先决条件。教导错误教义的人不能在正统的教会中领受圣餐(埃勒特，109页)。”大巴西流，凯撒利亚的大主教(c. 330-379)，坚持曾经持有异端观点的人如果希望在正统教会中被承认和领受圣礼，应该被教导尼西亚信经。
K. Further, the Early Church held that the terms of the Creeds conveyed exactly the meaning of Scripture; they were a summary of Scripture. The Early Church held to the absolute authority of Scripture as the source of all doctrine. Cyril of Jerusalem (c. 315-386) declared:
With regard to the divine and saving mysteries of faith no doctrine, however trivial, may be taught without the backing of the divine Scriptures…..For our saving faith derives its force, not from capricious reasoning, but from what may be proved out of the Bible.
另外，早期教会认为这些信经中的条款准确地传达了圣经的意思；它们是对圣经的概括。早期教会作为所有教义的来源对于解释圣经有绝对的权威。耶路撒冷的西里尔(c. 315-386)称：
关于信心的神圣和救恩的神妙，哪怕是微小的事也没有不依靠神圣圣经的…因为我们救恩信心的力量不是来源于变化无常的评论，而是来源于可以用圣经证明的东西。
L. The three Ecumenical Creeds are an accurate expression of the teachings of God’s Word. So are all the other writings in our Lutheran Book of Concord. For this reason we can call them all our Confessions. When a man is ordained as a Lutheran pastor, he should subscribe to (swear to abide by and teach) the Lutheran Confessions because they agree with the Word of God. We call this a quia subscription to the Lutheran Confessions (quia is the Latin word meaning because). Some men, however, subscribe to the Confessions only insofar as they agree with Scripture. We call this a quatenus subscription (the Latin word quatenus means insofar as). This means that they are not sure that the Lutheran Confessions really teach God’s Word entirely. It also allows them to teach otherwise if they so desire. It is important to study the three Ecumenical Creeds and the other Lutheran Confessions so thoroughly that one has no doubts about their Scriptural teaching. Then a person can honestly make a quia subscription to them.
三大公信经是对圣经教导的准确表述。我们路德的协同书中其他写作也都是如此。由于这个原因我们称他们都是我们的信仰告白。当一个人被任命为路德宗牧师时，他应该认同 (宣誓坚持和教导) 路德宗信仰告白，because因为它们与上帝的话一致。我们称之为对路德宗信仰告白的quia因为认同(quia在拉丁语中是因为的意思)。然而，一些人认为insofar as只有信仰告白与圣经相符才能认同。我们称之为quatenus只有认同(quatenu在拉丁语中是只有的意思)。这说明他们不确信路德宗的认信是真正完整地教导圣经。这也使得他们按他们自己的意志教导别的内容。完整地的学习三大公信经和路德宗的其他认信非常重要，它使得一个人对他们关于圣经的教导没有疑问。然后这个人才能坦诚地对他们做出因为认同。
M. Earlier (p.2, E) we wrote that “the confession represents the basic core of the Christian Faith” and “was also a personal declaration of the faith of the individual.” As you can see we use the term faith in two ways. On the one hand we can say that the three creeds and other Lutheran Confessions express the Christian faith. On the other hand we also believe or have faith in Jesus and have faith that what the confessions say and the Bible says is true. And so we use the word faith in two ways. These two uses can again be illustrated from two Latin expressions about faith (the Latin word for faith is fides):
Fides quae (which) creditor – the faith which is believed
Fides qua (by which) creditor – the faith by which it is believed
The first meaning of faith focuses on what we believe, the teachings of the Bible. When we use the word faith in this way, we emphasize the teaching or truths contained in the Creeds and other Lutheran Confessions. The second use of the word faith (fides qua creditor) directs our attention to the faith in our hearts, the faith created by the Holy Spirit through the Gospel. Most of the time the Bible uses the word faith in this way. It stresses the complete confidence or trust in Christ for our salvation and also in the truth of what Scripture teaches. The three Creeds then contain the fides quae creditur. When we study them we strengthen our fides qua creditur (our saving faith or our trust in Christ as our personal savior).
之前(第二页E部分)，我们写道“信仰告白所代表的就是基督徒信仰的基本核心”并且“它也是单个基督徒的个人信仰宣告”。如你们所看到的，我们在两种情况下使用“信心”这个词。一方面我们会说三大信经和其他路德宗信仰告白表达了基督徒的信仰。另一方面我们也相信或信靠耶稣和相信信仰告白和圣经中所说的是真理。因此我们在两种情况下使用信心这个词。这两种用途可以从拉丁语中对信心的两种表述中再次被说明(拉丁语中信心这个词是fides)：
Fides quae (which) creditor – 所相信的信仰
Fides qua (by which) creditor – 由此所相信的信仰
信心的第一层意思关注的是我们所相信的，圣经的教导。当我们以这种方式使用信心这个词时，我们强调的是包含在这些信经和其他路德宗信仰告白中的教导和真理。信心这个词的第二种用途 (fides qua creditor) 关注的是我们心中由圣灵通过福音所创造的信心。圣经中大多数情况下都是以这种方式使用信心这个词。它强调具有完全的信心或完全相信基督给我们的救恩和圣经中教导的真理。因此三大信经具有fides quae creditur。当我们学习它们时，我们坚定了我们的fides qua creditur（我们救恩的信心或我们相信基督为我们个人的救主）。
N. But exactly what is the relationship between Holy Scripture and our Lutheran Confessions? Do we have two equal sources for our faith and doctrine ? Of course not! The Confessions are man-made, while the Bible is God-breathed. However, since the Confessions accurately summarize the teachings of the Bible, both give us the standards or norms for our teaching. The relationship between the two can again be expressed by two Latin phrases which show that both are norms (Latin norma) for teaching. The Bible is the norma normans (the norming norm), the norm which sets the standard. The Lutheran Confessions are the norma normata (the norm having been normed), the norm which has itself been set by Scripture. Thus Scripture sets the standard for Christian doctrine, and the Lutheran Confessions are a standard against which to judge Christian doctrines because they have been drawn up from the norm of Scripture. Clearly the Lutheran Confessions are very important, yet we do not elevate them to the level of God’s inspired Word.
但是到底圣经和我们的路德宗信仰告白之间有怎样的关系？我们拥有关于我们信心和教义的两个相平等的来源吗？当然不是！信仰告白是人所创造的，而圣经是神所默示的。然而，因为信仰告白准确地概括的圣经的教导，两者给了我们教导的标准和准则。两者之间的关系再一次通过两个拉丁语表示教导的准则(拉丁语norma)的短语来诠释。圣经是norma normans (the norming norm规范准则)，设立标准的准则。路德宗所有的信仰告白都是the norma normata (the norm having been normed被规范的准则)，这个准则本身由圣经所设立因此圣经为基督徒的教义设立标准，而且因为路德宗信仰告白是以圣经为准则设立的，因此它们被用作判定基督徒教义的标准。很明显，路德宗信仰告白是非常重要的，但是我们不能将它们放在与上帝所默示的话语的同等地位。
O. We will now begin our study of the three creeds which are a great heritage from the Early Church. Our Lutheran confessors showed their high regard for these creeds by making them a part of the Lutheran Confessions. These three creeds testify to the great truths of Scripture by which we live constantly before our God and before the world, and to which we are to give testimony of our faith (1 Pet. 3:15). Think of this next Sunday when you confess with your fellow Christians: I BELIEVE.
我们由此将开始学习早期教会留给我们的伟大遗产三大信经。我们路德宗的认信者通过将这些信经作为路德宗所有信仰告白的一部分，显示出了对它们的高度重视。这三大信经为圣经的伟大真理作了见证，由此我们在上帝和世界面前永远活着，并且我们也以它们为我们的信心作了见证(彼得前书3:15)。下个星期日当你与其他基督徒承认：我相信的时候就会想到这一点。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第一课作业题(Worksheet for Lesson One)我相信</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第一课作业题(Worksheet for Lesson One)我相信
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：2155
Worksheet for Lesson One: I Believe 第一课作业题：我相信
Introduction: 引言： Borrow your pastor’s copy of the Book of Concord and list its nine main writings below: 向你们的牧师借用协同书的副本并列出以下九个主要内容：
The Three &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; 三个
The Augsburg &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; 奥古斯堡
The Apology &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- 认罪
The Smalcald &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- 施马加登
Of the Power &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- 的权能
The Small &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- 小
The Large &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- 大
Epitome &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; 概论
Thorough Declaration &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- 详述宣言
Important Note: 重要提示： In this course we will be introducing a number of Latin and Greek words still used in theology today. On the chart that you will find in lesson eight, page eight, of the textbook lessons, write each one down together with its meaning. Use this chart for constant review. 在这一课中我们将介绍一些当今神学中仍在使用的拉丁语和希腊语单词。在课本第八课课文的第八页上的表格中写上每个词以及相应的含义。用这个表格进行不断复习。
Section A-D A-D 部分 1. In Romans 10:9-10, how does Paul describe the connection between saving faith and confession? 在罗马书10:9-10，保罗怎样描述救恩的信心与信仰告白之间的关系？
Define the following words and phrases: 给出以下单词和词组的定义： A. Creed 信经
B. Confession 信仰告白
C. Lutheran Confession 路德宗信仰告白
Section E. E 部分 1. What should be contained in a confession? 一篇信仰告白中应该包含什么内容？
Section F. F部分 1. Ask your pastor about your congregation’s baptism ceremonies for both adults and children. Are there questions asked and answered? 向你们的牧师询问你们教会中成人和婴孩洗礼仪式的内容。这些仪式中是否有问和答的内容？
Do they form a confession of faith? 这些问答是否形成一篇信仰告白？
Do they include all member of the Trinity? 这些问答是否包括三位一体中的所有位格？
Section G. G 部分 1. Of what did symbols or creeds become a mark or badge in the early church? 标志或信经中的什么内容成为了早期教会的记号或标记？
Describe how you think this happened. 请描述你对产生这样情况的看法。
Section H. H 部分 1. From the passages given in section H, why does Scripture repeatedly warn us about false teachers? 从H部分所提到的章节来看，为什么圣经中反复强调要警惕假文士？
Section I. I 部分 1. How were creeds used to determine church fellowship? 信经如何被用来决定教会的团契合一？
Section J. J部分 1. What were the requirements for participation in Holy Communion in the early church? 早期教会中参与圣餐礼的要求是什么？
2.How does this compare with church practice today? 与此相比，当今的教会是怎样做的？
A. in your congregation 在你们教会中
B. in most churches 在大多数教会中
Section K. K部分 1. What is the relationship between creeds and Scripture? 信经和圣经之间是什么关系？
Section L. L部分 1. Define the two Latin words: 给出以下两个拉丁语单词的定义：
quia 因为认同
quatenus 只有认同
2.How are these words related to a pastor’s ordination vow? 这两个词与牧师的就职宣誓有什么关系？
3.Which kind of vow would you make? 你会做这两种中的哪一种宣誓？
Section M. M 部分 1.Tell in your own words what the following Latin expressions about faith mean: 用你自己的语言解释以下拉丁语所表述的信心的含义：
A.Fides qua creditur所相信的信仰–
B.Fides quae creditur由此所相信的信仰–
2.Which kind of faith are we talking of when we say, “the Creeds summarize the Christian faith”? 当我们说“信经概括了基督徒的信仰”时，指的哪一种信仰？
3.Which kind are we talking of when we say, “I have faith in Jesus”? 当我们说“我信耶稣”时，指的哪一种信仰？
Section N. N 部分 1.What is the Latin expression for the standard which sets the standard? 表述设立标准的准则的拉丁语词组是什么？
2.What is the Latin expression for the standard which has been set? 表述这个准则是被设立的拉丁语词组是什么？
3.Which expression describes Holy Scripture? 哪一种表述描述的是圣经？
4.Which expression describes the Lutheran Confessions? 哪一种表述描述的是路德宗信仰告白？
5.Write several sentences below about the Lutheran Confessions, using properly 3 of the following 6 用以下6个词组中的3个合适的词组组成几句话来描述什么是路德宗信仰告白： quia, quatenus, fides qua creditur, fides quae creditur, norma normata, norma normans 因为认同，只有认同，所相信的信仰，由此所相信的信仰，设立标准的准则，这个准备是被设立的&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第二课 （lesson 2）使徒信经-历史背景</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第二课 （lesson 2）使徒信经-历史背景
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：2249
Lesson Two: The Apostles’ Creed – The Historical Background
第二课： 使徒信经-历史背景
A. The Apostles’ Creed is the most commonly used creed in our church. It is also one of the first pieces of Christian literature that children and adult Christians learn. Apart from the Lord’s Prayer, the Christian uses no set of words more frequently. It is the first of the three so-called “Ecumenical Creeds” or “Ecumenical Symbols” (the other two being the “Nicene Creed” and the “Athanasian Creed”). The word ecumenical comes from a Greek word meaning universal, general, or from the whole world. The word ecumenical is attached to these three Creeds because Christians in most parts of the world accept these Creeds as an accurate confession of their Christian faith.
使徒信经是我们教会中最常使用的信经。它也是儿童和成人基督徒的首要学习资料之一。基督徒除了主祷文与使徒信经以外，没有其他使用更加频繁。它是三部信经中的第一部，因此被称为 “普世信经”或 “普世标志” (其他两部为尼西亚信经和亚大纳西信经)。ecumenical这个词来自希腊语，意思为普世的，普遍的或世界范围的。用ecumenical这个词代表这三部信经是因为世界上大部分基督徒都承认这三部信经是基督徒信仰的准确告白。
B. For nearly two thousand years these Ecumenical Creeds have been standards of confession for Bible-believing Christians. In 1580, the Lutheran Church was accused of being a new church with new teachings. To demonstrate that it had that same teaching as the Ancient Church, Lutherans made these three Ecumenical Creeds part of their Confession, the Book of Concord. At least one of the three Creeds are quoted or mentioned in every Lutheran Confession in the Book of Concord.
这些信经作为相信圣经的基督徒的告白标准已经将近两千年了。1580年时，路德宗教会因为是带有新教导的年轻教会而被指责。为了说明这些教导与先前教会的教导是一致的，路德宗教徒将这三部普世信经作为他们的认信，协同书的一部分。这三部信经中至少有一部在协同书中每一个路德宗信仰告白中被引用或被提及。
C. The Creed which we use most often on Sunday is The Apostles’ Creed. However, there is no evidence that it comes word-for-word directly from the Twelve Apostles. The title, “Apostles’ Creed” (Symbolum Apostolorum in Latin) was already used by a council at the Italian City of Milan in A. D. 390. When we look at the teaching of the Apostles’ Creed we see that it agrees perfectly with the teaching of the Bible. So the name is still a good one. The Apostles’ Creed presents the teachings which Jesus gave to the apostles and which they have passed on to us. Luther said in a sermon on Trinity Sunday in 1535:
“Neither we nor the early fathers invented this confession of faith, but just as a bee collects honey from all kinds of beautiful flowers, so is the whole of the Apostles’ Creed a finely constructed summary of the whole of Scripture, the writings of the beloved prophets and apostles, for the benefit of children and simple Christians.”
我们在主日最常使用的信经就是使徒信经。然而，没有证据表明它的一字一句都直接来自十二使徒。标题，“使徒信经”(在拉丁语中是Symbolum Apostolorum) 已经于公元39年在意大利米兰的议会上被使用。当我们看使徒信经的教导时，我们可以看到它与圣经的教导是完全一致的。因此这个名称是合适的。使徒信经呈现了耶稣给使徒们以及由他们传递给我们的教导。路德曾在1535年三一节的一次讲道中说到：
“不是我们也不是我们的祖先发明了这个信仰告白，而是正如蜜蜂从各样美丽花朵中采取蜂蜜一样，使徒信经为了儿童和普通基督徒精确构建了圣经和我们所爱的先知及使徒写作的概要。”
D. We can find the foundation for our Apostles’ Creed in the words of Christ’s great commission:
All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit. (Matt. 28:18-19)
Essentially, the Apostles’ Creed is an expansion and explanation of Jesus’ command.
我们能在基督的大使命中找到使徒信经的根基：
天上地下所有的权柄都赐给我了。所以，你们要去，使万民作我的门徒，奉父、子、圣灵的名给他们施洗(马太福音28:18-19)。
实际上，使徒信经是耶稣诫命的延伸和解释。
E. The Apostles’ inspired writings contain many short direct statements of their faith. These served as short confessions of doctrine and told both Jew and Gentile what the Christian believed. Two good examples are in 1 Corinthians:
Yet for us there is but one God, the Father,
From whom all things came and from whom we live;
And there is but one Lord, Jesus Christ,
Through whom all things came and through whom we live. (8:6)
We were all baptized by one Spirit into one body
– whether Jews or Greeks, slave or free –
and we were all given the one Spirit to drink. (12:13)
Similar one-line arrangements can be made of Phil. 2:5-11, 1 Tim. 2:4-6, 1Tim. 3:16. Thus the Apostles could confess important Christian doctrine in short precise statements.
受到默示由使徒们写下的篇章包含许多关于他们信心的简短而直接的陈述。这些篇章被用作教义的简单告白并告知犹太人和外邦人基督徒所信的是什么。哥林多前书中两个很好的例子是：
然而我们只有一位神，就是父，
万物都本于他，我们也归于他；
并有一位主，就是耶稣基督，
万物都是藉着他有的，我们也是藉着他有的。(8:6)
我们不拘是犹太人，是希腊人，是为奴的，是自主的，
都从一位圣灵受洗，成了一个身体，饮于一位圣灵。(12:13)
类似的一句话式组合可以由腓立比书2:5-11，提摩太前书2:4-6，提摩太前书3:16组成。因此，使徒们能以简短而精确的陈述告白重要的基督徒教义。
F. Before anyone was baptized, the early Christians gave him instruction in the teachings of Jesus. Then, as part of the baptism ceremony, they were asked questions about their faith. The church father Hippolytus gives us the following description (描述) of part of the baptismal ceremony at Rome about A. D. 215:
When the one being baptized goes down into the water, the one baptizing puts his hand on him and says, “Do you believe in God, the Father Almighty?” And he that is being baptized says, “I believe.” Then putting his hand on the head of the one being baptized, he baptizes him once. Then he says, “Do you believe in Christ Jesus, the Son of God, who was born of the Holy Spirit, of the Virgin Mary, and was crucified under Pontius Pilate and died and was buried, and rose up again on the third day, alive from the dead, and ascended into heaven, and sat at the right hand of the Father, about to come to judge the living and the dead?” And when he replies, “I believe,” he is baptized a second time. And again he asks, “Do you believe in the holy Spirit and the holy Church and the resurrection of the flesh?” And he replies, “I believe.” And then he is baptized the third time.
So those who were baptized gave testimony to their knowledge of and trust in Christ and in the doctrines of the Gospel. The early baptismal ceremonies were similar to our present day ones. We also ask questions whose answers are given in the words of the Apostles’ Creed.
任何人在受洗之前，早期的基督徒们会给予这个人关于耶稣教导的指导。然后，作为洗礼仪式的一部分，他们会被问到关于他们信心的问题。牧师希波里图斯给了我们如下公元215年罗马洗礼仪式的部分描述：
当一个人在受洗时进入水中，施洗的人按手在他头上并说，“你相信上帝，全能的父吗？” 受洗的人说，“我相信。”接着施洗的人按手在受洗的人头上，为他施洗一次。然后施洗的人说，“你相信耶稣基督，上帝的儿子，由圣灵和童贞女马利亚所生；在本丢彼拉多手下受难，被钉于十字架，受死，埋葬，第三天从死人中复活；升天，坐在父的右边；将来必从那里降临，审判活人死人吗？”当受洗的人回答“我相信”，为他施洗第二次。施洗的人再问，“你相信圣灵，神圣教会和身体复活吗？”受洗的人回答“我相信”。就为他施洗第三次。
因此那些已经受洗的人见证了他们所了解的基督并相信基督和福音的教义。早期的一些洗礼仪式与我们现在的洗礼仪式类似。我们也用使徒信经作为提问的内容。
G. Many of these fragmentary baptismal creeds, all of which are somewhat similar, are found in the writings of the Early Church. The words vary somewhat from place to place, but most (following Matt. 28:18-19) have three parts, one for each member of the Trinity. As the years went by and the liturgy and customs became more fixed, these baptismal formulas also became more standardized. Individual words and clauses were added from time to time to show the true teaching as opposed to new heresies that arose.
我们能在早期教会的一些文章中发现许多洗礼信经中片段都有相似之处。不同信经中的词语做了些许改变，但是大多数(根据马太福音28:18-19)都是由三部分组成，每一部分各说的是三位一体中的一个位格。随着时间推移，礼拜仪式和习惯固定下来，洗礼的形式也变得更加规范化。个别词语和句子不时被添加进来从而体现真理的教导来抵挡新出现的异端。
H. One of the earliest local creeds is the ancient Roman baptismal creed (also called “The Old Roman Symbol”). Our oldest copy of it in Latin is from A. D. 404, set down in a commentary on the creed by the priest Rufinus. But the quote from Hippolytus (cited above) shows that a creed very similar to this one was already in use much earlier. We also have the witness of Marcellus, a bishop of Ancyra in Asia Minor, who was accused of heresy. To defend himself against those charges, he sent a creed almost identical to the Old Roman Symbol (but in the Greek language) to a council in Rome in the year 341. All of these versions are very close to the Apostles’ Creed we use today in our services. (Compare them on the chart in Appendix 2). Thus, while the Apostles’ Creed was not written directly by the apostles, it has a very ancient origin. Its main use was in the baptismal liturgy. It was used chiefly in the Western or Latin-speaking Church (Yugoslavia, Italy, Western Europe and the western part of North Africa). However, it was also known and quoted in the Eastern or Greek- speaking Church (Greece, Turkey, Syria, Palestine and Egypt).
当地最早的信经之一是罗马洗礼信经(也被称为 “古罗马信经”)。我们最早的拉丁文版罗马洗礼信经，于公元404年由祭司鲁菲纳斯写在了这部信经的注释中。但是从上文中引用的希波里图斯的话中可以看出在早于此信经很久以前就已经使用了与之非常相似的信经。我们还有马赛路，小亚西亚安吉拉的一位被控告为异端的主教作为见证。在公元341年他将一个几乎与古罗马信经相同的(不过是用希腊语写的)信经递交给在罗马的一个会议，用来作为他对那些指控的辩护。所有这些版本都与我们现在在我们的敬拜仪式中使用的使徒信经非常相似 (将他们与附件2中表格里的内容作比较)。因此，虽然使徒信经不是使徒们直接所写，但是它的来源可以追溯到很早以前。它主要是用于洗礼仪式中。尤其是用在西方或拉丁语教会中(南斯拉夫、意大利、西欧和北非西部)。然而，它在东方或希腊语教会中也被人们所了解和引用(希腊、土耳其、叙利亚、巴勒斯坦和埃及)。
I. Today, the Apostles’ Creed reads as follows:
I believe in God, the Father almighty,
maker of heaven and earth.
I believe in Jesus Christ, his only Son, our Lord;
who was conceived by the Holy Spirit,
born of the virgin Mary,
suffered under Pontius Pilate,
was crucified, died, and was buried.
He descended into hell.
The third day He rose again from the dead.
He ascended into heaven,
and is seated at the right hand of God the Father almighty.
From there he will come to judge the living and the dead.
I believe in the Holy Spirit,
the holy Christian Church, the communion of saints,
the forgiveness of sins,
the resurrection of the body,
and the life everlasting. Amen.
我们现在使用的使徒信经内容如下：
我信上帝，全能的父，
创造天地的主。
我信我主耶稣基督，上帝的独生子，
因圣灵感孕，
由童贞女马利亚所生，
在本丢彼拉多手下受难，
被钉于十字架，受死，埋葬。
降在阴间。
第三天从死人中复活。
升天，
坐在全能父上帝的右边。
将来必从那里降临，审判活人死人。
我信圣灵，
我信圣而公之教会，我信圣徒相通，
我信罪得赦免，
我信身体复活，
我信永生。阿们！
J. The actual text of the Apostles’ Creed, as we have it, dates from the early Middle Ages. It differs somewhat from the old Roman Creed in that it adds certain phrases from some of the other early creeds in use throughout Christendom. Note the following seven small changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;after the word “almighty,” it adds the phrase “maker of heaven and earth”;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“born from the Holy Spirit and the virgin Mary” becomes “conceived by the Holy Spirit, born of the virgin Mary”;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it inserts “He descended into hell” after “buried”;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it expands “at the right hand of the Father’ to “at the right hand of God the Father almighty”;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it replaces “holy Church” with “holy Christian Church”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it inserts after “Church” the phrase “the communion of saints”; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it adds at the end of the Creed the phase “the life everlasting.”
Clearly the Apostles’ Creed developed over several centuries as words and phrases were added until it reached the form in which we recite it today. We will speak more about these changes in the next chapter.
我们现在所用的使徒信经原文要追溯到早期中世纪时期。它与以前的罗马信经不同的是它添加了一些在所有基督徒中使用的其他早期信经中的一些短语。以下为七处细微的变化：&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在“全能的”这个词之后，添加了“创造天地的主”；&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“由圣灵和童贞女马利亚所生”改为了“因圣灵感孕，由童贞女马利亚所生”；&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在“埋葬”后面插入了“降在阴间”；&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;将“坐在父的右边”扩展为“坐在全能父上帝的右边”；&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;将“神圣教会”替换为“圣而公之教会”；&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在“教会”这个词之后插入“圣徒相通”；&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在信经的结尾添加了“我信永生”。
很显然，使徒信经经过了几个世纪的发展，词语和短语的添加形成了我们今天所诵读的形式。我们会在后面的章节谈到更多关于这些变化的内容。
K. In his Small Catechism, Luther wrote three little gems explaining the meaning of each of the three articles of the Apostles’ Creed. These explanations are still masterpieces in summarizing the Bible’s teaching in a clear and moving way.
在路德小问答中，他以个人所感对使徒信经三部分的意义分别进行了阐述。这些解释还是以清晰和令人感动的方式概括圣经教导的杰作。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第二课作业题(Worksheet for Lesson Two)使徒信经 - 历史背景</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-4/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第二课作业题(Worksheet for Lesson Two)使徒信经 - 历史背景
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：2206
Worksheet for Lesson Two: 第二课作业题：
The Apostles’ Creed – The Historical Background 使徒信经 - 历史背景
Section A. A部分
1.From what two Lutheran books do most Lutherans learn the Apostles’ Creed?
大多数路德宗信徒从路德的哪两本书学习到使徒信经？
Section B. B部分
1.What is the original meaning of the word ecumenical?
大公这个词的原有含义是什么？
2.What new meaning does it often have today?
这个词当今常常具有的一种新的含义是什么？
3.Which meaning does it have when we say the Apostles’ Creed in an ecumenical creed?
当我们说到大公信经中的使徒信经时，它具有的是哪种含义？
Section C. C部分
1.In what way is the title Apostles’ Creed an appropriate one?
从哪方面来说，使徒信经是一个合适的名称？
2.What does this title not mean?
这个名称不具有什么含义？
3.Luther spoke of bees and honey. Can you think of an illustration from the modern world to describe the relationship between the Apostles’ Creed and Scripture?
路德提到了蜜蜂与蜜。你是否能想到当今社会中的一个例子来说明使徒信经和圣经之间的关系？
Section E. E部分
1.Which thoughts from the 1 Corinthians passages are also found in the Apostles’ Creed?
哥林多前书的这些章节中哪些看法也出现在使徒信经中？
2.Read the 3 other passages cited. Which members of the Trinity do these passages especially confess?
阅读所引用的其他三个章节。这些章节中尤其强调三位一体中的哪个位格？
3.Can you see a similarity to the Apostles’ Creed in this regard?
从这方面来看，你能否在使徒信经中找到相似之处？
Section G. G 部分
1.Why do you think the baptism creeds differed in the various geographical areas?
你认为为什么洗礼信经根据地理位置的不同会有所不同？
Section H. H部分
1.If the Apostles’ Creed was used in the church already in A. D. 400, what does that indicate about its teachings?
关于使徒信经的教导，如果它在公元400已经被用于教会中，这说明了什么问题？&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第三课 （lesson 3）使徒信经的教义内容</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第三课 （lesson 3）使徒信经的教义内容
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：2218
Lesson Three: The Doctrinal Content of the Apostles’ Creed
第三课: 使徒信经的教义内容
A. The Apostles’ Creed is not a dry or lifeless piece of writing. It confesses great truths from God’s revealed word. And by its use as a “Symbol” (a token by which the true Christian can be known from the non-Christian or heretic), it has great doctrinal significance. Note that the Apostles’ Creed is divided into three paragraphs. Each begins by confessing faith in a member of the Trinity.
使徒信经不是一部枯燥、毫无生气的作品。它告白的是从上帝揭示的话语而来的真理。并且由于它作为“标志”的作用(可以作为区分真正基督徒与非基督徒或异端的标志)，使它具有了伟大的教义上的重要性。每一段都以对三位一体其中一位的信仰告白作为开始。
B. THE FIRST ARTICLE 第一部分
I believe in God, the Father almighty, maker of heaven and earth. This opening phrase takes us back to Genesis 1:1: “In the beginning God created the heaven and the earth.” The Apostles’ Creed does not contain the phrase “one God,” as do the Nicene and Athanasian Creeds. Yet, it clearly is based on the belief that there is but one God who is revealed as the Trinity in Christ’s baptismal command (Matt. 28:19).
我信上帝，全能的父，创造天地的主。开篇的第一句使我们想到了创世纪1:1：“起初神创造天地” 。 使徒信经不像尼西亚信经和亚大纳西信经，它没有 “一位上帝”这个词。然而，它很显然是基于对在基督洗礼的诫命中所揭示的三位一体独一上帝的相信(马太福音28:19)。
C. There is only one God, as opposed to the many gods of paganism (polytheism). In the Early Church, “Father” and “Almighty” were taken as two separate thoughts, each describing God. This follows the New Testament pattern which associated the term “Father” with God (Gal. 1:3; Phil. 2:11, 1 Thess. 1:1; 1 Peter 1:2). The emphasis was on God the Father; He is the Father in relation to the Son, who is begotten of the Father; He is the Father in goodness, as Luther says: “All this God does only because he is my good and merciful Father in heaven. And not because I have earned or deserved it.” (Small Catechism).
只有一位上帝，是针对相信有很多神的外邦人(多神论)而说的。在早期教会中，“父”和“全能的”被当作两个不同的思想，分别来描述上帝。这符合新约将 “天父”与上帝联系在一起的模式(加拉太书1:3；腓立比书2:11；帖撒罗尼迦前书1:1；彼得前书1:2)。这里强调的是上帝是父；在与从父来的子的关系中，他是父；他是满有慈爱的父，如路德所说的：“上帝所做的一切都是出于他作为父神的良善和怜悯，并非是我功劳或配得的”(路德小教义问答)。
D. The Early Church Fathers also emphasized the word “almighty” (the Greek word pantokrator), meaning “ruling over all.” As the early Christian Theophilus of Antioch wrote, “He rules and compasses all things.” Later on, the emphasis shifted. Today we connect “almighty” with “Maker of heaven and earth,” thinking more specifically of God’s ability to do all things. This power of God was demonstrated in his creation of the universe.
早期教会中的教父们也强调“全能的”这个词(希腊语中是pantokrator)，意思为“掌管一切”。如早期安提阿的基督徒提阿非罗所写，“他掌管和指导一切”。后来，强调的重点改变了。我们现在将“全能的”与“创造天地的主”连在一起，更确切地理解上帝所做一切事情的能力。上帝的这种能力在他创世中展现出来。
E. THE SECOND ARTICLE 第二部分
I believe in Jesus Christ, His only Son, our Lord. The deity of Jesus (that is, the fact that he is truly God himself) is confessed by calling Jesus God’s Son. Though the bible says that men can become the sons of God by adoption, Jesus is God’s son in a totally different way (John 1:14; 1:18; 3:16; 3:18; 1 John 4:9). All these passages point to the unique or special Sonship of Jesus. He is Gods “only” son from the very beginning. Jesus Christ alone is one with the Father and complete in His knowledge of the Father.
我信我主耶稣基督，上帝的独生子。基督的神性(即，事实上他就是真正的上帝本身)通过称耶稣上帝的儿子而被承认。虽然圣经说人通过领养可以成为上帝的子女，但是耶稣以完全不同的方式成为上帝的儿子(约翰福音1:14；1:18；3:16；约翰福音4:9)。所有这些章节都指出耶稣独一或特殊的儿子的名分。唯独耶稣基督与父一体并完全认识父。
F. The opening words of the Creed also direct our attention to Jesus’ office (that is, his appointed duty as the Mediator between God and man). The name “Christ” focuses our attention on the work He came to do. The Greek word Christos means the anointed one. By calling Jesus “the Christ” we are confessing that he is the great Prophet, Priest and King promised in the Old Testament, the one and only Savior of the world. The word “Lord” translates the Greek Kyrios, the Greek Old Testament translation for Jehovah, the living God of Israel. Thus it reinforces the confession of Jesus as true God. Paul also states that, “No one can say, ‘Jesus is Lord’ except by the Holy Spirit” (1 Cor. 12:3). Thus when we confess Jesus to be “our Lord” we acknowledge both his divinity and our Spirit-created faith in Him.
信经开篇还使我们注意到耶稣的职责(即，他被差派作为上帝与人之间中保的职责)。“基督”这个名字要我们关注的是他到来后所做的工作。希腊语中Christos是受膏者的意思。通过称耶稣为“基督”，我们承认他是旧约中应许的大先知、大祭司和大君王，和这个世上唯一的救主。“主”这个词在希腊语中的翻译为Kyrios，希腊语旧约对耶和华的称呼，以色列永活的上帝。因此它强调了认耶稣为真正的上帝。保罗也陈述说，“若不是被圣灵感动的，也没有能说‘耶稣是主’的”(哥林多前书12:3)。所以当我们认耶稣是“我们的主”的时候，我们承认他的神性和我们在他里面由圣灵创造的信心。
G. Who was conceived by the Holy Spirit, born of the Virgin Mary.
因圣灵感孕，由童贞女马利亚所生。
This is just what we are told in Luke 1:31 and 35. Before the world was created or anything else existed, the Son of God was God along with His Father. Now, however He was to become incarnate (from the Latin words for in and flesh). This means that he took on the nature and form of a human being. We thus call Jesus’ act of becoming a man his incarnation. Yet unlike every other man, Jesus was without a human father. He was born of a virgin mother. The Holy Spirit foretold (预先告知) this about the Savior in the Old Testament Scripture (Isaiah 7:14; Matt. 1:23). Because this miracle goes beyond all our understanding, many modern people (even some who call themselves Christians) reject this particular Bible teaching.
这是路加福音1:31和35节告诉我们的。在创世或任何事物存在以前，上帝的儿子就与他的父同在。然而他将道成肉身(来自拉丁语中in和flesh这两个词)。这意味着这意味着他取了人的属性并成为了人。我们因此称耶稣成为人的行为为道成肉身。但是和任何其他人不同的是，耶稣的父不是普通的人。他由作为童贞女的母亲所生。在旧约中，圣灵预先告知了关于救主的这件事(以赛亚书7:14；马太福音1:23)。因为这个神迹超越我们所有人的理解能力，当今许多人(甚至是一些称他们自己是基督徒的人)拒绝承认圣经中教导的这一点。
H. In the three Ecumenical Creeds, the confession of the doctrine of the Trinity of God and the incarnation (his becoming human) of the second person of the Trinity go hand in hand. Both opponents outside the church and false teachers within it made these two teachings the center of their attacks. As we continue our study, notice how the next two creeds become more and more precise about these two teachings: 1) that there is a unity or one-ness of God, one Creator yet three persons of equal wisdom and goodness, and 2) that the Son of God took on human nature in the womb of the Virgin Mary. When you study the Augsburg Confession, you will see this emphasized in Articles I and III.
在三大公信经中，上帝三位一体的教义与三位一体中的第二位道成肉身(成为人)的教义的告白是结合在一起的。教会外的敌人和教会里的假文士把这两个教导作为他们攻击的重点。当我们继续学习会发现后面两部信经如何在这两点的教导上变得越来越精确：1) 上帝的合一或合而为一，一位创世主中三个同等智慧和良善的位格，2) 上帝的儿子在童贞女马利亚腹中时取了人的属性。当你学习奥古斯堡信条时，你会看到在它的第一和第三条款中强调了这一点。
I. After his incarnation, Jesus also voluntarily underwent a state of humiliation. To save us he willingly gave up the use of his divine majesty and took on the form of a servant during his life on earth. Jesus “emptied himself, taking the form of a servant” (Phil. 2:7, literal translation) and becoming like all other men. He did this so that he could do and suffer all that was necessary for our salvation (Heb. 2:17). Though his miracles show that he still had his divine power, he did not make full and continuous use of it. From his conception until his death, Jesus lived as one of us.
在他道成肉身之后，耶稣还自愿保持卑微的样子。为了拯救我们他甘愿放弃使用他的神权并且以仆人的样子在世上生活。耶稣“倒空自己，取了奴仆的形象”(腓立比书2:7，直译)并成为与其他人一样的样式。他这么做是为了我们的救恩做所有需要他做和遭受的一切事情(希伯来书2:17)。尽管他的神迹显示他仍具有神的能力，但是他没有完全不断地使用它。从他在母腹中直到他死时，耶稣就像我们中的一位一样生活。
J. Suffered under Pontius Pilate, was crucified, died and was buried.
在本丢彼拉多手下受难，被钉于十字架，受死，埋葬。
St. Paul exhorts the young preacher Timothy in the sight of God and before Jesus Christ “who while testifying before Pontius Pilate made the good confession” (1Tim. 6:13). Here, and especially in the Gospels, the redeeming work of Christ is placed into the center of world history. Pontius Pilate was the Roman governor of Judea (26-36 A. D.) at the time of Jesus’ crucifixion. Christianity is rooted in history. The Biblical authors wrote about real historical events. Rufinus, the first man to write a commentary on our Creed (404 A. D.), noticed how important this was: “Those who handed down the Creed showed great wisdom in emphasizing the actual date at which these things happened. In this way there could be no uncertainty or vagueness to upset the stability of what was handed down to us.” St. Paul singles out the crucifixion as a significant aspect of Christ’s Passion (1 Cor. 2:2, Gal. 3:1), as St. Peter does also (Acts 2:23; Acts 4:10). Paul also includes Christ’s burial (1 Cor. 15:4).
圣徒保罗在上帝和耶稣基督面前劝勉年轻的牧师提摩太“在向本丢彼拉多作过那美好见证的基督耶稣”(提摩太前书6:13)。此处，同时尤其是在福音书中，基督救恩的工作被放在世界历史的中心位置。本丢彼拉多是在耶稣被钉十字架时罗马帝国犹太地区的长官(公元26-36年)。基督教植根于历史。圣经的作者们写下了真实的历史事件。鲁菲纳斯，第一位为我们的信经写评论的人(公元404年)，注意到这一点有多么重要：“那些传承信经的人在强调这些事情发生的实际日期上显示出了大智慧。通过这样的方式就不会存在不确定或含糊的内容使我们为传递给我们的东西的确定性感到不安”。圣徒保罗将耶稣被钉十字架作为基督受难的重要方面来强调(哥林多前书2:2；加拉太书3:1)，圣徒彼得也是这样做的(使徒行传2:23；使徒行传4:10)。保罗还强调了基督的被埋葬(哥林多前书15:4)。
K. He descended into hell. The third day He rose again from the dead. He ascended into heaven, and is seated at the right hand of God the Father almighty.
降在阴间。第三天从死人中复活。升天。坐在全能父上帝的右边。
With these words, the Creed confesses the second important part of Jesus’ work, what we call the state of exaltation of our Savior. This part of Jesus’ mission began with His return to life. But before He gives proof to men that He was again alive, He descended into hell (1 Pet. 3:18-20; Col 2:15). In hell he showed to the devil and his angels along with the spirits of those who during their life had been disobedient to the Word of God what a great victory he had won. Christ appeared before them as Lord over death and life and as Victor over death and Satan.
信经的这几句话告白了耶稣工作的第二个重要部分，我们称之为我们救主被高举。耶稣这部分工作开始于他复活的时候。但是在他向人们证明他复活之前，他将在阴间(彼得前书3:18-20；歌罗西书2:15)。在地狱里，他向魔鬼和他的天使以及那些在世时违背上帝话语的人的灵魂显示了他获得的伟大胜利。基督作为掌握生和死的主以及战胜死亡和撒旦的胜利者在他们面前显现。
L. The Lutheran Formula of Concord, using words from a sermon by Luther, urges us “not to concern ourselves with high and abstract speculations about how this occurred.” Rather, “we must only believe and cling to the Word. Then we shall retain the heart of this article and derive from it the comfort that neither hell nor the devil can take captive or harm us or any believer in Christ.” (Formula of Concord, Solid Declaration IX, 3).
路德协同信条用路德一次讲道中的话劝诫我们“不要用我们想入非非和抽象的推测考虑这是如何发生的”。而是，“我们必须只相信和依靠圣经。因而我们应该记住这个信条的核心并从中获得安慰，这样无论是地狱或是魔鬼都不能夺走或伤害我们或任何在基督里的信徒”(协同信条，完全宣言第九部分，3)。
M. Today this statement of the Creed is denied by many people and denominations, since they believe there is no hell for condemned souls. One new translation of the Apostles’ Creed being prepared for use in liberal churches has the ambiguous sentence, “He descended to the dead.” This leaves out any mention of hell.
信经中这样的陈述被当今许多人和教派所否认，因为他们认为没有定灵魂罪的地狱。自由教会中准备使用的新版使徒信经中一句带有歧义的话是，“他降在死人中”。这句话没有提到任何关于地狱的事。
N. Christ’s resurrection from the dead is the central teaching of the Gospel (1 Cor. 15; Rom. 1:4; Rom. 4:25). Jesus rose from the dead on the first day of the week (Sunday), and ever since Christians have gathered for worship on Sunday and confessed their faith: “The third day He arose again from the dead.” Jesus resurrection is the heart of all apostolic teaching and preaching. Still today the church proclaims the resurrection and its meaning to the world – that God was in Christ reconciling the world unto Himself (2 Cor. 5:19-21).
基督从死里复活是福音教导的中心(哥林多前书15；罗马书1:4；罗马书4:25)。耶稣在那一周的第一天(星期日)从死人中复活，并且因此基督徒从那时起在星期日聚集在一起敬拜耶稣和认信：“第三天从死人中复活”。耶稣的复活是所有使徒教导和传道的重点。直到今天，教会称复活和它对于世人的意义为-上帝在基督中与世人和好(哥林多后书5:19-21)。
O. Closely linked to this confession of Christ’s resurrection are two clauses: “He ascended into heaven,” and He “is seated at the right hand of God the Father almighty.” These are almost word-for-word quotations of 1 Peter 3:22 (cf. also Rom. 8:34; Col. 3:1; Eph. 1:20; Heb. 1:3). After Christ had shown Himself to His disciples for forty days, He was taken up into the heavens (Acts 1:9). Although He withdrew His visible presence from them, He promised to remain with them to the end of the world (Matt. 28:20). The expression “is seated at the right hand of God the Father Almighty” signifies that this Son of God who had taken the form of a servant and become a human being like us was now again taking up or assuming the full divine glory and dominion. Together with Him our Brother, we to are exalted. However we have to remember that because he had never stopped being God, our Savior as the Son of God had always been at the right hand of God, His Father.
与基督复活的告白紧密相关的两句是：“升天”和“坐在全能父上帝的右边”。这两句几乎上是逐字引用的彼得前书3:22(参看罗马书8:34；歌罗西书3:1；以弗所书1:20；希伯来书1:3)。在基督向他的门徒显现四十天后，他被接回天上(使徒行传1:9)。尽管他不再以可见的形象与他们在一起，他应许与他们同在直到世界的末了(马太福音28:20)。“坐在全能父上帝的右边”的表述显示出上帝的儿子在取了奴仆的形象并成为像我们一样的人之后，现在又接受了或承担了完全的神的荣耀和权利。我们也与我们的这位弟兄一起被高举。然而我们应该记住因为他从没有停止过作为上帝，我们的救主作为上帝的儿子永远在上帝，他的父的右边。
P. This glorious majesty was also communicated to the human nature at His Incarnation. But during His humiliation, the Savior refrained from making full use of it; but now as our brother, a human being as we are, Jesus Christ has been exalted to the highest majesty and power over all things. The Divine-Human Savior, the son of God, and the Brother of sinners governs and rules all things for the glory of His own name and for the comfort and safety of His church here on earth.
荣耀的权柄与人性在他道成肉身时得以连结。但是在他取了卑微形象期间，他没有完全使用他的权柄，而现在作为我们的弟兄，一个和我们一样的人，耶稣基督被高举拥有超越一切的最高权柄和能力。神人二性的救主，上帝的儿子和罪人的弟兄为了他名的荣耀和他在世上的教会得安慰和安全而管辖和治理一切。
Q. From there He will come to judge the living and the dead.
将来必从那里降临，审判活人死人。
As a result of our Savior’s glorious victory, His final visible return is confessed in the last words of the Second Article. Later some doubters might ask the question, “Where is the promise of His coming?” (2 Pet. 3:2-4). The angel gave the answer to that question at Jesus’ Ascension (Acts 1:11). So the Apostles’ Creed simply repeats as its faith that this Jesus was “appointed as judge of the living and the dead” (Acts 10:42, cf.2 Tim. 4:1; 1 Peter 4:5). This section of the Apostles’ Creed confesses and rejoices in the Scriptural revelation of the eternal Son of God coming in the flesh, His triumph over death and the devil, and His second coming on the clouds of heaven on the Last Day.
由于我们救主荣耀的胜利，我们在第二部分的最后一句话中告白了他最终可见的归来。后来的一些质疑者会问这样的问题，“主要降临的应许在哪里呢？”(彼得后书3:2-4)。天使在耶稣升天时给出了这个问题的答案(使徒行传1:11)。因此使徒信经只是简单地复述了这样的信心即耶稣是“神所立定的，要作审判活人死人的主”(使徒行传10:42，参看提摩太后书4:1；彼得前书4:5)。使徒信经的这一部分告白并喜悦上帝的儿子成为肉身、他超越死亡和魔鬼的胜利、他在末日在天上云彩中的第二次到来的圣经启示。
R. THE THIRD ARTICLE 第三部分
The Third Article simply lists and summarizes a number of doctrines, which teach us through whom and by what means God pours out His grace upon all believers and the Church. The first one, I believe in the Holy Spirit, completes the confession of the Trinitarian baptismal formula commanded by Christ (Matt. 28:19). The Holy Ghost is put on the same level with the Father and the Son. The Holy Spirit is distinct from the Father and the Son, but the divine being is not split into three parts, each person being one-third of the Godhead. We are baptized into the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit, and these three are equal in authority, dignity, and essence (or being).
第三条款简单地列举并概括了一系列教导上帝通过谁以及用什么方式将他的恩典倾注在所有信徒和教会上的教义。第一句，我信圣灵，使基督所吩咐的三位一体洗礼论的认信得以完全(马太福音28:19)。圣灵被置于与圣父和圣子同等的地位。圣灵不同于圣父和圣子，但是神性没有被分为三部分，每一个位格都是三个神格中的一位。我们以圣父、圣子和圣灵的名受洗，并且这三位在权力、荣耀和实体(或本质)上是同等的。
S. The holy Christian Church. From this point on the Apostles’ Creed confesses the activity of the Holy Spirit. He creates the church. The word “church” is a translation of the Greek ekklesia. The Church of God consists in the believers whom the Holy Spirit brings to faith by His powerful working through the Gospel and the Sacraments. The Scriptures declare that the Holy Spirit alone accomplishes the entire work of conversion (1 Cor. 6:11; 1 Cor. 12:3; Titus 3:5). The Holy Spirit creates faith through the Word and Sacraments (Rom. 1:16; Rom. 10:17; 1 Thess. 1:5; 1 Thess. 2:13). For this reason too the church is called “holy.” This word points to Eph. 5:25-27. In these words Paul describes the church of Jesus Christ as being justified, cleansed and made holy by the Word of God and Baptism.
我信圣而公之教会。从这个角度看，使徒信经承认圣灵的活动。他创立了教会。“教会”这个词是从希腊语ekklesia翻译而来。上帝的教会由圣灵通过福音和圣礼充满能力的做工带来信心的信徒们组成。圣经宣告了唯独圣灵完成了使人信主的全部工作(哥林多前书6:11；哥林多前书12:3；提多书3:5)。圣灵通过圣经和圣礼建立信心(罗马书1:16；罗马书10:17；帖撒罗尼迦前书1:5；帖撒罗尼迦前书2:13)。也是由于这个原因教会被称为“圣”。这个词指向以弗所书5:25-27。在这几节中保罗形容耶稣基督的教会是藉着圣经和洗礼被称为义，被洗净并成圣。
T. The first version of the Apostles’ Creed, as we have it from Rufinus (404 A. D.), had only the words “the holy church.” Later the word “catholica” (a word used in both Greek and Latin) was added. The word “catholic” meant “general, or universal.” Thus the “holy catholic church” meant God’s church that had spread throughout the whole world. Later, however, “catholic church” came to mean Roman Catholic Church, the church controlled by the Pope in Rome. Therefore, since the 15th century, Lutherans and many other Christians have used the words “I believe in the Holy Christian Church” to testify that they believe that all Christians everywhere (not just in the Roman Catholic Church or their own denomination) are part of God’s kingdom.
使徒信经的最初版本，就是我们从鲁菲纳斯(公元404年)那里获得的，只有“圣教会”这个词。后来，“catholica”(这个词被用于希腊语和拉丁语中)被添加进来。“catholica”这个词的意思是“普遍的或全世界的”。因此“圣而普世之教会”的意思是上帝的教会在全世界兴起。然而，之后“公之教会”变成了代表被罗马教皇统治的罗马天主教。因此，从十五世纪开始，路德宗教徒和许多其他基督徒开始使用“我信圣而公之教会”来表明他们相信所有地方的信徒(不只是罗马天主教会或其他教派的信徒)都是上帝的国的一部分。
U. The communion of saints. This phrase in our version of the Creed, “the communion of saints,” is usually looked on as an appositive, that is, as a description of the previous words. It emphasizes that the “holy Christian church” is actually the “communion” or gathering of those who have been justified by faith and are therefore counted blameless (or “saints”) before God. This fits well, not only with Paul’s words in Eph. 5, but also with 1 Cor. 1:2, where he calls the church those “that are sanctified in Christ Jesus, called to be saints” (cf. also 2 Cor. 1:1).
我信圣徒相通。我们使用的这个版本的信经中，“圣徒相通”这个短语常被看作是对前面所说的话的积极描述。它强调“圣而公之教会”实际上是“相通的”或是那些因信称义并因此在上帝面前成为无可指摘的人(或 “圣徒”)的集合。这不仅非常符合保罗在以弗所书第五章中的话，也符合哥林多前书第一章第二节中说到的他呼召的教会就是那些 “在基督耶稣里成圣，蒙召作圣徒的”(参看哥林多后书1:1)。
V. But this phrase, “the communion of saints,” was not in the early Roman baptismal formula. It was a later addition. While the Apostles’ Creed was used chiefly in the Roman, or Western Church, it seems that this phrase came into the Creed from the Greek or Eastern Church and that originally it may have meant “participation in the holy things.” This would make it a reference to the Means of Grace, the Gospel, Baptism, and especially the Lord’s Supper. This, too, would fit very well, not only with the words of Scripture but also with the doctrine of the Ancient Church, which taught that the Church of God is created by the Holy Spirit working through the Means of Grace.
但是“我信圣徒相通”这个短语，不存在于早期罗马洗礼圣经中。它是后来被添加进去的。而使徒信经主要被用于罗马或西方教会，因此这个短语似乎是由希腊或东方的教会添加到信经中的而且它原本可能具有 “参与神圣的事情”。这使它成为施恩具福音、洗礼并且尤其是圣餐的一个参考。同时，这不仅非常符合圣经的话语，也符合早期教会的教义中教导的上帝的教会是由圣灵通过施恩具创造的。
W. The Christian is holy or a “saint” before God because through faith in the atoning work of Jesus Christ he is declared righteous by God. Still he sins much every day to the end of his life. Through the Gospel, Baptism, Absolution, and the Sacrament of the Altar he is constantly offered and assured of the forgiveness of sins. So, he simply confesses, “I believe in the forgiveness of sins.”
靠着在被上帝称为义的耶稣基督赦罪工作里的信心，基督徒在上帝面前是圣洁的或是一个“圣徒”。但是他每天直到去世的那天仍然犯很多的罪。通过福音、洗礼、赦罪和不断提供给他的圣餐礼以及对罪得赦免的确信，他只须承认，“我信罪得赦免”。
X. With this assurance from God, the Christian boldly declares, “I believe in the resurrection of the body and the life everlasting.” The Scriptures, both in the Old and New Testaments, clearly teach the resurrection of the body (Job 19:26; Dan. 12:2; John 5:28-29; 11:23-26; 1 Cor. 15:12; 1 Thess. 4:16), that is, that the soul will be united with the same body which died. When it is reunited, however, it will be an immortal and perfect body.
有了从上帝来的保证，基督徒大胆宣告，“我信身体复活，我信永生”。圣经的旧约和新约中都明确地教导身体复活(约伯记 19:26；但以理书 12:2；约翰福音5:28-29；11:23-26；哥林多前书15:12；帖撒罗尼迦前书4:16)，就是，灵魂将与已死的身体结合。而当它重新结合时，它将成为不朽和完美的身体。
Y. Apparently in the Early Church some worried that the resurrection of their bodies might be like that of Lazarus, who rose only to die again, and not like Christ, who rose never to die again but to live forever. Therefore St. John Chrysostom, the greatest preacher of the Early Church, explained the last phrase of the Creed in this beautiful way: “After you have said FORGIVENESS OF SINS, you go on to confess the RESURRECTION OF THE DEAD…After that, since a mention of the resurrection is not sufficient to bring out the whole teaching (for many men who have arisen from the grave have died again, as the example of some Old Testament people, Lazarus, and the people who rose at the time of the crucifixion shows), you are also encourage to confess, AND IN THE LIFE EVERLASTING.”
很显然，早期教会中有些人担心他们身体的复活也许只是像拉撒路一样从死亡中再一次复活，而不是像基督一样复活而不再死亡得到永生。因此，早期教会最伟大的牧师，圣徒约翰克里索斯托以这样优美的方式解释了信经中最后一个短语：“在你已经说过我信罪得赦免之后，你进一步承认我信身体复活…然后，由于已经提到了复活就不需要拿出全部的教导(因为许多从坟墓中复活的人已经经过了第二次死亡，例如旧约中的一些人，拉撒路和耶稣被钉十字架时显现的复活的人)，而且作为鼓励承认，我信永生”。
Z. AMEN 阿们！
“Amen.” The Holy Christian Church ends its confession with the word “Amen.” This was a Hebrew word meaning “it is reliable or true.” “Amen” was used in the church as a confession of certainty: “Surely,” “in very truth.” A Christian’s faith is built upon the promises of the God of Truth (Is. 65:16), upon the Lord Christ who calls Himself “the Amen” (Rev. 3:14), and in whom all the promises of God are Yes and Amen (2 Cor. 1:20). Surely what God says and promises will come true for every believer!
“阿们。”圣洁的基督教会以“阿们”这个词作为认信的结束。这是一个希伯来语单词，意思是“这是可信的或真实的”。“阿们”用于教会中作为对所确信的事的承认：“当然”，“的的确确”。一个基督徒的信心是建立在上帝应许的真理之上的(以赛亚书65:16)，也因主基督称自己“阿们”(启示录3:14)，而且在基督里上帝所有的应许都是肯定的和阿们(哥林多后书1:20)。当然对于所有信徒来说，上帝所说和所应许的都将实现。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第三课作业题</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-6/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第三课作业题
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：2117
Worksheet for Lesson Three: 第三课作业题：
The Doctrinal Content of the Apostles’ Creed 使徒信经的教义内容
Section C. C 部分
1.What might be the difference in emphasis between the words “Our Father” in the Lord’s Prayer and the words “the Father” in the Apostles’ Creed? 在主祷文中强调“我们的父”以及在使徒信经中强调“父”会有怎样不同的效果？
Section D. D部分 1.Why is it good that the Creed includes the word “almighty” (pantokrator) as well as confessing that God made heaven and earth? 为什么信经中包含“全能的”(pantokrator)这个词并承认上帝创造了天地是有好处的？
Section E. E部分
1.In what way are each of the following “God’s sons”: 从哪方面来看，以下的词都是指“上帝的儿女”：
A.  every person: 每个人
B.  Christians: 基督徒
C.  Jesus: 耶稣
Section F. F部分
1.What do we mean when we call Jesus: 当我们用以下名称称呼耶稣时，所包含的意思是什么：
A.  our Lord? 我们的主
B.  Christ? 基督
Section G. G部分
1.What does the word incarnation mean? 道成肉身这个词的含义是什么？
Section I. I部分
1.Define what we mean by Christ’s humiliation. 给出基督降卑的含义。
2.When did it begin and end? 它从何时开始以及何时结束？
Section J. J部分
1.Why do you think the Creed skips from Jesus’ birth to the last week of his life? 你认为信经中为什么从耶稣的降生直接跳跃他在世上的最后一周？
2.If you had the opportunity to add 1 additional line to the Creed to fight against modern false teachings, what would you add and why? 如果你有机会在信经中添加一行来反对当今的错误教导，你会添加什么内容？为什么？
Section K. K部分
1.What is meant by Christ’s exaltation? 基督的升高是什么意思？
2.When did it begin and end? 它从何时开始以及何时结束？
3.Which facts about Christ’s descent into hell are taught in the following passages: 以下章节中教导了哪些关于基督降在阴间的事实： A.1 Peter 3:18-20 彼得前书 3:18-20 B.Col. 2:15 歌罗西书 2:15
Section M. M 部分
1.In what way are the words He descended into hell more important today than ever? 从哪方面来看，他降在阴间这句话在当今比以往更重要？
2.What does this say about the use of the creeds over a long period of time? 信经历经了很长时间的使用说明了什么？
Section N. N部分
1.How often do Christians celebrate Christ’s resurrection? 基督徒们多久庆祝一次基督徒的复活？
2.What did early Christians call Sunday? (cf. Rev. 1:10) 早期的基督徒称主日为什么？(参看启示录1:10 )
Section O. O部分 1.What does the expression right-hand man mean today? 如今右手边的人所代表的是什么意思？
2.In what way is this similar or dissimilar to Jesus being at God’s right hand? 从哪方面来说，它相似于或不同于耶稣在上帝的右边？
Section Q. Q 部分
1.How will Jesus judge the living and the dead? 耶稣将来如何审判活人和死人？
2.What will be the Father and the Spirit’s role? 圣父和圣灵将来会发挥怎样的作用？
Section R. R 部分
1.What might you conclude from the fact that so little is said in the Creed about who the Holy Spirit is? 你从信经中说到的一点关于圣灵的事实中可以得出什么结论？
Section S. S部分
1.In what way is the church holy? 从哪方面来说，教会是圣洁的？
2.The word church has many different meanings. Because it is called holy here, what meaning or church is meant? 教会这个词有很多不同的含义。因为它在这里被称为圣洁，这个教会的含义或所指的是什么？
Section T. T 部分
1.What was the original meaning of the word catholic? 天主教这个词原有的含义是什么？
2.What is the more common meaning today? 当今这个词更普遍的含义是什么？
3.In what way is the whole church catholic? 从哪方面来说，整个教会是普世的？
Section U. U 部分
1.What are the 2 possible meanings of the phrase communion of saints? 圣徒相通这个短语可能具有的两个含义是什么？
A.
B.
2.Which do you think fits best? 你认为哪一个含义最合适？
Section W. W 部分
1.Put an X in front of the statement you think is more accurate: 在你认为以下更准确的一个表述前打X：
&amp;mdash;A. The Lutheran Church doesn’t believe in saints. 路德宗教会不信圣徒。
&amp;mdash;B. Everyone in the Church is a saint. 教会中的每个人都是圣徒。
2.Explain your choice. 解释你的选择。
Section X. X 部分
1.Some people would rather shorten the Creed to say only the resurrection and the life everlasting. Why do you think they might want to omit the words of the body? 一些人宁愿将信经缩减成为我信复活，我信永生。你认为这些人为什么想要删去身体这个词？
2.Which of the cited Bible passages would you use to defend the words resurrection of the body? 引用圣经中的哪些章节可以用来捍卫我信身体复活这句话？
Section Y. Y 部分
1.The Creed confesses a belief in everlasting life but not everlasting death, even though this is also a biblical teaching. What might this tell us about the use of the Creed? 虽然永久的死亡是圣经中的一个教导，但是信经承认的是永生中而不是永久死亡中的信仰。这教导了我们怎样使用信经？
Section Z. Z 部分
1.In what way is the final word of the Creed (Amen) much more important than just saying the end? 从哪方面来看，信经中最后一个词(阿们) 比仅仅说结束重要得多？
2.Why is it an especially appropriate way to end a creed? 为什么它是结束信经的一种特别合适的方式？&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第四课 （lesson 4）尼西亚信经的历史背景</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第四课 （lesson 4）尼西亚信经的历史背景
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：2299
Lesson Four: Historical Background to the Nicene Creed
第四课： 尼西亚信经的历史背景
A. As the Christian Church grew after Pentecost, opposition to Christianity came from both Romans and Jews. For a time there were fearful persecutions which the early Christians endured because of their faith. But with the rise of the first Christian emperor, Constantine (ruled the western half of the empire beginning in 312 and the entire empire from 324-337), the church began to achieve social acceptance and respectability. However, opposition to the Christian faith continued. During this time such opposition took the form of false teachings. They threatened to destroy the true teaching of the Bible and to split the church itself. One of these early controversies concerned the central doctrine of the Bible and Christianity, the doctrine of the God. While it actually had to do with the Biblical doctrine of the Trinity, the immediate theological issue was the relation of the Word or the second person of the Trinity to the Godhead. It raised two very basic questions: Was Jesus Christ really God? In what way if he were God, did God become a human being?
当基督教会在五旬节之后开始壮大时，在罗马人和犹太人中出现了仇视基督教的人。有一段时间早期的基督徒由于他们的信仰遭受了可怕的迫害。但是随着第一个基督徒皇帝，康斯坦丁的即位(从公元312年开始统治西方帝国的一半并于公元324-337年统治整个帝国)，教会开始获得社会的承认和尊重。然而，仇视基督徒信仰的实力继续存在。这个时期的敌对形式为错误教导。他们威胁要毁掉圣经的真理教导并分裂教会。其中一个早期的争论关注的是圣经和基督教的核心教义，上帝的教义。然而它的确与三位一体的圣经教义有关，最直接的神学问题就是关于道的关系或者说是上帝三位一体中第二位的关系。出现的两个最基本的问题是：耶稣基督真的是上帝吗？如果他真是上帝，上帝以怎样的方式成为人？
B. The Old Testament had particularly emphasized the unity or oneness of God (monotheism) over against the multiple gods (polytheism) of the pagan religions. The New Testament carries the same emphasis (Mark 12:29,32). At the same time, the New Testament clearly teaches the Trinity of God, that is, that there are three distinct persons in the undivided being of God (Matt. 28:19). As long as there was a large number of Jewish converts to the Christian faith, monotheism (the teaching that God is one) was unquestioned.
旧约已经特别强调了合一或一神论(monotheism)来反对异教的多神论(polytheism)。新约强调了同样的内容(马可福音12:29,32)。同时，新约明确地教导上帝的三位一体是，有三个不同的位格的在一位不可分割的上帝本体里(马太福音28:19)。既然有一大批犹太人转变相信基督徒的信仰，一神论(教导上帝只有一位)是毫无疑问的。
C. But as the number of Gentile converts increased and became a majority and as the church began to play a larger role in society, pagan philosophies of various sorts came to influence the thinking of some Christians, especially some of the intellectual Christian leaders. One of the first problems they began to wrestle with was how to maintain monotheism and yet recognize the three persons. To put the question more specifically: How can the Bible say that the Son is not the same person as the Father and yet teach that the Son is of one substance with the Father?
但是由于大量的外邦人信主并且占多数以及教会开始在社会中扮演更重要的角色，各样异教徒哲学家开始影响一些基督徒的思想，特别是一些善于思考的基督徒领导者。他们首先挣扎的一个问题就是如何保持一神论而又承认存在三个位格。这个问题更具体地说就是：圣经怎么能说子与父不是同样的位格而又教导子与父是同质的呢？
D. This controversy developed chiefly in the Eastern Greek-speaking part of the church, starting at Alexandria in Egypt. There a theologian named Arius (c. 250-336) began to preach about the Son in a way that disagreed with the Scriptures. Although many of the clergy were quick to see that his theology would undermine the certainty of our redemption and open the door for a return to paganism, others were quite slow to recognize this.
这个争论主要在东方部分希腊语教会中发展，开始于埃及的亚历山大港。有一个叫阿里乌的神学家(大约公元250-336年)开始用与圣经不同的方式传讲圣子。虽然很多神职人员立刻就发现他的神学理论将渐渐破坏我们对救赎的确信并为异教徒的归来开来一扇门，但是其他人用了相当漫长的时间才意识到这个问题。
E. Arius began his reasoning with a true biblical statement – that God is absolutely unique and alone in being “un-generated.” By this he meant that God alone is eternal, without a beginning and exists with no help from anyone or anything else. But by the term, “God” he meant only God the father. The Son, or the Logos (Word) as Greek Bible calls him in the first chapter of the Gospel of John, must therefore be a creature, that is, part of God’s creation. He is a perfect creature to be sure, and not to be compared with the rest of creation; but He is still a creature.
阿里乌开始以圣经中的陈述来进行他的推理-上帝是绝对独特和唯一“不可造的”神。通过这句话他所说的是唯有上帝是永恒的，亘古就存在并且他的存在不靠任何人或任何其他物体的帮助。但是通过这个词，他所指的“上帝”只是圣父。因此圣子，或希腊语圣经的约翰福音第一章中称他为Logos (道)，一定是一个受造物，就是说，上帝所创造的一部分。可以确定他是一个完美的受造物，而且其他受造物无法与他相比；但他仍然只是一个受造物。
F. Arius said that since the Son, or Logos (Word), was a creature, he must have had a beginning. Arius taught that the Father had brought the Son (Logos) into being so that this Son might create all things or as one of Arius’ slogans went, “there was a time when He did not exist.” From this it follows, asserted Arius, that although we can speak of the Son as God’s Word and Wisdom, He is not that Word and Wisdom which belongs to God’s very essence. The Son was an intermediary between God and the world and could hence be called the Word, or even the Son of God, or even God, but these were only titles of courtesy. The net result of Arius’ teachings was to reduce the Son to a sort of half-God.
阿里乌说因为圣子，或道，是一个受造物，他一定有一个起始的时间。阿里乌教导圣父使圣子(道)成为神这样这位圣子才能创造一切或如阿里乌的一个口号中说的，“曾有一段时期他不存在”。由这一结论，阿里乌断言，虽然我们谈到子同样有上帝的道和智慧，他不是属于上帝本质的道和智慧。圣子是上帝和世人之间的一位中保，因此，他被称为道，或者甚至被称为上帝的儿子，或者是上帝，但是这些只是出于礼节的称呼。阿里乌教导的最终目的是将圣子降低为类似于半神的人。
G. Since Arius was brilliant, politically sophisticated and tactful, he quickly gained a following for his new doctrine. However just as quickly many voices were raised against him in Alexandria, his home city. Finally his bishop, Alexander, called a meeting of the church of Alexandria, came out strongly against him, and excommunicated him. But the number of Arians (those who followed Arius’ teachings) continued to grow, and they threatened to divide the church, especially in the Eastern part of the empire where they were very numerous and powerful.
由于阿里乌如此精明，在政治方面老练和圆滑，他很快为他的新教义赢得了追随者。然而同样很快很多反对他的声音在亚历山大，他的家乡出现。最终，他的主教，亚历山大，召集了一次亚历山大港教会会议，结果强烈反对阿里乌的教导并开除了他的教籍。但是一些阿里乌派(那些追随阿里乌教导的人)继续壮大并威胁分裂教会，特别是在帝国东部地区的阿里乌人数众多并势力强大。
H. THE COUNCIL OF NICEA (325 A. D.) 尼西亚会议(公元325年)
Emperor Constantine believed that the Roman Empire could only remain strong if it had a unified religion. When he realized how sharply the church was divided by Arianism (the teachings of Arius), he resolved to summon church leaders or bishops to a meeting at which the problem could be discussed and solved. Though most of the bishops who attended were from the eastern half of the empire (where Arius’ teachings had especially taken root) it is called the “First Ecumenical (or General) Council” in contrast to local councils or synods. Although Constantine had not yet been baptized, he considered himself a Christian. However, Hossius of Cordova, a bishop from Spain, was his chief theological advisor.
皇帝康斯坦丁相信只有拥有统一的宗教罗马帝国才能保持强大。当他意识到由阿里乌主义(阿里乌的教导)引起的教会分裂是多么严重时，他决心召集教会领导者或主教举行一个会议讨论哪些问题可以被讨论和解决。尽管参加会议的大多数主教来自帝国的东半区(阿里乌的教导建立的地方)，会议却被称为 “第一次全基督大会”这与地方会议或教区会议不同。虽然康斯坦丁还未受洗，但是他认为自己是一名基督徒。而克多瓦的胡西亚，来自西班牙的一个主教，是他的首席神学顾问。
I. The Council met in May and June, 325, in Nicaea, a city not far from Constantinople (in modern Turkey), where Constantine has a palace. More than two hundred bishops were present. Though the council dealt with many issues, its main purpose was to formulate clearly what the Scripture taught about the Lord Jesus Christ. The great question was: Is the Son true God of true God? Is he truly and completely divine, or was he, as Arius and his supporters said, a lesser being, in some way divine but not with the same divinity as God the Father?
会议于公元325年五月和六月在距君士坦丁堡(在如今的土耳其)不远的尼西亚康斯坦丁的一个宫殿中举行。超过200名主教出席了这次会议。虽然会议涉及许多问题，但是它的主要目的是清楚地找出圣经中关于主耶稣基督的教导。最主要的问题是：圣子是从真神所出之真神吗？他是真的和完全的具有神性吗？还是他正如阿里乌和他的支持者所说的，他的神性少一些，从某些方面来说他的神性是与天父的神性不同的？
J. At the Council of Nicaea, the opposition to Arius was led by Bishop Alexander, who had sought to keep Egypt and its capital city of Alexandria (the second largest in the Empire) true to the Biblical teaching. As the debate at the council proceeded, the vast majority of bishops came to understand the false teaching of Arius and completely rejected it. The council knew without doubt that Arius was wrong. Still because Arius could accept almost all Scriptural terms which seemed to eliminate his false view and twist them around so that he could read his own teachings into them, the council had a harder time finding clear and unmistakable language with which to confess the truth of the Bible and yet reject what Arius had said.
在尼西亚的会议上，领导反对阿里乌的人是主教亚历山大，他试图使埃及以及它的首都亚历山大港(帝国的第二大城市)忠实于圣经的教导。随着会议上辩论的进行，大多数主教明白了阿里乌的教导是错误的并完全拒绝了它。会议上明确了毫无疑问阿里乌是错误的。但仍因为阿里乌基本上接受所有圣经的话语，看似可以使他的错误观点和歪曲圣经的话语被忽视，从而将他自己的教导加入圣经中，会议为了找出明确无可置疑的语言来告白圣经中的真理同时拒绝阿里乌所说的经历了更艰难的时期。
K. To solve this problem and to overcome the difficulty, the Council began with an already existing creed. This creed (probably the baptismal creed from Jerusalem) was very similar to the Apostles’ Creed. The council then inserted some new clauses in order to explain very clearly what the scriptural doctrine was. The clauses were worded in such a way that the followers of Arius could not twist them to suit their own meaning.
为了解决这个问题和克服困难，会议开始讨论一个已经存在的信经。这个信经(可能就是从耶路撒冷来的洗礼信经)与使徒信经非常相似。然后会议加入了一些新的短语从而非常清楚地解释圣经教义是什么。这些短语的措辞方式使得阿里乌的追随者们不能歪曲圣经中的话语而适用于他们的目的。
L. The council added several important new clauses to emphasize the Biblical doctrine about the Son. These are “from the substance of the Father” and “of one substance with the Father.” The Greek word which Emperor Constantine himself had suggested be inserted was homoousion, and it is translated “of the same substance with.” The English word which in theological language has come to stand for this term is “consubstantial.”
会议添加了一些重要的新短语来强调圣经中关于圣子的教义。这些短语是“从父本身而来”和“与父同质”。由皇帝康斯坦丁本人建议而插入的一个希腊语单词是homoousion，并且这个词被翻译为“与…同质”。在神学中代表这个短语的英语单词是 “consubstantial”“同质的”。
M. Besides Arius, only five persons at the council refused to sign the statement. The Emperor banished them. But because of their interest in political peace and unity, Constantine’s successors later allowed them back and, at times, even supported the Arian party, with the result that the church remained divided.
除了阿里乌以外，只有另外五个人在会议上拒绝签署声明。皇帝驱逐了他们。但是出于他们在政治和平和统一中的利益，康斯坦丁的继任者们允许他们回到教会中，甚至有时支持阿里乌派，其结果就是教会仍处于分裂中。
N. Also present at the Council at Nicaea was a young Egyptian pastor who served as secretary for Bishop Alexander. His name was Athanasius (296-373), and he became bishop at Alexander’s death. We are told that physically Athanasius was a small man; in fact, his opponents called him a dwarf. But as a Biblical theologian, his was a giant. Ever since the time of the council of Nicaea and because of his unwavering loyalty to the truth of that confession and all the persecution he suffered because of it, people have described his life as “Athanasius against the world.” He was a person of great stability and of genuineness of character. In a long life he remained immovable in the convictions he had gained from Scripture.
一位年轻的埃及牧师，主教亚历山大的秘书也出席了尼西亚会议。他的名字是亚大纳西(公元296-373年)，并且在亚历山大死时，他成为了主教。我们所知道的亚大纳西在身材上是个矮小的人；事实上，他的对手称他为侏儒。但作为一个圣经神学家，他是一个巨人。自从尼西亚会议开始，他遭受的所有迫害都是因为他对告白的真理毫不动摇的忠心，人们描绘他的一生是 “亚大纳西与世人为敌”。 他是一个具有坚定和真挚品格的人。很长一段时间里他都保持着他从圣经中所获得的确信毫不动摇。
O. Because of his opposition to the Arian party, which had achieved considerable political power during the decades following the Council of Nicaea, Athanasius spent many years of his life on the run or in exile. Five times he was exiled for his Biblical faith. The Arian party was for a time known as the Eusebians, when Bishop Eusebius of Nicomedia was their leader. They tried to get the church to accept the team homoousion (of a similar substance with) as a compromise between the position of Arius and that of the Council of Nicaea. Athanasius, however, always continued preaching that Jesus was true God and homoousion (of the same substance) as the Father. He was the great champion of the orthodox (straight or true) Biblical teaching. Today his name remains an inspiration for those who resist society, popular interest, and even the leaders of the external church when those leaders give up the faith that was once delivered unto the saints (Jude 3).
因为他所对抗的阿里乌派在接下来几十年的尼西亚会议中获得了相当大的政治权利，亚大纳西在他一生中的许多年里都过着逃亡或流亡的生活。由于他的圣经信仰，他五次被流放。阿里乌派曾一度因优西比乌派而为人们所熟知，那时尼克米迪亚的主教优西比乌是他们的领导者。他们试图使教会接受他们 (具有相似本质)的观点作为他们在阿里乌的立场与尼西亚会议中间的妥协。然而，亚大纳西继续坚持传讲耶稣是真正的上帝而且与天父同质。他是正统(直白的或真实的)圣经教导的伟大胜利者。如今当那些领导者们放弃曾使他们成为圣徒的信心时，他的名字仍是对那些抵抗社会、公众利益甚至是教会外部领导者们的人的启示(犹大书3)。
P. Athanasius helped preserve the biblical teaching by his clear explanations of the doctrine of the Consubstantiality of the Son with the Father. He was that if Arius was right and the Word were not eternal, then the Triune God is not eternal. Only if the Son shares in the same nature and substance as the Father, can we speak of One God. He saw further that the Arian view destroyed the certainty of our salvation. If the word (Jesus) is a created being, as the Arians insisted, then He could not reveal the Father to us and He certainly could not be our Redeemer. Only if the Mediator was Himself divine could He reconcile us to the Father.
亚大纳西通过他对子与父同质的教义的明确解释帮助维护圣经的教导。他说如果阿里乌是正确的而且道不是永恒的，那么三位一体的上帝就不是永恒的。只有圣子与圣父拥有同样的属性和本质，我们才能说一位上帝。他进一步说阿里乌的观点将毁掉我们对救恩的确信。如果道(耶稣) 如阿里乌派所坚持的是一个受造物，那么他不可能向我们揭示圣父而且也绝对不可能成为我们的救主。只有这位中保具有圣父的神性才能使我们与圣父和好。
Q. In 381 a Second Ecumenical Council was held at Constantinople. Thanks to the work of Athanasius and that of three great church leaders in Cappadocia (Basil of Caesarea, Gregory of Nyssa, and Gregory Nazianzus), the doctrine approved at Nicaea was reaffirmed in a new and expanded creed. This is the form that we use in our churches today and still called the Nicene Creed. The fourth Ecumenical Council held at Chalcedon in 451 officially endorsed this expanded form of the Creed.
公元381年第二次全基督徒大会在君士坦丁堡举行。幸亏有了亚大纳西和卡帕多西亚的三位伟大教会领导者(凯撒利亚的巴兹尔、尼撒的格利高里和格利高里 纳齐安)的努力，在尼西亚获得认可的教义重新以新的和扩充的信经再次获得确认。这就是我们如今在教会中所用的版本并仍称为尼西亚信经。公元451年召开的第四次全基督徒大会正式承认了这个扩充后的信经。
R. The Nicene Creed with the additions of 381 reads as follows:
We believe in one God, the Father, the Almighty,
maker of heaven and earth,
of all that is,
seen and unseen.
We believe in one Lord, Jesus Christ, the only Son of God,
eternally begotten of the Father,
God from God, Light from Light, true God from true God,
begotten, not made,
of one being with the Father.
Through him all things were made.
For us and for our salvation, he came down from heaven,
was incarnate of the Holy Spirit and the virgin Mary,
and became fully human.
For our sake he was crucified under Pontius Pilate.
He suffered death and was buried.
On the third day he rose again in accordance with the Scriptures.
He ascended into heaven
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.
He will come again in glory to judge the living and the dead,
And his kingdom will have no end.
We believe in the Holy Spirit,
the Lord, the giver of life,
who proceeds from the Father [and the Son],
who in unity with the Father and the Son is worshiped and glorified,
who has spoken through the prophets.
We believe in one holy Catholic and apostolic Church.
We acknowledge one baptism for the forgiveness of sins.
We look for the resurrection of the dead
and the life of the world to come. Amen.
公元381年扩充后的尼西亚信经内容如下：
我等信独一之神，即全能之圣父，创造天地，及一切有形无形之万物之主。
我等信独一之主耶稣基督，上帝独生之圣子，是圣父在万世之先所生，是从神所出之神，从光所出之光，从真神所出之真神，是生非造，是与圣父同体，万物皆借圣子而造；圣子为要拯救我等世人，从天降临，为圣灵感动之童贞女马利亚所生，成为人身，在本丢彼拉多手下，为我等钉十字架，被害而葬，照圣经之言，第三日复活，升天，坐在圣父之右；将来复必有荣耀而降临，审判生人死人，其国无穷无尽。
我等信圣灵即是主，是赐生命者，是从圣父、圣子所出，与圣父、圣子，同是当拜， 当称颂者，众先知说预言，皆是被圣灵感动；我等信使徒所立独一圣而公之教会；我等信因为赦罪设立之独一洗礼；我等望死后复活，又望来世之永生。阿们。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Worksheet For Lesson Four</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-8/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Worksheet For Lesson Four
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：2097
Worksheet for Lesson Four: 第四课作业题：
Historical Background to the Nicene Creed 尼西亚信经的历史背景
Section B. B部分
1.Give 2 examples of the following types of religions: 举出以下宗教类型的两个例子：
A. Monotheism: 一神论
1.
2.
B. Polytheism: 多神论 1.
2.
Section C. C部分
1.Where or how does the Bible indicate that: 圣经中何处以及怎样指出：
A. Jesus is different from the Father 耶稣不同于圣父
B. Jesus is the same as the Father 耶稣与圣父一样
Section E. E 部分
1.In theology it is very important to define the words we use. How is that shown by Arius’ contention that “God alone is eternal and un-generated?”
在神学中，定义我们所用的词是非常重要的。这一点在与阿里乌关于“唯独上帝是永恒和不可造的”的争论中是如何体现的？
Section F. F 部分
1.What are the two different meanings of “Word” and “Wisdom” according to Arius? 根据阿里乌所说的，“道”与“智慧”的两个不同含义是什么？ A.
B.
Section H. H 部分
1.Can you sense a problem that might develop if an emperor summons church leaders to solve a doctrinal problem?
你是否意识到如果皇帝召集教会领袖解决教义问题可能会产生的问题？
Section I. I 部分
1.Examine the following three diagrams: 查看以下三个图示：
Father God 天父上帝Father God 天父上帝
↓↓ Father God ↔ Son God
Son 圣子Son God 上帝之子 天父上帝 上帝之子
Put the letter A above the diagram which best represents the teaching of Arius and B above the diagram which best represents the teaching of the Bible.
在最适合代表阿里乌教导的图示前写上A并且在最适合代表圣经教导的图示前写上B。
Section L. L 部分
1.Look at our English version of the Nicene Creed (Lesson 4 pg. 4). Which expression in the Second Article do you think is a translation of the Greek word homoousion?
看我们英文版的尼西亚信经(第四课第四页)。你认为第二部分中哪一句的表述是对希腊语单词homoousion的翻译？
Section N. N 部分
1.In what way is the saying “Athanasius against the world” an accurate one.
从哪方面来看，说“亚大纳西与世人为敌”是一个准确的说法？
2.What comfort can we take for today from that saying?
当今我们能从这种说法中得到怎样的安慰？
Section O.
1.What does homoousion mean? homoousion的意思是什么？
2.What does homoiousion mean? homoiousion的意思是什么？
3.Is there a Biblical compromise between these two words and the doctrines they represent?
在这两个词和他们所代表的教义之间是否存在符合圣经的妥协？
Section Q. Q 部分
1.In what way is the title “Nicene Creed” somewhat misleading?
从哪方面来看，“尼西亚信经”这个标题带有一些误导？
2.In what way is that same title very accurate?
从哪方面来看，这个标题是非常准确的？
3.What role did each of the following play in defeating the heresy of Arius: 以下所列举的在对抗阿里乌的异端邪说上发挥了什么作用：
A. Emperor Constantine 皇帝康斯坦丁
B. Athanasius 亚大纳西
C. The Council of Nicaea 尼西亚会议
D. The Council of Constantinople 君士坦丁堡会议
4.Which of the above do you think was the most important? Explain your answer.
你认为上面所列举的最重要的一个是什么？解释你的答案。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第五课 （lesson 5）尼西亚信经的意义</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-9/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第五课 （lesson 5）尼西亚信经的意义
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：2273
Lesson Five: The Meaning of the Nicene Creed
第五课： 尼西亚信经的意义
A. THE FIRST ARTICLE 第一部分
When the doctrine of the Trinity is rightly believed and confessed, it focuses attention on Christ the Savior who became incarnate for man’s salvation. But it also includes more. To know and worship God as Triune is to acknowledge Him as a God of grace, who through His Spirit seeks and converts sinners for Christ’s sake.
当三位一体的教义被正确地相信和承认时，它所关注的就是为了人的救恩，道成肉身的救主基督。但同时它还包括其他内容。为了了解和敬拜三位一体的上帝，就要知道他是充满恩典的上帝，因为基督的缘故，他通过圣灵寻找罪人并使他们信主。
B. The first article of the Nicene Creed is quite similar to that of the Apostles’ Creed, taking from it the expression “Creator of heaven and earth.” By using the expression, “We believe in one God,” it emphasized that there is only one God, the God of the Scriptures. All other gods are idols, gods of this world (1 Cor. 8:4). The expression “one” God was also added to reject other false teachers who taught that Father, Son and Holy Spirit were really three separate Gods. This one God is also Creator and God of all things “see and unseen” – not just the physical world around us, but also Creator and God of the spirit world, including Satan and his evil angels.
尼西亚信经的第一部分与使徒信经的第一部分非常相似，都采用了“创造天地的主”这样的表述。通过使用“我等信独一之神”这样的表述，它强调了只有一位上帝，圣经中的上帝。所有其他的神都是偶像，是这个世上的神(哥林多前书8:4)。“只有一位”上帝这样的措辞添加进来也是为了阻止其他假文士所教导的圣父、圣子和圣灵是真正三位分别独立的上帝。这一位上帝也是创世者和所有“有形无形之万物”的上帝-不仅是我们周围有形的世界，也是属灵世界，包括撒旦和他罪恶天使的创造者和上帝。
C. THE SECOND ARTICLE 第二部分
The second article of this creed, however, is the decisive importance: “We believe in one Lord, Jesus Christ, the only Son of God, eternally begotten of the Father, God from God, Light from Light, true God from true God, begotten, not made, of one being (or substance) with the Father.” Quite obviously this Creed is more doctrinally complete than the Apostles’ Creed, since it was specifically designed to correct the errors of Arianism. For this reason Jesus Christ is called true God of true God. This phrase asserts that Jesus Christ is truly and completely divine. The Son is true God in the same sense the Father is true God. He is not, as the Arians imagine, a lesser created being, called divine, but with a divinity only similar to that of God the Father.
而这部信经的第二部分是起决定作用的重要部分：“我等信独一之主耶稣基督，上帝独生之圣子，是圣父在万世之先所生，是从神所出之神，从光所出之光，从真神所出之真神，是生非造，是与圣父同体(同质)”。很明显这个信经在教义方面比使徒信经更完整，因为它具体针对纠正阿里乌的错误而写的。由于这个原因耶稣基督被称为真神所出之真神。这个短语坚持耶稣基督真正完全的神。圣父是真神，同样的道理圣子也是真神。他不像阿里乌所想象的是一个被称为神而次于神的受造物，而是具有与天父相同的神性。
D. With the phrase “eternally begotten of the Father,” the Creed testifies to the pre-existence of the Son of God. He existed before time, before the foundation of the world, from eternity. This phrase thus clearly rejects one of the slogans used by the Arians: “There was a time when He was not.” The statement in the Creed is based solidly on the Scriptures (Col. 1:17, 19; John 17:5; John 10:30; John 8:58-59; John 1:1-2; Heb. 1:3).
用“是圣父在万世之先所生”这个短语，信经证明了上帝儿子的预先存在。在亘古以前，在世界的根基被创造以前就存在直到永恒。因此，这个短语明显抵制阿里乌所用的一个口号：“曾有一段时期他不存在”。这部信经中的陈述是以圣经为坚实基础的(歌罗西书1:17,19； 约翰福音17:5；约翰福音10:30；约翰福音8:58-59；约翰福音1:1-2；希伯来书1:3)
E. OF ONE SUBSTANCE 同质
The clause “of one substance with the Father” (homoousion), is the most famous one in the Creed. It goes to the heart of the controversy with Arius. Arius had taught that the Word (the Son of God) is different from and unlike the substance (ousia). Arius also taught that the Word (the Son) did not share in the peculiar nature (idiotes) of the Father in all respects and hence did not have the same attributes (almighty, all-knowing, etc.) as the Father. Many who followed after Arius (the Eusebians mentioned earlier) tried to compromise by saying the Jesus’ substance was similar to that of the Father (homoiousion). In opposition to all these wrong ideas the words of the Nicene Creed confess that the Son shared the divine essence to the full; whatever belonged to the Godhead belonged to the Son.
“是与圣父同质”(homoousion同质)这个短语是这部信经中最著名的一点。它涉及到与阿里乌争论的重点。阿里乌教导道(上帝的儿子)不同于上帝并具有不同的本质(ousia)。阿里乌还教导道(圣子)从各方面来看都不享有圣父的特有属性并且因此他没有拥有与圣父同样的属性(全能的，全知的，等等)。许多追随阿里乌的人试图通过说耶稣与圣父本质相似(homoiousion)来作出妥协。与所有错误观点相反的是尼西亚信经告白了圣子享有与圣父完全一样的神性；任何属于上帝的也属于圣子。
F. The Greek term for “one substance” is homoousion. It was a new term in theology at this time, but it expresses the Scriptural idea that Christ is both God and Lord in the absolute sense, without any limitations. The Arians, of course, would have found it impossible to accept this term without a real change of heart regarding their theology. Some orthodox theologians were at first a little uncomfortable with the word also. In the third century the term had been used in several different ways by the heretics Sabellius and Paul of Samosata. So these orthodox leaders were understandably cautious about approving new terms and wanted to make sure they were not adding new or unbiblicalideas to the church’s confessions. Also they wanted to make sure that the new term, homoousion, would not remove the clear distinction between the person of the Father and the person of the Son.
希腊语中“同质”的单词是homoousion。这在当时的神学中是一个崭新的词汇，但是它表达的圣经意思是上帝和主绝对没有任何局限。当然，阿里乌根据他自己的神学理论在不改变这个词中心意思的情况下接受这个词。一些正统的神学家一开始也对这个词感到一点不适应。在三世纪是，这个词被异端撒伯流和撒摩撒他的保罗以不同方式加以运用。因此这些正统的领袖们对于认可这个新的词表示出了可以理解的谨慎并希望确保他们没有在教会的认信中添加新的或非圣经的意义。同时他们希望确定这个新词homoousion，不会去掉父与子在位格上不同这一点。
G. The Second Ecumenical Council (Constantinople, 381), however, reaffirmed the Creed of Nicaea and the team homoousion. By that time the bishops were sure in agreement with Athanasius. The Son (the Word) was homoousion, ‘of one substance with the Father’ or ‘of equal substance with the Father.’ By using the term “homoousion” the Church was clearly expressing what the Bible taught.
然而第二次大公会议(君士坦丁堡，公元381年)上再次确认了尼西亚信经和homoousion这个词。到那时，主教们确定同意亚大纳西的观点。圣子(道)是homoousion同质的，‘与圣父同质’或‘与圣父等质’。通过使用“homoousion”这个词，教会清楚地表达了圣经所教导的内容。
H. “By whom all things were made.” Scripture not only teaches that the Son existed before the creation of all things but that he was active in the creation itself (John 1:3; Heb. 1:2; Col. 1:16; Eph. 3:9). These passages clearly show that the Son is in no sense one of God’s creatures, but one with God himself since all things were created by Him. At this point it is worth noting (in view of the wording of the first article of the Apostles’ Creed), that the creeds do not intend to teach that only the first person of the Godhead was active in the work of creation. Rather Scripture teaches that Father, Son, and Holy Spirit were all active in the creation of the world. At times Scripture uses the term “Father,” more broadly and not exclusively for the first person, but also for the godhead, the entire Trinity (Matt. 23:9; Eph. 4:6). All persons in the Trinity are active in creating and preserving the world of creation, because all things are of God, through God, and to God (Rom. 11:36).
“万物皆借圣子而造。” 圣经不仅教导了圣子在创世以前就存在而且他参与了创世(约翰福音1:3；希伯来书1:2；歌罗西书1:16；以弗所书3:9)。这些章节清楚地显示圣子不可能是上帝的其中一个所造之物，而是与上帝一起从上帝创造所有一切时起。在这一点上值得注意的是(根据使徒信经第一部分的措辞)，这些信经并不是想要教导在创世的工作中只有神的第一位格参与了做工。恰恰相反正如圣经教导的圣父、圣子和圣灵都参与的创世。有时候，圣经更宽泛地用 “父”这个词，不仅只用于第一位格，也用于上帝和整个三位一体(马太福音23:9；以弗所书4:6)。三位一体中的所有位格都参与了创世和维护所创造的世界，因为万有都是本于上帝，倚靠上帝并归于上帝(罗马书11:36)。
I. The next paragraph confesses the incarnation of the Son of God, the eternal Word: “Who for us men and for our salvation, came down from heaven and was incarnate by the Holy Ghost of the virgin Mary, and was made man and was crucified also for us under Pontius Pilate; He suffered and was buried.” Because our entire salvation depends on the person of Christ, we should remember that the special purpose of the Council of Nicaea was to assert the Son’s full divinity and equality with the Father, out of whose being he was derived and whose nature he therefore shared.
下面一段告白的是上帝的儿子，永恒的道的道成肉身：“圣子为要拯救我等世人，从天降临，为圣灵感动之童贞女马利亚所生，成为人身，在本丢彼拉多手下，为我等钉十字架，被害而葬”。因为我们的全部救恩都是靠着基督的位格，我们应该记住尼西亚会议的特殊目的是肯定圣子与圣父完全一致的神性和相等地位，由于他来自于那一位本身并因此拥有那一位的属性。
J. But the Creed also briefly testified to the saving work of Christ, and in this respect it is quite similar to the Apostles’ Creed. The expanded form of the Creed, adopted at the Council of Constantinople in 381, carries an important addition. In 325, the Creed simply said “came down and became incarnate, becoming man,” but the expanded form has “came down from heaven and was incarnate by the Holy Ghost of the virgin Mary.”
但是这个信经也简要地为基督救恩的工作作了见证，并且在这一方面它与使徒信经非常相似。公元381年在君士坦丁堡会议上被采用的扩充后的信经承载着重要的补充内容。公元325年，信经只简要地说了“降临成为肉身，变成人”，但是扩充之后说到“从天降临，为圣灵感动之童贞女马利亚所生”。
K. Apollinarius of Laodicea was probably the reason for the addition of these words. He began as a friend of Athanasius and a supporter of the decrees of the Council of Nicaea. Later in his life, however, he started teaching that when the Son of God became man, he did not become a complete human being because he did not have a human soul or personality. Rather, Apollinarius taught that the eternal Word was substituted for the normal human soul or personality in Christ. This teaching denies the completeness of the Lord’s humanity. This teaching would have meant that Christ had not been a human being in the same way each of us is, except that he was without sin. As a result, he could not have been our Savior, because as our substitute he could not have sacrificed his body and soul for our body and soul. Opinions like as those of Apollinarius were declared heretical at the Council of Constantinople in 381. This clause was a safeguard against such an heretical opinion.
老底嘉的阿波利拿里可能是添加这些话的原因。他一开始是亚大纳西的朋友和尼西亚会议的支持者。然而之后，他开始教导当上帝的儿子成为人时，他没有成为完全的人因为他不具备人的灵魂或特征。更确切地说，阿波利拿里教导永恒的道在基督里代替了普通人的灵魂和特征。这种教导否认主人性的完全性。这种教导意味着基督成为人的方式与我们不同，除此以外他没有罪。因此，他能成为我们的救主，因为作为我们的替代者他不可能为了我们的身体和灵魂而牺牲他的身体和灵魂。那些类似于阿波利拿里观点的教导在公元381年的君士坦丁堡会议上被宣告为异端邪说。这一条款是抵制这样异端观点的预防措施。
L. The phrases, “for us men,” “for our salvation,” and “also for us” are very significant. They emphasize the very heart of the gospel, for they are a great confession of the substitutionary atonement of Christ the Son of God. Jesus came as a great High Priest to reconcile sinful man to God. Since he was both God and man, Jesus was able to give a ransom that was sufficient and acceptable to God. The ransom could not be paid with silver and gold (1 Peter 1:18). Nor could the Old Testament sacrifices of the blood of bulls and goats cleanse us from sin (Heb. 10:4). Only God could reconcile the world to Himself (2 Cor. 5:19). Christ fulfilled the Law of God in our place (Gal. 4:4-5). And Christ carried our sins in His own body on the tree (1 Peter 2:24). The Lord laid on Him the iniquity of us all (Is. 53:5-6), and mankind was redeemed by His vicarious suffering and death (1 Peter 1:19, 1 John 2:2).
“为我等世人”、“为拯救我们”和“也为我等”这些短语非常重要。他们深刻地强调了福音，因为他们是上帝儿子基督代替我们赎罪的极好告白。耶稣作为至高的祭司来使罪人与上帝和好。因为他是上帝也是人，耶稣能够付足够的并被上帝接受的赎价。这样的赎价不能以金银来偿还(彼得前书1:18)。旧约中祭祀用的牛羊的血也不能将我们从罪里洗净(希伯来书 10:4)。只有上帝能使世人与他自己和好(哥林多后书5:19)。基督为我们成全了上帝的律法(加拉太书4:4-5)。并且基督以他自己的身体在十字架上承担了我们罪(1 Peter 彼得前书2:24)。主为我们所有人的罪而死(以赛亚书53:5-6)，同时人通过他代替我们受苦和死被赎回(彼得前书1:19；约翰一书 2:2)。
M. The Exaltation of Christ is confessed in much the same language as the Apostles’ Creed. At the Council of Constantinople in 381, a phrase at the conclusion of this section was added to the original Nicene Creed of 325: “Whose kingdom shall have no end.” Obviously these words come straight from Luke 1:33, where the angel Gabriel reveals to the virgin Mary the glory of the child she was about to bear.
基督的升高用与使徒信经非常相似的话语被告白。在公元381年的君士坦丁堡的会议上，这部分结尾处被添加到原有的公元325年尼西亚信经中一个短语是：“其国无穷无尽”。很显然这些话直接来自路加福音1:33，其中天使加百列向童贞女马利亚揭示她将要生下的孩子的荣耀。
N. The writers of the Nicene Creed probably inserted this clause in response to the false teaching of Bishop Marcellus of Ancyra. He was another man who began as a supporter of the Nicene phrase homoousion. Then he started teaching that the Word (logos) came to earth and took on body. Thus the Word became Jesus, God’s Son and King only while here on earth. Marcellus further taught that when Christ’s substitutionary work on earth was finished, the Word laid aside its body and its rule and returned to exist in the Father. Another bishop (St. Cyril of Jerusalem) had exclaimed: “If ever you hear anyone saying that there is an end to the Kingship of Christ, hate the heresy!” The Christian’s comfort is that his Savior has established for him a kingdom of grace which will never end and in which he will reign throughout all eternity.
尼西亚信经的作者插入这个短句可能是回应安吉拉主教马赛路的错误教导。他是起初支持尼西亚信经中 “本体同一” 这个短语的人。之后他开始教导道(logos)来到世上并取了肉身。因此道只在世上成为了耶稣，上帝的儿子和王。马赛路还教导当基督完成他在世上替代者的工作之后，道将肉身和统治搁置在一边回到了天父身边。另一位主教耶路撒冷的西里尔曾惊呼：“如果你听到有任何人说基督的王权有尽头，恨恶这个异端！” 基督徒的安慰就是他的救主为他建立了一个恩典的国，这个国不会终止并且救主要在其中统治万物。
O. THE THIRD ARTICLE 第三部分
The third article of the Nicene Creed, as we confess it today, was also greatly expanded in 381. The first or 325 version drawn up at Nicaea read simply, “And the Holy Spirit.” The bishops at Constantinople expanded this section of creed quite a lot. As a result the second half of the Constantinople version of the third article is quite similar to the third article of the Apostles’ Creed, except that it adds the confession of “one baptism for the remission of sins.” These points of doctrine were customarily found in most of the baptismal creeds.
我们如今所告白的尼西亚信经第三部分也是在公元381年时得到很大扩充。第一或公元325年在尼西亚制定的版本写得很简单，“和圣灵”。主教们在君士坦丁堡对信经的这一部分进行了极大地扩充。因此，除了所添加的“因为赦罪设立之独一洗礼”以外，第三信条君士坦丁堡版本的后半部分与使徒信经的第三信条非常相似。教义中的这些观点通常在一些洗礼信经中出现。
P. But what is striking is the enlarged statement on the Holy Spirit: “And I believe in the Holy Spirit, the Lord, the giver of Life, who proceeds from the Father [and the Son]; who with the Father and the Son together is worshiped and glorified; who has spoken by the prophets.” The Early Church had simply accepted the fact of monotheism (that there is only one God). It advanced as proof of monotheism the revelation Christ had given before His ascension, namely that by baptism into the name of the Father, the S on, and the Holy Ghost, one entered into a saving relationship with God. The church recognized the Father as God, the Son as God, and the Holy Spirit as God, and yet it confessed not three Gods but only one God.
但是值得注意的是这是对圣灵的扩大描述：“我等信圣灵即是主，是赐生命者，是从圣父、圣子所出，与圣父、圣子，同是当拜，当称颂者，众先知说预言”。早期教会只是简单承认一神论(只有一位上帝)这个事实。它进一步作为一神论证明基督在升天之前所给的启示，即通过以圣父、圣子和圣灵的名受洗，这个人就得着上帝的救恩。教会承认圣父是神，圣子是神，同时圣灵也是神，但是它还承认并没有三位神而是只有一位神。
Q. This deep mystery goes beyond all human understanding. At first the Early Church had not thoughtfully looked at all the Scriptural material regarding the Triune God, but had accepted the simple fact that all three Persons were true God. But since this truth is unacceptable to human reason, speculation within the church arose, not only regarding the Son’s (Word’s) relation to the Father but also the relation of the Holy Spirit to the Father.
这个深奥的迷题是超越人的理解能力的。起初，早期教会并没有仔细地关注整部圣经中三位一体的上帝，但是接受三个位格是真神的简单事实。然而由于这个真理无法被人的理性所接受，教会中产生了猜测，不仅是关于圣子(道)与圣父的关系还有圣灵与圣父的关系。
R. Arius, who had held that in some way the Son is a creature of the Father, had made no secret of his belief that the Holy Spirit, too, was a creature of the Father. Between the two councils, however, the relationship between the Father and the Holy Spirit came in for considerable study and debate. Athanasius and his allies soon realized that there was not only a great deal of unclarity about the Holy Spirit but that there were actual anti-Scriptural points of view regarding the Holy Spirit. While some regarded Him as God, others regarded Him merely as an “energy” or an impersonal force, and others looked upon Him simply as a creature of God. And, as often happens, still others, generally considered quite orthodox, declined to commit themselves at all.
阿里乌，认为从某方面来说圣子是圣父的一个创造物的人，毫不掩饰他相信圣灵也是圣父的一个创造物。然而，在两次会议之间，产生了关于圣父与圣灵关系相当多的研究和辩论。亚大纳西和他的支持者很快就意识到关于圣灵不仅有很多不明确的地方而且还有一些实际上是反圣经的观点来看待圣灵。但是一些人认为他是上帝，其他人认为他仅仅是一种“能量”或一种非人的力量，还有一些人只认为他是上帝的一个受造物。同时，向往常一样，还是会一些人被普遍认为是相当正统的，避免自己犯任何这样的错误。
S. Athanasius again took the lead in bringing the church’s official doctrine about the Holy Spirit into line with the full Scriptural truth. He showed from the Bible that the Holy Spirit has the same substance and essence as the Father and the Son; in other words, the Spirit is also homoousion with Father and Son. The English term used to testify to this truth is “consubstantial,” which means that the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit share one and the same substance.
亚大纳西再一次率先使教会关于圣灵的正式教义与整个圣经的真理保持一致。他展示了圣经所说的圣灵与圣父和圣子具有同样的本质和实质；换句话说，圣灵也是与圣父和圣子同质。用来证明这个真理的英语单词是 “consubstantial”，意思是圣父、圣子和圣灵享有唯一和相同的本质。
T. The three bishops who are called the “Cappadocian Fathers,” Basil the Great (c. 330-379), Gregory of Nazianzus (329-389), and Gregory of Nyssa (330-395), also contributed to the clarification of the doctrine of the Trinity. They showed that the one Godhead exists simultaneously (同时) in three Persons, the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit. The Council of Constantinople clarified the church’s teaching on the Holy Spirit just as the Council of Nicaea had clarified the proper teaching about the Son. The expanded third article of the Nicene Creed uses Scriptural language to confess this truth. Paul used the word “Lord” of the Spirit (2 Cor. 3:17, 18). He also called Him the Spirit of Life (Rom. 8:2; 2 Cor. 3:6).
被称为“加帕多家教父”三位教父是大巴西流(大约公元330-379年)，纳齐安的格利高里(公元329-389年)和尼撒的格利高里(公元330-395年) 也致力于澄清关于三位一体的教义。他们向人们说明一位上帝同时存在三个位格，圣父、圣子和圣灵。君士坦丁堡会议阐述了教会关于圣灵的教导正如尼西亚会议上阐述了关于圣子的正确教导一样。扩充后的尼西亚信经第三信条用圣经的语言告白这个真理。保罗对圣灵用了“主”这个词(哥林多后书3:17, 18)。他还称圣灵为“赐生命的圣灵”(罗马书8:2；哥林多后书3:6)。
U. The next phrase, “who proceeds from the Father and the Son,” is also Biblical (John 15:26; 1 Cor. 2:12). The expression “and the Son” (Latin says this in the one word filioque) was added several centuries later in the Western Church and is neither confessed nor recited in the Eastern Church. This phrase is Scriptural, however, because the Spirit is described in Scripture as the Spirit both of the Father (Matt. 10:20) and the Son. He proceeds from the Father and at the same time is sent by the Son (John 20:22). Since He is consubstantial with the Father and the Son, He is to be worshiped and glorified together with them.
接下来“是从圣父、圣子所出”这个句子也是符合圣经的(约翰福音John 15:26；哥林多前书2:12)。“和圣子”(拉丁语中用来表示的一个词是filioque)这样的表述是在几个世纪之后在西方的教会中被添加进去的，但没有被东方的教会承认或诵读。而这个短语是合乎圣经的，因为圣经中描述的圣灵是圣父和圣子的圣灵(马太福音10:20)。他来自圣父并且同时由圣子差派(约翰福音20:22)。因为他与圣父和圣子同质，他将与他们一同被敬拜和荣耀。
V. One more clause deserves our attention: “who spoke through the prophets.” This phrase recalls directly the words of Peter: “For prophecy never had its origin in the will of man, but men spoke from God spoke as they were carried along by the Holy Spirit” (2 Peter 1:21). The Nicene Fathers confessed the doctrine of verbal inspiration, that is, that the holy men of God wrote only what the Holy Spirit communicated to them by inspiration. Because the Scriptures are the very Word of God, the Nicene Fathers could confess in the second article that Christ “rose again according to the Scriptures.”
还有一句值得我们关注的话是：“众先知说预言，皆是被圣灵感动”。这句话让我们立刻想到彼得的话：“因为预言从来没有出于人意的，乃是人被圣灵感动，说出神的话来”(彼得后书1:21)。尼西亚信经承认口头默示的教义，就是说，上帝的圣徒只写了圣灵通过默示与他们交通的话。因为圣经就是上帝的话语，尼西亚的长老们才能在第二部分中承认“照圣经之言复活”。
W. As has often been noted, the Nicene Creed is the only truly Ecumenical Creed; that is to say, it is accepted by the entire Christian world. It is unfortunate but probably not far from the truth, what the famous Oxford scholar J. N. D. Kelley says: “The Christian who repeats it or hears it sung today. . . is rarely conscious of the deeper theological intention which lies concealed beneath certain majestic clauses.” One can also say that if anyone will not accept the teachings of the Nicene Creed, he is not an orthodox Christian.
尼西亚信经一直以来被誉为唯一一部真正的大公信经；就是说它被整个基督徒世界所接受。虽然很不幸，著名的牛津学者J. N. D.凯利说“复述或听到它被人颂赞的人…很少意识到更深层次的宗教意图是华丽词语下掩盖的谎言”，但这也许就是现实存在的情况。一个人还可以说如何任何不接受尼西亚信经教导的人都不是正统的基督徒。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Worksheet for Lesson Five  第五课作业题</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-10/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Worksheet for Lesson Five: 第五课作业题：
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：1581
Worksheet for Lesson Five: 第五课作业题：
The Meaning of the Nicene Creed 尼西亚信经的意义
Section B. B 部分
1.What does the Creed mean by saying the Father is “maker…of all that is, seen and unseen?”
尼西亚信经中说“一切有形无形之万物之主”所代表的意思是什么？
Section C. C 部分
1.Why is it important to say that Jesus, the Son, is “true God?”
为什么说耶稣，圣子是“真神”很重要？
2.Can you think why Jesus is called “Light from Light?” (see John 1:1-5)
你能想出为什么称耶稣是“从光所出之光”吗？(参看约翰福音1:1-5)
Section D. D 部分
1.Why were the words “eternally begotten of the Father” and “begotten, not made” added?
为什么“是圣父在万世之先所生”和“是生非造”被添加进尼西亚信经？
Section E. E 部分
1.What was the relationship between The Father and Jesus according to: 以下关于圣父和耶稣之间关系的不同观点是什么：
A. Arius 阿里乌
B. The Eusebians 优西比乌
C. The Bible 圣经
Section F. F 部分
1.Give 3 reasons why some Orthodox Christians hesitated to accept the term homoousion? 给出正统基督徒对接受homoousion这个词显出迟疑的三个理由：
A.
B.
C.
Section G. G 部分
1.Where and when was the term homoousion finally accepted as the best expression to use about the relationship between God the Father and God the Son?
何时何地这个词最终作为天父上帝和上帝之子关系最好的表述被接受？
Section H. H 部分
1.What was the Son’s role in creation? 在创世中圣子发挥的作用是什么？
Section K. K 部分
1.What important addition about Jesus’ incarnation was made to the Creed in 381?
公元381年写进信经中关于耶稣道成肉身的重要补充是什么？
2.Which false teacher made this addition necessary?
哪个假教师使得这个补充具有必要性？
3.Describe in your own words what he taught about Jesus:
用你自己的语言描述他关于耶稣的教导是什么：
4.What council examined his teaching and what was their decision?
在什么会议上他的教导被审查并且审查的决定是什么？
Section L. L 部分
1.Explain what “substitutionary atonement” means and tell which part of the Creed teaches it:
解释“代替我们赎罪”的意思是什么并且说出信经的哪一部分教导了这一点。
2.What is meant by Jesus’ “vicarious” suffering and death?
说耶稣“代替”受苦和死的意思是什么？
Section N. N 部分
1.What words were added to the Creed because of the teaching of Marcellus of Ancyra?
因为安吉拉的马赛路的教导，使得什么被添加进信经？
2.Summarize what he taught:
概括他的教导：
Section O. O 部分
1.Which part of the Third Article is greatly expanded over the Apostles’ Creed?
第三部分的哪一部分较使徒信经得到了极大的扩充？
Section P. P 部分
1.In what way is the Holy Spirit: 从哪方面看，圣灵是：
A. Lord: 主
B. Giver of Life 赐生命者
Section R. R 部分
1.Why do you think the teaching about the person of the Holy Spirit was not studied in detail until the Second Ecumenical Council of 381?
你认为为什么直到公元381年的第二次大公会议，关于圣灵位格的教导才被细致地研究？
Section S. S 部分
1.How did the fight with Arius about the Son help also in the discussions about the Holy Spirit?
对抗阿里乌关于圣子的教导如何同时也帮助了关于圣灵的讨论？
Section U. U 部分
1.What does the Latin word filioque mean?
拉丁词语filioque的意思是什么？
2.Use your Bible to explain why the Western Church teaches that the Holy Spirit proceeds from the Father and the Son?
用圣经解释为什么西方教会教导圣灵是从圣父、圣子所出？
3.In what way was it unfortunate that this phrase was added so much later to the creed?
从哪方面来看，这个词太晚才被添加到信经中是不幸的？
Section V. V 部分
1.What do we call the doctrine taught in the words “who spoke through the prophets?
我们称用“众先知说预言”所教导的教义为什么？&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第六课 （lesson 6）亚大纳西信经的历史背景</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-11/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第六课 （lesson 6）亚大纳西信经的历史背景
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：1749
Lesson Six: Historical Background to the Athanasian Creed
第六课: 亚大纳西信经的历史背景
A. The Athanasian Creed is a magnificent confession. Luther once said, “I doubt whether the New Testament church has a more important document since the Apostolic Age.” The name of this creed like with that of the Apostles’ and Nicene Creeds, can easily lead to misunderstanding. It is named after Athanasius, the fourth-century bishop who fought so tenaciously against the false teaching of Arius. However, Athanasius was not the author of this confession, even though he was thought to be by most people in the Western church throughout the Middle Ages. They thought he wrote it while he was in exile in the West. In view of this tradition, this Creed was formally accepted into the Lutheran Book of Concord (1580) with the title, “The Athanasian Creed.” The Church of England in its official confession (The Thirty-Nine Articles) also accepted this creed under the same name. But even at this date many scholars questioned whether Athanasius had written it. Another name often used for this Creed is the Quicunque, since that is the opening word, translated into English, “Whoever….”
亚大纳西信经是庄严的信仰告白。路德曾说过，“我怀疑自使徒时代之后新约教会是否拥有比这更加重要的文件”。这部信经的名称与使徒信经和尼西亚信经相似，容易导致误解。它以亚大纳西，四世纪时顽强地与阿里乌的错误教导抗争的一位主教命名。然而，亚大纳西不是这个信仰告白的作者，尽管中世纪西方教会中的大多数人认为他是。他们认为他在被流放到西方时写了这部信经。考虑到这样的说法，这部信经以“亚大纳西信经”这个名称正式被载入路德协同信条(1580)中。英格兰教会在它的正式信仰告白(三十九信条)中也以同样的名称接受了这个信经。但是现在仍有很多学者质疑亚大纳西是否写了这部信经。这个信经常用的另一个名称是Quicunque，因为那是信经一开始用到的词，翻译成英语是，“凡…的人”。
B. For several reasons we are quite sure that Athanasius did not write it. First of all, it was originally written in the Latin language. The author of the Quicunque wrote in a beautiful, sophisticated Latin style, giving careful attention to the rhythms of the paragraphs and of the sentences. The translations can catch some of this but, as scholars acknowledge, they can never do justice to the original Latin. Athanasius did spend years in exile for his faith, in the deserts of Egypt, in Rome and even as far away as Germany. His native language, however, was Greek, and it was in that language which he debated and wrote his treatises. Therefore, it seems unlikely that he could have written the Quicunque in such sophisticated Latin. The Quicunque was, of course, translated into Greek but not before the 12th century, hundreds of years after Athanasius had died.
出于几个理由我们非常确信亚大纳西没有写这部信经。首先，它起初是由拉丁文所写。亚大纳西信经的作者用优美、精确的拉丁风格对段落和句子的韵律进行了细致处理。翻译后的信经能够体现出原文中的一些特点，但是根据学者们经验，翻译不可能保持与原拉丁文完全一致。亚大纳西的确因为他的信仰被流放了几年，到了埃及的沙漠、罗马甚至远至德国。然而他的母语是希腊语，也是他在辩论和他的专著中使用的语言。因此，看似不太可能他用如此精确的拉丁语写了亚大纳西信经。亚大纳西信经当然被翻译成了希腊语，但是不是在十二世纪之前，而是在亚大纳西死后几百年。
C. Secondly, there is also no evidence that this Creed was known either to Athanasius or any of his followers. If Athanasius had actually written it, even when he was in exile in the West, it is difficult to understand why he, his students or his successors in Egypt would not have referred to it.
其次，也没有证据表明这个信经为亚大纳西或任何他的追随者所熟知。如果亚大纳西真的的写了这部信经，即使是在他被流放时所写，也很难理解为什么他自己、他的学生或他在埃及的继任者没有提到这部信经。
D. Finally, when one looks carefully at the theological content of the Creed, one sees that it really deals with controversies which arose in the church after the death of Athanasius (A. D. 373). After his death false teachers spawned new heresies regarding the Trinity and the person of Jesus Christ. These heresies had to be rejected by more careful explanations of what the Scriptures said about God and His essence. Because the author of this Creed uses language and phrases similar to those of St. Augustine, he obviously was well versed in the works of St. Augustine (354-430). Augustine had been forced to study the Scriptural doctrine of the Trinity and had written the most detailed treatises on this subject.
最后，当你仔细看这部信经的神学内容时，你会发现它实际上涉及的是亚大纳西死(公元373)后教会中兴起的争论。在他死后假文士制造出大量关于三位一体和耶稣基督位格的异端邪说。这些异端邪说必定被圣经中关于上帝和他本质更详细的解释所排斥。因为这部信经的作者使用的语言和句子与圣奥古斯丁所写的相似，他显然精通圣奥古斯丁的著作(354-430)。奥古斯丁被迫研究圣经关于三位一体的教义并他所写的大多数详细专著都是关于这个主题的。
E. But if Athanasius was not the author of the “Athanasian Creed,” who was? For years this fascinating question has intrigued scholars. We probably shall never know who it was, and his name has been lost, possibly for ever. Numerous theologians have been suggested as author, but without any sure evidence for any of them. Since it was written in Latin, it is known that it originated in the West, but when and where?
但是如果亚大纳西不是“亚大纳西信经”的作者，那么谁是呢？多少年来，这个极富吸引力的问题引起了学者们的兴趣。我们也许永远也不会知道谁是作者，他的名字可能从此遗失。许多神学家都被提名为作者，但是没有任何有力证据证明他们中的任何一个人是作者。既然它由拉丁文所写，众所周知它源于西方，那么是在何时何地呢？
F. Until about 60 years ago, the earliest conclusive evidence for its existence came from the Eighth Century. In 1931, however, a manuscript was discovered which contained selections of sermons by the famous theologian Caesarius. He was the Bishop of Arles in Southern France from 502-542. Among the sermons in this manuscript was the Athanasian Creed virtually as we have it today, under the title The Catholic Faith of St. Athanasius, Bishop. Although Caesarius knew and used the Quicunque, there is not proof that he is the author, as some scholars have thought. Some evidence suggests that the Quicunque or a very similar creed was known in Gaul (now France) during the middle of the Fifth Century. This is probably as close as we can come with regard to the date and place of origin for this famous document.
最早关于它存在的决定性证据来自与十八世纪。1921年，包括著名神学家凯撒利乌斯讲道节选的手稿被发现。他是502-542年期间法国南部阿尔勒地区的主角。这部手稿的讲道中题目为圣亚大纳西主教的大公信仰的讲道实际上就是我们现今所用的亚大纳西信经。尽管凯撒利乌斯了解并使用了亚大纳西信经，但是一些学者认为这不能证明他就是作者。一些证据显示亚大纳西信经或与之非常类似的信经在十五世纪中期在高卢(现今的法国)为人们所熟知。这也许是我们能提供的关于这个著名文件起源的时间和地点最接近的信息。
G. If our Athanasian Creed perhaps had its origin in ancient France, one addition point is worth noting. In the preface to the collection of Bishop Caesarius’ sermons, the compiler exhorts all clergymen and laymen to be familiar with the Catholic faith. Hence they were admonished to read the book of sermons, which included the Athanasian Creed, and “instruct others in it.”
如果我们的亚大纳西信经可能源于古代的法国，那么还有一点值得我们注意。在主教凯撒利乌斯讲道选集的序言中，编者劝告所有神职人员与平信徒熟悉大公信仰。因此他们被劝告要读那部讲道包括亚大纳西信经和“指导他人”的选集。
H. The significance of this admonition can be understood against the background of what had been happening in Western Europe. Germanic tribes (the Vandals and the Goths) had for several centuries put pressure on the Roman Empire from the North. At the beginning of the Fifth Century, they crossed the Rhine River and spread over what is now France. A few years later they invaded Italy, pillaged Rome and conquered northern Africa. These northern tribes did not have much use for Roman learning and culture. With them in control, the people of the former Roman Empire, including the clergy, soon became illiterate and ignorant of the Scriptures and the theology of the church.
这个劝告的重要性可以理解为在于它是以当时发生在西欧的事件为背景。日耳曼部族(汪达尔人和哥特人)几个世纪以来一直从北方向罗马帝国施压。在十五世纪初期，他们跨过莱茵河并入侵现在的法国。几年后他们入侵意大利，侵略罗马并攻克了非洲北部。这些北方部族对于罗马的学术和文化没起到多大作用。在他们的控制下，前罗马帝国的人民包括神职人员，不久就对圣经和教会神学一窍不通和一无所知。
I. The years 400-800 have been traditionally called “The Dark Ages” and many Christians were truly in the dark about the Bible’s teachings. Besides, most of the Goths who controlled France were Arian Christians. They had originally been converted by missionaries teaching the Arian heresy that Jesus Christ was not true God equal with the Father. Such circumstances were not only discouraging to the remaining pious clergy and Christians in France, but they were also a great peril to the doctrinal foundation of the church. Then, somewhere in France, in this time of disrespect for learning and orthodoxy, comes this clear, unambiguous Scriptural confession of the Trinity and the doctrine of the person and work of Jesus Christ. It is majestic in the great truths it confesses, and it speaks loudly and clearly: “Whoever wishes to be saved must, above all else, hold to the true Christian faith” (Sentence 1).
公元400-800年通常被称为 “黑暗时代”，并且许多基督徒对圣经教导确实是一无所知。另外，控制法国的大多数哥特人都是阿里乌派基督徒。他们起初因传教士教导阿里乌关于耶稣基督不是与天父同等的上帝的异端邪说而信上帝。这样的环境不仅使法国剩下的敬虔的神职人员和基督徒感到灰心，也对教会的教义根基构成了巨大威胁。然后，法国的一些地方在这个藐视学习和正统学说的时代，可以明显看到对三位一体的圣经信仰告白以及耶稣基督位格和事工的含糊其辞。这部信经的伟大在于它所认的重要真理和清楚明白地说到：“凡人欲得救，首先当持守大公教会信仰”(第一句)。
J. The Quicunque became a popular creed for instructional purposes, especially after the French king Charlemagne (died 814) decreed (发布命令) that all church leaders had to learn it. At a council held at Rheims in 852, a resolution was passed requiring the clergy to memorize it, grasp its meaning, and be able to expound it in popular language.
由于亚大纳西信经的指导性用途，它广受欢迎，尤其是在法国国王查理曼大帝(于公元814年去世)发布命令所有教会领导者都必须学习亚大纳西信经之后。公元852年在兰斯举行的一个会议上，通过了一项决议要求神职人员背诵它，掌握它的意思并能用通俗的语言进行阐述。
K. The Athanasian Creed never achieved the widespread use in worship that the Apostles’ and the Nicene Creed did, partly because of its length. Its recitation, however, was ordered in the Roman Catholic churches on some Sundays after Epiphany and Pentecost and on Trinity Sunday. The Book of Common Prayer of the Episcopal Church ordered its use at Matins on thirteen holy days throughout the church yea. The liturgical sections of our Lutheran hymnals also contain the Athanasian Creed and it is sometimes recited on Trinity Sunday.
亚大纳西信经从没有像使徒信经和尼西亚信经一样在敬拜中被广泛使用，其中一部分原因是由于它的长度。然而，罗马天主教会要求在主显节，五旬节之后的几个主日和三一主日诵读它。圣公会的公祷书要求在教会年中13个圣日的晨祷中使用它。我们路德赞美诗集的礼拜部分也包含亚大纳西信经并且有时会在三一主日时诵读它。
L. The Athanasian Creed reads as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whoever wishes to be saved must, above all else, hold to the true Christian faith.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whoever does not keep this faith pure in all points will certainly perish forever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now this is the true Christian faith: We worship one God in three persons, and three persons in one God,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without mixing the persons or dividing the divine being.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each person—the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit – is distinct,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But the deity of Father, Son, and Holy Spirit is one, equal in glory and co-eternal in majesty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What the Father is, so is the Son, and so is the Holy Spirit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Father is uncreated, the Son uncreated, the Holy Spirit uncreated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Father infinite, the Son infinite, the Holy Spirit infinite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Father is eternal, the Son eternal, the Holy Spirit eternal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet they are not three who are eternal, but there is one who is eternal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just as there are not three who are uncreated nor three who are infinite, but there is one who is uncreated and one who is infinite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the same way the Father is almighty, the Son is almighty, the Holy Spirit is almighty;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet they are not three who are almighty, but there is one who is almighty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So the Father is God, the Son is God, the Holy Spirit is God;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet they are not three Gods, but one God.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So the Father is Lord, the Son is Lord, the Holy Spirit is Lord;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet they are not three Lords, but one Lord. For just as Christian truth compels us to confess each person individually to be God and Lord,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So the true Christian faith forbids us to speak of three Gods or three Lords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Father is neither made nor created nor begotten of anyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Son is neither made nor created, but is begotten of the Father alone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Holy Spirit is neither made nor created nor begotten, but proceeds from the Father and the Son.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So there is one Father, not three Fathers; one Son, not three Sons; one Holy Spirit, not three Holy Spirits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And within this Trinity none comes before or after; none is greater or inferior,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But all three persons are coequal and co-eternal, so that in every way, as stated before, all three persons are to be worshiped as one God and one God worshiped as three persons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whoever wished to be saved must have this conviction of the Trinity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is furthermore necessary for eternal salvation truly to believe that our Lord Jesus Christ also took on human flesh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now this is the true Christian faith: We believe and confess that our Lord Jesus Christ, God’s Son, is both God and man.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He is God, eternally begotten from the nature of the Father, and he is man, born in time from the nature of his mother,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fully God, fully man, with rational soul and human flesh,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equal to the Father as to his deity, less than the Father as to his humanity;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And though he is both God and man, Christ is not two persons but one,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One, not by changing the deity into flesh, but by taking the humanity into God;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One, indeed, not by mixture of the natures, but by unity in one person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For just as the rational soul and flesh are one human being, so God and man are one Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He suffered for our salvation, descended into hell, rose the third day from the dead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He ascended into heaven, is seated at the right hand of God the Father almighty, and from there he will come to judge the living and the dead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At his coming all people will rise with their own bodies to answer for their personal deeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Those who have done good will enter eternal life, but those who have done evil will go into eternal fire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the true Christian faith. Whoever does not faithfully and firmly believe this cannot be saved.
亚大纳西信经内容如下：&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;凡人欲得救，首先当持守大公教会信仰。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;此信仰，凡守之不全不正者，必永远沉沦。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;大公教会信仰即：我等敬拜一体三位，而三位一体之神。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;其位不紊，其体不分。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;父一位，子一位，圣灵亦一位。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;然而父子圣灵同一神性，同一荣耀，亦同一永恒之尊严。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;父如何，子如何，圣灵亦如何。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;父不受造，子不受造，圣灵亦不受造。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;父无限，子无限，圣灵亦无限。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;父永恒，子永恒，圣灵亦永恒。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;非三永恒者，乃一永恒者。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;非三不受造者，非三无限者，乃一不受造者，一无限者。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;如此，父全能，子全能，圣灵亦全能。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;然而，非三全能者，乃一全能者。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;如是，父是神，子是神，圣灵亦是神。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;然而，非三神，乃一神。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;如是，父是主，子是主，圣灵亦是主。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;然而，非三主，乃一主。 依基督真道，我等不得不认三位均为神，均为主。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;依大公教，我等亦不得谓神有三，亦不得谓主有三。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;父非由谁作成：既非受造，亦非受生。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;子独由于父：非作成，亦非受造；而为受生。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;圣灵由于父和子：既非作成，亦非受造，亦非受生；而为发出。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;如是，有一父，非三父，有一子，非三子，有一圣灵，非三圣灵。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;且此三位无分先后，无别尊卑。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;三位乃均永恒，而同等。由是如前所言，我等当敬拜一体三位，而三位一体之神。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;所以凡欲得救者，必如是而思三位一体之神。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;再者，为求得永恒救赎，彼亦必笃信我等之主耶稣基督成为人身。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;依真正信仰，我等信认神之子我等之主耶稣基督，为神，又为人。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;其为神，与圣父同体，受生于诸世界之先；其为人，与其母同体，诞生于此世界。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;全神，亦全人，具有理性之灵，血肉之身。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;依其为神，与父同等，依其为人，少逊于父。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;彼虽为神，亦为人，然非为二，乃为一基督。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;彼为一，非由于变神为血肉，乃由于使其人性进入于神。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;合为一：非由二性相混，乃由于位格为一。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;如灵与身成为一人，神与人成为一基督。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;彼为救我等而受难，降至阴间，第三日从死里复活。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;升天，作于全能神父之右。 将来必从彼处降临，审判活人死人。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;彼降临时，万人必具身体复活；并供认所行之事。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;行善者必入永生，作恶者必入永火。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;此乃大公教会之信仰，人除非笃实相信，必不能得救。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Worksheet for Lesson Six  第六课作业题</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-12/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Worksheet for Lesson Six: 第六课作业题：
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：1462
Worksheet for Lesson Six: 第六课作业题：
The Athanasian Creed – Historical Background 亚大纳西信经的历史背景
Section A. A 部分
1.Why was this Creed called the Athanasian Creed?
为什么这部信经被称为亚大纳西信经？
2.What is a different name used for this same Creed, what does it mean, and why was it named this?
还有什么不同的名称被用于这部信经，这个名称的意思是什么，为什么这样命名？
3.In what way can the name “Athanasian Creed” still be used properly for this document?
从哪方面来看，“亚大纳西信经”这个名称适合于这个信经？
Sections B-D. B-D 部分
1.List below 3 reasons why scholars think that Athanasius did not write this creed:
列举学者认为不是亚大纳西写了这部信经的三个理由：
A.
B.
C.
Section F. F 部分
1.Why do some scholars think that Caesarius of Arles wrote it?
为什么一些学者认为凯撒利乌斯写了这部信经？
2.Where and when was it most likely written?
这部信经最有可能于何时何地所写？
Sections G-I. G-I 部分
1.List two reasons why this new creed was needed? 列举为什么需要这样一部新的信经的两个理由：
A.
B.
Section J. J 部分
1.The Athanasian Creed eventually was accepted as an official church document:
亚大纳西信经最终作为教会正式文件被接受：
A. By which king? 是通过哪位国王？
B. By which church council? 是通过哪次教会会议？
Section K. K 部分
1.When is the Creed used in the following denominations?
这部信经何时被用于以下教派？
A.Episcopal (or Anglican) Church 圣公会教会
B.Catholic Church 天主教教会
C.Lutheran Church 路德宗教会
2.Tell why you think it is or isn’t used in the following denominations:
说明你认为为什么它被用于或未被用于以下教派：
A.Baptist Church 浸信会
B.Pentecostal churches 灵恩派教会
C.Methodist Church 卫理公会
Section L. L 部分
1.Read through the Athanasian Creed and answer the following:
阅读亚大纳西信经并回答以下问题：
A.In what way is its form different from that of the other 2 creeds?
从哪方面来看，它形式不同于其他两部信经？
B.What doctrinal issues does it address in most detail?
它的大部分内容都是针对的哪些教义争论？
C.Do you think this Creed was meant to replace or to be used along side the other two creeds?Explain your answer?
你认为这部信经是为了替代其他两部信经还是与其他两部信经共同使用？解释你的答案？&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第七课 （lesson 7）亚大纳西信经的教导</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-13/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第七课 （lesson 7）亚大纳西信经的教导
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：1641
Lesson Seven: The Teaching of the Athanasian Creed
第七课: 亚大纳西信经的教导
A. This Creed is longer and more involved than the other two Ecumenical Creeds. Before analyzing its contents in detail, let us look at its basic structure. The Creed contains 40 sentences. The first two and the last serve as a sort of framework for the rest of the Creed. The middle part basically sets forth in detail two doctrines – the Godhead or the Trinity and the Person and work of Jesus Christ. An outline would appear like this:
这部信经比其他两大公信经使用的时间更长和更广泛。在我们详细分析它的内容之前，我们先来看看它的基本结构。这部信经有40条。开始的两句和最后一句用来作为信经其余部分的框架。中间部分基本上详细阐述了两部分的教义– 神性或者说是三位一体以及耶稣基督的位格和工作。概述如下：
Introduction (1-2): 引言
The necessity for holding to the Catholic Faith.
坚持天主教信仰的必要性
Part I: The Trinity (3-26) 三位一体
A. Explanation of the doctrine of the Trinity. (3-25)
B. Conclusion to the first part. (26)
A. 三位一体教义的阐述
B. 第一部分的结论
Part II: The Incarnation (27-39) 道成肉身
A. The teaching about Jesus Christ, fully divine and fully human. (27-35)
B. The teaching about the redeeming work of the Divine-Human Christ. (36-39)
A. 关于耶稣基督、完全神性和完全人性的教导
B. 关于神人二性的基督救恩工作的教导
Conclusion: (40) 结论
The necessity of holding to the Catholic Faith.
坚持天主教信仰的必要性
B. The Damnatory Clauses 受到指责的条款
Read Sentences 1, 2, 26, and 40. These sentences show a striking difference from the two other Creeds we have studied because they explicitly draw a line, between the true doctrine and all false doctrine, between what is Christian and what is not Christian. The Biblical doctrine must be fenced off from the heresies that had arisen within the external church. Sentences 1 and 2 show, first positively and then negatively, the absolute necessity of accepting the Biblically-revealed faith. The word faith is here used in the sense of the doctrine delivered by the inspired Apostolic teachers, in contrast to the usual meaning of saving faith in Jesus Christ. This is what Jude refers to when he exhorts in his letter: “Earnestly contend for the faith which was once delivered to the saints” (Jude 3).
阅读第1、2、26和40条。这几条展现了与我们学过的其他两部信经的显著不同，因为它在纯正的教导与错误的教导之间以及什么是基督教与什么不是基督教之间划出了明确的分界线。圣经教义必须与外部教会中兴起的异端邪说分开。第一句和第二句从正反两个方面向我们展示了领受圣经所揭示的信心的绝对必要性。信心这个词在此处是相对于通常所说的在耶稣基督里救恩的信心而言的受到默示的使徒教师所传授的教导。这就是犹大在他的信中提到的：“要为从前一次交付圣徒的真道竭力地争辩”(犹大书3)。
C. The negative statements, such as “he shall perish everlastingly,” reject false teaching and point out the consequences of personal unbelief. In theological terminology they are called the damnatory clauses. This phrase comes from the serious words of warning the Apostle Paul gave to the Galatians that they should reject anyone preaching a gospel contrary to that which Paul had preached:
But even if we or an angel from heaven should preach a Gospel other than the one we preached to you, let him be eternally condemned. As we have already said, so now I say again: If anybody is preaching to you a gospel other than what you accepted, let him be eternally condemned (Gal. 1:8, 9).
在否定的陈述中，如“他将永远灭亡”，拒绝错误教导并指出个人不信的后果。在神学术语中，他们给称为“咒诅的条款”。这个短语来自使徒保罗给加拉太人严厉的关于他们应该拒绝任何人传讲那些与保罗所传讲的相悖的福音：
但无论是我们，是天上来的使者，若传福音给你们，与我们所传给你们的不同，他就应当被咒诅。我们已经说了，现在又说：若有人传福音给你们，与你们所领受的不同，他就应当被咒诅！(加拉太书1:8,9)
D. The Greek word for “be condemned” or “be damned” is anathema. Hence, the clauses which reject false teaching are called Anathemas or damnatory clauses. Other confessions in the Book of Concord, particularly in the Formula of Concord, follow the Athanasian Creed in clearly condemning false teachings and spelling out their eternal consequences. Many people, both theologians and laymen, have objected to such damnatory clauses. They prefer teaching a gentle inoffensive doctrine of the Gospel. Such an approach is clearly unscriptural. For the bible teaches that the only way to be saved is by faith in Jesus Christ. It also clearly teaches that unbelievers will be excluded from God’s eternal kingdom (Acts 4:12; Mark 16:16). The Athanasian Creed deals with the most fundamental Christian truths: the Trinity, the Deity of Christ, and His redeeming work. Without knowledge of these truths saving faith is impossible. Thus our ultimate salvation is at stake if any teaching about these truths is changed or destroyed altogether.
希腊语中“被咒诅”或“被定罪”用的是“anathema诅咒”这个词。因此，这个拒绝错误教导的词组被称为诅咒或咒诅的条款。协同书中的其他认信，特别协同信条，在明确谴责错误教导和详细说明他们永恒的后果方面与亚大纳西信经一致。神学家和平信徒中的许多人都反对这样咒诅的条款。他们更喜欢温和不触犯人的福音教导。这样一种方式是非常明显的非圣经教导。因为圣经教导唯一得救的方式就是通过在耶稣基督里的信心。它也明确地教导了不信者不能进上帝永恒的国(使徒信经4:12;马可福音16:16)。亚大纳西信经教导的是最基本的关于基督的真理：三位一体、基督的神性、他救赎的工作。不了解这些真理而获得救恩的信心是不可能的。因此如果任何关于这些真理的教导被改变或被完全毁灭，那我们最终能否被拯救就不得而知了。
E. THE TRINITY 三位一体
Read Sentence 3. The catholic or universal faith consists, first of all, in worshiping one God in Trinity and in Unity. In the Apostles’ and Nicene Creeds, we confess first the Father, then the Son, and finally the Holy Ghost. Each of these creeds devotes one article to each Person. The Athanasian Creed takes a different approach. This Creed begins by setting forth the Trinity as a unit. The Scriptures declare that God is but one (1 Cor. 8:4) and yet ascribe divinity to three, namely, the Father, the Son, and the Holy Ghost (Matt. 28:19).
阅读第3条。普世的或全世界的信仰坚持，首先，敬拜三位一体和合一中的一位上帝。在使徒信经和尼西亚信经中，我们首先承认圣父，然后是圣子，最后是圣灵。这其中的每种信经都用一个条款阐述一个位格。亚大纳西信经用来不同的方式。这部信经一开始整体阐述了三位一体。圣经宣告上帝只有一位(哥林多前书8:4)，但是神性有三位，即圣父、圣子和圣灵(马太福音28:19)。
F. This statement of the Creed about God is biblical, yet it defies all attempts by our human reason to understand what it says. Our reason simply can not understand that the Godhead, while one indivisible substance (or reality) is simultaneously three Persons. So it is only by faith anyone can accept the Athanasian Creed. By confessing it he acknowledges that this truth has come directly from God’s Holy Scriptures, which are God’s direct revelation. Only when a person worships this Triune God does he truly worship the one and only God, as this Creed emphasizes.
这部信经中关于上帝的陈述是与圣经相符的，但是这样的阐述使人完全无法理解。简单来说，我们不能理解的是神性，一个不可见的物质 (或者说实体) 同时具有三个位格。因此只有凭着信心才能接受亚大纳西信经。通过对它的认信能了解这个真理直接来自上帝所直接揭示的圣经。只有当一个人敬拜三位一体的上帝时，他才是真正地敬拜独一的真神，这就是这部信经所强调的。
G. Read sentences 4-6. While the Bible does not explain to our limited reason the mystery of this revelation, it does give us considerable information about the doctrine of the Trinity. Sentences 4-6 hold these two apparently contradictory truths about God in tension [one God in Trinity and the Trinity in Unity]. The authors of the creed warn us not to mix the persons nor to divide the substance. Here it is necessary to define what the Early Church meant by the words person and substance.
阅读第4-6条。圣经没有针对我们有限的理性解释这个启示的奥秘，却给我们了关于三位一体的教导相当丰富的信息。4-6条中存在看似矛盾的两个关于上帝自身矛盾性(三个位格中的一位上帝和一位上帝中的三个位格)的真理。信经的作者们提醒我们不要混淆位格或分裂本质。在此有必要定义早期教会中所讲的位格和本质的意义。
H. The word person means that which exists in and of itself and is not a part or a quality of another (Augsburg Confession I, 4). The term substance (or essence) signifies the one undivided essence or reality belonging to God and manifested in the three Persons of the Deity. Only one such essence belongs to each Person of the Godhead, wholly and without division. The Quicunque then goes on to draw the conclusion, that since the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit, while three distinct Persons, are one and the same Godhead, each must have exactly the same glory and majesty as the other two.
位格这个词的意思是存在于并且自行存在，而不是另一个的一部分或一种特质(奥古斯堡信条I, 4)。本质(或实质)这个词指的是一个属于上帝不可分割的本质或本体而且在上帝的三个位格中显现。只有这样的本质完全地没有分割的属于上帝的每一个位格。亚大纳西信经在之后得出的结论是圣父、圣子和圣灵是三个不同的位格，但是是同一位上帝，每一个位格都与其他两个位格具有完全一样的荣耀和权柄。
I. Read Sentences 7-14. Because all three persons of the Godhead share or exercise the same attributes, the creed concludes that each person is God in every sense of the word. It confesses that each person or member of Godhead has the following characteristics: each is uncreated, infinite, eternal, and all-powerful. Yet we are warned against concluding that there are three infinites, three eternals, etc.
阅读第7-14条。因为上帝的全部三个位格共有或运用同样的属性，信经得出的结论是每一个位格都是完全的上帝。它承认上帝的每一个位格或每一部分都有如下特征：每一位都是非受造的、无限的、永恒的并且全能的。但是我们却被告诫不要推断三位是三无限者、三永恒者等等。
J. Read Sentences 15-19. In this section the Creed warns against Tritheism (the doctrine that the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit are three separate and distinct Gods). Each of the three Persons is God and Lord because each one of them is the one Godhead. Yet there are not three Gods or three Lords. The Creed insists on the Oneness of the Godhead. It places each of the three distinct divine Persons in balance with the other two in a series of statement that tie one Person in with the other two.
阅读第15-19条。信经在这一部分提醒我们要警惕三位异体论(教导圣父、圣子和圣灵是三位独立而且不同的上帝)。三个位格中的每一位都是上帝和主，因为他们中的每一位拥有同一神性。但是不存在三位上帝或三位主。信经坚持单一神性。它使得三个具有神性的不同位格中的每一位处于与其他两位同等的地位如一系列陈述所说一个位格与其他两个位格一致。
K. The question that immediately comes to mind is: what is the relationship among the three Persons in the Godhead, how may we speak about it. Scripture ascribes the entire Godhead, not only to the Father but also to the Son (Col. 2:9) and to the Holy Spirit (Acts 5:4). The three Persons are identical in substance and identical in attributers, yet they differ. But they differ only in one respect, namely, in the relation they bear to each other.
我们立刻想到的问题就是:上帝的三个位格之间有什么关系，我们该如何解释它。圣经将完全的神性不仅归给圣父也归给圣子(歌罗西书2:9)和圣灵(使徒行传5:4)。三个位格在本质上相同并且在属性上相同，然而他们不同。但是他们仅在一方面不同，即在彼此的关系上他们相互依存。
L. Read Sentences 20-23. With these words the Creed spells out this relationship. In eternity, the Father derives His Being from no one. But, in eternity the Son is begotten as a Person distinct from the Father. In other words, the Father Himself, unbegotten, begat the son from eternity (Psalm 2:7). Yet the Son in essence remains identical with the Father. In the Trinity from eternity, the Holy Spirit proceeds from the Father and the Son. He is a distinct and separate person but in such a way that He remains one with the Father and the Son in essence. And the Father and the Son remain one in essence with the Holy Spirit.
阅读20-23条。信经的这些话语详细说明了这种关系。在永恒中，圣父的本质来自于他本身。但是，在永恒中圣子成为与圣父不同的位格。换句话说，圣父本身自然而生，圣子从亘古就存在(诗篇2:7)。然而圣子在本质上与圣父相同。从亘古在三位一体中，圣灵就出于圣父和圣子。他是不同的并独立的位格，虽然如此他与圣父和圣子在本质上仍是一位。并且圣父与圣子也与圣灵在本质上相同。
M. Together with the Son, the Father “breathes” the Holy Spirit from eternity from the hidden majesty of the Godhead. The Holy Ghost proceeds from the Father and from the Son; from eternity. He is the Spirit both of the Father (Matt. 10:20) and of the Son (Gal. 4:6). He proceeds from the Father and at the same time is sent by the son (John 15:26; John 20:22). Evidence such as this from the Scriptures entitles us to declare that the three persons are different from each other and that each is unique as a person. The Latin word filioque (and the Son) occurs in Sentence 22. The John passages probably are the source from which this phrase was taken and later added to the Nicene Creed.
圣父、圣子从亘古“吹出”来自上帝隐藏的权柄的圣灵。圣灵出于圣父和圣子；从亘古而来。他是圣父(马太福音10:20)和圣子(加拉太书4:6)的灵。他出于圣父同时被圣子差派(约翰福音15:26；约翰福音20:22)。这样从圣经来的证明使我们能宣告三个位格彼此不同并且是每一个都是独一无二的位格。拉丁语中filioque (圣子)这个词出现在第22条中。这个词可能来自约翰的文章并在之后添加到尼西亚信经中。
N. Read Sentences 24-26. Sentences 24-25 make the further point that, though Scripture speaks of a difference of relationship within the One Divine Substance, none of the Three is greater or lesser than another, but all three are co-equal and co-eternal. As a result, orthodox Christians worship the Unity in Trinity and the Trinity in Unity. One can give no more details than these. The Triune God has not pulled aside any further the veil of what His essence is. It is beyond our understanding. We can only say what Augustine did about the Trinity: “We will empty the ocean with a sea-shell before we comprehend this subject with human language.” Sentence 26 concludes the section of the Creed about the Trinity.
阅读第24-26条。第24-25条进一步指出，虽然圣经中说到一个神圣本质中的不同关系，但是三位中没有一位比另一位地位更高或更低，而是三位同等并永恒。因此，正统的基督徒敬拜三位一体的合一以及合一的三位一体。没有任何其他说明能够提供比这更多的信息了。三位一体的上帝并没有将他本质的面纱向我们揭开更多。它是超越我们理解能力的。我们只能按照奥古斯丁关于三位一体的解释：“在我们用人类的语言理解这个主题之前，我们都将是在用贝壳倒空海水。”第26条总结了信经中关于三位一体的说明。
O. THE INCARNATION 道成肉身
Read Sentences 27-34. In order to be saved a person must not only believe in the Holy Trinity, but also know and believe in the work of Christ his Savior. It is necessary to his eternal salvation that he also believe faithfully (fideliter) the Incarnation of our Lord Jesus Christ. Sentences 27-35 assert that in the Incarnation, Christ is at once fully God and fully human. It also adds that because Jesus was a human being just like us, he also had a rational (reasoning) mind (Remember that Apollinaris of Laodicea had denied the full humanity of Christ, see Chapter 5 K). The son of God has a two-fold “generation”; that is, before time from the Father and in time from the virgin Mary. This Creed recognized a duality of natures and a unity of person in Christ the Redeemer.
阅读第27-34条。一个人如果要得救不仅要相信神圣的三位一体，而且要了解和相信救主基督的工作。对于永恒的救恩，他还需要坚信(亚大纳西信经)我们的主耶稣基督道成肉身。第27-35条主张在道成肉身中，基督既是完全的上帝也是完全的人。同时还补充到因为耶稣是和我们一样的人，他也有理智的(理性的)思想(老底嘉的阿波利拿里曾否认基督的完全人性，参见第五章K部分)。上帝的儿子具有双重“世代”；就是说，亘古圣父出现的时候以及童贞女马利亚所生活的时代。这部信经承认救赎主基督的双重属性以及与人的合一。
P. Christ in his talks with the Jews and his disciples makes it clear that he existed as a Person before he was born of the virgin Mary (John 8:58; John 17:5). At the same time, Scripture makes it clear that he took on human nature from the virgin Mary in the fullness of time (John 1:14; Rom. 9:5; 1 Tim. 3:16), becoming a complete human being with a body and soul (Sentences 29 &amp;amp; 30.) He exists in the two natures, the divine and human; and each of these two is truly genuine and complete (Sentences 30 &amp;amp; 31). But still there is not division in his person. From the time of incarnation and into all eternity He remains one person in two natures. This unity is an unity of the person. It does not involve any mixing of the divine and human. And it is not transformation of the divine into the human. What really happened at the incarnation was that God’s eternal Son took our human nature to himself and made it his very own (Sentences 32-34).
基督在他与犹太人和他门徒的谈话中明确表示在他由童贞女马利亚所生之前就作为一个位格存在(约翰福音8:58；约翰福音17:5)。同时，圣经也清楚地告诉我们及至时候满足，他由童贞女马利亚所生(约翰福音1:14；罗马书9:5；提摩太前书3:16)，成为具有肉体和灵魂的完全人(第29和30条)。他具有两种属性，神性和人性；并且两者中的每一个都是绝对真实和完全的(第30和31条)。但是在他本身两者并没有分离。在道成肉身的时候和在永恒中他都是两种属性一个位格。这是与人的合一。不是神和人的混合。也不是从神变为人。在道成肉身时真正发生的是上帝永生的儿子取了人性并使它成为完全的自己(第32-34句)。
Q. Read Sentence 35. The Quicunque rounds off this section with a famous analogy or a comparison. With the introductory word for, this sentence summarizes the doctrine set forth in the preceding sentences. It shows by a familiar illustration that while even though Christ has two distinct natures, he is nevertheless one person. He exists as one person without any mixture of the two natures whatsoever. In carefully balanced sentences, this Creed testifies to the Scriptural paradox of two natures, the divine and the human, united in the one Christ.
阅读第35条。亚大纳西信经以一个著名类比或对比结束了这一部分。以一个引导式的词汇“因为”，这句话总结了前一句话中阐述的教导。一个熟悉的说明向我们显示了虽然基督具有两个不同属性，然而他仍是一个位格。这部信经见证了一个非两种属性混合的位格，见 证了关于两种属性-神性和人性在一位基督里的合一。
R. The Creed then briefly explains what this divine-human Christ has done, still does, and will do for our salvation (#36-39). Its language and content is very similar to the second articles of the other two Ecumenical Creeds. The concluding sentence of the Creed (#40) brings us back to its beginning – how absolutely necessary it is to believe all that God has said, to trust in Jesus for salvation and to keep this faith pure until death. For without faith in the Holy Trinity and in Jesus as our Savior, only eternal punishment and damnation follow this life.
然后信经简单阐述了神人二性的基督为我们的救恩已经做的，正在做的以及将要做的工作(第36-39条)。它的语言和内容都与其他两部大公信经的第二部分非常相似。这部信经的总结句与开头部分相呼应-相信上帝所有的话语和耶稣带给我们的救恩并保持这种纯正的信心直到去世的一天是如此重要。因为不相信三位一体以及耶稣是我们的救主，我们所能得到的就只有永久的惩罚和咒诅了。
S. These are solemn words of warning, but a little reflection will show that every Christian needs this doctrine pure for the assurance of his personal salvation. Martin Chemnitz, a famous Lutheran theologian who lived in the generation after Martin Luther, in the middle of his large book, The Two Natures in Christ, writes a beautiful little chapter on the comfort of this doctrine. He begins by repeating a point that he had frequently made. We must not dispute “with curious and subtle arguments about the secret and inexpressible union by which the divine and human natures have been joined together in the person of Christ.”
这些是郑重的告诫，而这样的强调显示出每一位基督徒都需要这种纯正的教导来确信个人的救恩。马丁路德之后的著名路德派神学家马丁 克姆尼茨，在他的著作《基督的两种属性》中以一段优美的文字描写了这个给我们安慰的教导。这一段以重复一个他常提到的观点开始。我们不应争论“关于神性和人性在基督位格中神秘和不可言表的合一这个好奇与敏感的话题” 。
T. The Bible plainly teaches us why it was necessary for our Mediator, Redeemer, and Savior to be both God and man. The miracle of our salvation was part of God’s eternal plan. Since only God could save us and since we were human beings cursed by sin, it follows that our Savior had to be both God and man. He had to have both a divine and human nature to be a true Mediator between God and men. Since our human nature was doomed to the eternal punishment of death, the Son of God assumed our human nature and became one of us, so that we might not be destroyed by death. Since we were subject to the wrath of God and to death; it was therefore necessary the our Mediator who was like us in every way but without sin, make satisfaction for us. Because of the sin of, Adam, all human beings were separated from life and fellowship with God through sin. Therefore it was necessary that the Son of God in his own person unite God and man in a most intimate personal union and thus restore us to fellowship with God. The Son of God assumed our human nature so that we who are his brothers may receive the things which the head gives to his members. The writer to the Hebrews put it so well when he writes, “Since the children have flesh and blood, he too shared in their humanity so that by his death he might destroy him who holds the power of death…” (Heb. 2:14).
圣经清楚地教导我们为什么我们需要一位既是上帝也是人的中保、救赎主和救主。我们救赎的奇迹是上帝永恒的计划中的一部分。因为只有上帝能拯救我们并且因为我们是因罪被咒诅的人，所以我们的救主必须同时是上帝也是人。他必须具有神性和人性才能成为上帝和人之间真正的中保。因为我们的人性注定会使我们受到死亡的永久惩罚，上帝的儿子具有人性并成为我们中的一位，我们才不至于被死亡毁灭。因为我们是引起上帝怒气和死亡的对象；因此我们的中保就必须是除了罪以外和我们完全一样，为我们赎罪。由于从亚当来的罪，所有人都与永生和上帝的连结分离。因此上帝的儿子在他自己的位格中将上帝和人最紧密地结合在一起并且由此修复了我们与上帝的关系。上帝的儿子具有了人性使得作为他弟兄的我们能领受由我们的头赐予他身体其他部分的福分。希伯来书的作者对此明确写道：“儿女既同有血肉之体，他也照样亲自成了血肉之体，特要藉着死，败坏那掌死权的…”(希伯来书2:14)。
U. With those same words (quoted in #S), Chemnitz demonstrates that it is comforting for us to remember the reason the eternal Son of God had to be united with our human nature. It was necessary because no human being alone would not have been an adequate ransom for sin (Psalm 49:7-9). Only God’s Son suffering and dying in his own flesh could be enough payment for the sins of the world.
用同样的言语(S中所引用的)，克姆尼茨向我们展示了记住上帝永恒的儿子必须与人性合一的原因是要安慰我们。记住这一点的必要性在于没有一个人能作为罪的完全赎价(诗篇49:7-9).只有上帝的儿子以他肉身的受苦和死能作为世上所有罪的足够赎价。
V. In that same book Chemnitz also calls to our attention that it is equally a work of divine power by which the Son gathers His eternal church from the human race. He also converts, justifies, sanctifies saves, governs, preserves it, and bestows the Holy Spirit upon it, raises all men from the dead, and leads the elect into eternal life. Therefore, it was necessary that the Son of God himself take to himself our human nature. “In these duties, he gently embraces us as his brothers.”
在同一本书中克姆尼茨提出还有一点值得我们注意的是通过同样的神的大能圣子在众民中召聚他永恒的教会。他还使他的教会得着信心，称义，成圣得救，并管理，看顾它，同时使圣灵临到它里面，使死人复活并使所拣选的人得着永生。因此，必须由上帝的儿子将人性加在自己身上。“在这些职责中，他如兄弟般的温和地拥抱我们”
W. With these precious truths fresh in our mind we will want to read this great Creed again. We will want to close our meditation and review of this creed with the words some later copies have added to the manuscript containing the words of the creed:
GLORY BE TO THE FATHER, AND TO THE SON, AND TO THE HOLY SPIRIT; AS IT WAS IN THE BEGINNING, IS NOW, AND EVER SHALL BE: WORLD WITHOUT END. AMEN.
在明白了这些宝贵的真理之后，我们想要再读读这部伟大的信经。我们要用一些后来添加进这部信经手稿中的话语结束我们对这部信经的沉思和回顾：
荣耀归于圣父、圣子和圣灵；从前是这样，现在是这样，将来还会是这样：直到永远。阿门。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Worksheet for Lesson Seven  第七课作业题：</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-14/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Worksheet for Lesson Seven: 第七课作业题：
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：1446
Worksheet for Lesson Seven: 第七课作业题：
The Teaching of the Athanasian Creed 亚大纳西信经的教导
Section A. A 部分
Use the outline on page 1 (Lesson 7) to answer the following questions:
用第一页(第七课)的概要回答以下问题：
1.What two main doctrines does this Creed discuss?
这部信经讨论了哪两点重要的教导：
A.
B.
2.What might you deduce from the number of sentences devoted to each?
从用于这两点教导的这些句子中，你能推断出什么？
Section B. B 部分
1.In sentence 1 the word translated Christian is actually the word catholic.
第一句话中基督徒这个词实际上被翻译成大公。
A. What does the word catholic mean here? (review p. 4, lesson 7, section T)
大公这个词在此是什么意思？(复习第七课第四页T部分)
B. Is Christian a good translation here?
在这里翻译成基督徒可以吗？
2.What two theological meanings can the word faith have?
信仰这个词所具有的两个神学含义是什么？
A.
B.
3.Which meaning does it have in Sentences 1-3 of the Athanasian Creed?
它在亚大纳西信经的第1-3句中所具有的意思是什么？
Section D. D 部分
1.What Greek word does the bible use of all teachings contrary to the Christian faith?
圣经中用哪一个希腊语单词代表与基督徒信仰相悖的所有教导？
2.What do we call creedal statements that point out the eternal consequences of false belief?
我们将指出错误信仰永恒后果的信经陈述称为什么？
3.How would you answer the following arguments against such statements:
你如何回应以下反对这些陈述的争论：
A. God is the judge; we have no right to judge.
上帝是审判者；我们无权评判。
B.Such statement will alienate the lost, not help to convert them.
这样的陈述将使迷失的人远离而不会帮助他们转变信主。
Section F. F 部分
1.When studying the Bible, are we supposed to use our God-given reason or not? Explain your answer.
当我们学习圣经时，我们应不应该使用上帝所给的理由？解释你的答案。
Section G. G 部分
1.What is meant by holding the teachings of God’s unity and of the 3 persons of the Godhead in tension?
在矛盾中坚持上帝的合一性和神性的三个位格的教导是什么意思？
Section H. H 部分
1.Explain what is meant by the following terms when discussing the Trinity:
解释当我们讨论三位一体时，以下词语的意思：
A.Person: 位格
B.Substance: 本质
2.What Greek word have we already learned about which was used to denote substance?
我们已经学过的用来表示本质的希腊语单词是什么？
Section I. I 部分
1.List and give a definition of the attributes of the Triune God which are mentioned in Sentences 7-14.
列举第7-14句中提到的三位一体的上帝的特性并给出他们的定义：
A.
B.
C.
D.
Section K-M. K-M 部分
1.In Section K it states that the three persons of the Trinity are identical in substance and attributes but differ in the relation they have to one another. How does this Creed describe the relationship between:
在K部分中陈述到三位一体的三个位格在本质和特性上完全相同，但是在彼此的关系上不同。这部信经是怎样描述他们之间的关系的：
A.The Father and the Son 圣父与圣子
B.The Father and the Spirit 圣父与圣灵
C.The Son and the Spirit 圣子与圣灵
Section M. M 部分
1.Since sentence 25 says that all 3 persons are coeternal, what does that say about the terms begotten and proceeds in sentence 22?
由于第25句说到所有三个位格均永恒，人们是如何看待第22句中的由于和发出这两个词的？
2.Look up the Scripture references given in this section. Write below a paragraph on why the filioque can be called a biblical doctrine.
看这一部分给出的圣经参考章节。在下面写一段关于filioque为什么被称为符合圣经的教导的话。
Section N. N 部分
1.What does Augustine’s famous saying tell us about our understanding of the Trinity?
奥古斯丁的名言告诉我们关于我们对三位一体的理解的什么内容？
Section O-Q. O-Q 部分
1.Describe what is meant by the theological term nature?
描述神学词语属性是什么意思？
Section S-V S-V 部分
1.What is meant by the statement: Jesus has two natures in one person?
耶稣一个人拥有两种属性这样的陈述是什么意思？
2.How does the biblical truth help assure us of our eternal salvation?
圣经的真理如何帮助我们确信我们永恒的救恩？&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第八课 （lesson 8）信经的重要性</title>
      <link>/en/courses/211/creed-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/211/creed-15/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;替代文本&#34;&gt;第八课 （lesson 8）信经的重要性
分类：信经 Creed
作者：CSI
点击数：1551
Lesson Eight: The Importance of our Creeds
第八课: 信经的重要性
A. In a day of skepticism and relativism, creeds in general are not regarded very highly. In many denominations, the general viewpoint is that since the Holy Scriptures are a human book, liable to error, creeds express at best only a part of God’s truth. Hence many draw the conclusion that the church today cannot unite on doctrine but it can unite only in a common service to mankind. Many famous theologians do not accept such doctrines as the deity of Christ, his virgin birth, or his resurrection, not to mention other miracles. So, for years the Ecumenical Creeds, used so regularly for confession of faith through the centuries, have not represented the actual convictions of many theologians.
在怀疑论和相对论存在的时期，信经通常没有引起高度重视。在很多教派中，人们普遍认为因为圣经是人手所写的，可能会有错误，信经所表达的最多不过是上帝真理的一部分。因此很多人得出的结论是当今的教会不能在教义上合一，但是可以在公众的礼拜仪式中合一。很多著名的神学家不接受比如说基督神性，童贞女生子或基督复活这样的教导，更不用说其他神迹了。所以，已经经过了几个世纪常用于认信的三大公信经，多年来不能代表很多神学家的实际所信。
B. The Athanasian Creed in particular offends liberal theologians who recognize the contradiction between their views and those of this Creed. This is particularly true since this Creed explicitly affirms that anyone who denies the truths it confesses will perish forever. At times some of these liberal churchmen have made efforts to eliminate this Creed from the Confessions of the church. But these efforts have usually died when it was pointed out that the denial of the Athanasian Creed would imply a full acceptance of the other two, which, of course, not many were ready to affirm in any literal sense. Hence, the Ecumenical Creeds have remained in regular use in some denominations so as not to disturb the average parishioner. However, in these churches the Creeds are not taken seriously by the professional theologians and, as each year passes, by fewer and fewer laymen. This is a sad situation and hence it is necessary for everyone to study the Creeds to see where modern theology rejects them and whether one can honestly subscribe to them himself.
亚大纳西信经尤其触犯了那些认为这部信经中的一些观点与他们的观点相矛盾的自由派神学家。尤其是因为信经明确声明任何否认真理所告诉我们的事的人都将受到永久的惩罚。有时这些自由派神学家中的一些人试图将这部信经从教会认信中去掉。但是这样的努力常常是徒劳的，因为当它指出否认亚大纳西信经暗示着完全接受其他两部信经时，他们当然还没有准备好在文字意义上肯定这一点。因此，三大公信经仍然在一些教派中正常使用以免扰乱普通教区教友。然而，在这些教会中，信经并不受那些专业神学家的重视，而且随着时间的推移，它被越来越少的平信徒所重视。这是可悲，每个人都有必要学习这些信经从而了解当今神学所否认的内容并且一个人是否能诚实的认同它们。
C. Heresies have always been a fact of life in the Christian church. Though a single heresy usually attacks only some part of Christian truth, it is still dangerous. For the truths of Scripture are tightly tied together. To deny one is in the end to undermine or deny all the rest of them. Not to recognize this is simply not to recognize the nature of the doctrines Christ has revealed to us. The Christian faith is a systematic and integrated whole, built on a single foundation, the Prophetic-Apostolic Word. It might be helpful to picture the Christian body of doctrine as a church building. The foundation is the inspired Word of God; the main body is the doctrine of justification; and the head or pinnacle is the doctrine of Jesus Christ as true God and true man.
异端邪说的存在已经是在基督教会中常常需要面对的事实。尽管个别的异端通常只攻击一部分基督真理，但是它仍是危险的。因为圣经中的真理是紧密连结在一起的。否认一点最终会导致诋毁或否认其他所有的。不承认这一点就是不承认基督已经向我们揭示的教义的本质。基督徒的信心是一个有系统的，整体性的，建立在单一根基上的，和预言的-使徒的道。将基督身体比作教堂的教导也许能帮助我们理解。根基是所默示的上帝的话语；主体是公义的教导；同时头或顶端是关于耶稣基督是完全神和完全人的教导。
D. During the first four centuries of the history of the Christian church, we might say that the head of Christian doctrine was attacked, namely, that Jesus Christ is truly the Son of God and truly the Son of Man. Within the church these doctrines were settled and confessed at the Council of Nicaea in 325, the Council of Constantinople in 381, and the Council of Chalcedon in 451. At that time the church acknowledged the Trinity and also that the Second Person is at one and the same time the son of God and the Son of Man, “At once complete in Godhead and complete in Manhood.” These truths are embodied in the three Ecumenical Creeds.
在公元1-4世纪基督教会的历史中，我们可以说基督教义的头，即耶稣基督是完全的上帝的儿子和完全的人的儿子受到了攻击。在教会内部，这些教导于公元325年的尼西亚会议，公元381的君士坦丁堡会议和公元451年的卡尔西顿会议上被订立和承认。那时教会承认三位一体以及第二个位格既是上帝的儿子同时也是人的儿子，“同时在神性和人性中得以完全”。这些真理在三大公信经中得以呈现。
E. During the Middle Ages, the center of Christian doctrine, namely, justification by grace through faith in the of Jesus Christ without the deeds of the Law, had been debased into the teaching that man is justified by his own works. Through Martin Luther and his fellow Reformers, the Scriptural truth of justification was restored to the church.
中世纪时，基督教义的中心，即靠着恩典在耶稣基督功劳里的信心而不是守律法的行为得来的公义，已经掺杂了人是靠着自己的行为称义的教导。通过马丁路德和他一起的改教家的努力，圣经中关于称义的真理在教会中得以保存。
F. Ever since the beginning of the nineteenth century, when Rationalism gained a secure hold within the external Christian church, the attack against the foundation of the church, namely, Scripture (Eph. 2:20) has grown in intensity. We may call Scripture the foundation of the Church because Scripture in everything it says and teaches points us to Jesus Christ. This is the battle that is raging around us now: Has God spoken clearly and directly to us through His Son? Is the Scripture the inspired, inerrant Word of God, the only source of all doctrine, or is it merely the word of men? This is a struggle of immense proportions, the results of which have cosmic significance. If the foundation goes, then the whole structure falls. Then there is no basis for accepting any doctrine as infallibly revealed in Scripture, and if this becomes the position of the external church, then it no longer represents the invisible Church of God.
自从19世纪初期以来，当唯理主义在外部基督教会中获得稳固基础时，对教会根基的攻击，即圣经(以弗所书2:20)变得更加强烈。我们会称圣经为教会的根基是因为圣经中所说和所教导的每一点都是指向耶稣基督的。这场围绕我们的战争正愈演愈烈：上帝通过它的儿子明确直接地和我们对话过吗？圣经是否是默示的，毫无错误的上帝的话语，所有教义的唯一来源还是它只不过是人手所写的话呢？这是极大程度上的斗争，这场斗争的结果具有无比的重要性。如果根基不存在了，那么整个构造都将坍塌。那么没有依据将任何教导看作在圣经中被毫无错误地揭示而被接受并且如果这一点成为外部教会的立场，那么它将不再代表上帝无形的教会。
G. The Ecumenical Creeds assume that the Scripture is the only source for the truths which are to be believed and preached by the church. So these Creeds even today serve as excellent bulwarks against false doctrine in regard to the Trinity, the Person and work of Christ. The heresies the Early Church had to fight are still with us, although they appear under different names and guises.
三大公信经假定圣经是被教会相信和教导的真理的唯一来源。因此这些信经即使是在当今仍作为抗击关于三位一体、基督位格和工作的错误教导的坚固堡垒。早期教会中与异端的斗争仍然存在，尽管他们以不同名称和伪装出现。
H. UNITARIANISM AND FREE-MASONRY
一神论派和共济会
In the sixteenth century a number of Anti-Trinitarians who were mainly from Italy troubled the Reformation churches with their doctrine. Shortly after Luther’s death, Laelius Socinius and his nephew, Faustus Socinius, proclaimed a Unitarian theology which gained a good number of followers. The Socinians declared that the Bible was the source of religious truth, but they said a person should not accept into his theology anything that is contrary to human reason. Since the doctrine of the Trinity and particularly the deity of Jesus Christ are contrary to reason, they are not to be believed. To the Socinians Jesus Christ was a human being empowered to show man the way to heaven. The Unitarians became a powerful factor in the United States, especially New England, in the eighteenth century.
在十六世纪时，一批主要来自意大利的反三位一体论者用他们的教导扰乱了改革派教会。在路德去世后不久，莱利乌斯 苏西尼和他的侄子浮士德 苏西尼宣扬的一神论神学为他们获得了一大批追随者。苏西尼派宣称圣经是宗教真理的来源，但是一个人不应接受任何与人的理性相矛盾的宗教理论。因为关于三位一体，尤其是耶稣基督神性的教导与人的理性相矛盾，它们不应被相信。对苏西尼派来说，耶稣基督是被授予权利向人们显示通往天堂道路的人。一神论派在十八世纪的美国，尤其是新英格兰变得相当有影响力。
I. In the mid-seventeenth century a movement of rationalist thought grew under the leadership of the Englishman, Lord Herbert of Cherbury (1583-1684). This movement has also exerted no small influence both in Europe and the United States. It became the religion of the Masonic Lodge and all the other lodges patterned after it. This type of Anti-Trinitarianism goes under the name of Deism. It emphasized the results of scientific study as a means of revealing the true God. The Deists denied the Trinity, the incarnation of Jesus Christ, and other central doctrines pertaining to our salvation. They also taught that the deity did not intervene in this world after he had created nature and the laws of nature. The heart of Deism is similar to that of Unitarianism, the denial of the Trinity and the belief of man’s personal salvation by his own good character. The influence of Unitarianism and Deism on our country has been profound since many of our founding fathers (such as Thomas Jefferson) were Unitarians or Deists.
在十七世纪中期一场唯理主义思想运动在英国人赫尔伯特勋爵(1583-1684)的领导下逐渐扩大。这场运动还在欧洲和美国产生了不小的影响。它形成了麦逊共济会这个教派并且其他共济会随之进行模仿。这种反三位一体论派被称为自然神论。它强调将科学研究的结果作为揭示真神的方式。自然神论者否认三位一体、耶稣基督的道成肉身和其他与我们救恩有关的中心教导。他们还教导神在他创造自然和自然的法则之后就不再干涉世上的一切了。自然神论核心与一神论相似，都否认三位一体和相信人的救恩来自个人的良好品德。由于我们许多的开国元勋(如托马森 杰弗逊)都是一神论者或自然神论者，因此一神论和自然神论对我们国家有着深远的影响。
J. JEHOVAH’S WITNESSES AND MORMONS
耶和华见证人和摩门教
Nearly everyone has had members of the Jehovah’s Witnesses ring the doorbell. Without discussing the many false doctrines they teach, it is necessary to point out that they emphatically deny the doctrine of the Trinity. One of their leaders, Rutherford, called it “the Devil’s doctrine.” While their terminology is at times confusing because they sometimes call Christ the Son of God, they nevertheless expressly deny the equality of Christ with the Father, so clearly taught in John 10:30, and clearly confessed in the Ecumenical Creeds. Jehovah’s Witnesses also reject the Deity and the person of the Holy Spirit, much like one of the heresies which the Early Church rejected at the Council of Constantinople. The Jehovah’s Witnesses teach that the Holy Spirit is only “the power” of God.
摩门教徒几乎按过每家人的门铃。他们不谈论他们教义中许多的错误，而是指出他们强烈反对关于三位一体的教导。他们的领导人之一，卢瑟福，称三位一体的教导为“魔鬼学说”。而他们的用辞又时常很混乱，因为他们有时称基督为上帝的儿子，却又明确否认基督与父是同等的，其实这样同等的关系已经在约翰福音10:30中讲述得十分清楚并在三大公信经中被明确承认。耶和华见证人还否认圣灵的神性和位格，这很像被早期教会在君士坦丁堡会上拒之门外的异端之一。耶和华见证人教导圣灵只是上帝的“能力”。
K. Teams of Mormons cris-cross our land doing missionary work. Mormonism has some peculiar doctrines that deny the theology of the Ecumenical Creeds. They teach that man has an eternally pre-existent soul and that he is placed here on earth in order to gain remission of sins through obedience to the laws and regulations laid down by the priesthood. Such a belief erases the difference between God the creator and man the creature. Mormons may at times sound Trinitarian. They may hand out a pamphlet that says, “We believe in God the eternal Father, and the Son Jesus Christ, and the Holy Spirit.” But if one pursues the topic with them in any depth, say, on the basis of the Athanasian Creed, one will see that they, too, reject the Deity of Christ and the person of the Holy Spirit. In actuality, Mormonism seems to teach a type of polytheism. They believe that gods have families and raise spiritual children, as human families raise physical children. They also teach that by raising children man can become a god. Ideas such as these are far removed from the lofty concept of God revealed in the Scriptures and confessed in these Ecumenical Creeds.
摩门教的团体穿梭于我们国家各地进行传教。摩门教徒有一些专门的教义否认三大公信经的神学理论。他们教导的是人具有预先存在的灵魂并且这个灵魂被置于世上从而通过遵行祭司定下的律法和法规得以赦罪。这样一种信仰抹杀了创造者上帝与被造物人之间的区别。摩门教也许时常听起来像是相信三位一体的人。他们也许会递给你一个小册子说，“我们相信永恒的父上帝，子耶稣基督，和圣灵”。但是如果与他们再深入讨论这个话题，并说，是基于亚大纳西信经的，就会看到他们拒绝承认基督的神性和圣灵的位格。事实上，摩门教似乎教导的是一种多神论。他们相信各神有家庭并养育属灵的儿女，就像人的家庭养育亲生儿女一样。他们还教导通过养育儿女，人能成为神。这样的一些观点已经远离上帝在圣经中所揭示的以及我们在三大公信经中所告白的崇高信念。
L. MODERN LIBERALISM WITHIN THE CHURCH
教会中的现代自由主义
The denial of the biblical Trinitarian doctrine took many forms in the early church, at it still does today. Here, as perhaps in no other way, church history repeats itself. Early in the church a group of Jewish Christians denied the divinity of Christ, reducing the biblical doctrine to the thought that Jesus was the human son of Joseph and Mary. At his baptism he became the “adopted” Son of God. This heresy is called Adoptionism. Liberal theology at the beginning of the twentieth century propounded a similar view. For it Jesus was a man of such goodness that God exalted him to a divine status. These early liberals had accepted the historical-critical method of interpreting the Bible. This method accepts the critical historical outlook of modern historian and scientists that the Bible is no different than any other book or piece of literature from the past. Such a view of course results in the destruction of its divine and miraculous character. This leads to the belief that Jesus was primarily a good man who is an example for us. With the result that by imitating him we might become the sons of God in the same way he was. This theology is sometimes called the Social Gospel, and its chief slogan was “the fatherhood of God and the brotherhood of man.” This heresy is still quite common in newspaper editorials (at Christmas and Easter) and in many of the popularizations of Christianity that have been written for the practical, common-sense of man.
对圣经三位一体教义的否认在早期教会中呈现出多种形式，在当今也是如此。或许是别无他法，教会历史往往重演。早期教会中有一部分犹太基督徒否认基督的神性，删减圣经教导而认为耶稣是约瑟和马利亚所生的儿子。在他受洗时，他被“领养”成为上帝的儿子。这种异端邪说被称为“基督嗣子论”。在二十世纪初自由派神学提出了类似的观点。因为耶稣是良善的人而被上帝高举具有神的地位。这些早期的自由派已经接受将历史批判法作为释经的方法。这种方法承认现代历史学家和科学家批判历史的观点，即圣经与过去的其他著作或文学作品没有区别。这种观点肯定导致神性和奇妙位格被破坏。这也会使人相信耶稣首先是一个作为我们好榜样的良善的人。靠着效仿他我们也许会以同样的方式成为上帝的儿女。这样的神学理论被称为社会福音论，而且它的主要口号是“视上帝为慈父，视他人为手足”。这种异端邪说仍然在(圣诞节和复活节时的)报纸评论上相当常见并且由许多基督教大众写文章将此作为实际和人的常识。
M. At the end of the First World War (1918), a reaction set in against this type of optimistic religion about the goodness of man. The theologian Karl Barth (1886-1968) seemed to lead the way back to orthodox Christianity, and this movement is still with us today under the name of neo-orthodoxy. Barth wanted to regain a view of God as transcendent (far above the ways and knowledge of the human world). But since he did not accept all of the Scriptures as fully inspired, he attempted to work out his own view of the Trinity without letting the full weight of the Scriptural testimony guide him.
在第一次世界大战末期兴起了一场反对这种关于人善行的乐观主义宗教运动。神学家卡尔巴特(1886-1968)是要将人们引回到正统的基督教，并且这场运动在当今仍然在以新正统派的名称进行。巴特想要恢复人们对上帝是超然的(远高于人类世界的一切手段和认知)的看法。但是由于他不承认圣经是完全有上帝所默示的，他试图不让圣经见证的全部力量引导他创出他自己对于三位一体的观点。
N. As a result he developed a doctrine of the Trinity which appears very similar to the heresy which was a forerunner of the Arian heresy. That heresy is called Modalism or Monarchianismor Modal Monarchianism. This heresy, in trying to safeguard the unity of the Godhead, denied the distinction between the three Persons, holding that the Father, Son, and Spirit express three operations of God, or three modes or ways of the divine activity. In other words, we call God “Father” when we think of his creating activity, “Son” when we think of his saving activity, etc., but there is no real difference between them. God only puts on different disguises and names for the different roles he plays.
因此，他创出的一套关于三位一体理论明显可以看出与先前的作为阿里乌派先驱的异端非常相似。那个异端邪说被称为形态论或神格唯一论。这种异端试图保护神性的统一，但是否认三个位格之间的不同，坚持父、子和圣灵表现出上帝的三个阶段，或是神性活动的三种模式或方式。换句话说，当我们想到上帝创世的作为时，我们称他“父”，当我们想到他拯救的作为时，我们称他“子”，等等，但是他们之间没有真正的区别。上帝仅仅为他所扮演的不同角色换上了不同的装扮和名称。
O. When Barth speaks or writes about the incarnation of Christ, he does not use the distinction between the person and the two natures of Christ. In fact, he denies that it is permissible to speak about “persons in God.” One can speak only about a manner of being. As a result, the incarnate Jesus cannot be a divine person. Barth does not understand the virgin Birth as a miracle by which the eternal Son of God took human flesh from his human mother so that the historical Christ is at once fully God and fully Man. There are still many people in the neo-orthodox movement today who hold opinions such as these derived from Barthian theology.
当巴特说或写关于基督道成肉身时，他没有用基督与人的区别和他的两种属性。事实上，他反对说“在上帝中的位格”。一个人只能说那是神的样式。因此，道成肉身的耶稣不是神的位格。巴特不理解童贞女生子，通过这个神迹上帝永恒的儿子从他人类的母亲取了人的肉身从而历史上的基督同时是完全的神和完全的人。新正统派运动中的很多人如今仍持有这些源于巴特神学理论的观点。
P. But the neo-orthodox movement has gone far past Barth in following the teaching of his contemporary, Rudolf Bultmann (1884-1976), the most influential theologian today. In 1941, Bultmann delivered his famous lecture, “The New Testament and Mythology,” in which he held that the Bible was essentially mythical in character, and hence it must be demythologized, that is, all of the supernatural elements in the Bible are myths and they must be stripped off to get the original message. The “mythical elements” to be eliminated include the pre-existence of Christ, the virgin birth, the substitutionary atonement, and the resurrection.
但是新正统派运动在追随与巴特同时代的鲁道夫 布尔特曼(1884-1976)，当今最有影响力的神学家的教导中已经远远偏离了巴特所教导的。1941年，布尔特曼发表了他著名的报告，“新约和神话”。在这篇报告中他称圣经在角色上实际是虚构的，并且因此它必须被除去神话色彩，就是说，圣经中所有超自然的要素都是神话而且它们必须被剥除还原到原有的内容。要去掉的“神话的要素”包括基督的预先存在，童贞女生子，代赎和复活。
Q. Further, there is no God in the Trinitarian sense. So, all the terms applied to the three persons in the Trinity, the deity of Christ, etc., are simply “mythical” terms. If we apply divine terms to Jesus, they are only “courtesy titles,” as Arius had said 1650 years ago. Since Bultmann’s theology permeates many areas of the external church today, especially in the universities and the seminaries where pastors are trained, the situation is as serious as it was in the church in 325, when Arius was so influential, Arianism was a pagan reaction which gathered the support of worldly people who disliked the exclusiveness of Christianity. Similarly today, since Bultmannism is grounded in naturalism (the belief that there is no supernatural or spiritual creation, value, or significance), the popular philosophy of our time, it easily gets the support and the praise of the majority of people today.
另外，无法理解三位一体中的上帝。因此，三位一体中所有与三个位格有关的词语、基督的神性，等等，都只是“带有神话色彩的”词语。如果将神性用于耶稣，它们也只是出于“尊重的称呼”，正如阿里乌1650年前所说的一样。由于布尔特曼的理论渗透进当今外部教会的许多领域，尤其是在大学中和牧师们接受训练的神学院，问题的严重程度就如公元325年当阿里乌非常具有影响力时教会的情况一样。阿里乌派是聚集了世界上恨恶基督教排他性的一些人支持的外邦势力。今天亦然，由于布尔特曼以当代流行的哲学理论自然主义(相信不存在超自然或属灵的被造物、属性或意义的信仰)为依据，很容易就在当今获得了大多数人的支持和赞赏。
R. Another current threat coming from liberal theology is the idea that we really can know almost nothing about Jesus of Nazareth. Today you can read about theologians and so-called “New Testament scholars” who claim that the Gospels of the New Testament really do not give an accurate report about who Jesus was or what he did. Other Gospels (which were condemned by the early Church) give us a little more information about the historical Jesus, but really we can know little about him. All we can be sure about is that he was a Jewish peasant who purposely or unwittingly caused a popular uprising and who after his death was made into a divine hero by his followers.
当前另一个威胁来自于自由主意神学的观点是我们几乎对拿撒勒的耶稣一无所知。如今你能读到一些神学家们和所谓“新约学者”声称新约中的福音确实没有给出关于耶稣是谁以及他做了什么的准确叙述。其他福音(被早期教会所批判的)给了我们一些更多关于历史上的耶稣的信息，但是我们实际上几乎不了解他。我们所能确信的是他是一个特意或不经意导致民众起义并在他死后被他的追随者当成神一般英雄的犹太农夫。
S. Such a “quest for the historical Jesus” (as it is often called) leads only to a mockery of Christianity. By denying the accuracy of the biblical Gospel accounts, such scholars are left with so little information about Jesus that they can easily paint any picture about him that they wish. The Ecumenical Creeds prevented people from doing that for centuries. The Creeds point out who Jesus was, how and why he became man, what he accomplished on earth, where he went when that work was finished, and that his followers recorded accurately in the Holy Scriptures that He rose from the dead (cf. the Nicene Creed). The Creeds will guard us from such modern heresy as the scholars propound, and they should also warn such people:
It is furthermore necessary for eternal salvation truly to believe that our Lord Jesus Christ also took on human flesh. …that our Lord Jesus Christ, God’s son, is both God and Man. (Athanasian Creed, 27-28)
这种“对历史上耶稣的探索”(通常所说的)仅仅引起基督教对其的嘲笑。通过否认圣经福音书上的记载的准确性，这些学者几乎没有留下关于耶稣的信息，这样他们就能轻易按照他们的意志来描绘耶稣。三大公信经几个世纪以来一直阻止人们这么做。这些信经指出耶稣是谁，他怎样和为什么成为人，他在世上成就了什么，在他完成他的工作后他去了哪里，以及他的追随者在圣经中精确地记录了他从死人中复活(参看尼西亚信经)。这些信经将使我们免受当今学者提出的异端邪说的影响并告诫那些人：
再者，为求得永恒救赎，彼亦必笃信我等之主耶稣基督成为人身。神之子我等之主耶稣基督，为神，又为人。(亚大纳西信经27-28)
T. A serious study of the these three Ecumenical Creeds brings us back to the Sacred Scriptures and will enable us, under God, to withstand the mortal enemies of Christ’s doctrine. The strength of Athanasius’ position lay in his total dependence on God’s Word as truth. He was, indeed, an “Athanasius Against the world,” but he was also an Athanasius who could say, “If God be for us, who can be against us?” (Rom 8:31).
对这三大公信经的仔细研究使我们重新回到圣经上并在上帝的庇护下抵抗基督教义的死敌。亚大纳西坚持自己立场的力量在于他完全信靠上帝的话是真理。他的确是“与世人为敌的亚大纳西”，但是他也是曾说“神若帮助我们，谁能敌挡我们呢？”(罗马书8:31)的亚大纳西。
APPENDIX 1: EARLY DEVELOPMENT OF THE APOSTLES’ CREED
附录1：使徒信经的早期发展
Hippolytus (A.D. 215)
Marcellus (A.D. 341)
Rufinus (A.D. 404)
Apostles&amp;rsquo; Creed (today)
Do you believe in God
I believe in God
I believe in God
I believe in God
the Father Almighty
Almighty
the Father Almighty
the Father Almighty
maker of heaven and earth
Do you believe in Christ Jesus
and in Christ Jesus
and in Christ Jesus
I believe in Jesus Christ
the Son of God
His only begotten Son
His only Son
His only Son
our Lord
our Lord
our Lord
who was born of the Holy Spirit
who was conceived by the Holy
Spirit
who was born of the Holy Spirit
who was conceived by the Holy
Spirit
of the Virgin Mary
and the Virgin Mary
and the virgin Mary
born of the Virgin Mary
and was crucified under Pontius
Pilate
was crucified under Pontius Pilate
who was crucified under Pontius
Pilate
suffered under Pontius Pilate, was
crucified,
and died and was buried
and was buried
and was buried
died and was buried
He descended into hell
and rose again on the third day,
alive from the dead
and on the third day rose from the
dead
on the third day rose from the dead
The third day he rose again from
the dead
and ascended into heaven
ascended into heaven
ascended into heaven
He ascended into heaven
and sat at the right hand of the
Father
and sat at the right hand of the
Father
and sat at the right hand of the
Father
and is seated at the right hand of
God the Father Almighty
about to come to judge the living
and the dead
from where He will come to judge
the living and the dead
from where He will come to judge
the living and the dead
from there He will come to judge
the living and the dead
Do you believe in the Holy Spirit
and in the Holy Spirit
and in the Holy Spirit
I believe in the Holy Spirit
and the holy Church
the holy Church
the holy Church
the holy Christian Church
the communion of saints
the forgiveness of sins
the forgiveness of sins
the forgiveness of sins
and the resurrection of the flesh
the resurrection of the body
the resurrection of the flesh
the resurrection of the body
life everlasting
and the life everlasting
APPENDIX 2: DEVELOPMENT OF THE NICENE CREED
附录2： 尼西亚信经的发展
Original Creed From Nicea - A.D. 325
Revised Creed from Constantinople - A.D. 381
We believe in one God, the Father, the Almighty,
We believe in one God, the Father, the Almighty,
maker
maker of heaven and earth,
of all that is, seen and unseen.
of all that is, seen and unseen.
And in one Lord Jesus Christ, the Son of God,
And in one Lord Jesus Christ, the only-begotten Son of God,
the only-begotten of the Father, that is , of the substance of the Father
eternally begotten of the Father,
God from God, Light from Light, true God from true God,
God from God, Light from Light, true God from true God,
begotten, not made, of one being with the Father.
begotten, not made, or one being with the Father.
Through whom all things were made, those in heaven and on earth.
Through him all things were made.
For us and for our salvation, he came down,
For us and for our salvation, he came down from heaven,
was incarnate,
was incarnate of the Holy Spirit and the virgin Mary,
and became fully human.
and became fully human.
For our sake he was crucified under Pontius Pilate.
He suffered death.
He suffered death and was buried.
On the third day he rose again.
On the third day he rose again in accordance with the Scriptures.
He ascended into heaven.
He ascended into heaven and is seated at the right hand of the Father.
He will come to judge the living and the dead,
He will come again in glory to judge the living and the dead,
and his kingdom will have no end.
And in the Holy Spirit.
And in the Holy Spirit,
the Lord, the giver of life,
&lt;em&gt;Those who say that &amp;ldquo;there was a time when he [Christ] did not exist&amp;rdquo; and
who proceeds from the Father, **
&amp;ldquo;before he was begotten he did not exist&amp;rdquo; and that &amp;ldquo;he came into being
who in unity with the Father and the Son is worshiped and glorified,
from nothing,&amp;rdquo; or are affirming that he is of another substance or being
who has spoken through the prophets.
[than the Father] or that the Son of God is changeable or subject to
And in one holy Catholic and apostolic Church.
change, these the catholic and apostolic church of God declared
We acknowledge one baptism for the forgiveness of sins.
to be damned.&lt;/em&gt;
We look for the resurrection of the dead and the life of the world to come.
Amen
Amen.
*This condemnation was an appendix later dropped.
**&amp;ldquo;and the Son&amp;rdquo; added a century later in the West
APPENDIX 3: IMPORTANT THEOLOGICAL TERMS
附录3：重要的神学术语
替代文本&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;替代文本
附录1：使徒信经的早期发展
希坡吕托 (公元215年)
你信神，
全能的父吗？
你信基督耶稣， 神的儿子；
因着圣灵，从童贞女马利亚所生；
在本丟彼拉多手下，被钉在十字架上，受死，埋葬；
第三天从死里复活；
升天，
坐在父的右边；
将来要从那里降临，审判活人、死人吗？
你信圣灵、圣教会、和身体复活吗？
Your title here&amp;hellip;马赛路(公元341年)
我信全能的上帝，
和我主基督耶稣，由上帝所出的独生子，
由圣灵和童贞女马利亚感孕，
在本丢彼拉多手下被钉于十字架，埋葬。
第三天从死人中复活。
升天，
坐在父的右边。
将来必从那里降临，审判活人死人。
我信圣灵，
我信圣教会，
我信罪得赦免，
我信身体复活，
我信永生。
鲁菲纳斯(公元404年)
我信上帝，全能的父，
和我主基督耶稣，上帝的独生子，
由圣灵和童贞女马利亚所生，
在本丢彼拉多手下被钉于十字架，埋葬。
第三天从死人中复活。
升天，
坐在父的右边。
将来必从那里降临，审判活人死人。
我信圣灵，
我信圣教会，
我信罪得赦免，
我信肉体复活。
使徒信经(现今所用)
我信上帝，全能的父，
创造天地的主。
我信我主耶稣基督，上帝的独生子，
因圣灵感孕，
由童贞女马利亚所生，
在本丢彼拉多手下受难，
被钉于十字架，受死，埋葬。
降在阴间。
第三天从死人中复活。
升天，
坐在全能父上帝的右边。
将来必从那里降临，审判活人死人。
我信圣灵，
我信圣而公之教会，我信圣徒相通，
我信罪得赦免，
我信身体复活，
我信永生。
附录2：尼西亚信经的发展
原有的尼西亚会议所定的信经——公元325年
我等信独一之神，即全能之圣父，创造一切有形无形之万物之主。
我等信独一之主耶稣基督，上帝独生之圣子，与父同质，是从神所出之神，从光所出之光，从真神所出之真神，是生非造，是与圣父同体，天地间的万物皆借圣子而造；圣子为要拯救我等世人而降临，道成肉身，成为完全人。受死。第三日复活。升天。将来必从那里降临，审判活人死人。
我等信圣灵。
※那些说“曾有一段时期他【基督】不存在”和“在他出于神以先，他不存在”以及“他从无有被造”或是坚称他具有另一种实质或本质【与父不同的】又或是说上帝的圣子是可变的或有所变化的人，都是被上帝的普世和使徒教会所谴责的人。※
阿们。
君士坦丁堡会议修订后的尼西亚信经——公元381年
我等信独一之神，即全能之圣父，创造天地，及一切有形无形之万物之主。
我等信独一之主耶稣基督，上帝独生之圣子，是圣父在万世之先所生，是从神所出之神，从光所出之光，从真神所出之真神，是生非造，是与圣父同体，万物皆借圣子而造；圣子为要拯救我等世人，从天降临，为圣灵感动之童贞女马利亚所生，成为人身，在本丢彼拉多手下，为我等钉十字架，被害而葬，照圣经之言，第三日复活，升天，坐在圣父之右；将来复必有荣耀而降临，审判生人死人，其国无穷无尽。
我等信圣灵即是主，是赐生命者，是从圣父※※所出，与圣父、圣子，同是当拜，当称颂者，众先知说预言，皆是被圣灵感动；我等信使徒所立独一圣而公之教会；我等信因为赦罪设立之独一洗礼；我等望死后复活，又望来世之永生。
阿们。
“和圣子”于一个世纪后在西方教会中被添加进来。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
