<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grace Bible Institute – The Gospel of John</title>
    <link>/en/courses/109/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Gospel of John on Grace Bible Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:46:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/en/courses/109/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Introduction</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;the-gospel-of-john-is-different&#34;&gt;The Gospel of John is Different&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four accounts (gospels) of Jesus’ life and teachings in the Bible – Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John. The first three accounts (Matthew, Mark, and Luke) are sometimes called “the synoptic gospels” (“synoptic” means that they take a similar view of Christ’s life) because they witness to many of the same stories (parables) and events (miracles).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, John’s gospel is different from the other three in many ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ninety percent of the content of John is not found in the other three Gospels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John’s gospel omits all of the events of Jesus’ birth and childhood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John records none of the parables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John’s gospel contains only seven miracles (yet the only gospel to include the first miracle at the wedding at Cana (chapter 2) and the raising of Lazarus, chapter 11).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is more emphasis on the Holy Spirit in John than in any other gospel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John’s gospel contains the “I AM” statements of Jesus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John’s gospel has a prologue that is quite unique.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John’s gospel has the “upper room discourse” in John 14-17; the good shepherd discourse in John 10; the raising of Lazarus in John 11; and many post-Easter appearances in John 21.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-author&#34;&gt;The Author&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author identifies himself in John 21:20-24 &amp;ndash;  “Peter turned and saw that the disciple whom Jesus loved was following them. (This was the one who had leaned back against Jesus at the supper and had said, “Lord, who is going to betray you?”) This is the disciple who testifies to these things and who wrote them down. We know that his testimony is true.” From this we can know that the writer of this gospel was one of the twelve apostles, an eyewitness of the events and dialogue which he records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early Christians believed that John wrote this Gospel, and the evidence seems to agree, even though the apostle John is never mentioned by name in this Gospel. He is simply called “the disciple whom Jesus loved” (13:23; 19:26; 20:2; 21:7, 20, 24).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John was one of the first and closest disciples of Jesus and a leader in the early church, but is never mentioned by name in this Gospel—which would be natural if he wrote it, but hard to explain otherwise. He was there at the foot of the cross, and he even entered the empty tomb of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author knew Jewish life well, as seen from references to popular Messianic speculations (e.g., 1:20–21), to the hostility between Jews and Samaritans (4:9), and to Jewish customs, such as the duty of circumcision on the eighth day taking precedence over the prohibition of working on the Sabbath (see note on 7:22). He knew the geography of Palestine, locating Bethany about 15 stadia (about two miles) from Jerusalem (11:18) and mentioning Cana, a village not referred to in any earlier writing known to us (2:1; 21:2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of John has many touches that were obviously based on the recollections of an eyewitness—such as the house at Bethany being filled with the fragrance of the broken perfume jar (12:3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;biography-of-the-apostle-john&#34;&gt;Biography of the apostle John&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Son of Zebedee (and Salome?) (Mark 1:19-20)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brother of James.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fisherman on the Sea of Galilee (perhaps based in Capernaum).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was an acquaintance of the high priest (John 18:15-16).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the 12 apostles chosen by Jesus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the “inner circle” of 3 apostles (Peter, James, and John) who were privileged to witness the raising of Jairus’ daughter (Mark 5:37), the transfiguration (Mark 9:2), and the agony in the Garden of Gethsemane (Mark 14:33).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entrusted with the care of Jesus’ mother (John 19:25-27).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the leaders of the large Christian congregation at Jerusalem (Acts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote one of the four gospels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote 3 short epistles of the New Testament and the book of Revelation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote 20 percent of the entire New Testament&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;date&#34;&gt;Date&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no evidence in the Gospel itself as to the date of its writing. Most scholars assume that John’s was the last gospel written, and that John was aware of the other three gospels, therefore offering material not already well covered in the other three accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-purpose-of-this-gospel&#34;&gt;The Purpose of This Gospel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this gospel is stated in John 20:31. What is the purpose?
John states that he has written these things “so that you may believe that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of God, and that by believing in him you will have life” (John 20:31)&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 2 The Gospel of John, Chapter 1</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus: The Word and the Lamb&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gospel of John does not begin its record of Jesus by recording his birth, but by proclaiming the eternal existence of Christ. The gospel begins in the same was that the first book of the Bible begins, “in the beginning.” In other words, the gospel is saying that before Jesus was born in Bethlehem, before Moses, before Abraham, before Adam and Eve, there was Christ, eternal, almighty, one with the Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 1:1-18 (The prologue to the gospel)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What titles are given to Jesus in this prologue (and the rest of the chapter)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1:1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1:7,8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1:14,18)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1:29, 35)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1:34 and 49)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1:38 and 49)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1:41)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1:49)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1:51)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What truths does John reveal about Jesus in verses1-3?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what way is Jesus the light? (As you answer, look up Psalm 82:4-5; Proverbs 4:19; and John 12:35)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 5 John said that Jesus shined light in the darkness, but the darkness did not understand it. Where do we see examples of this happening in the world today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verses 6-8 tell us about John the Baptist. What was his purpose in life, according to 1:7?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 1:19-34 (John the Baptist testifies about Jesus)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What event is John recalling in verses 32-34? (See Mark 1:9-11.) Why was the voice from heaven and the Spirit descending like a dove important to John?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What things did John the Baptist make clear about himself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did John say about Jesus’ work in verses 29 and 34?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 1:35-51 (Jesus calls his first disciples)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 35 we read of “two of John’s disciples.” One of them was obviously Andrew, who was mentioned in v. 40. The other disciple is not mentioned by name. Since the writer of this gospel often chose not to use his own name (we have another example of this in John 20:3, where two disciples ran to the empty tomb), it is assumed that the other disciple was John himself, the author of this Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What brought the first two disciples to Jesus (verse 36)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What first brought you to Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus showed Nathanael one miracle. Nathanael confessed Jesus is the Son of God. What greater things would Jesus show him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our next lesson Jesus begins his ministry, performs his first miracle, and proclaims that he is the true Messiah, sent by the Father for the salvation of the world. Please prepare chapters 2 and 3. 
&lt;code&gt; &lt;/code&gt;PAGE 2&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 3 The Gospel of John, Chapters 2 and 3</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus: The Son of God&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time Jesus had 6 disciples (Peter, Andrew, James, John, Philip and Nathanael). These would serve as the witnesses of Jesus’ first miracle, as He began to reveal Himself as true God, the Son of the Heavenly Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this chapter begins, Jesus had left the place where John the Baptist was baptizing (Bethany beyond Jordan – John 1:28) and had traveled to into Galilee near the town where He grew up. He went to Cana, the hometown of Nathanael (John 21:2), to attend a wedding feast. Cana’s exact location is uncertain, but many believe that it was located a few miles north of Nazareth in Galilee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We notice that Mary is simply called “the mother of Jesus” in the gospel of John. Her name is never mentioned. See another example of this in John 19:25-27. The text does not say that Mary was invited, only that she was there. Perhaps she was there to assist in the wedding, and that is how she became aware of an embarrassing situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 2:1-11 (Jesus changes water into wine)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What problem arose at the wedding at Cana?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Mary expect when she came to Jesus and told Him that there was a shortage of wine?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 4 Jesus addresses his mother as “dear woman.” Some people think that this sounds a bit cold or even disrespectful. When Jesus called her “woman” this was not being rude or disrespectful.  Remember that she had come to Him not because He was her son, but because He was her Lord. And now Jesus answered her, not as her son, but as her Lord. This was a simple, informal form of address, the typical way that Jesus addressed women in John’s Gospel. Check out these references:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John 4:21  Jesus declared, “Believe me, woman, a time is coming when you will worship the Father neither on this mountain nor in Jerusalem.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John 19:26  When Jesus saw his mother there, and the disciple whom he loved standing nearby, he said to his mother, “Dear woman, here is your son,”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John 20:13  They asked her, “Woman, why are you crying?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to remember that Jesus is also our Lord. He is our Savior, who has died for us, and we must trust in Him. But He is also our Lord, who is over us, and we must obey Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why did Jesus tell Mary, “Why do you involve me? My time has not yet come”?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of Jesus’ answer to her, Mary still expected that Jesus would solve the problem. She trusted that He could and would help when the time was right. So she simply instructed the servants, “Do whatever he tells you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when His time was right, Jesus approached them and told them to fill six huge stone jars, that would each hold 60-100 liters) with water. Where would they get all that water? They could not just turn on the faucet until the jars were full. Not back then! They would need to go to the city well, or the spring, or wherever Cana’s water supply was. Can you imagine what they might say as they make trip after trip to the well carrying heavy buckets or skins filled with water? “What is that rabbi going to do with all this water? Doesn’t He know how hard this is? This doesn’t make any sense!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;Sound familiar? When Jesus tells you to do something, perhaps you might also object that it’s too hard or it doesn’t make any sense. It didn’t make sense to the fishermen, when Jesus told them. “Cast out into the deep water. Throw your net on the right side of the boat.” Didn’t they object, saying, “But Master, we have fished all night and caught nothing!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;Which of these things Jesus tells us to do don’t make sense to you, or just seems too hard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Do not resist an evil person. If someone strikes you on the right cheek, turn to him the other also.” &amp;ndash; Matthew 5:39&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Submit to one another out of reverence for Christ.” &amp;ndash; Ephesians 5:21&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Love your enemies, do good to those who hate you” &amp;ndash; Luke 6:27&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Repent and be baptized, every one of you, in the name of Jesus Christ for the forgiveness of your sins. And you will receive the gift of the Holy Spirit” &amp;ndash; Acts 2:38&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Do not be anxious about anything, but in everything, by prayer and petition, with thanksgiving, present your requests to God.” &amp;ndash; Philippians 4:6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;Like Mary, trust in Jesus and do whatever He tells you, because He knows better than us, and because His results are always best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What purpose did Jesus have in performing this miracle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus provided a very large amount of wine through this miracle (about 450-680 liters). Jesus’ gift of wine was excellent in quality and abundant in quantity. Of course, it could be misused or abused in drunkenness, but it could also be used to provide joy and gladness for a celebration. Psalm 104:14-15**  says, “He makes grass grow for the cattle, and plants for man to cultivate&amp;ndash; bringing forth food from the earth:  &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wine that gladdens the heart of man&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, oil to make his face shine, and bread that sustains his heart.” Wine is one of God’s gifts, to be received with thanks and used in moderation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But remember that God warns about drinking too much. Ephesians 5:18 says, “Do not get drunk on wine, which leads to debauchery. Instead, be filled with the Spirit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What can we learn about Jesus from this miracle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 2:12-25 (Jesus clears the temple)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 12 mentions that Jesus went to Capernaum with his mother and brothers. Did Jesus have brothers? Since Jesus was not the son of Joseph and Mary (but of Mary and the Holy Spirit) those brothers were actually younger “half-brothers” (the children of Mary and Joseph). Their names are mentioned in Mark 6:3 &amp;ndash; “Isn’t this Mary’s son and the brother of James, Joseph, Judas and Simon? Aren’t his sisters here with us?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From John 7:5 (“For even his own brothers did not believe in him.”) it is clear that Jesus’ half-brothers did not believe in him at first. Only after the resurrection do we read that Jesus’ brothers were included among the believers (see Acts 1:14). Later, one of the brothers, James, became a leader in the early church, and wrote the epistle of James in the New Testament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the time of the New Testament, Jewish believers from all over the world would gather at Jerusalem to observe the Passover, one of the three great Jewish religious festivals. The law required that each worship present a sacrificial animal or bird at the temple. The law also required that each worshiper pay the temple tax, using only the local coins that were acceptable at the temple. Because it would be difficult to travel a long distance with a sacrificial animal, and because people from other countries would need to obtain the local money needed for the temple offering, merchants sold sacrificial animals and changed coins into the local money as a convenience for the worshipers. But there was a problem with these customs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why was it necessary for Jesus to drive out those who were transacting business in the temple courts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leaders of the temple were angry with Jesus for interrupting their business. They asked Jesus for a sign to prove His authority to cleanse the temple. What sign did Jesus give them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 3:1-21 (Jesus teaches Nicodemus)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicodemus was a teacher (v. 10), a Pharisee, and a member of the Sanhedrin, the** Jewish ruling council. The Sanhedrin had 70 members who were responsible for religious decisions. This was the group that eventually put Jesus on trial (Luke 22:66).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicodemus is only mentioned in the Gospel of John. In John 7:50-51 we read that Nicodemus rebuked the Pharisees for condemning Jesus without hearing Him. And after Jesus’ death, Nicodemus donated a gift of spices and helped Joseph of Arimathea bury Jesus (19:39–40).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Nicodemus was a teacher of God’s Word in Israel, he did not understand the way of salvation and spiritual life. The main thing that the Scriptures had taught was confusing to this teacher of Israel. Unfortunately, this often seems to be the case today. There are many religious teachers in churches who do not seem to grasp the gospel or how God saves and gives spiritual life. They teach a social gospel, or they teach a way of salvation by works. How can you be a Christian teacher if you do not understand that God saves and gives life through His Spirit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did Nicodemus visit Jesus at night?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term “born again” is used in many different ways among Christians. What did Jesus mean when he used the term “born again”? (In preparing your answer, read Ephesians 2:1; Colossians 2:13; and John 6:63.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today many people will ask the question “Are you born again?” How would you answer that question using verses 16-18?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you explain the comparison between Moses lifting up the snake in the desert and Jesus’ being lifted up on the cross?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What important truths of the gospel does Jesus’ teach Nicodemus in verses 16-17?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 3:22-36 (John the Baptist’s testimony about Jesus)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Jesus’ interview with Nicodemus, the Lord took his disciples away from Jerusalem and down to the southern portion of the Jordan River, not far from ancient Jericho. There the disciples of Jesus began a baptism ministry (see John 4:2) which became very popular. In fact, the disciples of John the Baptist seem to have become envious that Jesus was gaining more followers than John had, and they complained about it to John.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John’s beautiful reply is recorded in verses 27-36. What were some of the faith-inspired truths that John confessed about Jesus?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 27-28 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 29 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 30 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 31 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 34 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 35 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 36 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 36 says, “Whoever believes in the Son has eternal life.” It doesn’t say that we &lt;em&gt;will have&lt;/em&gt; eternal life when we get to heaven. How do we have eternal life even while we still live in this world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does his answer say to us when we find ourselves becoming jealous of the successes others enjoy in their service to the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next lesson we will see how Jesus went to reach the people of Samaria through a woman he met at a well. Please prepare the lesson on John 4 and 5. May the Lord guide your study of his holy word.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt; &lt;/code&gt;PAGE 2&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Leson 4 The Gospel of John, Chapters 4 and 5*</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/4/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus: The Living Water&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 4:1-26 (Jesus and the Samaritan woman)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strong opposition to Jesus was already building in Judea, but it was not yet time for Jesus to be captured and put to death. He had much to teach us before He would offer His life to His enemies. At this time, because it would be difficult to minister in Judea, Jesus decided to return to Galilee for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;When traveling between Judea (in the south) and Galilee (in the north) most Jews would avoid the hostile territory of Samaria which lay between the two districts, and would travel the long route to the east of the Jordan River. But this time Jesus decided to travel directly through Samaria. In fact, in the original language of the Bible verse 4 says “it was necessary for him to go through Samaria.” Why was this “necessary”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is that this was the Father’s plan. God wanted to reach the Samaritan people, and that would begin with a woman at a well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In chapter 3, Jesus reached out to a man. In chapter 4, to a woman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In chapter 3 it was night. In chapter 4 it was the middle of the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In chapter 3 Jesus reached out to a Jew. In chapter 4 to a Samaritan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In chapter 3 Jesus reached to a highly respected person. In chapter 4 to a person of low morals and reputation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is that Jesus is the Savior of all nations, all genders, all social classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why didn’t Jews normally associate with Samaritans?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the living water Jesus spoke of? (There are three possibilities. Look up the references below and state them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 4:14 &amp;ndash; “whoever drinks the water I give him will never thirst”. Indeed, the water I give him will become in him a spring of water welling up to eternal life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 7:38-39 &amp;ndash; “Whoever believes in me, as the Scripture has said, streams of living water will flow from within him.” By this he meant the Spirit, whom those who believed in him were later to receive. Up to that time the Spirit had not been given, since Jesus had not yet been glorified.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;jeremiah-1713--lord-you-are-israels-hope-all-who-abandon-you-will-be-put-to-shame-they-will-disappear-like-names-written-in-the-dust-because-they-have-abandoned-you-the-lord-the-spring-of-fresh-water&#34;&gt;Jeremiah 17:13 – “Lord, you are Israel’s hope; all who abandon you will be put to shame. They will disappear like names written in the dust, because they have abandoned you, the Lord, the spring of fresh water.”&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would have to allow any of these three possibilities. Living water was a term for fresh water that was not stagnant. Much drinking water came from cisterns that caught and held the rain water. The living water was a spring or running water that was continually fresh. But Jesus had a spiritual meaning in mind. He was not talking about water at all, but about life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Jesus show the woman her need for the living water of the Gospel?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verses 23 &amp;amp; 24 Jesus talks about worshiping God in spirit and in truth. What does he mean by this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Jesus use the woman’s knowledge of Scripture to direct her to the truth that he is the Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 4:27-42 (Jesus brings the gospel to Samaria)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What changes occurred in the woman’s heart after she heard Jesus’ testimony?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 32 Jesus told his disciples he already had food to eat. What food was he talking about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Jesus mean when he told the disciples in verse 38 “I sent you to reap what you have not worked for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What were the results of Jesus’ testimony to the Samaritan woman and her testimony to the people in her hometown?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 4:43-54 (Jesus heals the official’s son)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The royal official came to Jesus because his son was near death and the situation looked hopeless. In desperation the father begged Jesus to come to heal his son. Jesus’ response in verse 48 seems heartless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why might Jesus have answered the way he did?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What good example did the royal official set through his request to Jesus in verse 49?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus didn’t go with the man to heal his son. Instead Jesus left the father with only a promise. How does God often deal with us in the same way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-five&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter Five&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 5:1-15 (The healing at Bethesda)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter tells us that Jesus went to Jerusalem to celebrate a “&lt;em&gt;feast of the Jews.”&lt;/em&gt; This feast was probably one of the three pilgrimage feasts to which all Jewish males were expected to go—Passover, Pentecost or Tabernacles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The identity of this feast is significant for the attempt to ascertain the number of Passovers included in Jesus’ ministry, and thus the number of years his ministry lasted. John explicitly mentions at least three different Passovers: the first in 2:13, 23 (see note on 2:13), the second in 6:4 and the third several times (e.g., in 11:55; 12:1). If three Passovers are accepted, the length of Jesus’ ministry was between two and three years. However, if the feast of 5:1 was a fourth Passover or assumes that a fourth Passover had come and gone, Jesus’ ministry would have lasted between three and four years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did many disabled people come to the pool at Bethesda?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did the Jews confront the man Jesus had just healed? (See Jeremiah 17:21-22)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did Jesus give such a stern warning to the man he just finished healing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 5:16-30 (Jesus answers the Jews who wanted to kill him)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did the Jewish leaders want to kill Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus had already performed many amazing miracles during his public ministry. In verse 22 he promised greater things were still to be shown. What greater things was he talking about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said the Father has entrusted all judgment to the Son. What according to verses 17-30 what things can we be sure of concerning all the Son’s judgments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 5:31-47 (The testimony about Jesus)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In verse 32 Jesus said that others had given valid testimony in His favor? Who were these people and what was their testimony?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v.33&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v.36&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v.37&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v.39&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v.46&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a court of law, simple testimony on your own behalf was not enough to establish the truthfulness of your statement. But when the same testimony was given by another witness, the truth was established. The Father giving authority to Jesus, and the power to do miracles, was the second witness that established the truth of Jesus in any human court of law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leaders of the Jews spent much time studying the Old Testament Scriptures. What did Jesus show them they were failing to see in their studies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes as Christians we do things we know are right according to God’s will yet it seems as if no one is supporting us or affirming that we are doing God’s will. How does Jesus’ testimony in these verses help us in those times?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next lesson will cover chapter 6, which contains one of the hardest sayings of Jesus. Take your time and prepare it carefully. Write down questions you want to ask. 
&lt;code&gt; &lt;/code&gt;PAGE 2&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 5 The Gospel of John, Chapter 6*</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/5/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus: The Bread of Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story of the miraculous feeding of over 5,000 is one of the few miracles recorded in all four Gospels (Matthew 14:13-21; Mark 6:32-44; Luke 9:10-17; John 6:1-13). This miracle took place in Galilee about a year before Jesus’ crucifixion. Many have debated whether or not “The Bread of Life Discourse” which follows this miracle is about the Lord’s Supper or only about believing in Him.  We will answer that question and learn how Jesus satisfies every physical and spiritual need we have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 6:1-15 (Jesus provides a miraculous meal)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why were large crowds following Jesus at this time? (vs. 2) How was this both a good thing and a bad thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 6 says that Jesus already knew how he was going to provide food for the large crowd, and that his question to Philip was only to test him. What was the purpose of this test? What was He leading His disciples to understand about themselves? About Him? What lesson was Jesus teaching all of us through this miracle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 11 we read that Jesus prayed (‘gave thanks”) before beginning the meal. Why did he do this? Is this something we should do before we eat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What good lesson did Jesus teach his disciples and us after everyone had plenty to eat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 15 we read that the people wanted to make Jesus a king by force. Jesus did not allow this to happen. We confess Jesus is our king. Why wouldn’t he allow the people to make him a king on this occasion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respond: If God is so good at taking care of people’s needs, why are there so many homeless and hungry people in the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 6:16-24 (Jesus walks on water)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Matthew and Mark also record this incident, and they add a number of things to John’s account. According to those gospel accounts,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus made the disciples get into the boat and go on ahead of him to the other side, while he dismissed the crowd (Matthew 14:22)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the fourth watch of the night (sometime between 3:00 am and 6:00 am) Jesus went out to them (Matthew 14:25)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When they saw Jesus in the darkness, the disciples first thought that he was a ghost (Matthew 14:26; Mark 6:49)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter tried to walk on the water too, but started to sink in fear (Matthew 14:29-30)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Jesus and Peter got into the boat, the disciples worshiped him, and confessed: “Truly you are the Son of God” (Matthew 14:33)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disciples were terrified when they saw Jesus walking on the water toward them. They certainly did not expect to see Him there. They were already tired and fearful because of the terrible weather conditions (wind and pouring rain, and stormy waves), and it was in the middle of the night. In the darkness, they thought he was a ghost. The entire situation was already very frightening, even for experienced fishermen. But now to see a figure out on the water was totally freaky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does Jesus teach us about himself through this miracle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 6:24-59 (The misguided search for a bread king)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Jesus and the disciples arrived on the shore of the Sea of Galilee near Capernaum, many people were looking for him. Why were they searching for Jesus (verses 26-27)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 26 Jesus mentioned the miraculous signs that he had been doing. These “signs” were marks that distinguished the genuineness of something. Many people have tried to make counterfeit (fake) money. How can you tell real money from the fake or counterfeit money? The real money has a distinguishing mark that the counterfeiters cannot duplicate. The mark tells the user that the money is genuine and real. The miracles of Jesus were the marks that identified Jesus as the real Messiah, the real Savior of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many think that the main idea of the Christian church today is to give out food and other earthly things that will make life better on earth. Humans are so earthly-minded that they neglect the needs of the soul. Jesus has so much more to offer. Though sin has blinded us to our deeper needs, Jesus wants to address them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In verse 27 Jesus spoke about the “food that spoils” and the “food that endures to eternal life.” What are these?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“food that spoils” =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“food that endures to eternal life” =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In verse 28 the people asked the one question every human being would like to ask Jesus: “What must we do to do the works God requires?” As we might expect, their assumption was that we must do something to be right with God. What did Jesus say the work of God is (vs. 29)?  What does it mean to do this (see verses 40 and 47)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 35 contains another powerful “I am” statement of Jesus. Here he calls himself “the bread of life.” In the Lord’s prayer we pray, “Give us this day our daily bread.” In that prayer, the word “bread” stands for everything we need to live. When he said that he is the bread of life, Jesus was saying that he is everything we need to live eternally. As he goes on, Jesus tells us that we should “eat the bread of life” (see verse 51).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did Jesus mean when he told us to eat the Bread of Life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v.35 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v.40 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v.51 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginning in verse 51 Jesus began speaking about giving his flesh to be eaten. Some have taken many verses in this chapter as references to the Lord’s Supper. All of the evidence, however, is to the contrary. Jesus says, “I am the bread of life.” He does not say: “I am the bread and wine of life.” He is not talking about the Lord’s Supper in this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, it is very unlikely that the Savior would command the sacramental eating of his body and blood before he had instituted his Holy Supper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 53 Jesus says: “Unless you eat the flesh of the Son of Man and drink His blood you do not have life in yourselves.” If Jesus were speaking of the Lord’s Supper it would mean: “Unless you go to the Lord’s Supper you don’t have God’s life in you.” That would automatically eliminate all the Old Testament believers and anyone who has not taken the Lord’s Supper. Nowhere does Scripture teach that anyone who has not taken holy communion can be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this chapter Jesus invites us to eat him spiritually as the Bread that gives eternal life. This means to take him into your inmost being by accepting that his body was sacrificed for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 6:60-71 (Many disciples desert Jesus)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people think that Jesus only had twelve disciples. That is not true. He did choose twelve of his disciples and designate them as apostles, but he actually had many more disciples who followed him and listened to his teaching. But now this teaching of Jesus that he had come down from heaven and that people must “eat” his flesh and “drink” his blood in order to have eternal life was shocking to them for the Jews would never eat anything with blood in it. Many of the disciples simply would not accept it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Jesus’ words in verses 36 and 64, why were many of these followers of Jesus having such a hard time accepting his teachings?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can anyone “come” to Jesus or believe in him according to these verses: 37, 44, 63, 65?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 37 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 44 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 63 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 65 =&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, no one can choose to come to Jesus by himself. God must draw believers to Jesus, and the Spirit will work new life through the words of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verses 68-69 what precious truths did Peter express in his answer to Jesus’ question?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to Peter’s confession what truth did Jesus reveal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we look at Jesus’ gracious message in John 6 and the people’s response what can we also expect as we continue to share the good news of Jesus in the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our next lesson we will follow Jesus to one of the great Jewish festivals where he proclaims himself as the true Messiah who has come to redeem the world. Please prepare chapter 7. 
&lt;code&gt; &lt;/code&gt;PAGE 2&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 6 The Gospel of John, Chapter 7*</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/6/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus: The One Sent From God&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six months have passed between John 6 and 7. There seems to be great confusion about Jesus. Even Jesus’ brothers do not understand His kingdom; in fact, although Jesus’ brothers know He is someone great, John states that at this point they do not believe in Him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Feast of Tabernacles (Sukkoth) drew near, the most popular festival of the Jewish calendar. This was celebrated from the 15th to the 21st day of the Jewish month &lt;em&gt;Tisri&lt;/em&gt;, which generally corresponds to our month of October. The Feast of Tabernacles was a thanksgiving festival for the harvest of corn and wine (Deuteronomy 16:13) and a festival of remembrance for the Lord’s abiding presence when the Israelites wandered in the wilderness and lived in huts (Leviticus 23:39–43). The Jews reenacted for one week the living in tents (“tabernacles”) outside the walls of Jerusalem. As you read this chapter, see yourself in Jerusalem as one of the participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 7:1-13 (Jesus delays going to Judea)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 3 mentions Jesus’ brothers. In Matthew 13:55 four of Jesus’ brothers are mentioned by name: James, Joseph, Simon, and Judas (Jude). These would actually be half-brothers of Jesus (the children of Mary and Joseph). From the various references to the brothers of Jesus in the Gospels, we may assume that at first none of them believed in Jesus as the Son of God. This is obvious from this text, and from Mark 3:21, where they thought “he was out of his mind”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after the resurrection of Christ, at least some of them changed their minds, and became believers (Acts 1:14). Later one of them, James, became one of the leaders of the church in Jerusalem, and wrote the epistle of James in the NT. His brother, Jude, wrote the book of Jude in the NT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why didn’t Jesus go to the feast right away?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why were the people in Jerusalem afraid to speak publicly about Jesus? (v. 13 and v.25)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What causes people today to be afraid to openly testify about Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 7:14-24 (Jesus teaches at the feast)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why were the people so amazed when Jesus began to teach in the temple courts? (see v. 15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verses 17-18 Jesus teaches us one way to distinguish between one who teaches falsely and one who speaks the truth. What is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain in your own words the force of Jesus’ argument in vs. 22-24. How were the Pharisees judging superficially?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 7:25-44 (Is Jesus the Messiah?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statement of the people in verse 27 shows how little some of them knew about the Messiah. They said, “When the Christ comes, no one will know where he is from.” Didn’t the prophet Micah (5:2) say that he would come from Bethlehem in Judea? Didn’t the prophet Isaiah (7:14) write that he would be born of a virgin? Didn’t all the prophets say that he would come from the Father? They should know if they read the Scriptures. It was clear that they didn’t know Jesus to be the Son of God. But in verse 28, Jesus said that they didn’t even know the Father who had sent him. How could that be? They were all at the temple to worship God and observe the festival. How could Jesus say that they did not know the Father?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Jesus mean when he said, “You will look for me, but will not find me; and where I am, you cannot come?” (verse 34）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 37 tells us what Jesus taught “on the last and greatest day of the Feast.” On each of the seven festal days, the officiating priest took a golden vessel at the morning service, and filled it with water from the fountain of Siloam in the Kidron valley, mixed the water with the wine of the drink offering, and poured it into two silver bowls on the west of the altar for the burnt offering, while the trumpets were sounded and praise was sung. The people chanted Isaiah 12:3:* “Therefore with joy shall ye draw water out of the wells of salvation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What great invitation and promise did Jesus shout out at the climax to the Feast of the Tabernacles? (verses 37-39）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verses 41-43 we read that the people of Jerusalem were divided over whether Jesus could be the Messiah. What was the main cause of their confusion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what ways are people still divided about Jesus today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 7:45-53 (The Pharisees reject Jesus)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did the Pharisees continue to show their pride and stubborn unbelief?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 50 Nicodemus, who had shown a willingness to consider the teachings of Jesus and had visited Jesus at night to ask him questions, suggested that they should at least give Jesus a fair hearing before condemning him, and he experienced ridicule for doing so. Would you agree or disagree that Jesus frequently gets judged by people today without ever giving Him a fair hearing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next lesson will cover chapters 8 and 9 and will be a longer lesson than this one. Please begin work on it soon so that we are ready for discussion in class. 
&lt;code&gt; &lt;/code&gt;PAGE 1&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 7 The Gospel of John, Chapters 8 and 9</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/7/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus: The Light of the World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 8:1-11 (The woman caught in adultery)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pharisees and the teachers of the law brought a woman before Jesus. They had caught her in the very act of adultery. Imagine the scene. They must have raided the bedroom, marched her through the streets of Jerusalem, barely clothed, while everyone was looking at her and shaking their heads. Some picked up stones along the street, so that they could join in giving her the punishment she deserved. They dragged her into the temple courtyard and thrust her into the middle of a morning Bible class. “This woman was caught in the act of adultery,” they scowled. In the very act. “The law of Moses says to stone her. What do you say, Rabbi?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The woman was defenseless. She could not deny it. She was guilty. Caught in the very act. What could she do? Could she plead for mercy from God? God’s spokesmen were standing there with stones in their hands. They had already passed judgment. She had no excuse, and no escape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is this situation a trap for Jesus? (v. 6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Jesus answered them, he stooped down and began writing something on the ground.  In all the record of Holy Scripture, this was the first and only time that Jesus ever wrote anything. What was He writing? Was it a message for her? Something for her accusers? We do not know, and cannot even guess. But consider this passage from the prophet Jeremiah (17:13) “Lord, you are the hope of Israel; all who forsake you will be put to shame. Those who turn away from you will be written in the dust because they have forsaken the Lord, the spring of living water.” Perhaps Jesus’ writing had something to do with that verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did Jesus avoid the trap and get to the heart of the issue at the same time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus showed mercy to the sinful woman and gave her the opportunity to repent and turn from her sinful ways. He reminded the people that they all needed God’s mercy. He demonstrated his own teaching that He had not come to condemn the world, but to bring mercy, forgiveness, and salvation to the world. (John 3:17).  When we have sinned, we can always go to Jesus for forgiveness, even when others condemn us. He showed us that He loves to show mercy, no matter how bad we have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus told the woman, “Neither do I condemn you.” How would you respond to someone who said, “It’s wrong for us to condemn sin.  Look how Jesus accepted this sinful woman?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said “Woman, where are they? Where are the accusers, the condemners?” Let’s ponder this question, not just for the woman, but for us. Dear children of God, where are your accusers, those who would condemn you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our accusers are out there in the world. “You aren’t good enough. You’re a failure. You will never change.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there are the voices in our heads! “You are nothing. God doesn’t care about you. You are too bad for Him to love you. There is no forgiveness for that sin.” Accusers. Condemners. In the world. In our consciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in addition to those voices, there is a great accuser, Satan (his name means “accuser”) The Bible says in Revelation 12:9-10 – “The great dragon was hurled down—that ancient serpent called the devil, or Satan, who leads the whole world astray. He was hurled to the earth, and his angels with him. Then I heard a loud voice in heaven say: “Now have come the salvation and the power and the kingdom of our God, and the authority of his Christ. For the accuser of our brothers, who accuses them before our God day and night, has been hurled down.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day after day, hour after hour, Satan accuses. It is his career, his delight. Satan’s accusations and condemnations bring no repentance, just regret. Jesus calls him a “thief, who has come to steal, to kill, and to destroy” (John 10:10). He has come to steal your peace, to kill your dreams, and to destroy your future. And he uses people to peddle his poison. People, who dredge up our past, preachers who preach law and no grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Condemnation. This is Satan’s specialty. He wants to repeat what happened to the adulterous woman in you. He wants to march you through life, drag you before the Lord on the day of judgment, and broadcast your sin for everyone to know. “This person was caught in the act of … stupidity, immorality, irresponsibility, dishonesty.” And he will pressure God to condemn you to an eternity in hell. And you will not be able to deny his accusations. You will not be able to plead innocence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Satan will not have the last word on that day. Jesus will. He has stooped on your behalf. He stooped low enough to sleep in a manger, to work in a carpentry shop, to sleep in a fishing boat, to walk with lepers, tax collectors, and sinners like that woman. He bent down and people spit on Him, slapped Him, and dragged Him through the streets of Jerusalem. He bent down and stretched out His holy arms on a cross for you. And then He bent down to be lowered into a grave for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now He stands beside you, victorious, almighty, and speaks the last word. “I have loved you with an everlasting love. I have died for your sin. I have paid with every drop of My blood for your wrongs. I have defeated Satan, death, and hell. I have given you grace. You are forgiven. Where are your accusers? Neither do I condemn you. Neither do I, the Son of God, the King of Grace, the Shepherd of your soul – neither do I condemn you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what Paul was thinking about when he wrote: “Who will bring any charge against those whom God has chosen? It is God who justifies. Who is he that condemns? Christ Jesus, who died—more than that, who was raised to life—is at the right hand of God and is also interceding for us. Who shall separate us from the love of Christ?” Not Satan. Not our accusers. Not our guilt. Because we have God’s grace. “There is no condemnation to those who are in Christ Jesus” (Romans 8:1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satan is silenced. Sins are washed away. The rocks are on the ground. Why? Because of Jesus. Because of grace. Because His grace is greater than our sin. Because He has stooped for us. Because He has risen up to dispel our accusers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 8:12-30 (The validity of Jesus’ claims)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of John contains many beautiful “I am” sayings of Jesus (“I am the bread of life,” “I am the light of the world,” “I am the good shepherd” – and many more). It is significant that each of them began with the words: “I am.” When the crowds heard Jesus say, “I am,” they immediately thought of the time when Moses met the Lord at the burning bush. Moses asked the Lord, “When I tell the people in Egypt your words, and they ask me what your name is, what should I tell them?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;God replied: “I AM WHO I AM. This is what you are to say to the Israelites, ‘I AM has sent me to you.’” (Exodus 3:14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;Thus, the God of the Bible is known as “I AM.” And when Jesus kept on saying “I AM,” people who knew the Old Testament understand that Jesus was claiming to be the I AM God of the Bible, Jehovah, the one true God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what way is Jesus the light of the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did the Pharisees challenge Jesus on this occasion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What points did Jesus make to affirm the validity of His testimony in verses 14-18?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On what occasions did the Father give witness that His Son is telling the truth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 3:17 =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 17:5 =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 10:38 =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 5:39 =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pharisees believed in God, yet Jesus said that they did not know the Father. Jesus said this because they did not know the Father who delights in showing mercy, and who had sent His Son to be the Savior of the world. They did not know the Father of free and faithful love. “The Lord, the Lord, the compassionate and gracious God, slow to anger, abounding in love and faithfulness, maintaining love to thousands, and forgiving wickedness, rebellion and sin. (Exodus 34:6-7). They did not know the Father, who so loved the world that He gave His one and only Son (John 3:16).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also true of many people who claim they know God today. They may know a God, but usually He is a God whose love has to be earned. Usually the God they “know” is a God of CONDITIONAL love. The true God is a God of UNCONDITIONAL love, who shows kindness and mercy to those who do not deserve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 8:31-47 (The true children of Abraham)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people claim to be disciples of Jesus. However, according to Jesus, his disciples are those who “hold to His teachings.” Exactly what did Jesus mean when he said, “If you hold to my teaching…” Surely he didn’t mean that we merely carry around a Bible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;First, he means that we should hold to his doctrine. God would never win a popularity contest these days with some of the things that are in the Bible. The doctrines that life begins at conception, that Christians ought to strive for complete unity in doctrine, that women are to submit to the leadership of men in the home and church—these doctrines and any others that happen to run contrary to someone’s current way of thinking or that may cause someone inconvenience are too easily cast aside. Pastors and church leaders are all too ready to compromise the teachings of Christ in order to gain or retain church members. But real disciples hold to the teaching, popular or not. They hold to His teachings, casting aside their personal opinions and judgments, bringing their thoughts into captivity to the Word of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;The second thing that Christ means when he says “hold to my teaching” is that those who are really his disciples not only accept his doctrines, but live them, too. One day a man who didn’t believe in going to church was sitting in his car reading the Sunday newspaper and waiting to give his wife a ride home from church. Members began streaming out of the church 10 minutes earlier than usual. The man rolled down his window and rather jokingly asked a passerby, “Is the sermon over already?” The church-goer quickly responded. “No, actually it’s only half-over. The preacher has preached it, but now we have to live it.” That person understood well. Real disciples pattern their behavior according to the Word. It influences their spending, rearranges their priorities, guides their decisions. Everything done in life takes the directives of God’s Word into consideration. The Word is not just heard, but kept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;The third thing that Christ means when he says “hold to my teaching” is that those who are really his disciples continue to make faithful use of His Word. They read the Bible. They study it. They ponder it. They search it. They review it. They grow with it. Christ’s disciples know that spiritual growth will stop and spiritual deterioration will set in if they stop reading or studying Holy Scripture. They see the direct connection between faith and spiritual maturity and the use of the Bible. So they welcome opportunities for Bible study. They rejoice when they have an opportunity to read Scripture. Have you ever found your old high school yearbooks when cleaning a closet or the garage? Did you find that you couldn’t resist opening that yearbook up and reading some of the things your friends wrote to you? Oh, that we couldn’t resist opening up that Bible again and reading the things that God has written to us on its pages! Oh, that we would all renew our hearts and minds by the power of His love recorded in Scripture!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do Jesus’ teachings set us free?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the difference between the children of Abraham the Jews claimed to be and the true children of Abraham Jesus spoke of?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 8:48-59 (Jesus testifies about himself)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What foolish charges did the Jews bring against Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Jesus mean when he said those who keep his Word would never see death?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 9:1-41 (The man who was born blind)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter gives us valuable insight into the cause and effect of human troubles and suffering. When Jesus and his disciples encountered a man who had been blind from birth, the disciples asked Jesus, “Who sinned, this man or his parents, so that he was born blind?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question assumed that the man’s blindness was a punishment for a sin – either his own sin or his parents’ sin. In v. 34 we hear that the Pharisees said that the blind man was “steeped in sin at birth.” It seems to have been the popular opinion that this man was born blind because of some sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disciples faced a theological problem. Believing that sin directly caused all suffering, how could a person be &lt;em&gt;born&lt;/em&gt; with a handicap? The conclusion was that it was either this man sinned in his mother’s womb (Ezekiel 18:4 – “The soul who sins is the one who will die”) or his parents sinned (Exodus 20:5 – “I, the Lord your God, am a jealous God, punishing the children for the sin of the fathers to the third and fourth generation of those who hate me.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cause of human suffering is still something people are trying to figure out. Some have concluded that illness, accidents, and all kinds of human suffering are the direct result of some sin we have committed. This was what Job’s so-called “friends” assumed. They (Job 4:7-8) accused him of doing something terrible that God was punishing him for his sins by making him suffer. In fact, this idea was carried out to the point that they even figured that if someone was born with a handicap, it must be because God was angry with the child’s parents for committing some sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;This view of human suffering as the result of God’s anger and vengeance over some human iniquity, as common as it is, is incomplete and inaccurate as an explanation for our troubles and handicaps. Here are more truths about this matter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sin has brought consequences on this world and all who live in it, as we can see from Genesis 3. Specifically, the wages of sin is death, trouble, hardship, and suffering of all kinds. The curse of sin affects all of creation, and all people, believers and unbelievers alike.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes sin has a direct consequence, such as crime resulting in imprisonment, or drunkenness resulting in a hangover, or adultery resulting in loss of a marriage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But God is not vindictive. The Bible says that He “does not treat us as our sins deserve or repay us according to our iniquities” (Psalm 103:10). If He did, if we or our parents were punished as our sins deserve, if God would strike everyone who sins with blindness, we would all be blind.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because sin has brought trouble and sorrow into this world, we all are affected. We will all experience pain, trouble, and physical death. Every human being is affected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even God’s Son, when He became human and entered our world, was affected by sin. He suffered pain, hardship, and death. Not because He sinned or did anything wrong. But because He lived in a world that was under the curse of sin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is an expert at taking lemons and making lemonade. What I mean is that God can take the troubles and trials that sin has brought into this world, and transform them into something good, even a blessing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That was the case with Jesus’ suffering and death. God transformed the suffering and death of Jesus into a blessing for the world (because God used the suffering and death of His Son to redeem the world from sin and hell).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Likewise, God can transform all forms of human suffering into blessing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus answered the disciple’s question by explaining that the man’s blindness was not a punishment for anyone’s sin, but for the purpose of revealing the work of God in his life. What is the “work of God”? See John 6:29 – “Jesus answered, “The &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;work of God&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is this: to believe in the one he has sent.”” (John 6:29). And also Romans 8:28 = “And we know that in all things &lt;em&gt;God works&lt;/em&gt; for the good of those who love him, who have been called according to his purpose.&amp;quot; (Romans 8:28).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God sometimes uses hardships to display his work in our lives. The healing of our bodies shows God at work, When God uses hardships to return our focus on His mercy and help, and shows us our great need for Him, then He is at work in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we experience the hardships, troubles, and suffering that are a part of our human existence, then we must remember that Jesus has suffered the penalty for all of our sins. John writes: “the blood of Jesus, his Son, purifies us from all sin.&amp;quot; (1 John 1:7). God will not punish us for the same sins that have been forgiven through the blood of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather our hardships are not to be viewed as punishments, but as discipline. See these passages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“When we are judged by the Lord, we are being disciplined so that we will not be condemned with the world.” (1 Corinthians 11:32).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Endure hardship as discipline; God is treating you as sons. For what son is not disciplined by his father? If you are not disciplined (and everyone undergoes discipline), then you are illegitimate children and not true sons. Moreover, we have all had human fathers who disciplined us and we respected them for it. How much more should we submit to the Father of our spirits and live! Our fathers disciplined us for a little while as they thought best; but God disciplines us for our good, that we may share in his holiness. No discipline seems pleasant at the time, but painful. Later on, however, it produces a harvest of righteousness and peace for those who have been trained by it.” (Hebrews 12:7-11).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Those whom I love I rebuke and discipline. So be earnest, and repent.” (Revelation 3:19).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Jesus healed the blind man, he did a strange thing. He put mud on the man’s eyes and told him to go and wash it off in the pool of Siloam in order to be cured. Why did Jesus use such unusual means to heal the blind man?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some examples of how God calls us to do things that don’t seem to make much sense on the surface?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that Jesus not only cured the man’s physical blindness, but also cured his spiritual blindness, bringing him gradually to the true faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In v. 11 he only called Jesus a “man.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In v. 17 he confessed that Jesus must be a prophet. (So this was progress in his understanding who Jesus was.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In v. 33, he says that Jesus must be “from God.” (He is coming to believe.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In v. 38, he worships Jesus and says that he believes in Him. (He not only can see, but He can see the Light of the world.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next lesson will cover chapter 10, known as the “Good Shepherd chapter” of the Bible. Please prepare the lesson prior to class. 
&lt;code&gt; &lt;/code&gt;PAGE 1&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 8 The Gospel of John, Chapter 10</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/8/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Good Shepherd&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;isaiah-4010-11-yes-the-sovereign-lord-is-coming-in-all-his-glorious-power-he-will-rule-with-awesome-strength-see-he-brings-his-reward-with-him-as-he-comes-he-will-feed-his-flock-like-a-shepherd-he-will-carry-the-lambs-in-his-arms-holding-them-close-to-his-heart-he-will-gently-lead-the-mother-sheep-with-their-young&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isaiah 40:10-11&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, the Sovereign LORD is coming in all his glorious power. He will rule with awesome strength. See, he brings his reward with him as he comes. He will feed his flock like a shepherd. He will carry the lambs in his arms, holding them close to his heart. He will gently lead the mother sheep with their young.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of chapter 9, we heard that the Pharisees had expelled from the synagogue the man that Jesus had healed from blindness. Jesus told the Pharisees that they were now the ones who are blind, for they could not see God at work in the ministry of Jesus. 
In this chapter, Jesus reminds the Pharisees, his disciples, and all who were present, of the Old Testament portrait of the leaders of God’s people who were unfaithful, evil shepherds of God’s sheep. The picture of God’s people as sheep, and the leaders of the people (kings, prophets, and priests) as shepherds of God’s flock, was very familiar to anyone who had read the Old Testament. A few examples of that picture are Psalm 23, Psalm 100:1; Jeremiah 23:1-4 and Ezekiel 34:1-10, 23-24. The kings of Israel were called “shepherds” in the Old Testament. For example, King David was called the shepherd of God’s people Israel in both 2 Samuel 5:2 and Psalm 78:72.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sheep are the people of God. The figure of comparing God’s people to sheep occurs in the psalms from the time of David. David used this metaphor, and it became common. David was calling himself a “sheep” when he wrote, “The Lord is my Shepherd,,,” (Psalm 23:1). In Psalm 100:3 it says, “Know that the Lord is God. It is he who made us, and we are his; we are his people, the sheep of his pasture.” The prophets often referred to the people of Israel as sheep, See Ezekiel 34:31 (“You my sheep, the sheep of my pasture, are people, and I am your God, declares the Sovereign Lord”) as an example. Jesus also used this picture in his parables. See the parable of the lost sheep in Matthew 18:12-14. After his resurrection, Jesus commissioned Peter and the other apostles to “Take care of … feed my sheep” (John 21:16-17). WE are the sheep. As Jesus says in the next few verses, His sheep listen to his voice, follow him, and he gives them eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus now uses that familiar concept to proclaim himself as the good and faithful Shepherd, who truly cares for his sheep, and saves them. (v. 11) In Hebrews 13:20 Jesus is called “that great Shepherd of the sheep.” (“May the God of peace, through the blood of the eternal covenant brought back from the dead our Lord Jesus, that great Shepherd of the sheep…”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter is the fulfillment of the prophecy of Ezekiel: “I will place over them one shepherd, my servant David, and he will tend them; he will tend them and be their shepherd. I the Lord will be their God, and my servant David will be prince among them. I the Lord have spoken” (Ezekiel 34:23–24). (The “David” the prophet was referring to was not the man who killed Goliath, because this prophecy was written at least 400 years after the time of David. Rather this is a reference to Jesus. The angel told Mary about her child, “The Lord God will give him the throne of his father David” (Luke 1:32). Just as David, a shepherd, fought the giant and defended his people, Jesus (our David) fought the devil and our mightiest enemies and won the victory for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a comforting chapter for every believer, and one of the most loved chapters of the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 10:1-10 (The gate for the sheep)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In verse 1, Jesus warns us about “robbers” that do not approach the sheep by using the gate, but by climbing over the fence. Who are these robbers Jesus was warning us about? They are described as men who …&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v.1 =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v.5 =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v. 10 =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At night, whenever possible, the shepherd would take his sheep into an enclosed pen made of stones or sticks. Then the shepherd would lay down across the only opening, the gate of the enclosure. Thus, the shepherd himself was the gate. In what way is Jesus the gate for the sheep?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does Jesus mean when he says that we will have life “to the full?” (verse 10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said his followers will listen to his voice but not the voice of false teachers. Why are many who were once Christians led astray by false teachers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 10:11-21 (The good shepherd)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section Jesus speaks about bad shepherds who mislead, forsake, and destroy the flock. Jesus calls these bad shepherds “hired hands”. Their main concern is not the welfare of the sheep, but the advantage they can gain by leading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many such “hired hands” who would like to be our shepherds. They include the teachers and professors in our schools who would lead us to believe that the world has evolved by chance and that we are descended from apes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are the astrologers and fortune tellers who would lead us to believe that our destiny is controlled by the movements of the stars, tides, and moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are the humanistic authors, television producers, and personalities, the so-called “shepherds of the masses,” who would lead us in their own brand of self-serving philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also find many bad shepherds in the churches. They are the preachers who speak smooth words of flattery, saying that we are all basically good as they downplay sin and tell us to “think positive.” Contrary to many clear passages of Scripture that teach salvation by the grace of God alone, there are many false shepherds in the churches who teach that we cannot enter heaven unless we work hard to earn it, or they teach that we must work alongside of Jesus to earn our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because people are always looking for guidance in the wilderness of life, these bad shepherds have misled many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like helpless, frightened sheep, we long for and need a good shepherd who will lead us through the untracked wilderness of life, through the shadows of the valley of death, and into the eternal pastures of life in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about the work a shepherd does. In what ways is Jesus “the good shepherd” according to verses 11-14?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v. 11 =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v.12-13 =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;v. 14 =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are the other sheep Jesus will bring into his fold? (v.16-19)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Jesus why does the Father love the Son? (v. 17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus had already promised he was going to need to sacrifice his life. In v. 18 Jesus adds two important details about his death. What are they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus spoke about his personal relationship with his sheep. What are some things your good shepherd has done for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt; &lt;/code&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 10:22-30  (Jesus confesses he is true God)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we now come to 10:22 a new time reference appears – The Feast of Dedication. This feast is sometimes called Hanukkah or the Festival of Lights, and the Jews celebrate it in mid-December. The festival remembers the rededication of the temple after its desecration by Antiochus IV in 165 B.C. Though about two months had passed since Jesus’ words in the first half of John 10, he returns to that familiar theme of him as shepherd and his followers as sheep. In the second half of the chapter we see the conversation between Jesus and his enemies turn to the central theme of John’s gospel – Jesus is the true Son of God, one with the Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;This account takes place at the temple in Jerusalem under the shelter of “Solomon’s Colonnade.” This large columned porch of the temple ran along the entire east side of the temple mount. Rabbis would use this covered porch to teach classes, and later Jesus’ disciples often met here (Acts 3:11; Acts 5:12).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the Jews demanded that Jesus tell them plainly whether or not he was the Messiah. (John 10:24 – “The Jews gathered around him, saying, “How long will you keep us in suspense? If you are the Christ, tell us plainly.”) Jesus had previously told the Samaritan woman very plainly that he was the Messiah (see John 4:25–26 &amp;ndash; The woman said, “I know that Messiah” (called Christ) “is coming. When he comes, he will explain everything to us.” Then Jesus declared, “I who speak to you am he.”) However, most of the Jewish people had a false concept about the Messiah, believing that the Messiah would lead a rebellion against the Roman authorities and establish a new earthly kingdom in Israel. If Jesus were to simply say, “I am the Messiah,” most of the people would misunderstand and think that he had come to be a rebel and political leader. Therefore, Jesus could not simply tell them that he was the Messiah in so many words. Instead, he told them in a special way that would make it clear that he had not come as a political Messiah, but as a divine King.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;In reply, Jesus said that he had already told them that he was the true Messiah. When was this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus told them time and time again that He was sent by the Father.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus answered the Samaritan woman about the Messiah, “I am He”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He said, “I am the Bread of Life”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus claimed to be the Light of the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus told them He was the Fountain of Living Water.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus said, “before Abraham was, I AM”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus informed the blind man that He was the Son of God.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He just told them that He alone was the Shepherd of the sheep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every miracle that he did was proof that he had come as the true Messiah.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 28 records three promises from Jesus. What are these promises and what do these precious promises mean to us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does Jesus mean when he says in verse 30 “I and the Father are one”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 10:31-42  (The Jews try to kill Jesus)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus claim to be one with the Father was understood by the Jews as a claim to be God. Some modern day Bible scholars have said Jesus never claimed to be God, but that his early disciples made up that teaching. The reaction of the Jews makes it clear that they understand that Jesus was indeed claiming to be God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, they did not accept this claim, but considered him to be a “mere man.” Therefore they tried to stone him for what they considered to be blasphemy against God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The claims of Jesus still make people upset. Many people today consider Jesus to be a mere man (though a good one), but his claim to be the only way for people to get to heaven is still widely rejected by people all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In v. 34, Jesus defends his right to call himself God’s Son because in the Old Testament, even those who held the office of judge were called “gods” in Psalm 82:6 (“I said, ‘You are “gods”; you are all sons of the Most High.’) What did the psalm mean by referring to the assembly of judges as “gods”? It meant that their authority to judge was given them by God, and they were to use his laws, as given through Moses, as the basis for their judgments. Thus, with God’s own authority, and with God’s words guiding their work, they were to be respected as “gods” when they rendered their decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus’ argument was that since they could not object to the fact that the Scriptures called the judges “gods” – and the Scriptures could not be broken (because they were true in every respect) – how much more true it must be that God’s own Son, sent into this world on God’s saving mission and with God’s authority, could call himself God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time that Jesus defended his right to call himself God, he also proclaimed another important truth about the Holy Scriptures (verse 35). What is that truth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last several chapters of John we’ve seen many examples of Jesus being rejected by the Jews. What does Jesus teach us by his response to those who oppose God’s Word?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our next lesson we will study one of Jesus’ most amazing miracles, a miracle so amazing that it remains a continual comfort to all of us in the dark days of human death. Please prepare the lesson carefully prior to class. 
&lt;code&gt; &lt;/code&gt;PAGE 6&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 9 The Gospel of John, Chapter 11</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/9/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus: The Resurrection and the Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our study of the Gospel of John, we have been looking at “Portraits of Our Savior.” Thus far we have seen Jesus portrayed as
&lt;code&gt; &lt;/code&gt;PAGE 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Word of God&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Lamb of God&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Son of God&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Living Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bread of Life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Light of the World&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Good Shepherd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, the portrait is of Jesus as &lt;strong&gt;“The Resurrection and the Life.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the three or so years of His public ministry, Jesus did at least 35 miracles. The record is probably incomplete, because “Jesus did many other things as well. If every one of them were written down, I suppose that even the whole world would not have room for the books that would be written” (John 21:25).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think of all the miracles that Jesus did (healing people, multiplying food, walking on water, exorcizing demons, and raising people from the dead) is there any particular miracle that stands out in your mind as being especially convincing, especially impressive? Many people feel that the miracle recorded in John 11 is the most astounding miracle that Jesus ever performed (aside from His own resurrection, of course).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 11:1-16 (The death of Lazarus)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lazarus was the brother of Mary and Martha, and is only mentioned here in John 11-12. He is not mentioned in the familiar story of Mary and Martha recorded in Luke 10:38-42. Lazarus had become very ill with some disease that was threatening his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Jesus heard about Lazarus’ sickness, he said this had happened “for God’s glory, so that God’s Son may be glorified through it.” What did he mean by that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Jesus say to his disciples with his response in verses 9 and 10?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 11 Jesus calls death a “sleep.” Jesus had done this before with Jairus’ daughter (Luke 8:52). Jesus does not do this because dead people look like they are asleep. Nor was this just a euphemism that everyone uses, and it sounds better than saying “dead”. Jesus says this in order to comfort us by reminding us that God can awake someone from death just as easily as someone can wake us from sleep. Because of Christ, death is like a blessed sleep from which we will awaken into a new day and more beautiful existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus told the disciples plainly that Lazarus was dead. (verse 14) What did he mean when he said, “For your sake I am glad I was not there, so that you may believe?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 16 we read that the disciple Thomas suggested that they all go back to Judea, even if that would mean that they would all die with Jesus if they did. As you know, Thomas has a reputation for being the “doubter.” So isn’t it beautiful to hear that Thomas was so loyal to Jesus that he was even willing to die with Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 11:17-44 (Jesus brings Lazarus back to life)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often think of Martha as the woman who once urged Jesus to tell her sister Mary to help her serve the guests rather than listen to Jesus teach. (Luke 10:38-42) But what do we learn about Martha’s faith in verses 21-27?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does Jesus mean when he says in verse 25, “I am the resurrection and the life?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 35 is the shortest verse in the Bible. What is comforting about the fact that as he observed the mourning of Mary and Martha and saw their grief, he was deeply moved in spirit and wept himself at the tomb of Lazarus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this event, all the people expressed a feeling of hopelessness in the face of death. Martha objected because there would be a strong odor from the decaying body of Lazarus. Earlier Martha had earlier expressed a strong faith in Jesus, even saying, “Lord, I know that even now God will give you whatever you ask” (v. 22). But now her human reason led her to question Jesus when he commanded that the stone be taken away from the entrance to the tomb (verse 38). How did Jesus strengthen her faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martha had previously told Jesus, “I know that even now God will give you whatever you ask” (verse 22). So now, when the tomb stone had been taken away, Jesus prays to the Father. What were the main reasons for Jesus’ prayer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose someone said to you “Jesus raised Lazarus from the dead. Why won’t he do the same for my loved one who just died?” How would you answer them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 11:45-57 (The plot to kill Jesus)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Jesus raised Lazarus from the dead, his popularity among the people grew by leaps and bounds. Many put their faith in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the opposition against him also intensified. The chief priests and Pharisees were increasingly concerned about Jesus because he represented a threat to their own teachings. They were losing their grip of influence on the common folk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So they called for a meeting of the Sanhedrin, the ruling body of the Jewish nation, at which they cried out, “What are we accomplishing?” The implied answer was, “We are getting nowhere!” All of their efforts were useless because they could not do what Jesus could do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus could still storms and heal the sick. They could not. Jesus could raise people from the dead. They could not. Jesus could take away sins. They could not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The religious leaders of the people could only offer a wearisome religion where everyone had to work hard to gain their own little piece of paradise. In contrast, Jesus offered the people a religion where God comes with almighty power to save them. There was no question which was the better way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, let’s each ask ourselves the same question that the chief priests and Pharisees asked themselves: “What are we accomplishing?” Can we keep God’s law perfectly &amp;ndash; like Jesus can? Can we fulfill the demands of God for a righteous and holy life &amp;ndash; like Jesus can? Can we remove the filthy record of our past &amp;ndash; like Jesus can? Can we gain for ourselves or others the certainty of life with God in heaven &amp;ndash; like Jesus can? We can accomplish none of these things, but we don’t need to, because our Savior has already done them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chief priests and Pharisees thought they were so powerful, so important, and it was hard for them to accept that they could not even save themselves. So they rejected Jesus, who offered them the saving grace of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Luke 16:19-31 Jesus told the story of the rich man and Lazarus. It is interesting that in Jesus’ story, one of the characters had the name Lazarus, the same name as the man that Jesus had just raised from the dead. At the end of the story in Luke 16, we read that the rich man told Abraham, “If someone from the dead goes to them, they will repent” (Luke 16:30). But Abraham said, “If they do not listen to Moses and the prophets, they will not be convinced even if someone rises from the dead” (Luke 16:31).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now compare the reaction of the Pharisees to the raising of Lazarus with what Jesus said in Luke 16:30-31. Instead of coming to believe in Jesus, as many others did, the Pharisees only became hardened against Jesus, and more determined to kill him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did the Pharisees feel so threatened by Jesus, according to verse 48?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Caiaphas the high priest mean when he said, “It is better for you that one man die for the people than the whole nation perish?” (verse 50)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caiaphas was feeling rather smug. In his pride he thought himself smarter than everyone else. His idea was “inspired”, he thought. And actually, it was &amp;ndash; but not because of his brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His words were inspired because God was controlling his tongue. And God chose to have this high priest, as evil and scheming as he was, give a prophecy or prediction of a wonderful truth. Though Caiaphas sought only to express his murderous intent, God was using his words to express divine grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of one man dying to save many others was not Caiaphas’ clever idea. It was God’s plan. His words were exactly what God wanted said. Though Caiaphas wanted Jesus to die for his own selfish purposes, God wanted Jesus to die for his own saving purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caiaphas didn’t realize that he was giving expression to the truth that sinners have found so comforting over the years. Jesus died for others. Jesus died for many. Jesus died for me. In God’s wonderful way, he had the high priest that year summarize the gist of God’s glorious plan of salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would be the final prophecy given of the Messiah. For thousands of years, ever since Adam and Eve’s fall into sin, God had been revealing his plan of salvation. Through the words of the prophets, and through portrayal in solemn ceremonies, God had revealed his intent to give the world a Savior and establish a kingdom of grace for sinners. Now Caiaphas summarized it all: Jesus would die for the nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus fulfilled all those prophesies. He was the Seed of the woman (Genesis 3:15). He was the prophet greater than Moses (Deuteronomy 18:15). He was the star out of Jacob (Numbers 24:17). He was the virgin’s Son (Isaiah 7:14). He was the suffering servant (Isaiah 53). He was the risen Redeemer (Job 19:25).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They couldn’t stop Jesus from fulfilling these prophecies. Nor can Satan. Whatever the Lord has promised us, he will keep. He promises to answer prayer. He will. He promises to return and take us to heaven. He will. He promises to raise us from the dead. He will. Nothing can stop it. In the case of the Sanhedrin, God used their evil plans and schemes to achieve his saving purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;Our next lesson will take place as pilgrims were arriving to celebrate the Passover. Mary, Martha and Lazarus invited Jesus to their home in Bethany in order to demonstrate their gratitude for bringing Lazarus back to life. Please enjoy your preparation of chapter 12.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 10 The Gospel of John, Chapter 12</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/10/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus: The King of Israel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have reached the second half of John’s gospel. Previously Jesus had said that His hour had not yet come (2:4; 7:30; 8:20). But now Jesus knew the hour for his greatest act of love had come (12:23). Nearly half of the words and events recorded in the book of John occur during Holy Week, the period between Palm Sunday and Easter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter begins on the Friday evening before Palm Sunday. Jesus and His disciples had just returned to the little Judean village of Bethany, just south of Jerusalem, where, a month earlier, Jesus had wonderfully raised Lazarus from the grave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;	&lt;/code&gt;Jesus and his disciples were gathered for supper in the house of Simon the leper (Mark 14:3), a man whom Jesus had healed from the dreaded disease of leprosy. Lazarus, and his two sisters, Mary and Martha, were also there. It was an opportunity for those people that had received so many blessings from Jesus to show their gratitude to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 12:1-11 (Mary anoints Jesus)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Lazarus, Mary and Martha honor Jesus on this occasion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did Judas object to Mary’s offering to Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What insight does God’s Word give us about Judas’ objection?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today many people will say they won’t go to church because it is full of hypocrites. The example of Judas reminds us there will be hypocrites among God’s people. What can we learn from both Mary and Jesus when it comes to dealing with hypocrites in the church?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some ways that we can show Mary-like devotion to our Savior and Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to verses 10-11 how far were the wicked religious leaders willing to go to keep their position as Israel’s leaders?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 12:12-19 (The Palm Sunday procession)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All four of the gospels record the events of Palm Sunday, but John’s gospel is the shortest account of them, and the only account that mentions “palm” branches. The palms were an emblem of victory (Revelation 7:9), and the people sometimes carried and waved them at the feast of tabernacles (Leviticus 23:40). Now they spread them before Jesus and gave him a royal welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What were the people saying with each of these phrases?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hosanna” =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“in the name of the Lord” =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“King of Israel” =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“your king is coming, seated on a donkey’s colt” =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does verse 16 teach us about the way in which Christians gain their spiritual understanding of God’s Word and will?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you describe the reaction the Pharisees had to this large, public display of support for Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 12:20-36 (Jesus predicts his death)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event occurred sometime during the first part of Holy Week, when Jesus was in the temple courts. The Gentiles were always treated as outsiders by the Jews, and if they came to worship in Jerusalem they had to do so from a distance in the courtyard of the Gentiles. Perhaps these Gentiles approached Phillip because they were familiar with him (He has a Greek name). Isn’t it ironic in the same chapter Jesus is identified as the King of Israel that we see here the kingdom of God passing from the Jews (exclusively) to the Gentiles?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Gospel of John we hear Jesus say, “I tell you the truth” a total of 24 times. Doesn’t He always tell the truth? Of course. But when Jesus begins a teaching with that statement, it indicates that something very important is about to be said so we should listen carefully. It also means that he is about to correct some misunderstanding that people have about God. We may think we know the truth (because we have our own opinions), but Jesus now tells us the REAL truth, so that we can change our thinking and learn God’s ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus preached primarily to the Jews during his public ministry. What do verses 20-21 tell us about the effects of Jesus’ work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you explain Jesus’ parable in verse 24?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does a person hate his or her life in the way Jesus is talking about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What invitation, challenge and promise does Jesus make to us in verse 26?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What were the reasons for the Father speaking audibly from heaven in response to Jesus’ request that He glorify His name? (Verses 28-32)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where are the gospel messages in the following phrases?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Now is the time for judgment on this world.” =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Now the prince of this world will be driven out.” =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When I am lifted up from the earth …” =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I will draw all men to myself.” =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 12:37-50 (The Jews continue in their unbelief)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What explanation did John give concerning the unbelief of many of the Jews? (verses 37-40)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does God finally blind the eyes and deaden the hearts of those who reject him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does Jesus teach us about the relationship between God the Father and God the Son? (Verses 44-50)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verses 49-50 Jesus emphasized that he spoke everything his Father commanded him to say. What comforts does this truth bring to us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next lesson will take us to an upper room somewhere in Jerusalem where Jesus and his disciples celebrated the last Passover. Chapters 13 and 14 contain some of the most beautiful statements of Jesus. Enjoy the study. 
&lt;code&gt; &lt;/code&gt;PAGE 1&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 11 The Gospel of John, Chapters 13 and 14</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/11/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;_jesus-the-way-the-truth-and-the-life_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus: The Way, the Truth, and the Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of John alone records the foot washing, Jesus&#39; final words to the disciples, and his amazing prayer of intercession for all Christians in chapters 13-17.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All people are lost. All people are confused. All people are sorrowful. But they need not be. Jesus came to seek and save the lost. Jesus came to comfort them. Even Jesus&#39; disciples, during the night when he was betrayed, were confused and sorrowful. One could call these chapters, &lt;em&gt;The Learning Chapters&lt;/em&gt;, because of the many questions the disciples ask in them. Jesus has the answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are just like the disciples. Often we feel lost, confused and sorrowful. &amp;quot;Do not let your hearts be troubled.&amp;quot; Let us listen to Jesus: the Way, the Truth, and the Life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 13:1-17&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus washes the feet of his disciples)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The celebration of the Passover was about to begin. This would be the most special Passover for Jesus, his disciples, and for the whole world, for this was the hour that the Father had determined for his Son to redeem us. It was time for Jesus to fulfill His destiny. It was time for the cross, time for the suffering and death, and then returning to the Father. It was time to show the world the full extent of His love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before humbling himself even to death on a cross, Jesus would teach us all a lesson in humble service by taking the role of a servant and washing the feet of the guests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why was Peter at first reluctant to let Jesus wash his feet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Jesus mean when he said, &amp;quot;Unless I wash you, you have no part with me?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What lesson did Jesus teach his followers by his example of washing their feet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We follow his example by serving each other, visiting the sick, helping the poor, doing acts of kindness, volunteering, helping others in need. We were created not to be served, but to serve others. When we put our faith into practice and love and serve others, we are blessed because we are doing what God made us to do. Sometimes old people living in a nursing home just want to die because they no longer feel needed or useful. Everyone wants to be needed and useful. That&#39;s a blessing which gives purpose to our lives and makes us content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 13:18-30&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus predicts his betrayal)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did Jesus want his disciples to know in advance that one of them was about to betray him (see verse 19)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 26 it says that when Judas received the piece of bread, &amp;quot;Satan entered into him.&amp;quot; What does that mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 13:31-38&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus predicts Peter&#39;s denial)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did Jesus mean when he said, &amp;quot;Now is the Son of Man glorified and God is glorified in him?&amp;quot; (verse 31)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look closely at Jesus&#39; &amp;quot;new command&amp;quot; in verse 34. We might think, &amp;quot;But Lord, the command to love one another was certainly not new. Thousands of years earlier You gave commandments to Moses about how to treat other people that You summarized by saying, &amp;quot;Love your neighbor as yourself&amp;quot; (Matthew 22:39). Lord, how can you say that loving one another is a NEW COMMAND?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the sermon on the mount Jesus explains this for us. He said, &amp;quot;If you love those who love you, what credit is that to you? Even &#39;sinners&#39; love those who love them.And if you do good to those who are good to you, what credit is that to you? Even &#39;sinners&#39; do that.And if you lend to those from whom you expect repayment, what credit is that to you? Even &#39;sinners&#39; lend to &#39;sinners,&#39; expecting to be repaid in full.But love your enemies, do good to them, and lend to them without expecting to get anything back. Then your reward will be great, and you will be sons of the Most High, because he is kind to the ungrateful and wicked&amp;quot; (Luke 6:32-35).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old command was &amp;quot;Love your neighbor as yourself.&amp;quot; The new command is, &amp;quot;Love one another AS I HAVE LOVED YOU.&amp;quot; He is commanding a new KIND of love. the kind of unconditional and voluntary love which He has shown to us. The laws of Moses required love out of obedience. The love which Jesus is instructing us to show is a free and voluntary love, a love that is given unconditionally and simply motivated by His love for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unconditional love does not mean that we tolerate sin or approve of things that are wrong. It does, however, mean that we still love the sinner, even while rebuking sin and calling it out. We can show love to the homosexual person without condoning or approving of their sin. We can love the sinner and treat the sinner with kindness, while disapproving and rebuking the sin at the same time. The love that Jesus teaches us is different than the love the world knows and understands. It is not dependent upon another person&#39;s behavior, but upon a heart that is filled with love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how can we have a heart that is filled with love? The apostle John writes: &amp;quot;We love because he first loved us.&amp;quot; (1 John 4:19). We must experience the love of Jesus. He is the source of this new kind of love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This love is one of the marks of true Christian discipleship. Jesus says that others will know that we are his disciples when we show this kind of love (v. 35). This is because unconditional love is special and is rarely seen in the world outside of Christianity. In his first epistle, the apostle John writes that love for others is one of the tests for a true Christian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter Fourteen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 14 Jesus comforts his troubled disciples, preparing them for his suffering, death, and departure. Though the moment is near when he will drink the Father&#39;s bitter cup of wrath in payment for the world&#39;s sin, Jesus thinks of us and speaks words that will enable us to live in confidence as we face the challenges of living as a Christian. At the end of chapter 13, Jesus was speaking to Peter. But now he turns to address all of his disciples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 14:1-14&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus comforts his disciples)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 1 Jesus said, &amp;quot;Do not let your hearts be troubled.&amp;quot; What were some reasons why the disciples were so troubled that evening?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some things that trouble our hearts today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus was not speaking empty words of comfort. Because Jesus loved them, and they could trust His love, there is no need to worry or be afraid. He will make everything work out for the good of those who love him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agree or Disagree? It is impossible for anyone to get to heaven apart from saving faith in Jesus Christ. (Explain your answer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people will say, &amp;quot;It doesn&#39;t matter what a person believes, as long as he is sincere. All religions are just different ways to the same place.&amp;quot; This idea has been expressed so often that we may be tempted to think it is true. Wherever the idea originated, it did not originate with Jesus Christ. When the disciples asked him about the way to heaven, he replied, &amp;quot;I am the way.&amp;quot; Notice that Christ says, &amp;quot;I am THE way.&amp;quot; He does not say, &amp;quot;I am one of the ways,&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;I know the way,&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;I show the way.&amp;quot; No, Christ&#39;s idea about the road to heaven was definitely exclusive – &amp;quot;no other way but me!&amp;quot; Some people may not agree, but this is the clear teaching of Jesus and his apostles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter once told the Jewish leaders: &amp;quot;Salvation is found in no one else, for there is no other name under heaven given to men by which we must be saved&amp;quot; (Acts 4:12). Through the years people have sought other ways to heaven. The ancient Canaanites sacrificed their own children, and the Hindus tortured their own bodies, hoping that these things would appease the anger of their imaginary outraged gods, and smooth the way into a happy hereafter. And many people today look for the way to heaven in something they do, or say, or offer, or sacrifice. But these salvation‑by-character religions have only destroyed hope and bred fear. Forgiveness cannot be purchased. Only Christ can bridge the gulf between the holy God and the helpless sinner. Through his holy life, his innocent death, and his mighty resurrection, he has secured an eternal pardon for all. All other ways are simply dead-ends. Jesus alone is the way – the only way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, thank God, Christ is also an all-inclusive way. Any person can get to heaven through Christ. His way of salvation is universal: &amp;quot;Whoever comes to me, I will never drive away,&amp;quot; Jesus said (John 6:37). So, trust in Jesus alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 8 Philip makes a request that reveals a lack of understanding that Jesus had been showing (revealing) the Father to them all along. Because Jesus is God, whoever see and observes Jesus will be able to see what God is like. Jesus came down from heaven to reveal the Father to us. Through Jesus we can see and know God the Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 12 Jesus says that those who believe in him will do &amp;quot;even greater things&amp;quot; than the works that he had been doing. Can it really be possible that ordinary people, weak and sinful people like us, will do the same things and even greater things than the almighty, sinless Son of God? Yes, this is true, Jesus says. And He emphasizes this truth, perhaps because it is so hard for us to believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what great works are these that Jesus is thinking about? Building churches? Bringing the Gospel to more people all over the world? Suffering for the sake of the truth? Showing compassion and kindness and establishing institutions of mercy, healing, and education (such as hospitals and schools and universities) all over the world? Perhaps. &amp;quot;Even greater&amp;quot; can refer to the greater number of future believers they would win for the kingdom by proclaiming the Gospel through the power of the Holy Spirit. Jesus knew that only in His death and resurrection could He send the Holy Spirit that would enable the disciples to spread the message that would change the lives of millions of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 14:15-31&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus promises the Holy Spirit)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus would soon complete his mission and return to heaven. The gospel message of God&#39;s great love and amazing grace would be entrusted to his disciples. They would need power to witness in the face of great persecution. They would need guidance to remain in the truth. They would need a new heavenly Counselor who would help them in their mission of taking the gospel to the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Jesus promised to send them a special Helper who would be with them forever. That Helper is the Holy Spirit, whom Jesus calls the &amp;quot;Spirit of truth&amp;quot;. This is the first of many specific promises about the Holy Spirit that Jesus gave his disciples in the next few chapters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said the world cannot accept the Spirit. Why? See 1 Corinthians 2:14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What specific examples of this do we see today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 22 a disciple named &amp;quot;Judas&amp;quot; speaks. Actually, two of Jesus&#39; twelve apostles were named Judas. One of them was Judas Iscariot, who would betray Jesus. The other Judas was also called by the name Thaddaeus (Matthew 10:3). This is the Judas (not Judas Iscariot) who speaks here in John 14:22. He could not understand why Jesus would show himself to them, but not to the rest of the world. Remember that even the twelve disciples had some false expectations about the Messiah at this time. Like many others, they expected that Jesus would become a glorious earthly King who would bring a new era of peace and prosperity to Israel. The disciples still struggled to understand what kind of Messiah Jesus would be. Only when the Holy Spirit came upon them on the day of Pentecost did they fully understand who the Messiah would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Spirit would do two things: a) Remind them of all that Jesus had said; and b) Teach them all. Jesus is very gentle toward weak and floundering believers. That includes you and me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In John 14:26 Jesus says that the Father will send the Holy Spirit. (&amp;quot;But the Counselor, the Holy Spirit, whom the Father will send in my name, will teach you all things and will remind you of everything I have said to you.&amp;quot;) Then, in John 15:26 Jesus says that he will send them the Holy Spirit (&amp;quot;When the Counselor comes, whom I will send to you from the Father, the Spirit of truth who goes out from the Father, he will testify about me.&amp;quot;) So who will send the Holy Spirit – Jesus, or the Father? Actually, it is both. This is why Christians use the Nicene Creed and confess: &amp;quot;I believe in the Holy Spirit, the Lord and Giver of Life, who proceeds from the Father and the Son …&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In verse 28 Jesus said, &amp;quot;If you loved me, you would be glad that I am going to the Father …&amp;quot; Why should Jesus&#39; followers be glad he returned to the Father?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verses 29-31 Jesus is speaking to the disciples about his death and burial. As the disciples watched Jesus suffer and die and as they laid his lifeless body in the tomb, it might seem to them that the &amp;quot;prince of this world&amp;quot; (Satan) had taken hold of Jesus and defeated him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, Jesus told them, &amp;quot;The prince of this world … has no hold on me.&amp;quot; Although the suffering and crucifixion and burial of Jesus might make it seem that Jesus was weak and powerless against the forces of evil, Jesus wanted them to know that his suffering and death was not a sign of Satan&#39;s power, but of the power of Jesus&#39; love for the Father, and his desire to do the will of his Father. Jesus would not be under the control of Satan, but under the control of love for the Father and for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Our Lord had no weak spots for Satan to attack. He was holy, and his holy life would be sacrificed to save the world from sin.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next lesson will focus on the comforting words of Jesus in chapters 15 and 16. In those words he promises the Holy Spirit, and encourages us to do the works of God, even in times of persecution and trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 12 The Gospel of John, Chapters 15 and 16</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/12/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;_jesus-the-true-vine_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus: The true Vine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the requirements for salvation? Have they been met? Then why are we still here on earth? Why doesn&#39;t Jesus just take us to heaven the moment that we come to faith? These chapters remind us all why we are here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus would soon (in a matter of hours) be hung on the cross and put in the tomb. It is a confusing time for the disciples. They are like students who just can&#39;t understand a subject, even if the best teacher in the world is tutoring them. They need clarification. Jesus gives it to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 15:1-17&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus is the vine)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 1 contains the seventh and final &amp;quot;I am&amp;quot; statement of Jesus in the Gospel of John. Can you name some of them? (Light of the world, gate, good shepherd, bread of life, way, truth, life, resurrection and life, vine). Jesus called himself the &amp;quot;true vine.&amp;quot; In what ways is Jesus the &amp;quot;true vine?&amp;quot; You may wish to read Isaiah 5:1-7 and Ezekiel 19:10-14 as you prepare your answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these verses Jesus describes his heavenly Father as the gardener. He has planted us (created us) and attached us to Christ, the good vine. His intention is that we bear fruit (do good works). Our purpose and reason for existence is to be and do what God the gardener planted us to do by bearing the fruit of good works. But in order to make us more fruitful, he may find it necessary to prune us. What are some of the ways that the Father prunes us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the fruits that Jesus has in mind for us to bear? (see Galatians 5:22-23)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are good works optional in the Christian life? Explain your answer. (See verse 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does obeying our Lord&#39;s commands make our joy complete? (See verse 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between a servant and a friend? (See verses 12-15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 15:18-27&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus warns us about persecution)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was important for Jesus to speak with His disciples about the hatred of the unbelieving world and the persecution that they would experience as his disciples. Because the world hated Jesus, it will also hate Jesus&#39; followers. Why? It hates us because we are different. It hates us because we proclaim sin and grace. It hates us because we proclaim one truth, one way, one life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does the world today show this hatred?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does knowing the world hates Jesus and his followers apply to our approach to evangelism?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verses 22-24. In what way would the Jews have not been guilty of sin, had Jesus not come and spoken to them and done miracles for them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the work of the Holy Spirit according to verses 26-27?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 16:1-16&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(The work of the Holy Spirit)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 16 begins a focus on predictions. In chapter 14 Jesus&#39; words were words of comfort. In chapter 15 there were admonitions. Now this chapter contains many predictions. He begins by predicting persecution. He does this so that they would be prepared for the time when things would be hard. Second that they would know that He was still in control even when things were hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What types of sufferings did Jesus tell his followers they would face?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 7, Jesus says, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Unless I go away, the Counselor will not come to you.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; Why must Jesus go away in order for the Holy Spirit to come?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some ways in which the Holy Spirit convicts the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What were some of the factors why the disciples could not bear at this time to hear the additional things Jesus needed to tell them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some of the factors today that prevent people from knowing and understanding God&#39;s word and will?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 16:17-33&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus&#39; final words of comfort)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the two &amp;quot;little whiles&amp;quot; that Jesus speaks of in verse 16?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain the parable Jesus used in verse 21?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to this time, when the disciples needed something, they went to Jesus. In the future they would go directly to the Father. What change would occur that allowed this to happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next lesson we shall study the amazing prayer that Jesus prayed on the night before he died for us. In that prayer, recorded in chapter 17, Jesus prays for himself, his apostles, and all of us. Enjoy the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 14 The Gospel of John, Chapters 18 and 19</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/14/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;_jesus-the-king-of-the-jews_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus: The King of the Jews&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The humiliation and death of the Son of God is found in these most sacred chapters.  Jesus&#39; courage, dignity, obedience, concern for others, and unswerving faith in the Father shine brightly in this account. Jesus is clearly not a victim of circumstances over which He had no control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pilate had a notice prepared and fastened to the cross.  It read &amp;quot;JESUS OF NAZARETH, THE KING OF THE JEWS.&amp;quot;  This sign was written in three languages. The Jewish leaders wanted Pilate to change the sign, but he refused to yield. He was weak in his response to the truth but strong when it touched personal pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of his role in these chapters, Pilate&#39;s name in every age is a name of shame. What will our names be in the annals of eternity? Because of Jesus they will be blessed. The cross became His victory &amp;ndash;as well as ours&amp;ndash; since upon this instrument of torture; He triumphed over evil for all mankind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 18:1-11&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus is arrested)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Jesus finished praying he and his disciples left Jerusalem and went to the Garden of Gethsemane. John did not record the details of Jesus&#39; prayers and his discussions with his disciples in Gethsemane because it was already recorded in the other three gospels. John did not need to record what had been so beautifully recorded by the other evangelists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The betrayal of Jesus took place in the lovely garden of Gethsemane. Jesus had chosen this time and this place for the betrayal. It was no coincidence that this was the very same place that David had been betrayed by his friend Ahithophel. (see 2 Samuel 15:23, 30-31). As the &amp;quot;Son of David&amp;quot; and the everlasting King, Jesus would fulfill every Old Testament event that portrayed his life and ministry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even though Jesus was about to be arrested how did he display his complete control of the situation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter still did not understand the divine plan which required that Jesus suffer and die for the sin of the world. He was still trying to prevent that. Luke says that two disciples were bearing swords (Luke 22:38), probably because they felt it was dangerous in Jerusalem. In Luke 22:49 we read that they asked Jesus if they should use their swords to defend Him. Peter didn&#39;t wait for an answer. Though the other gospels record that an ear was cut off, only John records the names of the two people involved, Peter and Malchus, probably because by this time it was safe to identify Peter as the swordsman, and because John was an acquaintance of the high priest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter thought he was helping Jesus by drawing his sword. What did Jesus emphasize in his response to Peter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though Jesus would not allow Peter to defend him by drawing a sword, are there ways that we can stand up for Jesus and defend him when he is being attacked by his enemies today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 18:12-14 and 19-24&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus is taken for trial before Annas)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The soldiers bound Jesus and led him to Annas, the former high priest (AD 6-15) and the father-in-law of Caiaphas, the current high priest. Annas made his living by subtle forms of extortion. He practiced the fleecing of worshipers in the temple tax, the selling of animals, and the changing of coins. Jesus cleansed the temple twice, once at the beginning of His earthly ministry that we studied in John chapter 2 and the second time near the end.  When Jesus chased the moneychangers out of the temple He was hitting Annas and Caiaphas where it hurt, in their pocketbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;False witnesses twisted Jesus words at the trial before Annas (words Jesus spoke when cleansing the temple). &amp;quot;Destroy this temple and I will rebuild it again in three days&amp;quot; (John 2:19-21). That was a prediction of what would now be fulfilled for our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Jesus respond to the improper treatment he received from one of the court officials?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can we learn from Jesus&#39; example when we face opposition for being a follower of Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is not the only one on trial.  Each and every human being either stands with Jesus or with the world.  Is Jesus who He claimed to be or is He a liar?  The trial goes on every day when God&#39;s truth is proclaimed. People either reject Jesus or praise Him as Lord through God&#39;s gift of faith worked by His word. The verdict rendered has eternal consequences for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 18:15-18 and 25-27&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Peter&#39;s denials of Jesus)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter had followed those who arrested Jesus to see what would happen. In order to get as close as possible, he even gained entrance into the courtyard of the palace of the high priest. Here his faith would be put to the test. How far did Peter fall? All the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter had once boldly promised he would never disown Jesus even if everyone else did. (&amp;quot;Even if all fall away on account of you, I never will&amp;quot; – Matthew 26:33). What poor judgment did Peter now show in the courtyard of the high priest?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus once told Peter, &amp;quot;Simon, Simon, Satan has asked to sift you as wheat. But I have prayed for you, Simon, that your faith may not fail. And when you have turned back, strengthen your brothers&amp;quot; (Luke 22:31–32). Now, in the courtyard, around the fire, Satan was attacking Peter. First, Satan surrounded Peter with Christ&#39;s enemies. Second, Satan isolated Peter from the support of other Christians. How does Satan use similar tactics when he attacks us today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter denied Jesus when his faith was put to the test. Satan constantly tries to make us do the same thing. This event teaches us that we walk in danger all the way. None of us, no matter how determined we might be, are immune from spiritual failure. Satan knows our weaknesses. and we have many. As the apostle said, &amp;quot;If you think you are standing firm, be careful that you don&#39;t fall.&amp;quot; (1 Corinthians 10:12).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must be aware of the tactics that Satan uses to &amp;quot;sift&amp;quot; us and make us fall. We must be diligent in watching and praying, as Jesus said, and faithful in making use of the gospel through which the Holy Spirit will strengthen and keep us in the true faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the grace of God, Peter was called back to repentance and Jesus gave him another opportunity to be his witness. Peter later became one of the leaders of the early Christian church, and it is said that he eventually died a martyr&#39;s death in Rome, faithful to the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 18:28-40&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus trial by Pontius Pilate)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the conversation between the Jewish leaders and Pilate. What statements make it clear the Jews had no interest in a fair trial of Jesus (v. 30)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Pilate asked Jesus if he were a king what truths did Jesus teach the governor (v. 36)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pilate responded to Jesus with the question, &amp;quot;What is truth?&amp;quot; What did he mean by that? (Choose one of the answers below and explain why you chose that answer.)
a. He meant, &amp;quot;It is not easy to determine what is truth.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. He meant, &amp;quot;What does truth matter?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 19:1-16&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus is sentenced to be crucified)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prophet Isaiah (53:5) once wrote of the Messiah: &amp;quot;But he was pierced for our transgressions, he was crushed for our iniquities; the punishment that brought us peace was upon him, and by his wounds we are healed.&amp;quot; What painful and humiliating tortures did the Romans inflict on Jesus in verses 1 and 2?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pilate hoped to satisfy the desire of the Jews to have Jesus punished and suffer. Pilate already recognized that Jesus was innocent (v.4), and so he was hoping that these beatings would satisfy the Jews and he would not have to condemn Jesus to die. This was another strategy to avoid the issue, and it did not work either. Notice how many times Pilate pronounced Jesus innocent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18:38 = &amp;quot;I find no basis for a charge against him.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;19:4 = &amp;quot;I find no basis for a charge against him.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;19:6 = &amp;quot;I find no basis for a charge against him.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even an unbiased observer could tell that Jesus was an innocent man. What does it mean that He was innocent of all the charges?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the Jews said that Jesus had broken &amp;quot;their law&amp;quot;: &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;We have a law, and according to that law he must die, because he claimed to be the Son of God.&amp;quot; (John 19:7).&lt;/em&gt; The law they were referring to was written in Leviticus 24:16 – &amp;quot;Anyone who blasphemes the name of the Lord must be put to death. The entire assembly must stone him.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now they are finally coming forward with the real charge against Jesus. All of the other charges were just made up, but this was their big concern. They had been accusing Jesus of blasphemy for a couple of years now, concluding that He must die, &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;because he claimed to be the Son of God.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; That&#39;s exactly what they had said a year earlier &amp;ndash; &amp;quot;We are not stoning you for any of these,&amp;quot; replied the Jews, &amp;quot;but for blasphemy, because you, a mere man, claim to be God&amp;quot; (John 10:33).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were right in understanding Jesus&#39; claims. He did claim to be the Son of God. But they didn&#39;t understand what that meant. If Jesus were indeed a &amp;quot;mere man&amp;quot; His death would have been unnecessary, and a miscarriage of justice. But precisely because Jesus is the Son of God, He had to die. Do you agree? Why or why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus was unfairly declared guilty and sentenced to death. Why should Christians not be surprised when we sometimes receive unfair treatment from secular governments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 19:17-27&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus is crucified for the sin of the world)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The place where Jesus was crucified had been given the nickname &amp;quot;Place of the Skull&amp;quot; perhaps because of the executions that were carried out there, or perhaps the place looked something like a skull. In Aramaic, the name of the place was &amp;quot;Golgotha.&amp;quot; The Latin term for the place was &amp;quot;Calvary.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There on Calvary, Jesus was put in a group of three, and was placed between two notorious criminals. The implication was that Jesus was a criminal also. Guilt by association. Jesus among the sinners. That&#39;s kind of how it was for most of His ministry. His critics always complained about the company that He hung around with tax collector&#39;s and sinners. Now that was literally true. He was hanging with the sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was in keeping with God&#39;s plan. The prophet Isaiah had written: &amp;quot;He poured out his life unto death, and was numbered with the transgressors. For he bore the sin of many, and made intercession for the transgressors&amp;quot; (Isaiah 53:12).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aren&#39;t you glad that Jesus was numbered with the transgressors? Just as in life, also in death He was willing to be associated with sinners, because that means that He is not ashamed to be associated with us. During his life Jesus had a reputation for being a friend of sinners. He ate with the despised tax collectors and spoke with the outcasts of society with whom the &amp;quot;righteous&amp;quot; members of society would have anything to do. Over and over they labeled Jesus as a &amp;quot;friend of tax collectors and sinners.&amp;quot; And so it was even in his death. He was numbered with them, willing to befriend them, willing to die for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn&#39;t that make you glad to think about this? No matter how messed up your life has been, no matter how often you have strayed from the truth and from what is right, Jesus is not ashamed of you. He comes to eat with you, and even die for you, because he is a friend of sinners. He is the hope of sinners. He is the Savior of sinners. He is your friend, hope, and Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why would Pilate write the notice &amp;quot;Jesus of Nazareth, The King of the Jews&amp;quot; in Aramaic, Latin and Greek?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was no accident that the identification of Him who was being crucified for the sin of the world should be written in every language used in the Mediterranean world. This was not only Pilate&#39;s idea, but God&#39;s. Here was a prophecy that the message of the cross should be proclaimed everywhere and include people of every language, culture and race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pilate may have intended the message of that sign to be a cruel joke, a mocking rebuke of the claims of this pitiful man. But what Pilate proclaimed in jest has become a living truth &amp;ndash; the truth that Jesus is King, the King who is worthy to be crowned not with thorns but with many crowns, the King of love and mercy, the King at whose precious name every knee will bow in sorrow over sin and acknowledgment of deity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the significance of the soldiers taking Jesus&#39; clothes and dividing them among themselves?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the soldiers thought that they would be able to profit a little from Jesus&#39; crucifixion. As far as they were concerned, the only thing that they could get from His death was a blood-stained shirt or worn out sandals. But you and I have profited much more from the crucifixion of Jesus Christ. He did not leave us with clothes, but with grace and forgiveness and peace and joy – things that money cannot purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the cross Jesus was surrounded by enemies. The soldiers who nailed Him and gambled for His clothing. Mockers, who ridiculed His claims and taunted Him. But finally, after several hours, a few friends courageously faced the danger and approached the cross. It was only five people, but what a comfort it must have been for Jesus to see His mother and some dear friends – his spiritual family &amp;ndash; near His cross!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of them was his dear friend, John, one of the twelve apostles. What a relief it is to hear that! The last we heard of the disciples was that they all deserted him and fled when Jesus was arrested in the Garden of Gethsemane. Now we hear that John was at the foot of the cross. It&#39;s good to know that he was there. Through him, we have an eye-witness account of what happened and what Jesus said that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also read that Jesus&#39; mother Mary was there, watching her Son suffer and die on the cross, helpless to do anything to save Him, or even to lessen His pain. What must have gone through her mind during those hours of her Son&#39;s crucifixion? Perhaps she recalled the words of old Simeon that day in the temple a little over thirty years earlier: &amp;quot;This child is destined to cause the falling and rising of many in Israel, and to be a sign that will be spoken against, and a sword will pierce your own soul too.&amp;quot; (Luke 2:35).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What lesson did Jesus teach us by providing for the care of his mother from the cross?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 19:28-37&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus dies for us)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While he was being crucified, Jesus spoke seven times. The last words of a dying man are always important, but these seven last words of Jesus as he was dying, are even more precious to us. Two of those last sayings are recorded in these verses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;_ &lt;strong&gt;I am thirsty&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; _ (v. 28)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give two reasons why Jesus said this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you remember when, in the Garden of Gethsemane, Peter drew his sword to defend Jesus against the arrest party? Jesus stopped Peter and told him, &amp;quot;Put your sword away! Shall I not drink the cup the Father has given me?&amp;quot; (John 18:11) This drink that God the Father had given Him was the cup of God&#39;s wrath, His anger over sin. This drink was the divine punishment for every lie and half-truth, every selfish act, every thoughtless word, every greedy lust, every unholy desire that had been thought, said or done by you and me and every sinner since the history of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In His incredible mercy, a mercy which we shall never fully comprehend or appreciate this side of eternity, God had given this cup filled with the fury of His anger not to us to have to drink, but to His own innocent Son! Amazing grace!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not until all things were accomplished, not until the cup of God&#39;s wrath had been completely drained, not until every one of my sins and your sins, and the sins of the entire world had been fully paid by His suffering, did Jesus seek relief for His thirst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;_ &lt;strong&gt;It is finished.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; _ (v. 30)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Jesus said this, what was finished?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Jesus has finished the work of redemption, it would be a waste of time to try to add anything. There is nothing left that we need to do, nothing left that we need to add. All is finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Son of God has done everything that was needed. The redemption of your soul, and the payment of our sin is finished. This cry from the cross raises us above the uncertainty that plagues the world, who hope that they will get to heaven, but can never be sure. It is not the teaching of the Bible that we must meet God halfway or even a little part of the way. Salvation is not made up of 50% of Jesus&#39; suffering and 50% of our own good works and good intentions. The proportion is not even 99% Christ and 1% us. Christ is everything. He has finished what was needed. He paid 100%. With his dying breath He testifies that nothing needs to be added to what He has already done in order to bring you to heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Gospel that the Savior sends us to proclaim, there are no question marks. We proclaim an accomplished fact. We preach a Gospel of full redemption. We do not add any conditions. Christ has paid for all your guilt. Believe it. Proclaim it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The death of Jesus occurred at about 3:00pm in the afternoon on Friday. In the Jewish way of reckoning time, the new day, the Passover Sabbath, was about to begin at 6:00pm. The law of Moses in Deuteronomy 21:22-23 stated that no body was to be left hanging overnight or it would defile the land. Therefore the Jewish authorities were in a hurry to have the bodies of the crucified men removed from the crosses and placed into a grave before the Sabbath would begin. There was not much time to get the bodies into a tomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, because time was short, the soldiers began to break the legs of those hanging on the crosses in order to hasten their death. But it was important that Jesus&#39; legs were not broken, but rather that they pierced his side with a spear. Why? Because of two Old Testament prophecies. One prophecy said, &amp;quot;Not one of [his bones] will be broken&amp;quot; (Psalm 34:20). What was true of all of the Passover lambs was also true of the Lamb of God who takes away the sin of the world. The other prophecy stated that the people would look at the one they had pierced: &amp;quot;They will look on me, the one they have pierced&amp;hellip;&amp;quot; (Zechariah 12:10).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 19:38-42&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus is buried)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section concludes the humiliation of our Lord but there is a hint of His exaltation as well. Jesus would not be left exposed to the world, uncovered, or heaped up with the common criminals in an unmarked grave. Yes, all His belongings were gone&amp;ndash; even His clothing. But in this borrowed grave we see hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do we admire about Joseph and Nicodemus, the two men who buried Jesus, and what sad fact is revealed about them in this section?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt; : In the creed we confess: &amp;quot;I believe in Jesus Christ… suffered under Pontius Pilate, was crucified, died and was buried.&amp;quot; It is sad to hear that Joseph and Nicodemus were secret disciples of Jesus, afraid to let others know that they were Christians. They could have defended Jesus at His trial. They could have let their light of faith shine and confessed Jesus as their Savior and Lord. Don&#39;t be secret disciples of Jesus. Don&#39;t be ashamed to speak about Him, and show your love for Him. Don&#39;t feel em­barrassed about going to church. Don&#39;t be afraid to live like a believer. Don&#39;t be a disciple in secret. Don&#39;t wait, like Joseph and Nicodemus did, to let it be known that you have faith in Christ. This world needs the Christian witness that only we can give to it. May God help us to show the courage and love for Christ now so that men may come to faith in Him through our witness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our next lesson, we shall rejoice in the great truth of the third day, &amp;quot;He is risen, just as he said.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 15 The Gospel of John, Chapters 20 and 21</title>
      <link>/en/courses/109/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/109/15/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;_jesus-the-risen-lord_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus: The Risen Lord&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that you wanted to invent the story of Jesus&#39; rising from the dead. Who would you &amp;quot;pencil in&amp;quot; as the first person to see Jesus alive again? How would you write up the reaction of the disciples to the news that Jesus had risen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final chapters of John&#39;s Gospel record a touching account of the way in which Jesus gently assured His followers of his ultimate victory. In their sorrow and confusion, they struggled with the whole idea of Jesus coming back to life again. Many were slow to accept the fact of the resurrection, despite Jesus&#39; repeated appearances to them (see the chart below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we read the wondrous story of the most amazing event in all of history. The founder of every other world religion is dead (Moses, Confucius, Mohammed, etc.). But our Lord is alive, and he lives to assure us of our own life after death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;the-eleven-resurrection-appearances&#34;&gt;The Eleven Resurrection Appearances&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;in-chronological-order&#34;&gt;In chronological order&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early Sunday morning: Jesus appears to Mary Magdalene, Joanna, and other women (Matt 28:8-10 and Luke 2410)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early Sunday morning: Jesus appears to Mary Magdalene alone (John 20:11-17)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometime on Sunday (afternoon?): Jesus appears to two disciples on the road to Emmaus (Luke 24:13-32)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometime on Sunday: Jesus appears to Peter (Luke 24:34, 1 Cor. 15:5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suppertime Easter day: Jesus appears to ten disciples in Jerusalem (John 20:19ff)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A week after Easter: Jesus appears to eleven disciples in Jerusalem (John 20:26ff)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometime later: Jesus appears to seven disciples at the Sea of Galilee (John 21:1-14)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometime later: Jesus appears to eleven disciples on a mountain in Galilee (Matthew 28:16-20)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometime later: Jesus appears to James (1 Cor. 15:7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometime later: Jesus appears to five hundred disciples at once (1 Cor. 15:6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forty days after Easter: Jesus appears to the disciples somewhere in Jerusalem, and leads them to the Mt of Olives, where he blesses them and ascends (Acts 1:3-12)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 20:1-18&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus is risen indeed)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to this chapter, who was the first one to …&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go inside the empty tomb (verse 6)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Believe that Jesus had risen (verse 8)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See the risen Savior (verse 14)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do the disciples&#39; findings at the tomb support our faith?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 9 tells us: &amp;quot;They still did not understand from Scripture that Jesus had to rise from the dead.&amp;quot; What are those Old Testament Scriptures that had predicted the resurrection of Jesus? Let&#39;s look them up. Here are a few:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psalm 16:10-11 &amp;ndash; &amp;quot;You will not abandon me to the grave, nor will you let your Holy One see decay. You have made known to me the path of life…&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Job 19:23-25 – &amp;quot;Oh, that my words were recorded, that they were written on a scroll, that they were inscribed with an iron tool on lead, or engraved in rock forever! I know that my Redeemer lives, and that in the end he will stand upon the earth.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Isaiah 53:11-12 &amp;ndash; &amp;quot;After the suffering of his soul, he will see the light of life and be satisfied; by his knowledge my righteous servant will justify many, and he will bear their iniquities. Therefore I will give him a portion among the great, and he will divide the spoils with the strong, because he poured out his life unto death, and was numbered with the transgressors. For he bore the sin of many, and made intercession for the transgressors.&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to those Scriptures, Jesus had also told them on several occasions that he would rise on the third day. Consider what Jesus had said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;He then began to teach them that the Son of Man must suffer many things and be rejected by the elders, chief priests and teachers of the law, and that he must be killed and after three days rise again.&amp;quot; (Mark 8:31)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;From that time on Jesus began to explain to his disciples that he must go to Jerusalem and suffer many things at the hands of the elders, chief priests and teachers of the law, and that he must be killed and on the third day be raised to life.&amp;quot; (Matthew 16:21)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;When they came together in Galilee, he said to them, &amp;quot;The Son of Man is going to be betrayed into the hands of men.&amp;quot; (Matthew 17:22)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;And he said, &amp;quot;The Son of Man must suffer many things and be rejected by the elders, chief priests and teachers of the law, and he must be killed and on the third day be raised to life.&amp;quot;&amp;quot; (Luke 9:22)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Jesus answered them, &amp;quot;Destroy this temple, and I will raise it again in three days.&amp;quot;&amp;quot; (John 2:19)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;He answered, &amp;quot;A wicked and adulterous generation asks for a miraculous sign! But none will be given it except the sign of the prophet Jonah. For as Jonah was three days and three nights in the belly of a huge fish, so the Son of Man will be three days and three nights in the heart of the earth.&amp;quot; (Matthew 12:39–40)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;A wicked and adulterous generation looks for a miraculous sign, but none will be given it except the sign of Jonah.&amp;quot; Jesus then left them and went away.&amp;quot; (Matthew 16:4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;The reason my Father loves me is that I lay down my life—only to take it up again. No one takes it from me, but I lay it down of my own accord. I have authority to lay it down and authority to take it up again. This command I received from my Father.&amp;quot;&amp;quot; (John 10:17–18)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could nearly everyone have forgotten about Jesus&#39; prophecies about his resurrection?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary knew Jesus very well. In verse 14 we read that she did not recognize Jesus at first. In fact, everyone seemed to have a hard time recognizing Jesus after his resurrection. (Mary, here; the two men on way to Emmaus in Luke 24:16; the eleven disciples in Luke 24:37). Why was this? Here are five possibilities. Which one do you prefer and why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus&#39; face was partially obscured by a head covering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were crying so much, their vision was blurry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus&#39; appearance was slightly changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were so convinced that Jesus was dead, they refused to believe it was Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God kept people from recognizing him immediately (Luke 24:16).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 20:19-31&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus appears to his disciples)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the disciples felt a bit like fools after the crucifixion of Jesus. They had believed that He was the long-awaited Messiah, the mighty Son of God who would rule the world. They had seen Him do many miracles, and they were believers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had heard others judge Jesus to be a deceiver or a lunatic, like someone possessed by demons. But not them. They were true believers. But now Jesus was dead. Truly dead. They knew where He was buried. Their hopes were shattered. The rug had been pulled out from under their faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then the women came and said that they had seen the dead Jesus alive again on Easter morning. &amp;quot;We have seen the Lord!&amp;quot; they reported with great excitement. But the disciples would not be so easily convinced this time. Luke reports of them, &amp;quot;They did not believe the women, because their words seemed to them like nonsense&amp;quot; (Luke 24:11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when Jesus appeared to them also on that first Easter, Luke says that they were &amp;quot;thinking they saw a ghost&amp;quot; (Luke 24:37). They were not fools. They were not gullible. Only after they watched Jesus eat some food in front of them did they accept that He was alive again, and that they were not seeing ghosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are you glad that the disciples doubted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What important work did Jesus give his disciples as their ongoing mission (verse 23)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Lord Jesus gave to his followers the authority to announce forgiveness of sins in his name. When are we to withhold this announcement of forgiveness? (see Luke 17:3-4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Thomas missed Easter. He wasn&#39;t with the others on Easter evening, and when they told him, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;We have seen the Lord!&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; He refused to believe. He wanted to see for himself. But it&#39;s significant that Thomas didn&#39;t say, &amp;quot;Unless I see Jesus in person and watch him eat a piece of fish too, I won&#39;t believe.&amp;quot; Instead, he wanted more. He wanted to see the place where the nails had pierced Jesus&#39; hands and feet, and the hole left by the spear thrust into His side. He wanted to see the proof that Jesus had died for him. He wanted to see … the marks of love, God&#39;s love for him and for the sinners of this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know about you, but I am so happy that Thomas asked to see that. He didn&#39;t ask to touch Jesus&#39; hair or to hear Jesus speak. He wanted to see the nail holes, the proof of Jesus&#39; suffering and death, the marks of God&#39;s grace and love for sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those marks are heavenly assurance. They teach us that Jesus has taken away our guilt forever; that He offers us a completed redemption, with nothing required for your salvation left undone or unpaid. The traces of these four wounds are God&#39;s guarantee to you of the full, free redemption which tells all sinners, &amp;quot;By grace you are saved, through faith.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can have doubts about many things. You can be skeptical about offers that are too good to be true. But let there be no more doubts about one thing: God Himself has suffered for your sin, and it has been fully paid. The holes are there. The marks of love. And the One that sin killed is alive, and He has shown Thomas and every skeptic the proof of His grace and power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 30 what important insights does John give us into Jesus miracles?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to verse 31 what is the great purpose of the Gospel of John?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 21:1-14&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus appears at the Sea of Galilee)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Matthew 26:32 Jesus promised to meet his disciples in Galilee after he rose from the dead: &amp;quot;But after I have risen, I will go ahead of you into Galilee.&amp;quot; On Easter morning, the angel reminded the disciples of this promise when he told the women: &amp;quot;Go quickly and tell his disciples: He has risen from the dead and is going ahead of you into Galilee. There you will see him.&amp;quot; (Matthew 28:7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, in keeping with his promise to them, Jesus appears to them by the Sea of Tiberias, also known as the Sea of Galilee (see John 6:1). It was there that Jesus first met and called many of His disciples. Now they all meet again back at the first location, probably near the northern shore of the sea where Peter, James and John had once held a fishing business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A total of seven of the remaining eleven are mentioned here. They were Peter, Thomas, Nathanael, James, John, and two unnamed disciples. It&#39;s suggested the reason the Holy Spirit names only five of the seven fishermen in the boat is so you and I can take our seat as the unnamed two. Matthew does not record or mention this occasion, so it is possible that he was one of the missing disciples. The whereabouts of the other 4 is not mentioned. Judas Iscariot, of course, was dead. Why were these seven at the Sea of Galilee? They were told that they would see Jesus there. So they went to Galilee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do you think the disciples didn&#39;t recognize Jesus when he first appeared to them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stranger on the beach seemed to know them. &amp;quot;Friends,&amp;quot; He called them. Actually, the Greek word is not exactly &amp;quot;friends.&amp;quot; It is the Greek word for &amp;quot;children&amp;quot; (paideia). The Man on the beach called them His &amp;quot;children&amp;quot; or, we might also say, His &amp;quot;boys.&amp;quot; Maybe the disciples wondered about what the Man on the beach called them. Maybe they even asked each other, &amp;quot;Isn&#39;t it a little weird for a stranger to call us His &amp;quot;children&amp;quot; and be concerned whether or not we&#39;ve got anything to eat?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this word Jesus used was a subtle clue that He wasn&#39;t mad at them. He did not come to judge them. This was a sign to them that even though they may have failed Him, they had nothing to fear. And this is so important for us to hear. Though we understand how often we have failed Him, we have nothing to fear. He loves us in spite of our sin. If we are believers, He has already forgiven us. Though we may be prodigal sons and daughters, we are still His children, His lads, His boys and girls, His precious and loved sons and daughters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their lack of success would mean that they would have nothing to eat that day. All their efforts resulted in failure to provide their daily bread. Jesus asked His question in verse 5 not just to rub it in that they were failures at fishing, but to teach them where their food would come from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In verse 6 Jesus gave the disciples what probably seemed like pointless instructions. Jesus told them, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Throw your net on the right side of the boat and you will find some.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; Why &amp;quot;right side&amp;quot;? Was this saying that they had been fishing on the &amp;quot;wrong side&amp;quot;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This incident sounds very much like that catch of fish recorded in Luke 5. It was a little over three years earlier, after a long day of fishing and catching nothing that a Stranger on the beach told them to push back out into the deep and throw down their nets. When they did, they caught so many fish that they could not haul them in and the nets began to break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point in both cases: We will only be successful when we do what the Lord says. We may think we know better than Jesus. We may be pretty good and experienced at what we do, and we may think that the only good way is our own way. But if Jesus tells us to do something, even if it seems odd to us, then we must do it His way to be successful. Many times in life the commands of the Lord may seem foolish. But faithful obedience leads to carrying out His will and then we are astounded at what He accomplishes through us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the large fish were taken out of the net and counted, there were 153. What was the significance of the number 153? Here are four choices. Which one do you prefer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It shows that this was such a large and impressive catch, that even years later they could still remember the exact number off fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It simply is saying that the number of fish caught was very large and impressive. It wasn&#39;t just a few fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number represents a record number of fish for a single catch. It was so many fish that they even took the time to count the exact number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exact number is recorded by John as a way of saying that this was not something they were making up. Even this little detail was recorded to show that the story was real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disciples had caught nothing and had nothing for breakfast. How did Jesus show his concern for his disciple&#39;s earthly needs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this account tell us about Jesus&#39; concern for the earthly needs of all his followers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 14 we read: &amp;quot;This was now the third time Jesus appeared to his disciples after he was raised from the dead.&amp;quot; Though this was now the seventh appearance of Jesus to someone after His resurrection (see the list of appearances at the beginning of this lesson), when John says that it was &amp;quot;the third time&amp;quot; (20:14), he was only counting the other two appearances at which he himself saw Jesus along with a group of disciples. The first time was on Easter evening in the locked room, without Thomas (John 20:19ff); the second time was a week later with Thomas (John 20:24ff).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why all these appearances? There were many reasons. First of all, He wanted them to be sure that He was risen so that they would never doubt it, even when faced with threats and strong opposition. Secondly, He wanted to teach them. He wanted them to know that they were forgiven, even after they had denied and deserted Him. He wanted them to know that He still loved them and that He still wanted them to be His witnesses to all the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first miracle that Jesus did after the resurrection. By doing so, He convinced the disciples one more time that He was alive and well, and that He could do anything that He could do before. The disciples knew it was the Lord by the miracles, and the marks of the nails in His hands and feet. All the signs were right before them. He was still true God and true man. He was their friend, and they were His children. He who died for them, was alive for them. They didn&#39;t have to ask. They knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read John 21:15-25&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Jesus restores Peter)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After breakfast on the beach, Jesus singled out Peter, and began to question Peter&#39;s love for him. And why not? Just a couple of weeks earlier Peter had sworn complete allegiance to his Lord, only to publicly deny a short time later with curses and swearing that he had ever heard of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon, do you truly love me more than these?&amp;quot; Peter surely must have recalled how he had told Jesus that he loved him more than the other disciples, and that even if the other disciples would forsake him, he never would. There in the courtyard of the high priest, Peter failed to admit his love for Jesus. Maybe he was too embarrassed. Certainly, he was afraid. But Jesus was giving him another chance. &amp;quot;Say it now, Peter. Say it in front of these men. Say that you truly love me.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many times hasn&#39;t the Lord given us a new chance to declare our love for Him? How many times haven&#39;t we been influenced or even intimidated by the unbelieving world around us into acting like we didn&#39;t know Jesus? How many times haven&#39;t we tried to talk and act like we were just like everyone else? How many times haven&#39;t we sworn and cursed, and walked around like we aren&#39;t disciples of Jesus? Then, ashamed of how we behaved, and repenting of it, haven&#39;t we thought, &amp;quot;Lord, if you only give me another chance, I won&#39;t behave like that again. Lord, if you only give me another chance, I will do better and show my love for you.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Jesus mean when He told Peter: &amp;quot;Feed my lambs … feed my sheep?&amp;quot; (verses 15-16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus reinstated Peter. But what did Jesus make clear would one day happen to Peter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord appeared to those disciples and gave them convincing proofs that He is truly Divine, that He rose again on the third day, just as He said, and that He has conquered death and the grave for us. Now those eyewitnesses, the skeptics who had to be convinced themselves, the ones who were so slow to believe, but who saw the marks of love and touched the risen Savior, have recorded what happened so that all of us who were not there may know and believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the verses immediately following our text, John, who was there, says: &amp;quot;Jesus did many other miraculous signs in the presence of his disciples, which are not recorded in this book.But these are written that you may believe that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of God, and that by believing you may have life in his name&amp;quot; (John 20:30-31).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter, who also was there, wrote: &amp;quot;We did not follow cleverly invented stories when we told you about the power and coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, but we were eyewitnesses of his majesty&amp;quot; (2 Peter 1:16).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, John wrote: &amp;quot;That which we have heard, which we have seen with our eyes, which we have looked at and our hands have touched—this we proclaim concerning the Word of life&amp;quot; (1 John 1:1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke notes: &amp;quot;After his suffering, he showed himself to these men and gave many convincing proofs that he was alive&amp;quot; (Acts 1:3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For forty days, appearing to hundreds of people, Jesus removed all doubts. Those men and women, so slow to believe, so hard to be convinced, had no more doubts. No threats or persecution could stop or change their testimony. Jesus is Lord and God. He has died for the sin of the world. He has risen on the third day as He said, and one day He will come again to raise us and take us to Himself in heavenly glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, no more doubts. It is a fact. Believe, and in believing you will be blessed with eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resurrection of a human body is a hard thing to accept. And we don&#39;t want to be fools. We don&#39;t want to be gullible. We can have doubts about many things, and we may be fooled by people and their claims. But we know two things for sure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God&#39;s Son died and paid for our sins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God&#39;s Son rose and defeated death for us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have read the testimony of John, an eyewitness of the life and teaching of Jesus Christ. He has written these things so that we may believe in Jesus as our promised Savior, and the redeemer of our souls. May God grant you this faith and keep you in it all the days of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A final exam will be available for those who would like to review this gospel and for those who wish to receive credit for this course. Ask your instructor if you would like to take this exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God bless you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pastor Robert O. Balza&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
