<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>恩典圣经学院 – 诠释圣经</title>
    <link>/zh-cn/courses/206/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 诠释圣经 on 恩典圣经学院</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:41:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/zh-cn/courses/206/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第一课(lesson 1) “诠释” —如何理解《圣经》</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/206/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/206/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第一课(lesson #1) “诠释” —如何理解《圣经》&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INTERPRETING THE BIBLE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诠释圣经&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Interpretation”-understanding what the Bible means&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“诠释”-如何理解《圣经》&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Context is very important in understanding what a Bible verse means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上下文对于理解圣经中的字句是非常重要的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we are going to understand correctly what a particular Bible verse means, we need to read not only the verse, but the entire chapter, and sometimes the entire book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;假如我们要正确地理解圣经中某一处字句的意思，我们不仅需要阅读该处的字句，而且还需要阅读该字句的整章经文，有时候甚至是阅读整本书卷。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples. . .例子：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should try to learn what the original writer of a Bible verse was trying to say to the original reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们应该尽量获悉，该处字句的原作者想对当初的第一读者表达什么样的意思。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we study a portion of the Bible we should examine who wrote it, when, for what purpose, to what people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们学习圣经的某处经文时，我们应该查考是谁写的，什么时候写的，出于什么样的目的，写给哪些人们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples. . .例子：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAYS=MEANS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;言说＝意义&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should assume that what a Bible verse says, it means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们应该假设某一节经文所言说的正是它的意思所在。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we try to learn what the original writer meant, we have several ‘gaps’ to overcome. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们试着查考圣经原作者的本意时，我们需要超越一些‘差距’……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language 语言&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Culture 文化&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spiritual 灵性的&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: 1 Corinthians 1:18-25 ; 1 Corinthians 2:14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;参考：林前1：18-25 ; 林前2：14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NO ONE CAN READ THE BIBLE WITH A ‘NEUTRAL’ ATTITUDE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;没有一个人能够带着一种‘中立的’态度来阅读圣经&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. As Christians, we read the Bible with the understanding that CHRIST IS THE CENTER AND MOST IMPORTANT PERSON IN THE BIBLE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A.作为基督徒，我们带着一种对基督是圣经的中心、也是圣经最重要的人物的理解来阅读圣经。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: John 5:39 ; Luke 24:27 ; 1 Corinthians 2:2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;参考：约 5：39 ; 路 24：27 ; 林前 2：2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. As Christians we read the Bible, believing that the Holy Spirit has INSPIRED every word in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. 作为基督徒，我们阅读圣经，并且相信圣灵已经默示圣经的每一句话。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: 2 Peter 1:21 ; Hebrews 1:1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;参考:彼后1：21 ; 来 1：1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we study the Bible, we should remember that it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们查考圣经时，我们应该记住的是：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A very old book 圣经是一本很古老的书&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A record of history 圣经是对历史的记录&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A book of different kinds of literature 圣经是一本有着不同文学类型的书&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God’s book 圣经是上帝的书&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第二课(lesson 2) 规则一—只有圣经中的经卷是上帝的话语</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/206/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/206/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;There are 6 rules for interpreting the Bible correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;正确解释圣经的六个规则&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule #1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;规则一&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONLY THE BOOKS IN THE BIBLE ARE GOD’S WORD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;只有圣经中的经卷是上帝的话语&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;替代文本 How do we know this for sure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们如何确实知道这一规则？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: Hebrews 4:12 ； Luke 24:32 ； John 6:63 ； John 17:17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;参考：来 4：12 ； 路 24：32 ； 约 6：63 ； 约 17：17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know for sure that the books of the Bible are God’s Word because. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们确实知道圣经中的经卷是上帝的话语，是因为……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: Luke 24:24 ； John 10:35 ； 2 Timothy 3:16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;参考：路 24：24 ； 约 10：35 ； 提后 3：16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know for sure that the books of the Old Testament are God’s Word because. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们确实知道旧约中的经卷是上帝的话语，是因为……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: John 16:12-15 ； 1 Corinthians 2:12,13 ； 1 Thessalonians 2:13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;参考：约 16：12－15 ； 林前 2：12，13 ； 帖前 2：13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know for sure that the books of the New Testament are God’s Word because. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们确实知道新约中的经卷是上帝的话语，是因为……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ANY WRITINGS THAT ARE NOT IN THE BIBLE ARE NOT GOD’S WORD, SO THEY SHOULD NOT BE USED TO CHANGE OR DENY WHAT THE BIBLE SAYS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;任何不在圣经之内的著作都不是上帝的话语，因此，它们不应该被用来改变或否认圣经的话语。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some churches that do this are: the Catholic Church, the Mormon Church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这样的教会有：罗马天主教，摩门教。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第三课(lesson 3) 规则二—圣经将世界视为有着一位施行神迹的上帝的世界</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/206/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/206/3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Rule #2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;规则二&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE BIBLE VIEWS THE WORLD AS HAVING A GOD THAT DOES MIRACLES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经将世界视为有着一位施行神迹的上帝的世界&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God is not just a distant, uninterested observer who does not care what happens in the world, but has sent his Son to the world to live here and to die for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝并不是那位离我们很遥远、对世界所发生的一切漠不关心的、不感兴趣的旁观者，相反，上帝差遣了他的儿子来到这个世界，生活在这个世界，并为我们而死。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our method of interpreting the Bible is called: HISTORICAL-GRAMMATICAL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们解释圣经的方法被称为：历史－文法学研究的方法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One wrong way of interpreting the Bible is called: HISTORICAL-CRITICAL. This method of interpreting the Bible denies part or all of the ‘supernatural’ in the Bible. Unfortunately, this is the most popular form of interpreting the Bible today. People who approach the Bible this way deny most or all of the miracles in the Bible, and deny also that the Bible was inspired by God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一种错误地解释圣经的方法则称为历史－批判法。这种方法否认了圣经中部分或所有的‘超自然’现象。不幸的是，这种方法还是现今解释圣经最流行的方式。使用这种方法的人们否认了圣经中大部分或所有的神迹，并且也否认了圣经是由上帝所默示的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible shows us that God has always been active in the events on earth, and is still active here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经向我们启示了上帝总是主动地参与世界上的诸事件，并且，目前仍是主动的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: Psalm 46 ； Acts 13:17-41&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;参考： 诗46：； 徒 13：17－41&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible tells us about many MIRACLES that God performed throughout history. Miracles are also a way that Jesus proved he was the Son of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经告诉我们上帝施行的许多神迹贯穿着历史。神迹也是耶稣用来证明他是上帝之子的一种方式。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: Matthew 1:20-21 ； John 10:38 ； John 14:11 ； 1 Corinthians 15:14-19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;参考： 太 1：20－21 ； 约 10：38 ； 约14：1 ；林前15：14－19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INSPIRATION is the activity by which God gave us the Bible. Inspiration is a MIRACLE of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝藉着默示这一作为，赐予我们圣经。默示是上帝的一个神迹。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第四课(lesson 4) 规则三—上帝默示的最初话语有着至高无上的权威</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/206/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/206/4/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Rule #3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;规则三&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE ORIGINAL WORDS THAT GOD INSPIRED ARE ABSOLUTELY AUTHORITATIVE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝默示的最初话语有着至高无上的权威。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the Bible was written a long time ago, the original writings by the original writers are no longer preserved. The original writings were copied by many people and translated into many languages. There was great care given to copying the writings because the copyists believed these were the words of God. Today we can be sure that we have the true Word of God because with all these copies of the original, it is not difficult to determine what the original words in Greek or Hebrew were, which God inspired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;由于圣经在很久以前就写完了，原作者所写的原文原稿已失传了。原文原稿已被文士抄录、并且被译为许多种语言。 文士们在抄圣经的过程中极其小心，因为他们相信这些都是上帝的话语。今天，我们确信我们有着上帝真正的语言，因为，我们通过这些所有的手抄本去检验上帝最初在希腊文或希伯来文中所默示的意思并不困难。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some passages in the New Testament in which we have ‘variant readings.’ We need to examine what copies and translations show us about variant readings so as to determine what the original text said. In those passages where there is a variant reading, no doctrine of Scripture is affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们对于一些新约的圣经段落有着‘异读’。我们需要查考一下手抄本和译本对于‘异读’都说了什么，从而使得我们决定圣经原文文本说了什么。这些有着‘异读’的段落并不影响圣经的教义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of ‘variant readings’:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘异读’的例子：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Byzantine and Alexandrian approaches to studying text variants are faulty because both use only certain copies of the New Testament as being the most accurate and reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;拜占庭和亚历山大学派研究文本异文的方法是错误的，因为他们都只使用了一些新约手抄本作为最正确和可靠的文本。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Recension” is a deliberate effort to rewrite portions of the Bible in a different way. Some people say that this happened in the centuries after Christ ascended into heaven. But there is no evidence that this ever happened. People who believe that ‘recensions’ took place want to try to disprove that the Bible is reliable and is God’s Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“修订” 是一项深思熟虑的工作，即从一个完全不同的方式来重写圣经的某部分。有人认为，这项工作发生在基督升天之后的几个世纪里。但是没有证据能证明这项工作曾发生过。相信‘修订’发生过的人们是想试图来反驳圣经的可靠性及圣经是上帝的话语这一真理。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of a ‘recension’:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一个‘修订’文本的例子：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible was copied by hand from 100 A.D. to 1450 A.D., when the printing press was invented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经从公元100年开始都是用手抄本得以流传，自到1450年印刷业发明为止。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A “witness” is a copy of the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一本“抄本”就是圣经的复制本。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1)We do not have any of the original documents of the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;我们没有任何一卷圣经的原文原稿。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2)All of the copies of the Bible have some variant readings which happened during hand copying over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2)圣经所有的手抄本在多年历经手抄的过程中出现了一些异读。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3)God has preserved so many copies of the Bible that it is not difficult to determine what the original text said, except for a few passages that do not affect doctrine in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3)上帝保存了这么多的圣经手抄本，这使得我们确定圣经原文的意思并不困难，除了少数的圣经段落 的意思之外，不过这些经文并不能以任何方式来影响圣经的教义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Types of New Testament ‘Witnesses’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;新约 ‘抄本’的类型&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A.Greek 希腊文&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;替代文本&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B.Translations 译本&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latin, Syriac, Coptic, Gothic, and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;拉丁文，古代叙利亚语，埃及古语，哥特古语及其他语种。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Guidelines for New Testament Variant Readings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;新约异读的二种指导原则&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Readings which are in the most ANCIENT and WIDESPREAD witnesses are true to the original text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;那些最为古老的、并且流传甚广的抄本的解释，对于圣经的原始文本来说，是最接近原文的真实意思。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the CONTEXT and AUTHOR’S USE OF WORDS to help determine what the original said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;考虑上下文及作者的用词有助于我们确定圣经原文的意思。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第五课(lesson 5) 规则四—为了正确地解释某一处经文，我们应该查考该处经文的历史背景</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/206/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/206/5/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Rule #4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;规则四&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TO INTERPRET A BIBLE PASSAGE CORRECTLY, WE SHOULD STUDY THE HISTORICAL SETTING OF THE PASSAGE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为了正确地解释某一处经文，我们应该查考该处经文的历史背景。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writers of the Bible wrote in the language of the time and place in which they lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经作者运用了他们当时所生活时代和地点的语言来写作。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writers wrote about life situations that were common at their time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;作者所写的有关生活情境在当时时代是非常普遍的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What they wrote was dependent upon the stage of God’s plan of salvation at which they lived. This is especially important to remember in studying the writings of the Old Testament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他们所写的依靠于上帝对他们那个时期的救恩计划的阶段。这一点对于查考旧约的经卷极其重要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the Bible relates historical events that are connected to God’s plan of salvation, and the words and verses have a historical setting in which God chose to have his Word inspired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因此，圣经将与上帝救恩计划相关的历史事件联系起来，并且，上帝选择用来默示的言语和经文都有着历史背景。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we examine the historical setting of a passage we ask the questions: Who is speaking? To whom? Where? When? Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们查考该处经文的历史背景时，我们要问以下几个问题：谁在说话？对谁说的？在什么地方说的？什么时候说？为什么这样说？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE HISTORICAL SETTING OF A PASSAGE SHOULD NEVER BE USED TO CHANGE THE SIMPLE MEANING OF THE PASSAGE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该处经文的历史背景永不能用来改变该经文的字面意思。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible itself provides much information about the historical setting of events. This is true, for example about Paul’s letter to the Philippians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经本身提供了许多事件的历史背景的信息。这是真的，比如保罗所写的腓立比书就是如此。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should study the places, persons, customs, and events that are mentioned in the Bible, but are not explained. For this we may use research books like Bible dictionaries and encyclopedias. However, this information should not be used to change the evident meaning of a Bible passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们应当研究圣经中所提到但未被解释的地点、人物、风俗和实践。为此，我们可以使用像圣经字典和圣经百科全书这样的研究书籍。但是这些信息不能用来改变一段圣经经文的明显意思。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: 例子： Psalm 23 诗23 ; Matthew 21 太 21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 17 约 17 ; Luke 2 路2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KNOW THE AUTHOR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;知道作者&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many books of the Bible, we know who wrote it. We know his experiences, his background, his education, etc. It is helpful to know his purpose for writing, and the time and place of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于圣经中的许多经卷，我们知道是谁写的。我们需要知道作者的经历，背景及其教育情况等等。这对于知道作者的写作意图、写作时间和地点都是非常有用的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: Isaiah ； Daniel ； Matthew 例子： 以赛亚 ； 但以理 ； 马太&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KNOW THE PEOPLE TO WHOM OR ABOUT WHOM THE BOOK WAS WRITTEN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;知道圣经的第一读者或他们的情况。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这包括以下内容：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social situation 社会现状&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cultural situation 文化处境&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The economic situation 经济处境&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The educational situation 教育现状&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The religious situation 宗教处境&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The political situation 政治处境&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The geographic situation 地理位置&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agricultural situation 农业情况&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The personal situation 个体情境&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KNOW THE STAGE OF GOD’S PLAN OF SALVATION DURING WHICH A PASSAGE IS WRITTEN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;知道在该处经文写作期间所处的上帝救恩计划的阶段。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples:例子：&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第六课(lesson 6) 规则五—为了正确地解释某一处经文，我们应该寻找该经文的基本意思，研究其文法情境</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/206/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/206/6/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Rule #5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;规则五&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TO INTERPRET A BIBLE PASSAGE CORRECTLY, WE SHOULD LOOK FOR ITS SIMPLE MEANING, STUDYING THE GRAMMATICAL SETTING&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为了正确地解释某一处经文，我们应该寻找该经文的基本意思，研究其文法情境。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our method of interpreting the Bible is called “Historical-Grammatical.” This means that when we study the Bible, we try to study the historical setting, and also study the grammatical setting. We have already studied how the historical setting is important (Rule #4). Now let us examine how we study the GRAMMATICAL SETTING of a Bible passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们解释圣经的方法被称为“历史－文法”的方法。这意味着，当我们查考圣经时，我们要尽量研究经文的历史背景和文法情境。我们已经研究过历史背景极其重要（规则四）。现在，让我们研究一下，我们如何研究某处经文的文法情境。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever we read anything, we try to understand it in the simplest possible way. For example: “Two cars were involved in an accident on the freeway this morning when they drove over an icy spot and lost control.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;无论我们读什么，我们尽可能以最简单的方式来理解它。比如：“今天早晨，两辆汽车在高速公路的一个结冰的地点，相撞发生一起车祸事故。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the simplest way to understand this sentence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;理解这句话的最简单方式是什么呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should practice this same method of understanding words and sentences ESPECIALLY when we are studying God’s Word. The Bible has NOT been written in some complicated, confusing, difficult, incomprehensible code that nobody can figure out. The Bible tells us that it is clear and understandable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们也应该用同一种方式来理解字句，尤其是我们查考圣经时。圣经并不是用任何人都没法理解的一些复杂的、令人混乱、不可理解的语码写成的。圣经告诉我们圣经的意思是清晰的、并且被人可以理解的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: 2 Timothy 3:15 (you have this memorized!) 参考： 提后 3：15 (你已经记住了这一点！)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 19:7 and 119:105&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗19：7 ；119：105&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does not mean that everything in the Bible must fit into our reason and understanding. What are some teachings and events of the Bible that are definitely impossible for us to understand or explain? Yet it is clear what these teachings and events are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这并不意味着圣经中的任何一处必须符合我们的理性和理解。圣经中有哪些教导和事件是我们明确不可理解或阐明的？然而，很清楚这些教导和事件是哪些。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APPLYING GOD’S WORD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;应用上帝的话语&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we preach and teach God’s Word, we need to apply it. This means that we take the meaning of God’s Word and teach people how it affects them, what it means that they should do or say or think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们宣讲和教导神的话语时，我们需要应用神的话语，这意味着我们领受神话语的意思，并且教导人们如何让话语来影响他们，他们的言行或思想应该如此行。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: 例子：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 4:1-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;太 4：1-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the application for us today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于今天的我们来说，这段经文如何应用？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 21:1-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;太 21：1-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the application today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这段经文在今天如何应用？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colossians 3:15-17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;西 3：15-17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the application today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这段经文在今天如何应用？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Samuel 17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;撒上第 17章&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the application today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这段经文在今天如何应用？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNDERSTANDING THE MEANING OF INDIVIDUAL WORDS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;理解个别字词的意义&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several steps that we can take to determine what individual words mean in the original Hebrew Old Testament or Greek New Testament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这里有几个步骤使得我们可以确定个别的字词在旧约希伯来文和新约希腊文中的意思。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One step that can be helpful is to study the ROOT MEANING of the word. Where did the word originally come from? How has it been used over history? What picture is connected to it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第一步就是查考该词的字根意思，这有助于我们的研究。该词原初来自哪里呢？它在历史中经常被如何使用呢？有哪些相关联的描述呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: Greek word ‘dikaios’ ; Hebrew word ‘cavod’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;例子： 希腊语 ‘dikaios’ ; 希伯来语 ‘cavod’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most valuable and reliable way to determine what a Greek or Hebrew word in the Bible means is to examine its USAGE. If we are studying a word in Romans 1:16, we should examine how Paul uses this same word in Romans 1, in the entire letter to the Romans, in other letters of Paul. Then we can examine how the word is used in other parts of the New Testament. Then we may also learn how the word is used in other Greek literature of the same time period as the New Testament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;决定一个希腊词或希伯来词在圣经中的意思，最有价值和最可靠的方法就是去考查它的用法。假如我们查考罗1：16节中的一个词，我们就应该考查保罗在罗马书第一章、在整本罗马书信和在其他书信中如何使用同一个词，然后，我们就去考查该词在新约其他经卷中的使用，接着，我们也可以学习该词在与新约同时期的其它希腊文学著作中的用法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may describe this process as the INTERPRETATION CIRCLE, which can be used for individual word meanings and also for the general meaning of a passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们可以将这种方法视为诠释循环，它既能用来诠释个别的字词，同时也用来诠释该处经文的大体意思。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also learn some things about word meanings by examining SYNONYMS, which are words that mean something similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;通过考查同义字，我们也可以学到字词意思的其它方面内容，这些字词的意思大约相近。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also can use Greek and Hebrew resource books to help determine the meaning of individual words from the Bible. One type of book is the Greek or Hebrew dictionary (lexicon) that provides definitions of words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们也可以使用关于希腊文和希伯来文的参考书来帮助我们考查圣经中个别的字词的意思。其中一种就是能提供字词定义的希腊文或希伯来文字典（词典）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNDERSTANDING THE GRAMMAR AND SYNTAX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;理解语法和句法&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we study the Bible in the original Greek or Hebrew, we need to examine words as to how they are used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们查考圣经的希腊或希伯来原文时，我们需要考查这些字词的使用。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What kind of word is it? (Noun, verb, participle, preposition, adverb, adjective, pronoun, conjunction)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;它是哪种词性的词？（名词、动词、分词、前置词、副词、形容词、介词、连词）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What form does the word have? (Verbs have tense, voice, mood, person and number. Nouns and adjectives have case, number and gender)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该词有着什么样的词形？（动词有时态、语态、语气，人称和数）名词和形容词有格，数和性)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What order are the words in? (Beginning or end of sentence, close to other key words)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这些词的顺序是什么样的？(位于句首或句末，接近其他关键词)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What groupings of words are coordinated or subordinated?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这些造句的关系是并列的或从属的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help understand the grammar and syntax we may use Greek and Hebrew grammar books, and also Bible commentaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们也可以使用希腊文和希伯来文的语法参考书及圣经的注释书来帮助我们理解语法和句法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE BIBLE HAS DIFFERENT KINDS OF WRITINGS/LITERATURE(This is also called different ‘genres’)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经有不同类型的文学(这也可被称为不同的‘文体’)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;History 历史&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which books of the Old Testament are ‘historical’? What story do they tell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;旧约中哪几卷书是‘历史’书呢？它们讲述了什么故事呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which books of the New Testament are ‘historical’? What story do they tell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;新约中哪几卷书是‘历史’书呢？它们讲述了什么故事呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poetry 诗歌&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which books of the Old Testament are ‘poetical’?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;旧约的哪几卷书是‘诗歌’呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also other, smaller poetical portions in the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经也有篇幅较短的其他诗歌。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: Exodus 15, Isaiah 6, Luke 1:46ff, Romans 11:33-36&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;例子： 出15，赛6，路 1：46及其下，罗11：33-36&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hebrew poetry, it is important to remember that often you will find a line repeated for the sake of emphasis, or to further explain the meaning (parallelism). For example, Psalm 51. .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在希伯来文的诗歌中，你将会经常发现一句诗歌由于强调而被重复，或者为了进一步解释其意思（以平行方式）而被重复，记住这一点是重要的。比如诗篇 51……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Letters 书信&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which books of the New Testament are letters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;新约中哪些经卷是书信？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the letters follow the same outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;大部分书信依循同一大纲：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction 简介&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanksgiving 感谢&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main Body of the Letter 书信的主体部分&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greeting 问候&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion 结论&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prophetical 先知书&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A.Teaching 教导&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What books of the Old Testament are prophetical? What do they talk about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;旧约哪些经卷是先知书？它们讲论了什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Apocalypse/Judgement/End Times 启示/审判/末世&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the kind of literature contained in the book of REVELATION. List some examples in Revelation of the special kind of literature this is and how we should interpret it so as to understand it correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;启示录含有这种类型的文学。列举启示录中这一特殊类型文学的例子，并对它们进行诠释，使得我们能够正确地理解。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In determining what kind of literature we are studying in a passage of the Bible, we may follow several steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们查考圣经中的某处经文，并确定其属于哪种类型的文学，可以依循以下几个步骤……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember which ‘literature section’ of the Bible a particular book belongs in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;记住这一特殊经卷属于圣经的哪个‘文学领域’。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the immediate context of the passage to discover if any special type of literature is being used (poetry, parables, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;考虑经文的直接的上下文，从而去发现是否有其他文学类型曾被使用（诗歌，比喻，等等）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FIGURATIVE LANGUAGE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;比喻性语言&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete the following statements. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;完成下列陈述……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is as hot as . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;天气热得像……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is as cold as. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;天气冷得像……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is as tall as a . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他长得和……一样高&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This meal tastes as bad as. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这顿饭跟……一样难吃&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these would be examples of ‘figurative language.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;所有这些例子都是‘比喻性语言’的例子。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figurative language is when we use figures or pictures to express ourselves clearly or to teach something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们用图形或图画来清楚表达我们自己的思想或者教导一些东西时，这就是比喻性语言。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible uses figurative language regularly. List 10 examples of figurative language in the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经很有规律地使用比喻性语言。请举圣经中十个使用比喻语言的例子。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be able to decide when a Bible passage must be taken figuratively, because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们将能够决定一段经文在什么时候运用了比喻的语言，因为：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer or speaker clearly indicates he is using figurative language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;作者或说话者清楚地表明了他正在使用比喻性语言。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context shows that the words must be taken figuratively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上下文显明了用语必须以比喻的方式出现。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice in the list above how we can determine that these are uses of figurative language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;注意在上面所列的例子中，我们是如何能够确定这些经文使用了比喻性语言的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we study figurative language in the Bible, it is important that we try to understand the picture in its historical setting, knowing what the Jews at the time of Jesus would have known. Look at the list of 10 examples on page 15, and identify what ‘homework’ we would need to do in order to understand the pictures used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们学习圣经中的比喻语言时，尽量去理解语言的历史情境，去知道耶稣时代的犹太人所知道的，这对于我们很重要。请参考第十五页的十个例子，识别一下我们需要做哪些 ‘家庭作业’从而使我们理解这一比喻语言使用的画面。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Bible uses figurative language, there is only ONE (1) point of comparison, and we should restrict our interpretation to that ONE point of comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当圣经使用比喻的语言时，那里只有一种（1）比较，我们应将我们对其的解释局限在这一种比较之中。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the following examples of figurative language in the Bible, and identify the key items. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请看下列圣经中的比喻语言的例子，并且识别出它们的主要部分……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;              Known     Unknown      Comparison

              已知的       未知的         对照
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 15 约15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 23 诗 23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 13 太 13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 25 太 25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short Figures of Speech&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;篇幅短小的比喻性言论&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simile. . .making a comparison using the word ‘like.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;明喻……用“象”一词进行了对比。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke 17:24 路17：24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metaphor. . .making a direct comparison without using the word ‘like.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;暗喻……没有使用“象”一字直接进行了比较。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 15:5 约 15：5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metonomy. . .using one word that stands for another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;转喻……使用一个词来代替另一个词。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 11:26 林前 11：26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synecdoche. . .using a part to stand for the whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;提喻法……使用部分来代替全部。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 16:9 诗16：9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ellipsis. . .omitting a word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;省略法……省略了字词。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 6:13 林前 6：13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Euphemism. . .softening a statement so that it is less harsh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;婉转法……就是委婉地陈述，以免过分尖锐。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acts 1:25 徒1：25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Litotes. . . is an understatement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;间接肯定法……就是故意轻描淡写，缩小事态，从而收到加强的效果。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Thessalonians 2:15 帖前 2：15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irony. . .is the use of words to express the opposite meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;讽刺……是用语言来表达相反的含义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark 7:9 可 7：9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperbole. . .overstating a point in order to emphasize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;夸张法……故意使用夸大或夸张的语句来强调。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 21:25 约 21：25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personification. . .is treating something as though it were a living being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;拟人法……把所描写的事物人格化,从而形象地表达。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 15:55 林前 15：55&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Longer Figures of Speech&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;篇幅较长的比喻性言论&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.Allegory. . .is an extended comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;寓意法……是一种延伸的比喻。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is almost NEVER used in the Bible. The only example in the entire New Testament is in Galatians 4:21-31&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这种几乎从不被用于圣经中。整本新约只有 加拉太书 4：21-31这一例子。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parable. . .is an extended comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(道德说教性的)比喻……是把深刻的道理寄于简单的故事之中,借此喻彼，这也一种延伸的比喻。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus uses many parables to teach the people spiritual truths by borrowing everyday experiences. When we interpret parables, sometimes NONE of the details are used, sometimes SOME of the details may be used, and sometimes ALL of the details are used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;耶稣借用每天生活中的经历以许多比喻的方式来教导人们属灵的真理。当我们诠释这种比喻时，有时候，其中的任何细节都不被用来诠释，有时候，部分细节可以被用在诠释，有时候，所有细节资料都被用来诠释。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an example of a parable where NONE of the details are used for interpretation, see Luke 10:25ff. What is the interpretation of this parable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;比喻中的任何细节都不能用来诠释的例子，请参考 路10：25及其下。那么，这一比喻如何诠释呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an example of a parable where SOME of the details are used for interpretation, see Matthew 25, 21:32-46. What is the interpretation of this parable and what details are used?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;比喻中的一些细节可以用来诠释的例子，请参考 太25：如何诠释这一比喻及其中的细节如何被使用？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an example of a parable where almost ALL of the details are used for interpretation, see Matthew 13 for several examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;比喻中几乎所有细节都可以用来诠释，请参考 太13：中的诸例子.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some parables have an EXTENSION, which means there is a second spiritual truth that is taught by it. For an example, see Luke 15:11ff. What are the spiritual truths taught with this parable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一些道德说教性的比喻有延伸意义，也就是说有第二层属灵含义。比如，路 15：11及其下。这一比喻所教导的属灵教训是什么呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symbols and Types&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;象征和预表&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symbol. . .does not teach something new, but reminds us of something we already know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;象征……借用某种已知、具体的事物来间接表达我们抽象的观念，它不教导我们新东西，而是提醒我们已知的东西。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples: CROSS ; RAINBOW&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;例子： 十字架 ; 彩虹&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type. . .is a picture of something that lies in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;预表. . .以现在的事预先表示出来将来要发生的事。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For examples, see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请参考以下经文：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deuteronomy 18:15 申18：15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebrews 9:3-12 来 9：3-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colossians 2:16 西 2：16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 2:15 太 2：15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 22 (especially verse 13) 创22 (特指第13节)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 3:14 and Numbers 21:4-9 约3：14和民 21：4-9&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第七课(lesson 7) 规则六—以经解经</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/206/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/206/7/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Rule #6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;规则六&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SCRIPTURE INTERPRETS SCRIPTURE ITSELF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以经解经&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way for us to understand what the Bible says, is to allow the Bible to interpret itself. The Bible is God’s Word. Therefore, it is clear and consistent. It does not contradict itself. Some passages may be more difficult for us to understand, but we should turn to other passages in the Bible to shed light on these passages that we may have trouble understanding. (2 Peter 3:16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于我们来说，最佳理解圣经的方式就是以经解经。圣经是上帝的话。因此，她是清晰的又是一致的，并不互相矛盾。有些经文对于我们来说可能存在着理解的难度，但是我们应当用圣经的其它经文来照亮那些我们难以明白的经文。（彼后3：16）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principle, “Scripture Interprets Scripture” is unique to the Lutheran church. In the Catholic Church, the work of interpreting the Bible is given to the Pope, church councils, and church tradition. The Pope is considered infallible whenever he speaks regarding matters related to the Bible. In the 1500&amp;rsquo;s, Martin Luther studied the Bible for himself, and discovered that the Pope and the Catholic Church were no longer teaching the truths of the Bible, but rather their own human interpretations and perversions of what the Bible said. (For example: purgatory, penance, praying to the saints, the role of the Virgin Mary, the buying and selling of forgiveness, the role of good works in salvation) These and other false teachings were developed by sinful men who did not allow the Bible to stand by itself as God’s Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于路德宗教会来说，“以经解经”的原则是唯一的。在罗马天主教，解经的工作属于教皇，教会公会议，教会传统。无论何时，教皇发表有关圣经的言论总被认为是无误的。在公元1500年，马丁路德自己研究圣经，发现教皇和罗马天主教不再教导圣经的真理，相反，他们传授自己对圣经的解释，曲解圣经的真理（比如：炼狱，苦行，向圣徒祈祷，童贞女马利亚，买卖赎罪卷，善工在救恩中的定位）。这些和其他错误的教导都是由那些不愿意尊圣经为上帝话语的罪人所发展出来。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Reformed churches (Baptist, Pentecostal, CMA, Methodist, Evangelical Free, and others) Scripture is subjected to human reason. So Reason must interpret the Bible. This has led the Reformed churches to believe and teach false doctrines in areas such as: double predestination, conversion, baptism, the Lord’s Supper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在改革宗教会（浸信会，五旬节会， (美国)基督教传教联盟，卫理公会， 福音自由派， 和其他宗派教会)，圣经受制于人的理性。因此，理性必须解释圣经。这必然导致改革宗教会去相信和教导错误教义，比如：双重预定，悔改，洗礼，圣餐。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Lutheran Church, we insist that the Bible must interpret itself. This means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在路德宗教会, 我们坚持以经解经，这就意味着：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We understand a passage by comparing it with other passages of the Bible which discuss the same subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们理解该处经文，是通过与讨论同一主题的其他经文进行比较。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: Genesis 3 and Romans 5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;举例： 创 3： 和罗 5：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We understand a passage in its context, both immediate and broader. (Hermeneutical circle).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们在该处经文的上下文中理解经文，其中包括紧临的上下文和更大的上下文（解释学循环）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: John 15, Romans 3, and James 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;举例：约15：，罗3：，和雅各书2：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We assume that since the Bible is inspired by God, the Bible is perfectly united in what it says, without errors or contradictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.我们认定，既然圣经是神所默示的，那么，圣经的内容是完全统一的，没有错误或矛盾。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note again: Romans 3 and James 2, also Matthew 25:31-46.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;再次注意： 罗3：和雅2：，太25：31－46。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unity in the Bible is also true when we compare the Old Testament and the New Testament. The Old Testament was written from 1400 to 400 B.C., and the New Testament from 30 to 100 A.D. There were more than 50 men who wrote parts of the Bible. Yet God is the ultimate author of everything in the Bible, and it is perfectly united in what it teaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们比较旧约和新约时，我们也可以发现圣经是前后一致。旧约写于公元前400年到公元前1400年，而新约则写于公元30年到公元100年。圣经的作者有50多位。然而，圣经的最终作者则是上帝，并且，圣经的话语是个整体，教导前后一致。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Testament authors often quoted the Old Testament in order to: show how a prophecy was fulfilled, prove that a teaching of God’s Word was accepted long ago by Jewish believers, illustrate a point that they are making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;新约作者经常引用旧约是为了：显明预言如何应验，证明上帝话语的教导早就被犹太信徒所接纳，说明他们正在立论的一个观点。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of fulfillment of prophecy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;预言应验的例子：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 22:1 and Matthew 27:46&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗22：1 和 太27：46&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 7:14 and Matthew 1:22-23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;赛 7：14 和 太 1：22-23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Samuel 7:11-16 and Luke 1:32-33&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;撒下 7：11-16和路 1：32-33&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we read, study, and teach the Bible, it is sometimes necessary for us to make judgments and deductions that are based on the Bible’s teachings. It was not God’s purpose when he inspired the Bible to write it in the form of long, detailed series of doctrinal statements, or as a series of legal codes that would give specific instructions for every conceivable situation a person may face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们阅读，查考和教导圣经时，有时候我们在圣经教导的基础上进行判断和推论是必要的。上帝并没有用长篇幅、逐条的教义陈述方式来启示圣经，或者用针对一个人任何可能遇到的境遇所提出一系列具体指示的律法规条来启示圣经，这些都不是上帝的本意。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Old Testament, God gave to the Israelites civil, ceremonial, and moral laws that were intended to impress upon them that they were to be a different, unique people in the world, and this should be demonstrated by every aspect of their lives. However in the New Testament, God has not given for us such an extensive code of laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在旧约里，上帝赐给以色列人民事法，礼仪法和道德法，目的是要他们铭记在心：他们是世界上一个不同的、独特的民族，并且这一点将在他们生活每个层面得到证实。然而，在新约里，上帝并没有赐给我们大量诸如此类的律法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us there are many matters of ADIAPHORA, where we need to apply the general principles of God’s Word for ourselves. God has not given us specific commands or prohibitions for these matters. (For example: drinking alcohol, dancing, how much money to give to church, how often to worship, what kind of job to hold, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝在一些日常的事上没有给我们具体的诫命或禁戒(比如：喝酒，跳舞，奉献给教会多少钱，多久需要去礼拜，应从事什么样的工作，等等。)。在这些方面，我们需要运用上帝话语的总原则。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Bible we observe that there are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们在圣经中注意到以下原则：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNIVERSAL PRINCIPLES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;普遍原则&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Commands of God that apply to all people of all times and places.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(上帝的诫命适合于所有时代的所有人们。)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APPLICATIONS OF PRINCIPLES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;应用原则&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Commands given by God to a particular group of people at a particular time and place.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(上帝在一个特定时间和地方将诫命赐给一个特定的团体。)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I know when I read a passage from the Bible whether I am reading a Universal Principle or an Application of a Principle? Examine the immediate and broader context of Scripture to see if the passage is limited in any way. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们阅读圣经中的某一处经文时，我如何知道我所读的此处经文是属于一个普遍原则或是一个应用原则？考查圣经经文的紧临的上下文和更大的上下文，去查考此段经文是否在某方面是有限的……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the passage intended only for certain people, and not others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;此段经文是否只指向一些特定的人群，不指其他呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the passage intended only for a certain place or time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;此段经文是否只指向一个特定的时期和地方呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we distinguish between principles and applications, we should be particularly cautious when we are reading historical events/narratives in the Bible. We dare not establish our own principles based on what actions are merely described. Examples. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们区分原则和应用时，我们应特别谨慎圣经中的历史事件和叙事。我们不能轻易地根据仅有的描述情节来建立我们自己的原则。 例子……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abraham in Genesis 16:1-4 and 20:1-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯拉罕在创世纪 16：1-4 和 20：1-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John the Baptist and Jesus in Matthew 3:6, 13-17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;施洗约翰和耶稣在太3：6, 13-17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus in Matthew 14:23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;耶稣在太14：23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A doctrine in which it is very important for us to clearly distinguish between principles and applications is the ROLES OF MEN AND WOMEN. Let us briefly examine the key Bible passages for this doctrine and identify the principles, the applications then, and the applications today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于我们来说，清楚地区分原则和应用两者，重要的一点就是男人和女人的角色这一教义。 下面我们概要地考查一下这一教义和识别这些原则、当时应用和现今应用的圣经主要关键段落。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: 参考： Genesis 2 创 2：; 1 Corinthians 11:3-16 林前11：3-16 ; 1 Corinthians 14:26-35 林前14：26-35 ; Ephesians 5:22-33 弗 5：22-33 ; 1 Timothy 2:9-15 提前 2：9-15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider also: 也考虑：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus’ calling his disciples 耶稣对门徒的呼召&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old Testament prophets, priests 旧约先知们、祭司们&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and kings 和诸君王&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principles 原则&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applications Then 当时的应用&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applications Now 现在的应用&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第八课(lesson 8) 诠释的历史</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/206/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/206/8/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the time of the Early Christian Church to the Reformation (100-1500 A.D.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;从早期基督教到改革时期(公元100-1500年)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not long after the New Testament was written that so-called ‘scholars’ began to introduce false and misleading ways to interpret what the Bible says and means. The method of interpretation that became popular is called ALLEGORIZING.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在新约成书以后不久，那些所谓的‘学者’开始介绍误导人的方法来解释圣经的内容。这种解释方法变得流行，并称为寓意法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The correct way of interpreting the Bible is to understand the words of Scripture in their simplest, clearest way. What the Bible SAYS, it MEANS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;解释圣经的正确方法就是以最简单、最清晰的方法来理解圣经的话语。也就是，圣经所说的就是它的意思。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allegorizing was a method of interpretation that stated that a single passage of the Bible can have 2 or 3 or 4 different meanings, and a smart interpreter will be able to determine all of them, or even dream up some new ones. It is interesting to note that this method of interpretation arose in the city of Alexandria, Egypt, which was a center for Greek culture and emphasized scientific learning. Already in that day scientific thought dictated that there must be a natural cause and explanation for everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;寓意地是解释的一种方法，认为，一段单一的经文能够有2或3或4层不同的意思。一个聪明的诠释者将能够决定这四种意思，或者甚至能空想出其它新的意思。有趣的是，这种解释方法竟然在推崇科学研究的、希腊文化中心之一的埃及亚历山大城所兴起。在那个时期，科学思想已经指出，世界必须存有能解释一切事物的一个自然起因。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider how our areas of science (astronomy, geology, anthropology, paleontology, physics, psychology) today have adversely affected the way people think about God and religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;考虑一下我们今天的科学领域 (天文学，地质学，人类学，古生物学，物理学，心理学)是如何已经有害地影响人们思考上帝和宗教的方式。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philo (1st century A.D.) added second meanings to passages when he thought it was necessary to avoid contradictions in the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当斐罗(公元1世纪)认为有必要去避免圣经中的冲突部分时，他就会增加第二层意思在圣经经文上。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Origen (250 A.D.) developed three meanings for Bible passages: literal sense, moral sense, mystical sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;奥利金或译俄利根(公元250年)发展出圣经经文的三层意思：字面意思，道德意思，神秘意思。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jerome and Augustine (400 A.D.) expanded the use of allegory. Augustine developed four meanings for passages: historical, moral, allegorical, analogical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;耶柔米和奥古斯丁(公元400年)扩大了寓意法的使用。奥古斯丁发展了圣经的四层意思：历史的，道德的，寓意的，类比的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Middle Ages allegory remained popular and was applied not only to Bible passages, but also individual words (for example: Jerusalem, bread, sea). Aquinas (1250 A.D.) also added the ‘dialectic method’ of Aristotle to Bible interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在中世纪，寓意法仍流行，并且不但应用在圣经经文的解释上，也被用在对个别词(比如，耶路撒冷，面包，海)的解释上。托马斯阿奎那(公元1250年)也将亚里士多德的‘辩证法’用在了圣经解释上。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Reformation, Martin Luther returned to sound principles of interpreting the Bible. A Bible passage has one simple, intended meaning. He also emphasized that all Christians, therefore, not just priests and popes, can interpret the Bible correctly for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在宗教改革时期，马丁路德回归到解释圣经的合理原则上。一段圣经经文有一个单一的预期意思。因此，他也强调所有基督徒，不仅仅是神父和教宗，能够为他们自己正确地解释圣经。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pietism (1700s)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬虔主义&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pietism was a religious movement that attempted to improve the spiritual life of the Christian church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬虔主义是试图提升基督教会属灵生命的一次宗教运动。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They believed that Christians were to busy preserving sound Christian doctrine and not working hard enough at leading a sanctified, Christian life. Therefore, they wanted to develop a more EMOTIONAL Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他们认为，基督徒太过于保护正确的基督教教义，而没有足够地努力去引导出一个成圣的基督徒生命。因此，他们想要发展一更富有感情的基督教。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a Christian reads the Bible, he should try to personally discover some truth in a passage for himself, relating to the emotional condition of the original writer of the passage. This compromised the OBJECTIVE TRUTH that is to be found in the Bible, and made Bible interpretation a matter of ‘choosing for yourself’ what you think it means to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当一个基督徒阅读圣经时，他会尽其所能在一段经文里为自己发现一些真理，并且也与经文的原始作者之情感状况相关联。这样做就会妥协了圣经中的客观真理，并且使得圣经的诠释成为一件‘由你自己来选择’你所想要的经文意思。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rationalism (1800s)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;理性主义&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rationalism taught that something is real only if it can be proved by modern methods of research. The supernatural and miraculous is impossible. (This is at the foundation of the ‘historical-critical method of interpretation popular today.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;理性主义认为，只有能被现代研究方法所证明的都是真实的。超自然和神迹的事都是不可能（这是今天流行的‘历史批判法’的理论依据）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rationalism suggests that the history of the human race is characterized by the EVOLUTION of religious truth. They would also say the Bible shows this in the Old and New Testaments. They claim the ancient religions of the Eskimos or Indians or tribes of Africa have much in common with the Bible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;理性主义认为人类历史是以宗教真理之进化为特征的。他们也认为圣经的旧新约也显明了这一点。他们宣称爱斯基摩人或印度人或非洲部落的古代宗教与圣经有着许多的相似之处！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existentialism (1800s)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;存在主义&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a philosophy founded by Kierkegaard that protested rationalism and the industrial revolution because these treat people like things and deny the uniqueness of each individual person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是一种由祁克果所开始的哲学，用来反对理性主义或工业革命，因为理性主义和工业革命视人如同事物，并且否定每个人体的独特性。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Religious faith is essentially irrational. Objective truth is less important than the subjective truth that a person discovers and applies to himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;宗教信仰在本质上是非理性的。客现真理相比于主观真理——一个个体发现真理并应用真理而言，显得较不重要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only important time frame for a person to consider is the present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于该个体来说，唯一需要考虑的重要时间框架就是当下或现在。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultimate goal is to discover one’s ‘authentic being’, which is a search for one’s own true existence and nature. The Bible may be helpful in this search, but will provide only part of the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;终极目标就是去发现某人的‘真实之存在’，这是对某人自我的真实生存和本性之追寻。圣经可能会对这样的追寻有帮助，但是将只是提供答案的一部分。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THREE HISTORICAL-CRITICAL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;METHODS OF INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;解释的三种历史－批判方法&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existential Demythologizing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;存在论式的去神话化&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started by Rudolph Bultmann in the 1920&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是由鲁道夫布特曼在1920年期间所提出来的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He emphasized NOT the simple interpretation of the words of the Bible, but rather what the message of the Bible means for the whole of human existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他不是强调对圣经话语的简单解释，相反，圣经的信息对于整个人类生存意味着什么。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said that the New Testament was not written as a history book, but as a series of fictional stories that tell a basic, spiritual message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他论到，新约并不是以一本历史书的方式写成的，相反，而是一系列虚构故事所组成，要告诉我们一个基本的、属灵的信息。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bultmann had his own strange ‘hermeneutical circle.’ When a person reads the Bible, he should ask basic questions like, “What does this say about human existence?” The Bible will answer this question in new and challenging ways which will help the reader ask other, more philosophical questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;布特曼有他自己的一套奇怪的‘诠释圈’。当一个人阅读圣经时，他应该问基本问题，比如，‘ 这对于人类生存论及了什么？’圣经将以新而又富有挑战的方式来回答这个问题，并且，这些回答的方式也将帮助读者提出其他更具思辨的问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ‘Christ event’ takes place when a reader searches the Bible and discovers the message relative to human existence (like enlightenment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当一位读者查考圣经并且发现与人类生存有关系的信息（比如启蒙）时，‘基督事件’就发生了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not important to emphasize the historical person named Jesus and what he did, but rather to discover how we should be what God intended us to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因此，重要的不是强调一位名叫耶稣的历史人物以及他所做的，相反，而是去发现我们应该如何成为上帝所要我们成为的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method of interpretation became common in the Evangelical Lutheran Church in America (ELCA), which is the largest Lutheran denomination in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这种解释方法在美国福音派的路德宗教会（是目前世界上最大的路德宗）较流行。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gospel Reductionism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;福音修正主义&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method was introduced into the Lutheran Church&amp;ndash;Missouri Synod in the 1960&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这种方法于1960年期间介绍至路德宗教会—密苏里会议。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach presumes that the only part of the New Testament that is really inspired by God is the part that deals specifically with the Gospel of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这种方法假设新约里只有一部分是真正由上帝所默示的，并且也只有这部分是特别论述耶稣基督的福音。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible is a combination of human and divine&amp;ndash;written by humans, but containing a message from God. Therefore, the Bible contains errors and contradictions. The only way to discover what parts of the Bible are historically correct is to allow ‘scholars’ to investigate it. The Bible is ‘inerrant’ not because it contains no errors, but because God always accomplishes what he wants with his Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经是神人合作之作——由人所写成的，但是包含了来自上帝的信息。因此，圣经里含有错误和互相矛盾。发现圣经里的哪些部分在历史上是正确的唯一办法就是，允许‘学者’对此进行调查。圣经是‘无误’的不是因为它没有错误，而是因为上帝总是要成就他的道所成就的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Divine-Human Mystery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神人奥秘&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach to the Bible was founded by Harry Boer, a Dutch Reformed author of the 1970&amp;rsquo;s and ‘80&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这种研究圣经的方法由1970年和1980年期间的荷兰改革宗哈利巴尔所开创。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said that just as the union of true God and true man in Jesus Christ is a mystery, so the Bible is a mystery because it is God’s Word, yet was written by human authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他认为，正如真正的神和真正的人在耶稣基督身上合一这是一个奥秘，因此，圣经虽然由人类作者所写，但是却是神的话，这同样也是一个奥秘。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there are many inconsistencies and contradictions in the Bible, but we should not worry about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因此，在圣经里存有许多不一致和互相冲突之处，但是我们不应为此而担心。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible is infallible only in the sense that it is reliable and trustworthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;只有在圣经是可靠和可信的层面来说，圣经是无谬误的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same way that God uses an imperfect world to accomplish his plan of salvation, so he uses an imperfect book to convey his message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同样，上帝使用一个不完美的世界来完成他的救恩计划，因此，他也使用一本不完美的书来传递他的信息。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that the Bible was inspired does not mean that it is free of typical human errors and weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经是默示的这一事实并不意味着它免于人类典型的错误和脆弱。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Evaluation of these three Historical-Critical Methods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对这三种历史-批判方法的一个评估&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three of these methods are wrong because: 1. They say the Bible is not a clear book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say the Bible does not contain an accurate history of events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say the Bible is not God’s revelation to men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say the Bible cannot be perfectly united in its message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say the Bible does not have the supreme authority of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say that Jesus Christ has not died for our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;所有三种方法是错误，是因为：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他们说圣经并不是一本清晰的书。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他们说圣经没有对历史事件的正确记录。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他们说圣经并不是上帝向人类的启示。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他们说圣经在其内容上不能完整地统一起来。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他们说圣经并不具有上帝至高无上的权威。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他们说耶稣基督并没有为我们的救恩而死。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Be sure to read the Postscript on pages 243-244.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;注意： 请阅读附记的第243-244页&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
