<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grace Bible Institute – 60 Gospel Texts Part 1</title>
    <link>/en/courses/407/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 60 Gospel Texts Part 1 on Grace Bible Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:53:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/en/courses/407/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Text Study # 2 Luke 1:26-38</title>
      <link>/en/courses/407/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/407/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This text is intended to be used during one of the Sundays of Advent, the four weeks prior to Christmas. The first four texts in this series were chosen with that pre-Christmas season in mind. 
God sends his angel, Gabriel, to make the grand announcement that he is sending his Son into the world be the Savior. Gabriel goes to Mary of Nazareth, a descendent of David, to tell her that she is God’s favored choice to be the mother of the Messiah.  By the miraculous work of the Holy Spirit in the Virgin Mary, the holy Son of God will take on a human nature and carry out his great work of the salvation of the human race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;commentary-and-study-notes&#34;&gt;Commentary and Study Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verses 26-27
In the sixth month, the angel Gabriel was sent from God to a town in Galilee called Nazareth, to a virgin engaged to a man named Joseph, who was from the house of David.  The virgin’s name was Mary.&lt;br&gt;
“In the sixth month” = Six months after Elizabeth became pregnant with John, God sent his faithful Gabriel to make a second divine announcement, much grander than the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“the angel Gabriel was sent from God” = Gabriel went to the obscure town of Nazareth in Galilee to visit Mary, a woman who was engaged to be married to a carpenter named Joseph, who was also from King David’s family line. We notice the quiet, humble manner in which God chose to send his great Son to the world.   He chose a lowly couple from a small, insignificant town to receive this gift and be responsible for caring for Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verses 28-29
He (the angel) came to her and said: “Greetings, highly favored one!  The Lord is with you.  &lt;Blessed are you among women.&gt;” She was deeply troubled at these words and wondered what kind of greeting this could be.
“Greetings, highly favored one!”  = Gabriel greeted Mary with warm, joyful, welcoming words.  He told her that the Lord God Himself was showing her great favor and giving her a tremendous blessing no other woman would have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“She was deeply troubled at these words” = As a common person, Mary was shocked and confused by Gabriel’s exalted greeting. She wondered why she should receive such favor from God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Blessed are you among women” = The phrase “Blessed are you among women” is not included in some Bible translations.  However, the evidence from the more reliable Greek manuscripts strongly indicates that the phrase is part of the original text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verses 30-33
The angel said to her: “Do not be afraid, Mary, because you have found favor with God. Listen, you will conceive in your womb and will give birth to a son.  You will give him the name ‘Jesus.’  This one will be great and will be called ‘the Son of the Most High.’  The Lord God will give him the throne of his father, David.  He will rule over the house of Jacob forever and there will be no end to his kingdom.” 
“Do not be afraid” = God’s angel comforted Mary’s fears and assured her that God truly does grant her his approval and blessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“will give birth to a son” = Gabriel went on to announce that Mary was chosen to be the mother of a most remarkable child.  She would conceive her child while remaining a virgin. She was to give him the name ‘Jesus,’ which means ‘Deliverer’ or ‘Savior.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“the Son of the Most High” = Mary’s child would be both divine and human in one unique person.  He would be the Son of God as well as the Son of Mary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“the throne of his father, David” = As the God-Man, he would be also be a descendant of King David and the heir to the promise God had made to David in 2 Samuel 7:11-16, the promise of a future descendant who would rule over an eternal kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verses 34-35
Mary said to the angel: “How will this be since I have had no sexual relations with a man?”  The angel answered her, saying: “The Holy Spirit will come upon you and the power of the Most High will envelop you.  So, the holy one to be born will be called the Son of God.&lt;br&gt;
“How will this be” = Unlike Zechariah, who did not believe Gabriel’s message about the birth of his son, John, Mary did believe.  In her question to Gabriel, Mary asked for an explanation to help her understand better how a virgin as she was could conceive a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Holy Spirit will come upon you” = Gabriel explained that this would happen by the miraculous work of the Holy Spirit who would exert his great creative power on Mary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“the holy one to be born” = Gabriel assured Mary that her sinfulness would not interfere with the nature of her Son. He would be holy and so qualified to be the Savior of sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verses 36-37
See, your relative, Elizabeth, has conceived a son in her old age.   This is the sixth month with her who was called sterile.  Nothing will be impossible with God.”
“Elizabeth has conceived a son” = Gabriel offered Mary the helpful information that her relative, Elizabeth, was pregnant with her own son in her advanced stage of life.  Elizabeth’s pregnancy would be proof that God can do the humanly impossible and will keep his word.  By letting Mary know of Elizabeth’s situation, God was also offering Mary a caring relative and fellow believer with whom she could share her great secret and receive much needed support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 38
Mary said: “See, I am the servant of the Lord!  Let it happen to me according to your word.”  Then the angel left her.
“I am the servant of the Lord!” = Mary responded with a tremendous expression of faith and obedience.  She declared herself to be God’s servant, who humbly and willingly accepted God’s role for her.  Her sincere self-surrender to her dear Lord is remarkable in light of the great challenge and burden she would face as the mother of the world’s Redeemer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Law and Gospel In This Text
Take a little time to identify some Law and Gospel teaching elements in the text.
Some Law Elements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vs. 26-27: Gabriel obeyed God’s command to make an announcement to Mary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 34: Mary humbly asks for more information from God&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 38: Mary expresses her faith, declares her confidence in God and her willingness to follow God’s will&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Gospel Elements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 28: the announcement of God’s favor and presence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 30: the comforting announcement of God’s favor repeated and the assurance that there is no need to be afraid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 31: the message of God’s gift of His Son to be the Messiah-Deliverer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 32: the message that the Messiah will be the great Son of God, who inherits David’s throne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 33: the message that the Messiah will rule over an eternal kingdom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 35: the message that the Holy Spirit will perform the miracle of God’s Son becoming a human being&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 36: the encouraging message that God has given Elizabeth a child&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 37: the assurance that God can do all things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preaching/Teaching Points in This text
Suggest two or more teaching points in this text. A teaching point is a truth found in the text that could be explored and expanded within the sermon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God makes a great, long awaited announcement: The Savior is coming to the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Son of God takes on a human nature to become a human being while remaining God.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The miracle of the Virgin Birth, worked by the Holy Spirit in Mary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus begins his humble state of existence as he sets aside divine glory and the full use of his powers to enter the world so he could live a lowly life and die a cursed death in the service of sinners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God can do what is humanly impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mary’s faith that believed God’s promise is also a great miracle of the Holy Spirit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minor Preaching Points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The holy angels are God’s compassionate, faithful messengers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God works in surprising ways that go against the expectations of human thinking (He sends his mighty Savior as a tiny baby to be born of a common virgin from an obscure village)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God keeps his promise of a great, eternal king from David’s descendants (2 Samuel 7:11-16, Isaiah 9:6-7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God’s Good News for the world is a joyful, comforting, encouraging message for troubled, fearful hearts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need God’s help and his word so we can grasp and begin to understand the great things he does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Father takes an active role in our salvation as he sends his Son and explains his works through his angel messenger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Holy Spirit takes an active role in our salvation as he uses his power so Jesus can be miraculously conceived in Mary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth’s pregnancy is convincing, comforting visible, verifiable proof of God’s power and truthfulness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sermon outline with Theme and Parts
Suggest a sermon theme and parts for this text. 
Like any text, there could be many different themes and parts. 
This outline covers the main elements of the text:
GOD ANNOUNCES THE SENDING OF OUR SAVIOR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He Sends His Angel To Deliver The Message  (verses 26,28)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He Chooses A Virgin To Become The Mother (verses 27, 34)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He Enlists The Spirit To Make It Possible (verse 35)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He Names Him “Jesus” To Give Us Hope (verse 31)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This outline focuses on the great miracles God performs as he sends Jesus to the world:
MARVEL AT THE MIRACLES OF JESUS’ BIRTH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Son Of God Also Becomes The Son Of Mary (The Incarnation) (verses 31-33)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Virgin Conceives by The Holy Spirit’s Power (The Virgin Birth) (verses 34- 35)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary Believes All That the Lord Has Told Her (Faith) (verses 36-38)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This outline concentrates on the wonderful identity of the Savior God sends to us:
WHO IS THIS CHILD GOD SENDS YOU?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He Is The Divine Son Of God (verses 32a, 35b)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He Is The Human Son Of Mary (verse 31a)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He Is the Royal Son Of David (verses 32b-33)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He Is Jesus The Christ, Your Savior (verse 31b)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Potential life Applications Suggested by the Text 
What are two applications for the faith and life of God’s people that you could make from this text?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marvel as the great miracles God performs to send the Savior we need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treasure how much God loves you that he comes in person to save you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receive God’s Good News of the Savior as Mary did in simple faith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is both willing and able to do what is humanly impossible to help you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Develop A 5-6 Question Bible Study That Leads Others To Grasp The Meaning Of The Text And Identify Applications For Their Lives. 
There are many possibilities for the students here. Here are some questions that could be used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What special assignment did God give his angel, Gabriel? (v. 26ff)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What important things does Luke tell us about Mary? (vs. 27)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As Gabriel starts his announcement to Mary, what does he want her to know? (v. 28)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does Mary respond at first to Gabriel’s greeting? (v. 29)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After he allayed Mary’s fears, what divine assignment did Gabriel announce to her? (vs. 31-33)
6 . List six things Gabriel told Mary about the special child she would bear? (vs. 31-33)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does Mary’s question in v. 34 let us know about the state of her soul and mind as she considered this unique assignment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would Mary, a virgin, be able to give birth to a boy who is also God’s Son? (v. 35)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How could Jesus be a holy person and yet be born of a sinful mother?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do you think Gabriel added the news that Mary’s cousin, Elizabeth, was pregnant? (vs. 36-37)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As you review Gabriel’s conversation with Mary, what impresses you about the holy angels as they serve God and His people?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would you describe Mary’s faith as she responded to Gabriel’s message from God? (v. 38)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you think it strange or inconsiderate that God did not seek Mary’s permission before assigning her the task of being the mother of the world’s Savior? (Why or why not?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Of all the wonderful and miraculous things mentioned in this story, which do you think is the greatest: a divine message sent by an angel, the virgin conception of the Savior, or the faith of Mary?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does the Annunciation let us know about how serious God is about saving us?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Sample Sermon 
by Pastor James Witt
MARVEL AT THE CHRISTMAS MIRACLES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke 1:26-38
In the sixth month, God sent the angel Gabriel to Nazareth, a town in Galilee, to a virgin pledged to be married to a man named Joseph, a descendant of David. The virgin&amp;rsquo;s name was Mary. The angel went to her and said, &amp;ldquo;Greetings, you who are highly favored!  The Lord is with you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
Mary was greatly troubled at his words and wondered what kind of greeting this might be. 
But the angel went to her, &amp;ldquo;Do not be afraid, Mary, you have found favor with God. You will be with child and give birth to a son, and you are to give Him the name Jesus. He will be great and will be called the Son of the Most High. The Lord will give Him the throne of His father David and He will reign over the house of Jacob forever; His kingdom will never end.” 
“How will this be,” Mary asked the angel, “since I am a virgin?”
The angel answered, “The Holy Spirit will come upon you, and the power of the Most High will overshadow you. So the Holy One to be born will be called the Son of God. Even Elizabeth, your relative, is going to have a child in her old age, and she who was said to be barren is in her sixth month. For nothing is impossible with God.”
“I am the Lord&amp;rsquo;s servant,” Mary answered. “May it be to me as you have said.”  Then the angel left her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peace to all of you who are in Christ.
It was a most unusual birth announcement. Actually it was the most unique birth announcement ever made. Consider this birth announcement was made by a holy angel sent from God and not by a sinful human being operating on his own authority. This birth announcement was made to the women chosen to become pregnant, not by the woman herself who was already pregnant. This birth announcement was made before the conception occurred, not after the birth took place. This birth announcement gave the most intimate details about the baby to be born - his gender, his name and his mission. This birth announcement is meant to bless not just one family or a few people, but rather every person in the world with salvation.
A woman was once asked by her hairdresser how she would like her hair to be done. The woman replied, “I would like a miracle because that is what I need.” When it comes to the matter of our salvation from sin and deliverance from eternal death, it is definitely a miracle that we need. It is certainly a miracle God gives us - and not just one miracle, but actually three of them.   The church father, Saint Bernard, commented on Luke’s account of Gabriel’s visit to Mary by declaring: “Here are three miracles. The first is that God and humanity should be joined in this Child. The second is that a mother gives birth but remains a virgin. The third is that Mary should have such faith as to believe that this marvel would be accomplished in her.” Each one of these miracles is important.  Today we will take some time to meditate on them so that we may treasure them and take great personal benefit from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GOD’S SON TAKES ON A HUMAN NATURE
The first miracle is that of the Incarnation. It is the miracle of God’s Son taking on a human nature. God gave the angel Gabriel the high privilege of announcing this miracle. This was Gabriel’s second major mission in a few month’s time. Six months earlier, God has sent Gabriel to the temple in Jerusalem to announce to Zechariah the birth of John, who would prepare the way for the Savior. Now Gabriel goes to the small Galilean town of Nazareth. He speaks to Mary, a virgin engaged to marry the carpenter, Joseph. He says: “Greetings, you who are highly favored! The Lord is with you.” Mary was greatly troubled at his words and wondered just what kind of greeting this might be.
Gabriel continued the message. He said: “Do not be afraid, Mary, you have found favor with God. You will be with child and will give birth to a son. You are to give Him the name Jesus. He will be great and will be called the Son of the Most High. The Lord God will give Him the throne of His Father David, and He will reign over the house of Jacob forever; His kingdom will never end.” The angel announced that the virgin Mary will give birth to a son. She is to name Him Jesus, the name that means ‘Savior’ or ‘Rescuer.’  This Son will be great. He will be the Son of the Most High, that is, He will be the Son of God. Mary’s child will also be the Son of David, a true human being, who will rule as a king forever. Gabriel announces the astounding truth that the Son of God will take on a human nature. He will become incarnate.
What a miracle this is! What love God shows! The eternal God takes the nature of a human being. The Creator takes the nature of one of His creatures. The Maker of all becomes the brother of sinners. What sacrificial love God shows!  The writer of the Book of Hebrews explains the purpose of the incarnation. He says: “Since the children have flesh and blood, He too, shared in their humanity so that by His death He might destroy Him who holds the power of death - that is the devil - and free those who all their lives were held in slavery by their fear of death. For this reason He had to be made like His brothers in every way, in order that He might become a merciful and faithful high priest in service to God, and that He might make atonement for the sins of the people.”
The incarnation of Gods Son means so much to us. Consider the embarrassing shame and the bitter agony Jesus spares us from. Job hunters who submit resumes with multiple spelling and grammatical mistakes and the disclosure of a lengthy criminal record are going to be embarrassed and rejected. Think about the embarrassment and penalty we all would face if we had to turn in the sordid, sinful record of our life without the Savior’s atonement erasing all the errors and crimes. It is the incarnation of the Son, His taking on our humanity, that made it possible for Him to atone for our sin.
We do well to marvel at this first of the Christmas miracles: the incarnation of Christ.  This miracle reveals God’s love to us and it declares our forgiveness. The hymn writer says it well: 
“He veils in flesh His power divine, 
A servant’s form to take. 
In want and lowliness must pine 
Who heaven and earth did make.
A wondrous change which He does make! 
He takes our flesh and blood. 
And He conceals for sinners’ sake His majesty as God.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A VIRGIN CONCEIVES BY THE SPIRIT’S POWER&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second miracle we consider is the miracle of the Virgin Birth. The virgin Mary will conceive her child by the power of the Holy Spirit. Mary heard the announcement and wondered (quite properly) how this would all work. She was to become a mother of a human child who was also God.  She was a virgin. How would this be possible? Gabriel answered her. He said: “The Holy Spirit will come upon you, and the power of the Most High will overshadow you so the Holy One to be born will be called the Son of God.” The angel explained that Mary would remain a virgin while conceiving and giving birth to Jesus. The Holy Spirit would use His power to allow her to conceive without a man playing any part in the process. In addition, the Holy Spirit would not allow Mary’s own sinfulness to interfere with the nature of the child. The baby would be a holy child, perfectly righteous and without any sin.
What a miracle this was! The Christ Child was conceived in Mary by the working of the Holy Spirit. In Mary’s womb, He would grow and develop and eventually be born of the Virgin mother.  What a miracle God performs! What great comfort He gives us!  The Virgin-born Child is a great comfort to us. This truth reminds us that Jesus is not just a mere human being; He is also God’s Son. This teaching assures us that Jesus’ human nature is sinless and holy. The virgin birth lets us know that Jesus is qualified and capable to save us from our sins. There are many who deny the virgin birth.  There are many others who do not consider it a vital teaching. One pastor announced: “The idea of the virgin birth is not important to salvation.” How wrong he is!  The virgin birth is vitally important. If Jesus is only the product of human intercourse, then He cannot be God - and He cannot even be a sinless human being.  If He is not those things, then He cannot be our Savior. Then we are without hope.
God does not deprive us of the spiritual comfort we sinful people need. He assures us that the Savior He sends is not defective or inadequate. It is frustrating to have a defective product like an airbag that will explode and injure a passenger or a fake medicine that makes a person sicker instead of healthier.  Jesus is the holy, sinless God-Man. He is a full and flawless Savior who rescues completely from sin’s guilt and condemnation. So we may well marvel also at this second miracle God works, the miracle of the virgin birth. With the hymn writer, we take comfort: 
“Savior of the nations, come, 
Virgin’s Son, make here Thy home! 
Marvel now, O heaven and earth, 
That the Lord chose such a birth. 
Not by human flesh and blood, 
By the Spirit of our God, 
Was the Word of God made flesh, 
Virgin’s offspring, pure and fresh.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;THE MAIDEN BELIEVES THE ANGEL’S MESSAGE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third miracle mentioned in our text from Luke 1 is perhaps the greatest of the three.  It is the miracle of Holy Spirit-worked faith. Mary believed what God had told her through the angel. Through His Word, God created a saving and submissive faith in Mary’s heart. Mary responded to Gabriel’s news of God’s choice of her to be the mother of the Savior. She said, “I am the Lord’s servant. May it be to me as you have said.” In response to the amazing message, Mary believes. She does not comprehend it all (who of us could?), but she accepts the truth of it.  She embraces her assignment and submits herself to the will of her God.  She welcomes the Child and the opportunity to serve God as the Savior’s mother.
What a great miracle God performs in Mary. Mary believes this tremendous message, even though it is so unusual and appears to be so unreasonable. She believes even though she has a low position in society and doesn’t seem to be a likely choice for the assignment.  She accepts the implications for her even though the cost of being Jesus’ mother will be very high. To be the mother of the Savior will not be an easy task. She must face some unpleasant things right from the start. There will be the suspicion of her fiance, Joseph, once he discovers that she is pregnant.   There will be criticism and ridicule from people in town. There will be the possibility of divorce and the prospect of foregoing a normal family life. There will be that rugged, bumpy 70-mile trip from Nazareth to Bethlehem in the 9th month of her pregnancy.  There will be the lonely delivery of the baby far away from family help. There will be the sudden flight to Egypt to escape the swords of Herod’s soldiers.  But in spite of the unlikeliness and improbability of it all - and the hardships that are in store, God enables this young woman to firmly believe that she of all women has been chosen to be the mother of her Savior and the Savior of the whole world.&lt;br&gt;
The hardest part of Jesus’ birth is the part about faith. The greatest difficulty we and others face is not so much to believe that Jesus came into the world or that He is the Son of the Virgin Mary or that He is also the Son of God. The hardest part for us and others is to believe that Jesus is the Son of God and Mary given to us, to embrace the truth that Jesus is our personal God-sent Savior from sin and hell. This is the crucial point.  It is one God emphasizes to us.  It is the message of God’s true prophets: Unto us a Child is born, unto us a Son is given. God’s Son, Mary’s Child is ours. He has come to be our Savior, our Brother, our Redeemer.  Those who will not believe this miss all the joy and benefit the Savior brings. Those who do believe become new creatures. They leave the darkness and live in the light. They are born all over again. They become sure of God’s forgiveness of their sins. They become strong against Satan’s accusations and temptations. They become joyful in the midst of difficult, deflating earthly circumstances. &lt;br&gt;
God’s powerful words through the angel transformed Mary’s heart, filling it with faith.  Those wonder-working words made her confident and determined. Those words of God can and will transform our hearts, filling them with faith, making us sure and give us comfort. Let us read them and think on them. As we do the Spirit of God will use their blessed meaning to give us the miracle of a renewed Christmas faith - all full of peace and joy.
May God grant you a marveling and marvelous Christmas this year as you marvel at the Christmas miracles. God’s Son takes on a human nature.  The Virgin conceives by the Spirit’s power. The maiden believes the angel’s words.  May God grant you the marvelous blessings they contain for you by His grace for Jesus’ sake.  Amen.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Text Study #1 Luke 1:5-25</title>
      <link>/en/courses/407/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/407/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This text is intended to be used during one of the Sundays of Advent, the four weeks prior to Christmas. The first four texts in this series were chosen with that pre-Christmas season in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke begins his Gospel with the story of how God’s angel, Gabriel, came to the aged priest, Zechariah, while he was on sacred duty in the Temple, to announce the joyous news of the birth of a son. This son, John, would be the Lord’s devoted, Spirit-filled prophet to prepare the hearts of God’s people for the coming of the Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;commentary-and-study-notes&#34;&gt;Commentary and Study Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verse-5&#34;&gt;Verse 5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days of King Herod of Judea, there was a certain priest by the name of Zechariah, who was of the priestly division of Abijah.  His wife was from the daughters of Aaron and her name was Elizabeth.&lt;br&gt;
“King Herod” = This is Herod the Great who ruled from 37 – 4 B.C. by the permission of the Romans.  His kingdom included all the parts of Israel (Galilee, Samaria and Judea).  He was a great builder of many magnificent structures (including the renovation of the Temple in Jerusalem begun in 20 B.C.), but he was also a cunning, cruel and murderous ruler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Zechariah” = Both Zechariah and Elizabeth were from priestly families descended from the line of Aaron, the first high priest and the brother of Moses. King David had organized the priests into 24 divisions during his rule. Abijah was the 8th division. Each division had its members serve at the temple twice a year for a week at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verse-6&#34;&gt;Verse 6&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of them were righteous before God, living without blame according to all the commands and righteous decrees of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
“righteous before God” = The Greek word for righteous is δίκαιοs.  To be δίκαιοs means “to be in a right condition before the standards of God or people.”  Zechariah and Elizabeth were not sinless people who lived perfect lives.  Rather they were humble, repentant believers who trusted in God’s gift of righteousness through the Savior to pardon them for their sins.  In thankful faith, they faithfully and sincerely strove to keep God’s commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verse-7&#34;&gt;Verse 7&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They did not have a child because Elizabeth was not able to have children and both of them were well along in years.
“not able to have children” = This aged couple did not enjoy the personal happiness of having children. It was especially true in biblical times that the gift of children was considered a sign of God’s favor (see Psalm 128:3) and the lack of children was generally considered a sign of God’s disfavor. Because they had no children, the couple occasionally received unfair, shaming comments from others. In this way, they were like Sarah (Genesis 16:2) and Hannah (1 Samuel 1:1-18) in the Old Testament, who longed for a child and had little human hope of ever having one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verses-8-10&#34;&gt;Verses 8-10&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While he was serving as priest before God, when his priestly division was on duty, he was chosen by lot, according to the custom of the priesthood, to go into the temple of the Lord and burn incense.  The whole crowd of people was praying outside during the hour of offering incense.
“burn incense” = It was the duty of the priests to keep the incense burning on the altar in front of the Most Holy Place in the Temple in Jerusalem. The priest on duty would add incense before the morning sacrifice and again after the evening sacrifice. A single priest could have the privilege of doing this only once in his life. Some never got the chance. Because there were so many priests, the privilege was determined by drawing lots. Zechariah was serving as the incense offering priest at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“the whole crowd of people was praying outside” = The assembly of worshippers prayed outside the Temple while the priest on duty offered the incense. We are not told whether this was the morning or the evening offering of incense time. Because we are told of the assembled crowd, it is more likely that this was the time of the evening offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verses-11-12&#34;&gt;Verses 11-12&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An angel of the Lord appeared to him, standing at the right side of the altar of incense. Zechariah was startled and overcome with fear.&lt;br&gt;
“the angel of the Lord” = During this special, sacred time, God sent an angel to stand right beside Zechariah on the south side of the altar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Zechariah was startled and overcome with fear” = Zechariah responded as a human being would in the sudden presence of a holy being.  He was shocked and afraid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verse-13&#34;&gt;Verse 13&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the angel said to him: “Do not be afraid, Zechariah, because your prayer has been heard.  Your wife, Elizabeth, will bear a son to you, and you will name him ‘John.’&lt;br&gt;
“Do not be afraid, Zechariah” = God’s angel comforted Zechariah by assuring him he had nothing to fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“your prayer has been heard” = The angel announced good news.  Zechariah’s prayer has been answered.  This prayer may have been the personal prayer for a child that he and Elizabeth had previously offered or the prayer for the redemption of Israel that he had offered that day as part of his priestly duties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“a son … you will name him ‘John.’” = The angel also made a wonderful announcement of a coming birth.  Zechariah and Elizabeth will be given a son. God had already given the child his significant name. The name “John” means “the Lord, the God of the covenant, has been gracious.”  The naming of the child by God showed that John would have a special relationship with God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verses-14-15&#34;&gt;Verses 14-15&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be joy and delight for you, and many will rejoice because of his birth, because he will be great before the Lord. He must not drink wine or other alcoholic drink. He will be filled with the Holy Spirit already from his mother’s womb.&lt;br&gt;
“There will be joy” = John would bring great joy, not only to Zechariah and Elizabeth, but also to many more people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“he will be great before the Lord” = Aside from Jesus Himself, John is the only human being in the New Testament who is called “great” in God’s opinion. God has great plans for John.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“he must not drink wine or other alcoholic drink” = In order to show that he was set apart for special service, John would be like the Nazirites in the Old Testament (Numbers 6:1-4) and not drink any alcoholic beverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“filled with the Holy Spirit already from his mother’s womb” = Unlike other human beings, John would be given the Holy Spirit and His gifts (including saving faith) while still in his mother’s womb.  This truth about John is very comforting for us.  It reminds us that while God obligates us to use his means of grace (the Gospel in the forms of the Word and the Sacraments of Baptism and Holy Communion) so the Holy Spirit can bring people to saving faith in Jesus, God does not bind himself to save only by those means. In the case of John, God gave him saving faith apart from those means. The comfort for us is that in cases such as babies who die in miscarriages or by abortion and do not have the opportunity to be baptized, God can still save them from their sin and give them eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verses-16-17&#34;&gt;Verses 16-17&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He will turn many of the children of Israel back to the Lord their God. He will go on before Him in the spirit and power of Elijah to turn the hearts of the fathers toward their children, and the hearts of the unbelieving to the understanding of the righteous in order to get ready a people who are prepared for the Lord.”
“in the spirit and power of Elijah” = God’s angel explained the special mission of John. John was to be a prophet, like the great Old Testament Elijah, who was a preacher of repentance to prepare people spiritually for God’s renewing work. John’s coming was a fulfillment of Malachi 4:5-6, which foretold the coming of an Elijah-like prophet to get people ready for the coming of the Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“turn the hearts” = The Greek word ἐπιστρέψαι means “ to turn back” or “to turn toward” and refers to spiritual conversion,  the inward “turning” of the human soul when the Holy Spirit works true sorrow for sin through the Law and then saving faith in the Savior through the Gospel.  John’s task was to proclaim God’s Word to people so they could be turned around people spiritually and be reconciled to God and His will and also to fellow human beings.  God’s wonder-working Word is able to restore the precious relationships of life that are ruined by sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“the hearts of the unbelieving” = The Greek word that we translate as “unbelieving” is the Greek word ἀπειθεῖς. This work is often translated in English Bibles as “disobedient.”  Its basic meaning is “a person who is unwilling to be persuaded”.  The translation “unbelieving” is probably a better choice in this context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verse-18&#34;&gt;Verse 18&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zechariah said to the angel: “How can I be sure of this?  I am an old man and my wife is advanced in years.”
“How can I be sure of this?” = Zechariah responded to the angel’s announcement with disappointing skepticism.  He does not believe God’s angel-delivered message of good news.   He demands more proof and reminds the angel that he and his wife are not able to have a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verses-19-20&#34;&gt;Verses 19-20&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The angel answered him: “I am Gabriel.  I stand in the presence of God.  I was sent to speak to you and to tell you this good news. Now you will be silenced and not able to speak until the day when these things happen because you did not believe my words which will be fulfilled in their proper time.
“I am Gabriel” = The angel answered Zechariah’s unbelief, first of all, by revealing his name.  He is Gabriel, which means “God is my hero” or “mighty man of God.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I stand in the presence of God” = Gabriel then declared that he stood the presence of God.  By this he lets Zechariah know that he is a holy angel, who enjoys God’s favor and is God’s authorized representative.  Gabriel had been specially commissioned by God to deliver a most important and serious message to Zechariah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“you will be silenced” = As a consequence of Zechariah’s unbelief, he would receive a sign, but not one that he might expect.  As a rebuke to the unbelief he expressed with his mouth.  Zechariah would be unable to use his mouth to speak until God’s word was fulfilled at the birth of John.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verses-21-22&#34;&gt;Verses 21-22&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the people were waiting for Zechariah and were wondering why he stayed so long in the temple. When he came out, he was not able to speak to them. They realized that he had seen a vision in the temple.  He kept making signs to them and remained unable to speak.&lt;br&gt;
“the people were waiting” = While Gabriel spoke with Zechariah, the assembly of worshippers were kept waiting for him to appear.  When he did leave the Holy Place, he found that he could not join the other priests in speaking the words of blessing on the people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“realized that he had seen a vision” = The people did not know exactly what happened to Zechariah but realized that he had seen some vision from God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verses-23-25&#34;&gt;Verses 23-25&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the days of his priestly service were completed, he went back to his home. After those days, his wife, Elizabeth, became pregnant.  She kept herself in seclusion for five months, saying: The Lord has done this for me.  In these days He has shown His favor by taking away my reason for shame among people.”
“he went back to his home” = After Zechariah completed his week of service, he returned to his nearby home in the hill country of Judea. We may wonder what Zechariah communicated to Elizabeth about his experience in the Temple. One pastor has suggested that perhaps Zechariah wrote a letter to Elizabeth that may have gone like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dearest Elizabeth:
I have some important things to tell you about the remarkable things I have seen and heard this week. This week I received the highest honor of my life. God, the blessed and holy One, chose me to burn the incense in the Temple.  I slowly entered the Holy Place carrying the censor filled with glowing coals. I saw the golden candlestick, the table of showbread, the golden altar of incense. I was so excited that I hardly dared to look at the curtain.
As I was putting incense on the coal, an angel of God appeared. His name was Gabriel.  He was standing on the right side of the altar in this sacred place. Elizabeth, I was scared to death. He talked to me. He called me by name. He knew me. He told me not to be afraid. The he told me the astounding news that you and I would have a son. 
We are going to have a baby, Elizabeth. You and I, an old and childless couple, are going to have a child.  The angel Gabriel told me that this boy, our son, is going to be a very special child with a most important mission.  He is going to be the long-promised prophet who prepares the way for the Messiah. The Messiah is coming, Elizabeth. The Messiah! Our Savior!  What favor God has shown us – and the whole world!
I should have believed Him, Elizabeth, but I didn’t. Your husband didn&amp;rsquo;t that believe God remembers His promises and keeps them. So I received a penalty for my unbelief.  The angel told that told me that I would not be able to talk until our baby is born. That is what has happened and that is why I have to share this news with you by writing it down.
I am embarrassed by my weakness of faith, Elizabeth. But the good news is that our prayers have been heard. We are going to be parents. The Messiah is coming.  Our son is going to prepare the way for him.  So, get ready, my dear, for some very big changes in our lives that will bring wonderful blessings for the whole world.
Your loving husband,
Zechariah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Elizabeth, became pregnant” = Zechariah had sexual relations with his wife, Elizabeth, and she became pregnant as the angel had said she would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“in seclusion for five months” = Elizabeth kept out of public view for 5 months, probably until the time when she would be showing her pregnant condition, and have visible proof that God had shown His favor toward her and had removed any stigma about Elizabeth being a childless woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;law-and-gospel-in-this-text&#34;&gt;Law and Gospel In This Text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a little time to identify some Law and Gospel teaching elements in the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-law-elements&#34;&gt;Some Law Elements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.v. 6: the obedience of Zechariah and Elizabeth, they lived without blame according to the commands and righteous decrees of the Lord
2.vs. 8-9: Zechariah fulfilled his duty as a priest
3.	v. 10: People worshipped and prayed at the Temple
4.	vs. 11, 13 and 19: Gabriel served as God’s faithful messenger
5.	v. 18: Zechariah expressed disbelief at God’s announcement
6.	vs. 19-20: Gabriel rebuked Zechariah for his unbelief and announced God’s punishment
7.	v. 22: Zechariah experienced the consequences of his unbelief
8.	vs. 23-24: Zechariah obeyed God when he returned home
9.	v. 25: Elizabeth rejoiced in God’s gift&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-gospel-elements&#34;&gt;Some Gospel Elements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 6: Zechariah and Elizabeth were righteous before God (this righteous verdict was God’s gift to them through faith in the coming Savior)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vs. 13-17: the message that God gives a son who will bring joy and will bring many to faith in the Lord&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;v. 25: the contents of Elizabeth’s praise: God has shown gracious favor toward her&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preachingteaching-points-in-this-text&#34;&gt;Preaching/Teaching Points in This text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggest two or more teaching points in this text. A teaching point is a truth found in the text that could be explored and expanded within the sermon. Here are a few suggestions by the author of this lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God works in surprising ways to accomplish His will (an angel messenger, a miraculous birth)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Messiah is coming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be prepared for the coming of the Savior with a turned-around (repentant) heart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receive God’s Word by faith. Do not reject it in unbelief.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God remembers and keeps His ancient promises to bring salvation to the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God gives us joy by means of His Word and those who proclaim it faithfully.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God plans a great mission for the Forerunner of the Messiah.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some minor teaching topics could include
•	The holy angels are God’s messengers
•	The sadness and pain of being childless
•	Children are a gift from God
•	God has a use for old people
•	Strive to live a faithful, pious life as God’s believer
•	God can give the Holy Spirit to a person apart from the means of grace
•	Sinners are afraid in the presence of holiness
•	God takes away our natural fear of Him
•	A chastened believer learns to obey
•	God hears our prayers and answers them
•	God will use afflictions to rebuke our unbelief and to train us
•	Strive to turn sinful people back to God by sharing His Word
•	John is the “second Elijah”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sermon-outline-with-theme-and-parts&#34;&gt;Sermon outline with Theme and Parts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggest a sermon theme and parts for this text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any text, there could be many different themes and parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;god-gets-us-ready-for-remarkable-things&#34;&gt;GOD GETS US READY FOR REMARKABLE THINGS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This outline covers the whole text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He Surprises Us with An Angel Messenger for An Aged Couple (verses 5-13)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He Delights Us with The Gift of The Coming Savior’s Prophet (verses 14-17)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He Cautions Us Against Refusing to Believe Him (verses 18-22)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He Comforts Us by Fulfilling His Saving Promises (verses 23-25)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;god-sends-his-prophet-to-bring-us-joy-verses-13-14&#34;&gt;GOD SENDS HIS PROPHET TO BRING US JOY (verses 13-14)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This outline focuses on the part of the text that discusses the person and work of John:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He Equips John with Special Gifts for His Mission (verse 15)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He Employs John to Change Our Turned-Away Hearts (verses 15-17a)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He Empowers John to Direct Us to Our Savior (verse 17b)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;zechariah-announces-the-coming-of-christmas&#34;&gt;ZECHARIAH ANNOUNCES THE COMING OF CHRISTMAS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This outline uses the text with a sermon preached from the viewpoint of Zechariah:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I Was Startled by God’s Message Of Wonderful News (verses 11-17)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I Was Rightly Rebuked When I Would Not Believe Him (verses 17-22)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I Became Fully Convinced That God Does Keep His Word (verses 23-25)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-potential-life-applications-suggested-by-the-text&#34;&gt;Two Potential life Applications Suggested by the Text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are two applications for the faith and life of God’s people that you could make from this text?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not doubt that God will keep his promises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God remembers the promises he makes to us, even though we may have to wait a long time for them to be fulfilled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God hears your prayers, even we do not always see evidences of it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God wants your heart to be turned back to him and to those you have conflicts with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God has joy for you in the coming of the Savior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God wants to use you in his service, even when you are old&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bible-study&#34;&gt;Bible Study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Develop A 5-6 Question Bible Study That Leads Others To Grasp The Meaning Of The Text And Identify Applications For Their Lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many possibilities. Here are some questions that could be used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What information does Luke give us about the people who would be the parents of the man who would prepare the way for the Savior? (vs. 5-7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do you think that Zechariah and Elizabeth would be a good choice to be the parents of a child with such a special life mission?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do you think that Zechariah and Elizabeth would be an unlikely choice to be the parents of a child with such a special life mission?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What important work was Zechariah doing when God’s angel appeared to him? (vs. 8-10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comment on Luther’s statement: “God often likes to make His will known to people when they are busy doing their appointed tasks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Zechariah react, at first, to the angel’s appearance? (vs. 11-12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What surprising, good news did the angel give Zechariah? (v. 13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some of the special features that would be part of this child’s life and character? (vs. 14-15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What special mission would this child carry out when he was older? (vs. 16-17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Zechariah respond to the angel’s astonishing news? (v. 18)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did Gabriel rebuke Zechariah for his response? (v. 19)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give three reasons why it should not have been so hard for Zechariah to believe Gabriel’s message to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What chastising penalty did God place on the skeptical Zechariah? (v. 20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your opinion, what purpose(s) would Zechariah’s silence serve?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did the silence placed on Zechariah affect him and the people he was serving at the time? (vs. 21-22)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened when Zechariah returned home from his temple service? (vs. 23-24a)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Elizabeth react to her pregnancy and the special news associated with her baby? (vs. 24b-25)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“By announcing the birth of John the Baptizer, God reveals Himself to be the God of good and great surprises.”  Explain what this comment means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-sample-sermon-by-pastor-james-witt&#34;&gt;A Sample Sermon by Pastor James Witt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COME LORD JESUS WITH PROOF FOR US WHO DOUBT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke 1:11-20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then an angel of the Lord appeared to Zechariah, standing at the right side of the altar of incense. When Zechariah saw him, he was startled and was gripped with fear. But the angel said to him: “Do not be afraid, Zechariah; your prayer has been heard. Your wife Elizabeth will bear you a son, and you are to call him John. He will be a joy and delight to you, and many will rejoice because of his birth, for he will be great in the sight of the Lord. He is never to take wine or other fermented drink, and he will be filled with the Holy Spirit even before he is born. He will bring back many of the people of Israel to the Lord their God. And he will go on before the Lord, in the spirit and power of Elijah, to turn the hearts of the parents to their children and the disobedient to the wisdom of the righteous—to make ready a people prepared for the Lord.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zechariah asked the angel, “How can I be sure of this? I am an old man and my wife is well along in years.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The angel said to him, “I am Gabriel. I stand in the presence of God, and I have been sent to speak to you and to tell you this good news. And now you will be silent and not able to speak until the day this happens, because you did not believe my words, which will come true at their appointed time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are those who read and hear the words of the Lord and take them to heart. The time in near for Jesus to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, don’t be such a doubting _______.  Were you ready to say the name “Thomas?”   That’s the name we often want to put there to complete the sentence. Thomas is the most famous of the doubters of the Bible. He did not accept the other disciples’ testimony about the risen Savior and expressed his stubborn reluctance to believe that Jesus was alive again. But we are now in the Advent season, so we have a different name to use.  It is the name of another famous doubter. He is Zechariah, an aged priest, the husband of Elizabeth, and the father of John the Baptist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zechariah is an interesting case. He teaches us what doubt is. He shows us that doubt is the thought that something may not be true or right. It is the attitude of uncertainty, a mood of disbelief.  Zechariah also shows us that doubting has no age limit. Young people can doubt. Middle aged people can doubt. Older people like Zechariah can doubt. Zechariah shows us that even believers in God can be plagued with doubts. More importantly, Zechariah shows us that doubting God and His Word is sinful and insulting to the Lord who always speaks the truth.  Even more importantly, he also shows us that God can help the person afflicted with sinful doubts and deliver them from the damage doubt causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a closer look at this Advent poster-child for people like us who can also struggle with doubts about God and His ways. Many of us know the basic story of Zechariah fairly well. Luke introduces him to us right at the start of His gospel about Jesus.  Zechariah lived at the time of Herod the Great, who ruled Israel with Roman permission, from 37-4 B.C.   Zechariah was a priest, who was married to a priest’s daughter. He was a devout believer in the true God and looked forward to the coming of the Messiah who would save people from their sins and spiritual enemies.  Zechariah was old and childless because Elizabeth was infertile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Luke’s account unfolds, we learn that Zechariah&amp;rsquo;s priestly division, Abijah, is taking its twice-a-year turn at serving in the temple.  Zechariah has been chosen by lot to be the priest to keep the incense burning on the altar in front of the Most Holy Place on that day. Because there were so many priests and only so many opportunities, this was a rare privilege for Zechariah.   The Jewish regulations for priests state that this was often a once-in-a-lifetime event.  It was on this very special day in Zechariah’s life and career as a priest that God sent His angel Gabriel to deliver an important announcement to Zechariah.
Gabriel appeared to Zechariah while he was tending the altar of incense. God’s angel stood at Zechariah’s right side and startled him. Gabriel told the fear-filled priest to set aside his fear and then assured him that God was answering a prayer he had offered. The angel announced that God was going to give him and Elizabeth a son whom they were name “John”.  The name “John” means “God is gracious.”  This son would bring Zechariah and Elizabeth great joy and he would also do much more. John would cause many to rejoice and he would be great in the sight of God. Zechariah’s special child was live a special life as a Nazirite who would never drink alcohol. He would be given the Holy Spirit to fill his heart with faith and strength even before birth. The angel also announced the special mission that John would have &amp;ndash; he would be a powerful Elijah-like prophet who would proclaim the word of God to lead many people to repentance and who would prepare their hearts to welcome the coming of the Messiah. Gabriel told Zechariah that his son would play a most important role in God’s plan of salvation. He would be God’s great messenger to get people ready for the Savior. The promise of God&amp;rsquo;s salvation was the great thing that Zechariah believed in and longed for. It was astoundingly good news that the angel delivered to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of welcoming this announcement with faith and joy, the priest in the temple responded with doubt.  He expressed his uncertainty with the question: “How can I be sure of this?” Then he gave the reasons for his disbelief. He was an old man and his wife was an old woman, well beyond the age and ability to have children. The angel’s message did not make sense to him. The opportunity for he and Elizabeth to have a child, much less such a special child. was long past. That ship had sailed, that train had left the station, that letter had already been mailed long ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we must understand that not all doubting is wrong or sinful. God has given people the ability to doubt. It is a helpful ability. There are times when doubting is the proper thing to do.   If the person or the thing that we are asked to believe is dishonest or unreliable, then thinking that the report or the promise may not be true or right is the correct reaction. God calls us to be discerning people. He commands us to “test the spiritual messages and messengers” we hear. He doesn’t want us to be deceived by lying people and their phony promises. He wants us to put our faith in people and things that are true and reliable.
While there is such a thing as good doubt, there is also such a thing as bad doubt.   Zechariah’s doubt was bad. It was bad because of whom Zechariah was doubting. He was doubting God, the God who does not lie and always tells the truth. He was doubting the God who is almighty and for whom nothing is impossible. God had selected and sent one of His most loyal, honored and powerful angels to give Zechariah this divine message. God had given Zechariah a message that was in full agreement with all the truth that He had revealed in the Old Testament.  God has given Zechariah a message that revealed God’s knowledge of the deepest, most personal longings of Zechariah’s and Elizabeth’s hearts. It should have been easy for Zechariah to accept this message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But God’s intimate message and reliable messenger was not enough for Zechariah. In his reluctant mood, he asked for a sign beyond the proof that God had already given him.  This was wrong. It was a failure of faith, a sinful weakness that plagued the elderly priest and that plagues people like you and me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Zechariah, we have our difficulties in fully trusting God and what He has promised and what He is working out for us.  Like Zechariah, we can question, complain to and demand of God, when we should just believe Him. We can and, at times, may doubt things about God, wondering whether He really is good or sincere or caring or watchful or wise or strong.  He can also and, at times, may doubt things about God’s Word, questioning whether the Bible really is God’s Word, or that God is telling us the truth, or that the message of God’s Word is relevant to our lives, or that the promises God gives us will be kept. We can doubt that the Word is powerful to accomplish God’s purposes or that our prayers are actually heard and answered or that our sins are all forgiven by Christ or that we will be raised from the dead to a life of endless glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sinful world in which we live conditions us to be doubtful of God. We live in a culture that has long cultivated the idea that the skeptical person toward God is always smarter than the one who believes Him. That thinking can infect and damage our thinking about our Creator and Savior. In addition, our sinful nature is a defiantly skeptical creature, always questioning and challenging God and His Word, continually trying to lead us into the pit of bad and sinful doubt. Our sinful doubts would betray us into losing the blessings that God would give us. Our sinful nature is forever resisting the evidence God gives us, dismissing His proofs as insufficient, demanding still more signs that, if met, will only be followed by more unreasonable demands. With Paul, we have to confess, “What wretched people we are! We are prisoners to the power of sin. Who will deliver us from our bodies of death with their sinful doubts?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God came to the rescue of doubting Zechariah. God’s angel rebuked Zechariah’s sinful doubt. He let Zechariah know that he was doubting the One who should never be doubted.  He told Zechariah that he would receive a sign. This sign would not the kind that Zechariah might be asking for, but it would the divine sign that would help him set aside his doubt. From that moment until the promised child would be born, Zechariah would not be able to speak. The mouth of the man who had uttered his disbelief would not be able to say anything for months.   The pain and inconvenience of the sign to Zechariah would be relatively mild, but it would be effectively real. In addition, God did not withdraw the promise he had made to Zechariah. He graciously kept His Word and included His wobbly in faith priest in working out His great plan of salvation for sinners. Elizabeth did conceive. Zechariah has more confirmation that God was right and he was wrong to doubt. By the time, the baby was born, Zechariah had given up his doubting ways and was stronger than ever in his confidence that God’s words are true and that God is not to be doubted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this Advent season, we can gain God’s help in our personal fight against sinful doubting of our Lord. We can take heart in the way God patiently and lovingly helped Zechariah escape his debilitating doubts. His rebuke of our groundless disbelief can help us recognize and repent of sinful skepticism. His fulfillment of all His promises can help us see and be sure that He always tell us the truth and is to be fully trusted.  He gracious pledge of pardon in the Savior, whose birth we celebrate again, assures us that God is with us and for us and moves us to be more and more willing to follow His commands for our life. As God’s powerful, reliable Word works in our hearts, we see the truth of the statement: “There will be haters, doubters and non-believers, and then there will be God proving them wrong.” As the Holy Spirit works persuasively through God’s Word and Sacrament, we will come more and more to agree with the confession of Russian writer: Fyodor Dostoyevsky: “It is not as a naive child that I believe and confess Jesus Christ. My hosanna is born out of a furnace of doubt.”  In Jesus, the Savior born in Bethlehem, we come to know the truth. That truth gives us full confidence and sets us free from the disabling damage and the devastating doom of our doubts.   Amen.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
