<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>恩典圣经学院 – 简介</title>
    <link>/zh-cn/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 简介 on 恩典圣经学院</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/zh-cn/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About: 信仰宣言</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/about/faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/about/faith/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;What We Believe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that there is only one true God, consisting of three persons, Father, Son, and Holy Spirit. (John 17:3, Matt. 28:19)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that God gave us the Bible through men whom He chose, and that in a miraculous way the Holy Spirit inspired these men to write His Word. Thus the Bible is the very Word of God. (2 Pet. 1:21)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that God created the heavens and the earth. (Gen 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that by nature man is separated from God by sin, and, without a Savior, will be judged by God and be eternally punished in hell. (Rom.6:23)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that Jesus Christ is true God and true man, who made full payment for our sins by His sacrifice on the cross (John 3:16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that man must receive this payment for himself by faith in Jesus Christ. Justifying faith is trust in Christ and His redemptive work. (John 1:12 and Eph. 2:8-9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that baptism is a God-ordained holy act through which God himself works or strengthens faith in the individual. It also is a time of full commitment to Christ for adults. (Acts 2:38-39)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that Communion is a God ordained holy act in which the true body and blood of Jesus Christ is present with the bread and wine in a supernatural way for the assurance of forgiveness. (Matt. 26:26, 28)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that on the Last Day Jesus Christ will return to judge the living and the dead. (Matt. 25:31-46)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIANITY AND GOVERNMENT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that Christians must submit themselves to governing authorities. (Romans 13:1-5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that Christians must pay their taxes and give respect and honor where each is due. (Romans 13:6-7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that government is not obligated to subsidize the church. Churches are to be self-supporting, or aided by the generosity of other churches. (2 Cor. 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIAN LIVING&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that the Ten Commandments provide a summary of how a Christian is to live. This involves the highest standards of life toward God, country, and our fellow man. This life includes honesty, morality, contentment, love, and helpful concern for others. This life excludes immorality, lying, stealing, gossip, or any other action harmful to others. (Exodus 20:1-17 et al)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE GOSPEL AND SOCIAL CHANGE&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About: 学院使命</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/about/misson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/about/misson/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;恩典圣经学院有三重使命:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;为学生提供以基督为中心的基督教神学教导，由高素质的老师帮助学生们在基督徒的信心和知识上一并增长成熟。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;为教会工人提供事工技能及基督教神学的训练，推进他们的事工，并使其证道和教导更加的以福音为中心。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;装备学生以使他们可以在属地的教会或小团契中担任合宜的事工职责。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
