<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>恩典圣经学院 – 认信和基督教信经</title>
    <link>/zh-cn/courses/211/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 认信和基督教信经 on 恩典圣经学院</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 03:17:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/zh-cn/courses/211/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第一课 认信</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/211/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/211/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;预备问题&#34;&gt;预备问题&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting Started Questions 课程开始前的思考题&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why must Christianity be a faith that is confessed by those who embrace it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么基督教的信仰要求凡相信的人必须公开地认信？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe a time when you were keenly aware that you were being called on to make a clear, true confession of your faith in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请讲述某个你自己清晰的认识到被神呼召，且清楚、真实的表达自己对基督的认信的经历。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you consider to be the great value of creeds for your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你认为基督教的信经对你生活的最大价值是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the primary reason that we use creeds as a regular part of our public worship services?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们在敬拜的时候，常常使用信经的主要原因是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-god-gives-christians-their-faith-and-moves-them-to-confess-it-神赐给基督徒信心并且感动他们认信&#34;&gt;A. God Gives Christians Their Faith and Moves Them To Confess It 神赐给基督徒信心并且感动他们认信&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God Himself makes believing Christians.  He gives spiritually dead sinners a new spiritual life by granting them faith in Jesus Christ, the Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神自己使人成为基督徒。藉着赐给人相信救主耶稣基督的信心，祂将属灵的新生命赐给在灵里死亡的罪人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But because of His great love for us, God who is rich in mercy, made us alive with Christ even when we were dead in transgressions. .  .  It is by grace that you have been saved through faith – and this not from yourselves, it is the gift of God – not by works, so that no one can boast.”  (Ephesians 2:4-5, 8-9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 然而，　神既有丰富的怜悯，因他爱我们的大爱，5 当我们死在过犯中的时候，便叫我们与基督一同活过来。你们得救是本乎恩。8 你们得救是本乎恩，也因着信；这并不是出于自己，乃是　神所赐的；9 也不是出于行为，免得有人自夸。 （以弗所书 2:4–5 ,8–9）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God also makes believing Christians to be confessing Christians. He moves the people that He has brought to faith in Christ by His Word to profess and testify to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神还使信徒成为认信的基督徒。祂感动那些藉着神的话而产生信心的基督徒去公开的认信且为之做见证。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Therefore I tell you that no one who is speaking by the Spirit of God says, ‘Jesus be cursed,’ and no one can say, ‘Jesus is Lord,’ except by the Holy Spirit.”  (1 Corinthians 12:3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 所以我告诉你们，被　神的灵感动的，没有说「耶稣是可咒诅」的；若不是被圣灵感动的，也没有能说「耶稣是主」的。 (哥林多前书 12：3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you confess with your mouth, “Jesus is Lord,” and believe in your heart that God raised Him from the dead, you will be saved.   For it is with your heart that you believe and are justified, and it is with your mouth that you confess and are saved.”  (Romans 10:9-10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 你若口里认耶稣为主，心里信　神叫他从死里复活，就必得救。10 因为，人心里相信就可以称义，口里承认就可以得救。 (罗马书 10：9–10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is written: ‘I believed, therefore I have spoken.’  With that same spirit of faith we also believe and therefore speak because we know that the One who raised the Lord Jesus from the dead will also raise us with Jesus and present us with you in His presence.”  (2 Corinthians 4:13-14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 但我们既有信心，正如经上记着说：「我因信，所以如此说话。」我们也信，所以也说话。14 自己知道那叫主耶稣复活的，也必叫我们与耶稣一同复活，并且叫我们与你们一同站在他面前。 (哥林多后书 4：13–14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As a faith without works is dead, so a faith without confession is dead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“正如信心若没有行为就是死的，没有认信的信心也是死的”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God calls on His Christians to confess and explain their faith publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神呼召祂的信徒公开的认信并讲明他们的信仰。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But what about you?” Jesus asked.  “Who do you say I am?”  (Matthew 16:15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 耶稣说：「你们说我是谁？」  (马太福音 16：15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But in your hearts set apart Christ as Lord.  Always be prepared to give an answer to everyone who asks you to give the reason for the hope that you have.  But do this with gentleness and respect.”  (1 Peter 3:15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 只要心里尊主基督为圣。有人问你们心中盼望的缘由，就要常作准备，以温柔、敬畏的心回答各人；  (彼得前书 3：15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Whoever acknowledges Me before men, I will also acknowledge him before My Father in heaven.  But whoever disowns Me before men, I will disown him before My Father in heaven.”  (Matthew 10:32-33)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;32 「凡在人面前认我的，我在我天上的父面前也必认他；33 凡在人面前不认我的，我在我天上的父面前也必不认他。」 (马太福音 10：32–33)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have a clear duty to profess the faith within us, to make ourselves knows as followers of Christ, and to lead others to Him by the influence of our testimony.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“我们有一个清楚的责任就是要承认我们里面的信心，清楚的知道自己是跟随基督的人，并藉着我们的见证来影响他人来到基督面前”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to God’s gracious gift of faith and His call to confess, Christians do testify to their faith:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为要回应神所赐的满有恩典的礼物——信心，和祂要我们去认信的呼召，基督徒们为他们的信心而做见证：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Courageously and Willingly 主动、勇敢的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They (The Jewish Council leaders) called them (Jesus’ apostles) in again and commanded them not to speak or teach at all in the name of Jesus.  But Peter and John replied, ‘Judge for yourselves whether it is right in God’s sight to obey you rather than God. For, we cannot help speaking about what we have seen and heard.’”  (Acts 4:18-20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18 于是叫了他们来，禁止他们总不可奉耶稣的名讲论教训人。19 彼得、约翰说：「听从你们，不听从　神，这在　神面前合理不合理，你们自己酌量吧！20 我们所看见所听见的，不能不说。」 (使徒行传 4：18–20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Honestly and Sincerely 诚实、恳切的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Rather, we have renounced secret and shameful ways, we do not use deception, nor do we distort the word of God.  On the contrary, by setting forth the truth plainly we commend ourselves to every man’s conscience in the sight of God.” (2 Corinthians 4:2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 乃将那些暗昧可耻的事弃绝了；不行诡诈，不谬讲　神的道理，只将真理表明出来，好在　神面前把自己荐与各人的良心。  (哥林多后书 4：2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Continually and Devotedly 持续、忠实的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Day after day, in the temple courts and from house to house, they never stopped teaching and proclaiming the good news that Jesus is the Christ.”  (Acts 5:42)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;42 他们就每日在殿里、在家里不住地教训人，传耶稣是基督。 (使徒行传 5：42)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. To Please God and So That Others May Come To Faith In Christ 为要得神喜悦且使他们也可以相信基督&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So we make it our goal to please Him  .  .  . For we must all appear before the judgment seat of Christ, that each one may receive what is due him.  Since, then, we know what it is to fear the Lord, we try to persuade men.”  (2 Corinthians 5:9a, 10 a, 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 所以…我们立了志向，要得主的喜悦。…因为我们众人必要在基督台前显露出来，叫各人按着本身所行的，或善或恶受报。 …我们既知道主是可畏的，所以劝人… (哥林多后书 5:9a, 10 a, 11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;b-some-biblical-confessions-of-christian-faith-圣经中关乎基督教信仰的认信&#34;&gt;B. Some Biblical Confessions Of Christian Faith 圣经中关乎基督教信仰的认信&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Simon Peter answered, “You are the Christ, the Son of the living God.”  (Matthew 16:16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16 西门·彼得回答说：「你是基督，是永生　神的儿子。」 (马太福音 16：16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Thomas said to Him, “My Lord and My God!”  (John 20:28)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28 多马说：「我的主！我的　神！」 （约翰福音 20：28 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. “Therefore let all Israel be assured of this: God has made this Jesus, whom you crucified, both Lord and Christ.”  (Acts 2:36)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;36 「故此，以色列全家当确实地知道，你们钉在十字架上的这位耶稣，　神已经立他为主，为基督了。」 （使徒行传 2：36 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. “For I received what I passed on to you as of first importance: that Christ died for our sins according to the Scriptures, that He was buried, that He was raised on the third day according to the Scriptures, and that He appeared to Peter, and then to the Twelve.” (1 Corinthians 15:3-5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 我当日所领受又传给你们的：第一，就是基督照圣经所说，为我们的罪死了，4 而且埋葬了；又照圣经所说，第三天复活了，5 并且显给矶法看，然后显给十二使徒看；（哥林多前书 15：3–5 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e. “Christ Jesus, who being in very nature God, did not consider equality with God something to be grasped, but made Himself nothing, taking the very nature of a servant, being made in human likeness.  And being found in appearance as a man, He humbled Himself and became obedient to death – even death on a cross!  Therefore God exalted Him to the highest place and gave Him the name that is above every name, that at the name of Jesus every knee should bow, in heaven and on earth and under the earth, and every tongue confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father.” (Philippians 2:6-11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 他本有　神的形象， 不以自己与　神同等为强夺的； 7 反倒虚己， 取了奴仆的形象， 成为人的样式； 8 既有人的样子，就自己卑微， 存心顺服，以至于死， 且死在十字架上。 9 所以，　神将他升为至高， 又赐给他那超乎万名之上的名， 10 叫一切在天上的、地上的，和地底下的， 因耶稣的名无不屈膝， 11 无不口称「耶稣基督为主」， 使荣耀归与父　神。（腓立比书 2：6–11 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;f. “For there is one God and one Mediator between God and men, the man Christ Jesus, who gave Himself as a ransom for all men – the testimony given in its proper time.” (1 Timothy 2:5-6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 因为只有一位　神，在　神和人中间，只有一位中保，乃是降世为人的基督耶稣；6 他舍自己作万人的赎价，到了时候，这事必证明出来。（提摩太前书 2：5–6 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;g. “And we have seen and testify that the Father has sent His Son to be the Savior of the world.   If anyone acknowledges that Jesus is the Son of God, God lives in Him, and He in God.”   (1 John 4:14-15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 父差子作世人的救主；这是我们所看见且作见证的。15 凡认耶稣为　神儿子的，　神就住在他里面，他也住在　神里面。（约翰一书 4：14–15 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The early Church was, from the start, a believing, confessing, preaching Church.  Early Christians knew they were bearers of a unique story of redemption. Possessing this saving message of Christ, they were driven by an inner impulse to proclaim it
in their witnessing and in their worship.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;初代教会从起初就是一个信靠、认信、广传的教会。早期的基督徒们知道自己拥有关乎救恩的独一无二的故事。带着基督的救恩信息，他们内里火热，推动他们在见证和敬拜中去广传。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-i-review-questions-复习题&#34;&gt;Part I Review Questions 复习题&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a Christian, what is the connection between believing and confessing the Christian faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;作为一个基督徒，对基督教的信仰的相信和认信之间有哪些联系？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give three reasons why Christians confess their faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请给出三个理由来说明基督徒为什么需要公开认信自己的信仰。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share three factors that determine the quality of a Christian’s profession of faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请分享三个决定一个基督徒信仰的质量的因素。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第二课 在信徒的大家庭中认信</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/211/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/211/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;a-gods-believers-confess-the-faith-together-基督徒们在一起共同认信&#34;&gt;A. God’s Believers Confess The Faith Together 基督徒们在一起共同认信&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God wants His believers to confess the Christian faith individually.  He also wants them to confess the faith together as members of His spiritual family in the Christian Church on earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神愿意基督徒们个人清楚的认信基督教的信仰。祂还愿意基督徒们作为地上教会的属灵成员能一同的认信他们的信仰。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As God unites people to Himself through faith in Jesus Christ, He also unites them with other people that He has brought to faith in Christ.   God creates the Church in order to have a special people who are His own and who glorify Him by their words and actions.  God leads His believers to join together in fellowship to obey His will and to confess Him in a variety of ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神藉着在耶稣基督里的信心把人团聚在祂里面。祂还把他们和其他有共同信仰的基督徒们团聚在一起。神建立教会使属于祂的子民得以藉着他们的话语和行为来荣耀祂。神带领祂的信徒团契在一起来遵行祂的旨意，并用各样的方式来认信基督。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;b-god-wants-his-christians-to-be-united-in-believing-and-following-all-that-he-teaches-in-his-word-神希望祂的子民联合在同一信仰中并且遵行所有祂所说的话语&#34;&gt;B. God Wants His Christians To Be United In Believing And Following All That He Teaches In His Word 神希望祂的子民联合在同一信仰中，并且遵行所有祂所说的话语&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 But you, dear friends, by building yourselves up in your most holy faith and praying in the Holy Spirit, 21 keep yourselves in God’s love as you wait for the mercy of our Lord Jesus Christ to bring you to eternal life. (Jude 20-21)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 亲爱的弟兄啊，你们却要在至圣的真道上造就自己，在圣灵里祷告，21 保守自己常在　神的爱中，仰望我们主耶稣基督的怜悯，直到永生。（犹大书 20–21 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the Jews who had believed him, Jesus said, “If you hold to my teaching, you are really my disciples. (John 8:31)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;31 耶稣对信他的犹太人说：「你们若常常遵守我的道，就真是我的门徒；（约翰福音 8：31 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, 20 and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you. And surely I am with you always, to the very end of the age.” (Matthew 28:19-20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 所以，你们要去，使万民作我的门徒，奉父、子、圣灵的名给他们施洗。20 凡我所吩咐你们的，都教训他们遵守，我就常与你们同在，直到世界的末了。」（马太福音 28：19–20 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 I appeal to you, brothers and sisters] in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, that all of you agree with one another in what you say and that there be no divisions among you, but that you be perfectly united in mind and thought. (1 Corinthians 1:10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 弟兄们，我借我们主耶稣基督的名劝你们都说一样的话。你们中间也不可分党，只要一心一意，彼此相合。（哥林多前书 1：10 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 It gave me great joy when some believers came and testified about your faithfulness to the truth, telling how you continue to walk in it. 4 I have no greater joy than to hear that my children are walking in the truth. (3 John 3-4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 有弟兄来证明你心里存的真理，正如你按真理而行，我就甚喜乐。4 我听见我的儿女们按真理而行，我的喜乐就没有比这个大的。（约翰三书 3–4 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;c-god-wants-his-believers-to-express-their-unity-in-faith-eagerly-in-the-fellowing-ways-神希望祂的子民在以下的方式里积极的表达他们在信仰中的合一&#34;&gt;C. God Wants His Believers To Express Their Unity In Faith Eagerly In The Fellowing Ways 神希望祂的子民在以下的方式里积极的表达他们在信仰中的合一&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publicly Worshipping God Together 一同公开的敬拜神&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 Do not giving up meeting together, as some are in the habit of doing, but encouraging one another—and all the more as you see the Day approaching. (Hebrews 10:25)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 你们不可停止聚会，好像那些停止惯了的人，倒要彼此劝勉，既知道那日子临近，就更当如此。（希伯来书 10：25 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celebrating Holy Communion 一同分享圣餐&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 Because there is one loaf, we, who are many, are one body, for we all share the one loaf. (1 Corinthians 10:17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 我们虽多，仍是一个饼，一个身体，因为我们都是分受这一个饼。（哥林多前书 10：17 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praying Together 一同祷告&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 Therefore I want the men everywhere to pray, lifting up holy hands without anger or disputing. (1 Timothy 2:8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 我愿男人无忿怒，无争论，举起圣洁的手，随处祷告；（提摩太前书 2：8 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 They all joined together constantly in prayer, along with the women and Mary the mother of Jesus, and with his brothers. (Acts 1:14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 这些人同着几个妇人和耶稣的母亲马利亚，并耶稣的弟兄，都同心合意地恒切祷告。（使徒行传 1：14 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Promoting The Faith By Preaching And Teaching and Baptizing 通过讲道、教导和洗礼来推广信仰&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, 20 and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you. And surely I am with you always, to the very end of the age.” (Matthew 28:19-20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 所以，你们要去，使万民作我的门徒，奉父、子、圣灵的名给他们施洗。20 凡我所吩咐你们的，都教训他们遵守，我就常与你们同在，直到世界的末了。」（马太福音 28：19–20 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 But you will receive power when the Holy Spirit comes on you; and you will be my witnesses in Jerusalem, and in all Judea and Samaria, and to the ends of the earth.” (Acts 1:8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 但圣灵降临在你们身上，你们就必得着能力，并要在耶路撒冷、犹太全地，和撒马利亚，直到地极，作我的见证。」（使徒行传 1：8 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;d-god-warns-us-that-there-are-people-inside-christian-churches-on-earth-that-are-not-faithful-to-god-and-promote-and-support-damaging-false-teachings-神警告我们地上的教会中有人并不忠信于神并且还有传讲并支持有害的假教训&#34;&gt;D. God Warns Us That There Are People Inside Christian Churches On Earth That Are Not Faithful To God And Promote And Support Damaging False Teachings 神警告我们地上的教会中有人并不忠信于神并且还有传讲并支持有害的假教训&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 But, dear friends, remember what the apostles of our Lord Jesus Christ foretold. 18 They said to you, “In the last times there will be scoffers who will follow their own ungodly desires.” 19 These are the people who divide you, who follow mere natural instincts and do not have the Spirit. (Jude 17-19)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 亲爱的弟兄啊，你们要记念我们主耶稣基督之使徒从前所说的话。18 他们曾对你们说过，末世必有好讥诮的人随从自己不敬虔的私欲而行。19 这就是那些引人结党、属乎血气、没有圣灵的人。（犹大书 17–19 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there were also false prophets among the people, just as there will be false teachers among you. They will secretly introduce destructive heresies, even denying the sovereign Lord who bought them—bringing swift destruction on themselves. 2 Many will follow their depraved conduct and will bring the way of truth into disrepute. 3 In their greed these teachers will exploit you with fabricated stories. Their condemnation has long been hanging over them, and their destruction has not been sleeping. (2 Peter 2:1-3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 从前在百姓中有假先知起来，将来在你们中间也必有假师傅，私自引进陷害人的异端，连买他们的主他们也不承认，自取速速地灭亡。2 将有许多人随从他们邪淫的行为，便叫真道因他们的缘故被毁谤。3 他们因有贪心，要用捏造的言语在你们身上取利。他们的刑罚，自古以来并不迟延；他们的灭亡也必速速来到。（彼得后书 2：1–3 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 For the time will come when people will not put up with sound doctrine. Instead, to suit their own desires, they will gather around them a great number of teachers to say what their itching ears want to hear. 4 They will turn their ears away from the truth and turn aside to myths. (2 Timothy 4:3-4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 因为时候要到，人必厌烦纯正的道理，耳朵发痒，就随从自己的情欲，增添好些师傅，4 并且掩耳不听真道，偏向荒谬的言语。（提摩太后书 4：3–4 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 I say this because many deceivers, who do not acknowledge Jesus Christ as coming in the flesh, have gone out into the world. Any such person is the deceiver and the antichrist. 8 Watch out that you do not lose what we have worked for, but that you may be rewarded fully. 9 Anyone who runs ahead and does not continue in the teaching of Christ does not have God; whoever continues in the teaching has both the Father and the Son. 10 If anyone comes to you and does not bring this teaching, do not take them into your house or welcome them. 11 Anyone who welcomes them shares in their wicked work.  (2 John 7-11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 因为世上有许多迷惑人的出来，他们不认耶稣基督是成了肉身来的；这就是那迷惑人、敌基督的。8 你们要小心，不要失去你们所做的工，乃要得着满足的赏赐。9 凡越过基督的教训不常守着的，就没有　神；常守这教训的，就有父又有子。10 若有人到你们那里，不是传这教训，不要接他到家里，也不要问他的安；11 因为问他安的，就在他的恶行上有分。（约翰二书 7–11 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;e-god-teaches-us-to-be-discerning-and-careful-about-our-association-with-those-who-promote-and-hold-to-false-teachings-神教导我们需要明辨且小心地处理我们和那些传讲假道理的人之间的关系&#34;&gt;E. God Teaches Us To Be Discerning And Careful About Our Association With Those Who Promote And Hold To False Teachings 神教导我们需要明辨且小心地处理我们和那些传讲假道理的人之间的关系&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God Tells Us To Test All Those Who Teach A Spiritual Message To Make Sure That They Are Telling Us What His Word Teaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神告诉我们说，需要试验那些传讲属灵信息的人，从而可以确切的知道他们是否在传讲圣经中的话语&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear friends, do not believe every spirit, but test the spirits to see whether they are from God, because many false prophets have gone out into the world. (1 John 4:1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 亲爱的弟兄啊，一切的灵，你们不可都信，总要试验那些灵是出于　神的不是，因为世上有许多假先知已经出来了。（约翰一书 4：1 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God Teaches Us To Watch Out For False Teachers And Be Aware Of The Dangers They Present To Our Christian Faith&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神教导我们需要提放那些假教师，并且认识到他们对基督教信仰所造成的伤害&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 “Watch out for false prophets. They come to you in sheep’s clothing, but inwardly they are ferocious wolves. 16 By their fruit you will recognize them. Do people pick grapes from thorn bushes, or figs from thistles? (Matthew 7:15-16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 「你们要防备假先知。他们到你们这里来，外面披着羊皮，里面却是残暴的狼。16 凭着他们的果子，就可以认出他们来。荆棘上岂能摘葡萄呢？蒺藜里岂能摘无花果呢？（马太福音 7：15–16 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God Tells Us To Avoid And To Separate Ourselves From Those Who Promote False Teachings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神告诉我们说要避免且远离那些教导假教训的人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 I urge you, brothers and sisters, to watch out for those who cause divisions and put obstacles in your way that are contrary to the teaching you have learned. Keep away from them. 18 For such people are not serving our Lord Christ, but their own appetites. By smooth talk and flattery they deceive the minds of naive people.  (Romans 16:17-18)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 弟兄们，那些离间你们、叫你们跌倒、背乎所学之道的人，我劝你们要留意躲避他们。18 因为这样的人不服事我们的主基督，只服事自己的肚腹，用花言巧语诱惑那些老实人的心。（罗马书 16：17–18 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God Also Teaches Us To Rebuke And If Necessary, Expel Those Who Might Try To Cause Spiritual Division With False Teaching In Our Church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神还教导我们必要时要指责他们，要驱逐那些可能试图在我们的教会中用错误的教导造成属灵分裂的人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 Warn a divisive person once, and then warn them a second time. After that, have nothing to do with them. (Titus 3:10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 分门结党的人，警戒过一两次，就要弃绝他。（提多书 3：10 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;f-god-has-given-us-sound-loving-reasons-to-oppose-and-separate-fromthose-who-do-not-faithfully-follow-his-word-上帝已经给了我们合理的充满爱心的理由让我们抵挡并与那些不忠实于他的话语的人分开&#34;&gt;F. God Has Given Us Sound, Loving Reasons To Oppose And Separate FromThose Who Do Not Faithfully Follow His Word 上帝已经给了我们合理的、充满爱心的理由，让我们抵挡并与那些不忠实于他的话语的人分开&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We Are To Separate Out Of Love For God And His True Word&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们要出于对上帝的爱和祂的真道的缘故而分离&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 Sanctify them by the truth; your word is truth. (John 17:17) 17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;求你用真理使他们成圣；你的道就是真理。（约翰福音 17：17 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 For certain individuals whose condemnation was written about[a] long ago have secretly slipped in among you. They are ungodly people, who pervert the grace of our God into a license for immorality and deny Jesus Christ our only Sovereign and Lord. (Jude 4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 Jesus replied, “Anyone who loves me will obey my teaching. My Father will love them, and we will come to them and make our home with them. 24 Anyone who does not love me will not obey my teaching. These words you hear are not my own; they belong to the Father who sent me.  (John 14:23-24)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;²³ 耶稣回答说：「人若爱我，就必遵守我的道；我父也必爱他，并且我们要到他那里去，与他同住。²⁴ 不爱我的人就不遵守我的道。你们所听见的道不是我的，乃是差我来之父的道。（约翰福音 14：23–24)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We Are To Separate Out Of Love For Those Who Hold To The Truth, Including Ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们要出于对那些坚持真理的人的爱而分离，包括爱我们自己。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 But I am afraid that just as Eve was deceived by the serpent’s cunning, your minds may somehow be led astray from your sincere and pure devotion to Christ. (2 Corinthians 11:3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 我只怕你们的心或偏于邪，失去那向基督所存纯一清洁的心，就像蛇用诡诈诱惑了夏娃一样。（哥林多后书 11：3 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 Therefore, dear friends, since you have been forewarned, be on your guard so that you may not be carried away by the error of the lawless and fall from your secure position. (2 Peter 3:17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 亲爱的弟兄啊，你们既然预先知道这事，就当防备，恐怕被恶人的错谬诱惑，就从自己坚固的地步上坠落。（彼得后书 3：17 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We Are To Separate Out Of Love For Those Who Are Caught Up In False Belief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们要出于对那些陷入错误信仰的人的爱而分离&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 This saying is true. Therefore rebuke them sharply, so that they will be sound in the faith 14 and will pay no attention to Jewish myths or to the merely human commands of those who reject the truth. (Titus 1:13-14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 这个见证是真的。所以，你要严严地责备他们，使他们在真道上纯全无疵，14 不听犹太人荒谬的言语和离弃真道之人的诫命。（提多书 1：13–14 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 Be merciful to those who doubt; (Jude 22)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 有些人存疑心，你们要怜悯他们；（犹大书 22 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 My brothers and sisters, if one of you should wander from the truth and someone should bring that person back, 20 remember this: Whoever turns a sinner from the error of their way will save them from death and cover over a multitude of sins. (James 5:19-20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 我的弟兄们，你们中间若有失迷真道的，有人使他回转，20 这人该知道：叫一个罪人从迷路上转回便是救一个灵魂不死，并且遮盖许多的罪。（雅各书 5：19–20 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-2-review-questions-复习题&#34;&gt;Part 2 Review Questions 复习题&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it important the Christians join in fellowship with those who share a common belief and loyalty to God and all that He teaches in His Word?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒必须只与那些忠信于上帝和他的话语中的一切教导的人结成团契，为什么这一点非常重要？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What harm can false teaching bring to a person’s spiritual life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;错误的教导会给一个人的属灵生活带来什么伤害？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does a person test as spiritual message he hears or reads to know if it is true or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一个人如何检验他所听到或读到的属灵信息，以了解它的真假？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the 3 loving reasons God gives us to spiritually separate from those who do not faithfully follow God’s Word?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神给我们哪三个在爱中的理由，以使我们在属灵生活中与那些不忠实于神的话语的人分开？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第三课 认信的原则</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/211/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/211/3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God uses His life-giving Word through which the Holy Spirit works to create Christians who believe the Word and confess that Word with their own words.  (2 Thessalonians 2:13-14, Romans 10:17, 1 Corinthians 12:3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;藉着圣灵的工作，神用祂的生命之道创造出相信这道并且自己的话语认信这道的基督徒。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 But we ought always to thank God for you, brothers and sisters loved by the Lord, because God chose you as firstfruits to be saved through the sanctifying work of the Spirit and through belief in the truth. 14 He called you to this through our gospel,  that you might share in the glory of our Lord Jesus Christ.  (2 Thessalonians 2:13-14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 主所爱的弟兄们哪，我们本该常为你们感谢　神；因为他从起初拣选了你们，叫你们因信真道，又被圣灵感动，成为圣洁，能以得救。14 神借我们所传的福音召你们到这地步，好得着我们主耶稣基督的荣光。（帖撒罗尼迦后书 2：13–14 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 Consequently, faith comes from hearing the message, and the message is heard through the word about Christ. (Romans 10:17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 可见，信道是从听道来的，听道是从基督的话来的。（罗马书 10：17 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Therefore I want you to know that no one who is speaking by the Spirit of God says, “Jesus be cursed,” and no one can say, “Jesus is Lord,” except by the Holy Spirit. (1 Corinthians 12:3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 所以我告诉你们，被　神的灵感动的，没有说「耶稣是可咒诅」的；若不是被圣灵感动的，也没有能说「耶稣是主」的。（哥林多前书 12：3 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God calls and moves His Christians to publicly proclaim (confess) their religious beliefs in a variety of ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神呼召并感动他的基督徒以各种方式公开宣布（承认）他们的宗教信仰。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. In worship as Christians confess their sins (Psalm 51:3-4), declare God’s praises (Psalm 51:15), and confess their faith (Psalm 51:13).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在敬拜中作为基督徒来承认自己的罪（诗篇51:3-4)，传扬赞美神的话 (诗篇51:15), 并且认信他们的信仰 (诗篇51:13).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For I know my transgressions, and my sin is always before me. 4 Against you, you only, have I sinned and done what is evil in your sight; so you are right in your verdict and justified when you judge. Psalm 51:3-4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 因为，我知道我的过犯； 我的罪常在我面前。 4 我向你犯罪，惟独得罪了你； 在你眼前行了这恶， 以致你责备我的时候显为公义， 判断我的时候显为清正。（诗篇 51：3–4 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open my lips, Lord, and my mouth will declare your praise. (Psalm 51:15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 主啊，求你使我嘴唇张开， 我的口便传扬赞美你的话！（诗篇 51：15 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I will teach transgressors your ways, so that sinners will turn back to you.(Psalm 51:13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 我就把你的道指教有过犯的人， 罪人必归顺你。（诗篇 51：13 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. In preaching (哥林多后书 4：5) 在讲道中&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what we preach is not ourselves, but Jesus Christ as Lord, and ourselves as your servants for Jesus’ sake. (2 Corinthians 4:5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 我们原不是传自己，乃是传基督耶稣为主，并且自己因耶稣作你们的仆人。（哥林多后书 4：5 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. In teaching (Matthew 28:20a) 在教导中&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you. And surely I am with you always, to the very end of the age. (Matthew 28:20a)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 凡我所吩咐你们的，都教训他们遵守，我就常与你们同在，直到世界的末了。」（马太福音 28：20a )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. In witnessing  (1 Peter 3:15) 在见证中&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in your hearts revere Christ as Lord. Always be prepared to give an answer to everyone who asks you to give the reason for the hope that you have. But do this with gentleness and respect, (1 Peter 3:15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 只要心里尊主基督为圣。有人问你们心中盼望的缘由，就要常作准备，以温柔、敬畏的心回答各人；（彼得前书 3：15 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e. In the use of the Keys (John 20:21-23 在使用钥匙职时&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;21 Again Jesus said, “Peace be with you! As the Father has sent me, I am sending you.” 22 And with that he breathed on them and said, “Receive the Holy Spirit. 23 If you forgive anyone’s sins, their sins are forgiven; if you do not forgive them, they are not forgiven.” (John 20:21-23)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;21 耶稣又对他们说：「愿你们平安！父怎样差遣了我，我也照样差遣你们。」22 说了这话，就向他们吹一口气，说：「你们受圣灵！23 你们赦免谁的罪，谁的罪就赦免了；你们留下谁的罪，谁的罪就留下了。」（约翰福音 20：21–23 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God’s Word, the Bible, is the only source and standard for the teachings that Christians are to believe and to confess.   (2 Timothy 3:14-17, Jeremiah 23:28)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝的话语，即圣经，是基督徒要相信和认信的教导的唯一来源和标准。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 But as for you, continue in what you have learned and have become convinced of, because you know those from whom you learned it, 15 and how from infancy you have known the Holy Scriptures, which are able to make you wise for salvation through faith in Christ Jesus. 16 All Scripture is God-breathed and is useful for teaching, rebuking, correcting and training in righteousness, 17 so that the servant of God may be thoroughly equipped for every good work. (2 Timothy 3:14-17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 但你所学习的，所确信的，要存在心里；因为你知道是跟谁学的，15 并且知道你是从小明白圣经，这圣经能使你因信基督耶稣，有得救的智慧。16 圣经都是　神所默示的，于教训、督责、使人归正、教导人学义都是有益的，17 叫属　神的人得以完全，预备行各样的善事。（提摩太后书 3：14–17 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28 Let the prophet who has a dream recount the dream, but let the one who has my word speak it faithfully. For what has straw to do with grain?” declares the LORD. (Jeremiah 23:28)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28 得梦的先知可以述说那梦；得我话的人可以诚实讲说我的话。糠秕怎能与麦子比较呢？这是耶和华说的。」（耶利米书 23：28 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important way that Christians confess their faith is through the use of carefully written Biblical statements or documents.   These written confessions have these characteristics:  They are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒认信其信仰的一个重要方式是通过使用精心编写的信仰陈述或文件。这些书面的忏悔有以下特点：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. orderly in structure
b. a summary of key teachings/principles
c. fixed in their wording
d. Biblical – drawing their teachings solely and clearly from the Bible
e. evangelical – centered in the Gospel of Jesus Christ
f. evangelistic – intended to proclaim truth to others
g. ecumenical – representing the faith of the one true Holy Christian Church
h. eschatalogical – accountable to God’s judgment and filled with urgency&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. 合理的结构
b. 对关键教导/原则进行总结
c. 措辞固定
d. 符合圣经&amp;ndash;完全明确地从圣经中汲取其教义
e. 福音式的&amp;ndash;以耶稣基督的福音为中心
f. 布道式的&amp;ndash;旨在向他人宣扬真理
g. 普世的&amp;ndash;代表唯一的圣而公之教会的信仰
h. 末世论的—要经受上帝的审判，充满紧迫感&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christian confession requires condemning false religious teachings and practices as well as affirming Biblical truths. (2 Corinthians 6:14-15; 10:5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒的认信要求谴责错误的宗教教义和做法，并肯定圣经中的真理。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 Do not be yoked together with unbelievers. For what do righteousness and wickedness have in common? Or what fellowship can light have with darkness? 15 What harmony is there between Christ and Belial[a]? Or what does a believer have in common with an unbeliever? (2 Corinthians 6:14-15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 你们和不信的原不相配，不要同负一轭。义和不义有什么相交呢？光明和黑暗有什么相通呢？15 基督和彼列有什么相和呢？信主的和不信主的有什么相干呢？（哥林多后书 6：14–15 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 We demolish arguments and every pretension that sets itself up against the knowledge of God, and we take captive every thought to make it obedient to Christ. (2 /Corinthians 10:5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 将各样的计谋，各样拦阻人认识　神的那些自高之事，一概攻破了，又将人所有的心意夺回，使他都顺服基督。（哥林多后书 10：5 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of important reasons for having and using written Biblical confessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;使用书面的认信文件有许多重要原因&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. They provide beneficial summaries of Christian teaching.
b. They proclaim and impart the truths of God’s Word to people.
c. They distinguish and separate God’s truth from human, devil-inspired errors and heresies.
d. They establish and preserve the Christian faith of God’s believers.
e. They give praise and honor to God.
f. They serve as useful secondary sources of authority to help solve disputes or misunderstandings about the meaning of Scripture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. 它们提供了基督教教导的有益总结。
b. 它们向人们宣扬和传授神的话语的真理。
c. 它们将神的真理与从人而来、受魔鬼启发的错误和异端邪说区分开来。
d. 它们建立和维护神的信徒的基督教信仰。
e. 它们将赞美和荣耀献给神。
f. 它们可以作为有用的次要权威，来帮助解决对圣经经文的含义的争议或误解。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific formulations of confessions depend on a variety of matters such as: current issues that Christians are facing; historical developments; and the cultural context in which people live.  (Acts 15:1-31)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;认信的具体形式取决于各种因素，如：基督徒目前面临的问题；历史发展；以及人们生活的文化背景。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 Certain people came down from Judea to Antioch and were teaching the believers: “Unless you are circumcised, according to the custom taught by Moses, you cannot be saved.” 2 This brought Paul and Barnabas into sharp dispute and debate with them. So Paul and Barnabas were appointed, along with some other believers, to go up to Jerusalem to see the apostles and elders about this question. 3 The church sent them on their way, and as they traveled through Phoenicia and Samaria, they told how the Gentiles had been converted. This news made all the believers very glad. 4 When they came to Jerusalem, they were welcomed by the church and the apostles and elders, to whom they reported everything God had done through them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 Then some of the believers who belonged to the party of the Pharisees stood up and said, “The Gentiles must be circumcised and required to keep the law of Moses.”  6 The apostles and elders met to consider this question. 7 After much discussion, Peter got up and addressed them: “Brothers, you know that some time ago God made a choice among you that the Gentiles might hear from my lips the message of the gospel and believe. 8 God, who knows the heart, showed that he accepted them by giving the Holy Spirit to them, just as he did to us. 9 He did not discriminate between us and them, for he purified their hearts by faith. 10 Now then, why do you try to test God by putting on the necks of Gentiles a yoke that neither we nor our ancestors have been able to bear? 11 No! We believe it is through the grace of our Lord Jesus that we are saved, just as they are.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 The whole assembly became silent as they listened to Barnabas and Paul telling about the signs and wonders God had done among the Gentiles through them. 13 When they finished, James spoke up. “Brothers,” he said, “listen to me. 14 Simon[a] has described to us how God first intervened to choose a people for his name from the Gentiles. 15 The words of the prophets are in agreement with this, as it is written:
16 “‘After this I will return and rebuild David’s fallen tent Its ruins I will rebuild, and I will restore it, 17 that the rest of mankind may seek the Lord, even all the Gentiles who bear my name, says the Lord, who does these things ]— 18things known from long ago.  19 “It is my judgment, therefore, that we should not make it difficult for the Gentiles who are turning to God. 20 Instead we should write to them, telling them to abstain from food polluted by idols, from sexual immorality, from the meat of strangled animals and from blood. 21 For the law of Moses has been preached in every city from the earliest times and is read in the synagogues on every Sabbath.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 Then the apostles and elders, with the whole church, decided to choose some of their own men and send them to Antioch with Paul and Barnabas. They chose Judas (called Barsabbas) and Silas, men who were leaders among the believers. 23 With them they sent the following letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apostles and elders, your brothers,  To the Gentile believers in Antioch, Syria and Cilicia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24 We have heard that some went out from us without our authorization and disturbed you, troubling your minds by what they said. 25 So we all agreed to choose some men and send them to you with our dear friends Barnabas and Paul— 26 men who have risked their lives for the name of our Lord Jesus Christ. 27 Therefore we are sending Judas and Silas to confirm by word of mouth what we are writing. 28 It seemed good to the Holy Spirit and to us not to burden you with anything beyond the following requirements: 29 You are to abstain from food sacrificed to idols, from blood, from the meat of strangled animals and from sexual immorality. You will do well to avoid these things. Farewell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 So the men were sent off and went down to Antioch, where they gathered the church together and delivered the letter. 31 The people read it and were glad for its encouraging message. (Acts 15:1-31)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 有几个人从犹太下来，教训弟兄们说：「你们若不按摩西的规条受割礼，不能得救。」2 保罗、巴拿巴与他们大大地纷争辩论；众门徒就定规，叫保罗、巴拿巴和本会中几个人，为所辩论的，上耶路撒冷去见使徒和长老。3 于是教会送他们起行。他们经过腓尼基、撒马利亚，随处传说外邦人归主的事，叫众弟兄都甚欢喜。4 到了耶路撒冷，教会和使徒并长老都接待他们，他们就述说　神同他们所行的一切事。5 惟有几个信徒是法利赛教门的人，起来说：「必须给外邦人行割礼，吩咐他们遵守摩西的律法。」 6 使徒和长老聚会商议这事；7 辩论已经多了，彼得就起来，说：「诸位弟兄，你们知道　神早已在你们中间拣选了我，叫外邦人从我口中得听福音之道，而且相信。8 知道人心的　神也为他们作了见证，赐圣灵给他们，正如给我们一样；9 又借着信洁净了他们的心，并不分他们我们。10 现在为什么试探　神，要把我们祖宗和我们所不能负的轭放在门徒的颈项上呢？11 我们得救乃是因主耶稣的恩，和他们一样，这是我们所信的。」 12 众人都默默无声，听巴拿巴和保罗述说　神借他们在外邦人中所行的神迹奇事。13 他们住了声，雅各就说：「诸位弟兄，请听我的话。14 方才西门述说　神当初怎样眷顾外邦人，从他们中间选取百姓归于自己的名下；15 众先知的话也与这意思相合。16 正如经上所写的： 此后，我要回来， 重新修造大卫倒塌的帐幕， 把那破坏的重新修造建立起来， 17 叫余剩的人， 就是凡称为我名下的外邦人， 都寻求主。 18 这话是从创世以来显明这事的主说的。 19 「所以据我的意见，不可难为那归服　神的外邦人；20 只要写信，吩咐他们禁戒偶像的污秽和奸淫，并勒死的牲畜和血。21 因为从古以来，摩西的书在各城有人传讲，每逢安息日，在会堂里诵读。」 22 那时，使徒和长老并全教会定意从他们中间拣选人，差他们和保罗、巴拿巴同往安提阿去；所拣选的就是称呼巴撒巴的犹大和西拉。这两个人在弟兄中是作首领的。23 于是写信交付他们，内中说：「使徒和作长老的弟兄们问安提阿、叙利亚、基利家外邦众弟兄的安。24 我们听说，有几个人从我们这里出去，用言语搅扰你们，惑乱你们的心。其实我们并没有吩咐他们。25 所以，我们同心定意，拣选几个人，差他们同我们所亲爱的巴拿巴和保罗往你们那里去。26 这二人是为我主耶稣基督的名不顾性命的。27 我们就差了犹大和西拉，他们也要亲口诉说这些事。28 因为圣灵和我们定意不将别的重担放在你们身上，惟有几件事是不可少的，29 就是禁戒祭偶像的物和血，并勒死的牲畜和奸淫。这几件你们若能自己禁戒不犯就好了。愿你们平安！」 30 他们既奉了差遣，就下安提阿去，聚集众人，交付书信。31 众人念了，因为信上安慰的话就欢喜了。（使徒行传 15：1–31 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Differences in faith and knowledge affect the degree to which Christians can confess the faith.  For example, those who are blessed with a greater faith and knowledge or more personal freedom will be able to confess to a more extensive and clearer degree to the truths of God’s Word than those with a lesser faith and knowledge or less personal freedom.   (Matthew 13:23)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;信心和知识的差异会影响基督徒对信仰的认信程度。 例如，那些有更大信心和知识或更多个人自由的人，将能够比那些信心和知识较少或个人自由较少的人更广泛和更清晰地承认神的话语的真理。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 But the seed falling on good soil refers to someone who hears the word and understands it. This is the one who produces a crop, yielding a hundred, sixty or thirty times what was sown.”(Matthew 13:23)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 撒在好地上的，就是人听道明白了，后来结实，有一百倍的，有六十倍的，有三十倍的。」（马太福音 13：23 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confessors of the Christian faith are to make their confession in a manner that is pleasing to God and suitable for the occasion.  God calls on His Christians to confess:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督教信仰的认信者要以神所喜悦的方式和适合的场合进行认信。 神呼召祂的基督徒如此认信：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. clearly and intelligibly   (1 Corinthians 14:8-9) 清楚明白地&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 Again, if the trumpet does not sound a clear call, who will get ready for battle? 9 So it is with you. Unless you speak intelligible words with your tongue, how will anyone know what you are saying? You will just be speaking into the air. (1 Corinthians 14:8-9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 若吹无定的号声，谁能预备打仗呢？9 你们也是如此。舌头若不说容易明白的话，怎能知道所说的是什么呢？这就是向空说话了。（哥林多前书 14：8–9 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. truthfully  (2 Corinthians 2:17, 4:2;  Ephesians 4:15) 诚实地&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 Unlike so many, we do not peddle the word of God for profit. On the contrary, in Christ we speak before God with sincerity, as those sent from God. (2 Corinthians 2:17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 我们不像那许多人，为利混乱　神的道；乃是由于诚实，由于　神，在　神面前凭着基督讲道。（哥林多后书 2：17 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Rather, we have renounced secret and shameful ways; we do not use deception, nor do we distort the word of God. On the contrary, by setting forth the truth plainly we commend ourselves to everyone’s conscience in the sight of God. (2 Corinthians 4:2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 乃将那些暗昧可耻的事弃绝了；不行诡诈，不谬讲　神的道理，只将真理表明出来，好在　神面前把自己荐与各人的良心。（哥林多后书 4：2 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 Instead, speaking the truth in love, we will grow to become in every respect the mature body of him who is the head, that is, Christ. (Ephesians 4:15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 惟用爱心说诚实话，凡事长进，连于元首基督，（以弗所书 4：15 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. lovingly    (2 Corinthians 6:11; Ephesians 4:15) 有爱地&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 We have spoken freely to you, Corinthians, and opened wide our hearts to you.(2 Corinthians 6:11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 哥林多人哪，我们向你们，口是张开的，心是宽宏的。（哥林多后书 6：11 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 Instead, speaking the truth in love, we will grow to become in every respect the mature body of him who is the head, that is, Christ. (Ephesians 4:15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 惟用爱心说诚实话，凡事长进，连于元首基督，（以弗所书 4：15 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. gently and respectfully, not harshly and contentiously   (2 Timothy 2:24-26; 1 Peter 3:15b-16) 温和恭敬地，而不是严厉地，有争议地&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24 And the Lord’s servant must not be quarrelsome but must be kind to everyone, able to teach, not resentful. 25 Opponents must be gently instructed, in the hope that God will grant them repentance leading them to a knowledge of the truth, 26 and that they will come to their senses and escape from the trap of the devil, who has taken them captive to do his will. (2 Timothy 2:24-26)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24 然而主的仆人不可争竞，只要温温和和地待众人，善于教导，存心忍耐，25 用温柔劝戒那抵挡的人；或者　神给他们悔改的心，可以明白真道，26 叫他们这已经被魔鬼任意掳去的，可以醒悟，脱离他的网罗。（提摩太后书 2：24–26 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 But in your hearts revere Christ as Lord. Always be prepared to give an answer to everyone who asks you to give the reason for the hope that you have. But do this with gentleness and respect, 16 keeping a clear conscience, so that those who speak maliciously against your good behavior in Christ may be ashamed of their slander. (1 Peter 3:15b-16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16 存着无亏的良心，叫你们在何事上被毁谤，就在何事上可以叫那诬赖你们在基督里有好品行的人自觉羞愧。（彼得前书 3：15b–16 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e. bravely and perseveringly   (2 Timothy 4:2,5) 勇敢，锲而不舍地&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Preach the word; be prepared in season and out of season; correct, rebuke and encourage—with great patience and careful instruction. .  . 5 But you, keep your head in all situations, endure hardship, do the work of an evangelist, discharge all the duties of your ministry.  (2 Timothy 4:2,5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 务要传道，无论得时不得时总要专心，并用百般的忍耐、各样的教训责备人，警戒人，劝勉人。5 你却要凡事谨慎，忍受苦难，做传道的工夫，尽你的职分。（提摩太后书 4：2，5 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who faithfully confess the Christian faith should expect that they will face some form of hardship or persecution from the enemies of God.  (2 Timothy 2:3; 3:12; Philippians 1:29)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Join with me in suffering, like a good soldier of Christ Jesus. (2 Timothy 2:3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;那些忠实地认信基督教信仰的人应该预料到，他们将更多的面临某些来自上帝敌人的艰难或迫害。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 In fact, everyone who wants to live a godly life in Christ Jesus will be persecuted, (2 Timothy 3:12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 不但如此，凡立志在基督耶稣里敬虔度日的也都要受逼迫。（提摩太后书 3：12 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 For it has been granted to you on behalf of Christ not only to believe in him, but also to suffer for him, (Philippians 1:29)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 因为你们蒙恩，不但得以信服基督，并要为他受苦。（腓立比书 1：29 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confessors of the Christian faith can also be comforted and strengthened by the knowledge that God will support them through their trials and ultimately deliver them from all earthly pain and loss.   (Hebrews 10:23, 32-39)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督教信仰的认信者也会得到安慰和力量，因为他们知道上帝将支持他们度过考验，并最终将他们从所有世上的痛苦和损失中解救出来。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 Let us hold unswervingly to the hope we profess, for he who promised is faithful. (Hebrews 10:23)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 也要坚守我们所承认的指望，不至摇动，因为那应许我们的是信实的。（希伯来书 10：23 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;32 Remember those earlier days after you had received the light, when you endured in a great conflict full of suffering. 33 Sometimes you were publicly exposed to insult and persecution; at other times you stood side by side with those who were so treated. 34 You suffered along with those in prison and joyfully accepted the confiscation of your property, because you knew that you yourselves had better and lasting possessions. 35 So do not throw away your confidence; it will be richly rewarded. 36 You need to persevere so that when you have done the will of God, you will receive what he has promised. 37 For, “In just a little while, he who is coming will come and will not delay”  38 And, “But my righteous one will live by faith.  And I take no pleasure in the one who shrinks back.”  39 But we do not belong to those who shrink back and are destroyed, but to those who have faith and are saved. (Hebrews 10:32-39)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;32 你们要追念往日，蒙了光照以后所忍受大争战的各样苦难：33 一面被毁谤，遭患难，成了戏景，叫众人观看；一面陪伴那些受这样苦难的人。34 因为你们体恤了那些被捆锁的人，并且你们的家业被人抢去，也甘心忍受，知道自己有更美长存的家业。35 所以，你们不可丢弃勇敢的心；存这样的心必得大赏赐。36 你们必须忍耐，使你们行完了　神的旨意，就可以得着所应许的。 37 因为还有一点点时候， 那要来的就来，并不迟延； 38 只是义人必因信得生。 他若退后，我心里就不喜欢他。 39 我们却不是退后入沉沦的那等人，乃是有信心以致灵魂得救的人。（希伯来书 10：32–39 )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Confessing Christian is a Biblical Christian.  A Biblical Christian is one who believes that Jesus Christ is his Savior from sin and eternal death.   He believes that the Bible is the true Word of God and accepts the Bible as the only source of spiritual authority and belief.  He also believes that people are saved as a gift of God’s undeserved love through faith in the redeeming work of Jesus Christ apart from their own works.  He also accepts the doctrines taught in written Christian confessions that are completely faithful to the teachings of the Bible.  In faithfulness to the teachings of the Bible, this person is diligent to make sure that the true, Biblical Christian faith is actually preached, taught and put into practice.  Some of the major, faithful written confessions are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;认信的基督徒是一个信仰符合圣经的基督徒。 这样的基督徒是相信耶稣基督是使他脱离罪恶和永恒死亡的救主。  他相信《圣经》是上帝的真话，并接受《圣经》作为属灵权威和信心的唯一来源。 他还相信，人们通过对耶稣基督救赎工作的信仰而得救，救恩是上帝所赐的，人不配得的爱的礼物，与人自己的行为无关。 他还接受基督教认信文件中所教导的教义，认可这些教义完全忠实于圣经的教导。 为了忠于《圣经》的教导，基督徒要勤勉地确保真正的、符合《圣经》的基督教信仰确实的被传讲、教导并付诸实践。 一些主要的、忠实的基督教认信文件包括：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Apostles’ Creed 使徒信经&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Nicene Creed 尼西亚信经&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Athanasian Creed 亚那他修信经&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martin Luther’s Small Catechism马丁路德小教理问答&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martin Luther’s Large Catechism 马丁路德大教理问答&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Augsburg Confession 奥格斯堡信条&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Apology (Defense) of the Augsburg Confession 奥格斯堡信条辩护书&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Smalcald Articles 施马加登条款&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Formula of Concord 协同书&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-3-review-questions-复习题&#34;&gt;Part 3 Review Questions 复习题&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why must the Bible be the source and standard for the things a person confesses about the Christian faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么说圣经必须是一个人认信基督教信仰的唯一的来源和标准？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do false religious teachings have to be condemned at times when a Christian confesses the faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么说基督徒在认信自己的信仰时，有时必须谴责虚假的宗教教义？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are 3 major reasons why you would use a written Biblical confession in your service to God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请列举三点原因来说明为什么在你的侍奉中要使用书面的认信文件？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it important that a Christian “speak the truth in love” when making a confession of Christian teaching?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么基督徒在认信基督教教义时要 &amp;ldquo;用爱心说诚实话&amp;rdquo;？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What helps a Christian make a faithful confession when encountering hardship or opposition?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在遇到艰难或抵挡时，什么能帮助基督徒做出忠信的认信？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List 3 written confessions besides the Christian Creeds that are faithful to Biblical teaching?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;除了基督教信经之外，请列举三个合乎圣经教导的书面认信文件。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第四课 基督教信经</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/211/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/211/4/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;a-creeds-defined-信经的定义&#34;&gt;A. Creeds Defined 信经的定义&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word “creed” comes from the Latin word “credo”, which means “I believe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“信经”一词来源于拉丁语 “credo”， 这个字的本意是 “我相信”。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A creed is basically “a statement of what a group of people believes and confesses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;信经从根本上来说是指“一个群体对他们所相信和认信的内容所做出的一份声明”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more complete and specific definition of a creed: A creed is “a firmly established statement that summarizes the essential articles of a religion and that enjoys the formal approval of religious authorities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;信经更完整和具体的定义：信经是 &amp;ldquo;一份牢固确立的声明，概括了一个宗教信仰的基本条款，并得到了其权威的正式认可&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Christian creed is a formal, authorized statement and confession of biblical, Christian teaching and belief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督教信经是一份正式的、被认可的声明，同时也是一份合乎圣经和基督教教导及其信仰的书面认信。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;b-the-purposes-of-christian-creeds基督教信经的目的&#34;&gt;B. The Purposes Of Christian Creeds基督教信经的目的&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To proclaim and summarize the biblical teachings that Christians believe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;宣扬和总结基督徒所相信的圣经教义&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To teach people the vital doctrines necessary for salvation and church membership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;教导人们关乎救恩和加入教会所需的关键教义&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To unite and identify people together in a true Christian fellowship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;使人可以认出真正的基督教团契并且在其中彼此联合&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To defend the truth of God’s Word against false teachers and false teachings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;捍卫上帝话语中的真理，抵挡假教师和假教导&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To preserve the faith of God’s people in Bible truth and against false belief&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保守神的子民在圣经真理中的信仰，抵挡错误的信仰&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;c-the-creation-of-christian-creeds基督教信条的制定&#34;&gt;C. The Creation Of Christian Creeds基督教信条的制定&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creeds were developed primarily because of some particular need or challenge that Christians faced.  Some of these situations were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;信条的制定主要是由于基督徒们面临的一些特殊需要或挑战。 其中一些情况是&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People needed to be instructed properly for baptism and church membership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;人们需要接受合宜的教导来领受洗礼并加入教会&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dangerous spiritual errors developed that threatened the true belief of Christians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;产生了危险的属灵谬误，威胁到基督徒的真正信仰&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians desired and required ways to promote scriptural unity among themselves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒渴望并且需要有具体的办法来促进他们在灵里的合一&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians desired to fulfill God’s will that they testify to God and His saving work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒希望能成就神的旨意，即为神和祂的救赎之功做见证&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians needed ways to determine those who hold faithfully to biblical teaching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒需要有方法来辨识出那些忠实于圣经教导的人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;d-terms-used-to-describe-christians-creeds用于描述基督教信条的术语&#34;&gt;D. Terms Used To Describe Christians Creeds用于描述基督教信条的术语&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Symbol” = the confession of faith serves as a distinctive identifying mark or emblem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;符号、标志&amp;rdquo;=以某种独特的识别标志或徽章来表达对信仰内容的认信&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Rule of faith” = a clear statement that serves as a test to determine correct belief&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;信仰的规则&amp;rdquo; = 一个明确的声明，用以检验并且辨识出正确信仰&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Foundation” = a settled statement of true belief and basic principles that allows for new formulations and  clarifications of biblical teaching to be developed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;根基&amp;rdquo;=对真实信仰和基本原则的固定陈述，并且可以按圣经教导对其进行新的表述和澄清&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Norma normata” (Latin = literally “the ruled rule” or “the authorized authority”, the creed serves as a secondary, lesser determiner of true teaching.  God’s Word, the Bible, is the “norma normans” (literally, “the ruling rule”) which is the primary determiner of true   teaching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Norma normata&amp;rdquo;（拉丁语=字面意思是&amp;quot;用以制定规则的规则&amp;quot;或 &amp;ldquo;用以授权的权柄&amp;rdquo;，信经作为正确教导的次级的、低一等的决定因素。 上帝的话语，即圣经，是 &amp;ldquo;norma normans&amp;rdquo;（字面意思是 &amp;ldquo;用以制定规则的规则&amp;rdquo;），圣经是正确教导的主要决定因素。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Passport to Communion” =  acceptance and confession of the creed allowed a person to be welcomed in the Christian community and partake of Holy Communion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;圣餐通行证（护照）&amp;quot;=接受并承认信经，就可以被基督徒团体接纳并一同领受圣餐。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;e-the-ecumenical-christian-creeds基督教大公信经&#34;&gt;E. The Ecumenical Christian Creeds基督教大公信经&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word “ecumenical” refers to the general worldwide influence, acceptance and application of these statements of belief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;大公 &amp;ldquo;一词是指这些信仰声明在世界范围内的具有普遍影响、被认可且应用。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These creeds all have teachings that are drawn from the Bible, proclaim the saving work of Jesus Christ and express the persons and work of the Triune God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这些信经都包含来自于圣经的教导，传讲耶稣基督的救赎之功，表述三位一体上帝的位格和工作。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three ecumenical creeds are 三个普世大公信经是&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) The Apostles’ Creed 使徒信经&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) The Nicene Creed 尼西亚信经&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c) The Athanasian Creed 亚他那修信经&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-iv-review-questions复习题&#34;&gt;Part IV Review Questions复习题&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a creed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;什么是信经？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List three reasons why Christians have developed and make use of creeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;列出基督徒制定和使用信经的三个原因。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are we saying about a creed when we call it a “symbol”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们称某个信经内容为 &amp;ldquo;符号、标志 &amp;ldquo;时，这条信经包含着怎样的意义？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are we saying about a creed when we call it a “norma nomata”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们称某个信经内容为 &amp;ldquo;用以制定规则的规则&amp;quot;时，这条信经包含着怎样的意义？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第五课 使徒信经</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/211/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/211/5/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;a-the-text-of-the-apostles-creed-使徒信经的文本&#34;&gt;A. The Text Of The Apostles’ Creed 《使徒信经》的文本&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in God, the Father almighty, maker of heaven and earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in Jesus Christ, His only Son, our Lord, who was conceived by the Holy Spirit, born of the virgin Mary, suffered under Pontius Pilate, was crucified, died and was buried.  He descended into hell.   The third day He rose again from the dead.  He ascended into heaven and is seated at the right hand of God the Father almighty.   From there He will come to judge the living and the dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in the Holy Spirit, the holy Christian Church, the communion of saints, the forgiveness of sins, the resurrection of the body, and the life everlasting.   Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信上帝，全能的父，创造天地的主。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信我主耶稣基督，上帝的独生子； 因着圣灵成孕，由童贞女马利亚所生； 在本丢彼拉多手下受难，被钉于十字架，受死，埋葬； 降在阴间； 第三天从死人中复活； 升天，坐在全能父上帝的右边； 将来必从那里降临，审判活人，死人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信圣灵； 我信圣而公之教会； 我信圣徒相通； 我信罪得赦免，我信身体复活； 我信永生。 阿们！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;b-characteristics-of-the-apostles-creed-使徒信经的特点&#34;&gt;B. Characteristics Of The Apostles’ Creed 《使徒信经》的特点&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed is Trinitarian. It has three parts that confess the three Persons of the Godhead revealed in Bible verses such as Matthew 28:19-20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经是三位一体式的。它有三个部分，分别认信马太福音28:19-20等圣经经文中所启示的神的三个位格。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed presents an orderly, historical, scriptural treatment of the divinely revealed plan of salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;信经对神所启示的救赎计划进行了有序的、基于史实的、符合圣经的处理。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed treats the fundamental articles of the Christian faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;信经论述了基督教信仰的基本条款。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed professes living facts and saving truths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;信经声明了鲜活的事实和救恩的真理。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed employs simple, clear, scriptural language.   “Christian truth could not possibly be put into a shorter and clearer statement (than in the Apostle’s Creed).” – Martin Luther&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经采用简明、清晰、合乎圣经的语言。  &amp;ldquo;基督教的真理不可能（比使徒信经）有更简短和更清晰的陈述了&amp;rdquo;- 马丁-路德&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apostles’ Creed is regarded as the “Creed of Baptism and of the Catechumen”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;使徒信经被视为 &amp;ldquo;预备洗礼和慕道者的信经&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed was developed gradually over a period of hundreds of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经是在数百年的时间里逐渐完善起来的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;c-the-development-of-the-apostles-creed使徒信经的发展&#34;&gt;C. The Development Of The Apostles’ Creed《使徒信经》的发展&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many years, the creed was incorrectly thought to be written by the Twelve Apostles.  The myth declared that the Holy Spirit prompted the Apostles to write the creed at the time of Pentecost.  Saint Peter is said to have written the first phrase and then each apostle wrote another phrase until the last apostle, Matthias, wrote the final phrase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;许多年来，人们错误地认为信条是由十二个使徒写的。 人们传说，圣灵在五旬节时促使使徒们写下了该信经。 据说圣彼得写了第一句话，然后每个使徒写了另一句话，直到最后一个使徒马提亚写了最后一句话。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Jesus’ Twelve Apostles did not write the creed, the contents of the creed are based on the teachings that the divinely inspired Apostles recorded in the New Testament.  “If the Apostles’ Creed was never actually compiled by the Apostles, it was faithfully put together out of their writings.” – John Calvin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;虽然耶稣的十二个使徒没有写该信经，但信经的内容是基于使徒们在神所启示的新约中记录的教义。 &amp;ldquo;即便使徒们实际上从未亲自编撰《使徒信经》，然而它仍是从他们的著作中忠实地摘选出来的&amp;rdquo;- 约翰-加尔文。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed is a product of the Western Church (the part of the Church that developed in the western part of the Roman Empire, primarily in western Europe and northern Africa).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;信经是西方教会（在罗马帝国西部，主要在西欧和北非发展的那部分教会）的产物。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early centuries after Christ, local Christian churches developed oral baptismal creeds which were used as confessions by those being instructed for Baptism and church membership.   These creeds were interrogative in nature, employing a question-and-answer format.  The three primary baptismal questions were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在基督之后的几个世纪里，各个地方的基督教会制定了口头的洗礼信条，这些信条用来给那些预备接受洗礼和加入教会的人作为认信的内容。  这些信条具有询问性质，采用了问答的形式。 三个主要的洗礼问题是。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Do you believe in God the Father?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你相信父神吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Do you believe in Jesus Christ, the Son of God, who was incarnate and died and rose again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你是否相信上帝的儿子耶稣基督，祂曾道成肉身，死而复活？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Do you believe in the Holy Spirit of God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你相信圣灵吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written creeds started to appear at the beginning of the 2nd Century.  Ignatius was one of the first to record a creed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第二世纪初，书面信经文本开始出现。 伊格那丢（Ignatius）是最早记录信经的人之一。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ireneaus (Asia Minor and France) and Tertullian (Carthage) continued the development of written creeds at the end of the 2nd Century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;爱任纽（Ireneaus）（小亚细亚和法国）和特图良（迦太基）在2世纪末继续发展书面的信经。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The churches in Rome, Aquileia, Milan, Ravenna, Carthage and Hippo provided the most popular forms of a baptismal creed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马、阿奎利亚、米兰、拉文纳、迦太基和希波的教会提供了最流行的洗礼信经的形式。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Early Roman Baptismal Creed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in God, the Father Almighty,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in Christ Jesus, His only Son, our Lord,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the Holy Spirit, the holy Church, the resurrection of the body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;早期罗马洗礼信经&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信上帝，全能的父。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信基督耶稣，祂的独生子，我们的主。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信圣灵、圣洁的教会、身体的复活。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcellus of Ancyra (340 A.D.) gave the Greek form and Rufinus of Aquileia gave the Latin form of the Roman Creed by the end of the 4th Century.  This Roman Creed would serve as the basic model for the Apostles’ Creed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;安吉拉的马塞勒斯（Marcellus of Ancyra）（公元340年）供献了希腊语版本。阿奎利亚的鲁菲努斯在4世纪末给出了拉丁语形式的罗马信经。 这个罗马信经将作为《使徒信经》的基本模板。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Old Roman Creed旧罗马信经&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in God the Father Almighty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in Jesus Christ, His only Son, our Lord, who was born of the Holy Spirit of the Virgin Mary, who under Pontius Pilate was crucified and buried. The third day He rose from the dead, He ascended into heaven and sits on the right hand of the Father. From there He shall come to judge the living and the dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the Holy Spirit, the holy Church, the forgiveness of sins, the resurrection of the body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信全能的父神。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信耶稣基督，祂的独生子，我们的主，祂藉圣灵从童贞女玛利亚所生，在本丢彼拉多手下被钉死并埋葬。第三天，祂从死里复活，升天，坐在父的右边。祂将来必从那里降临，审判活人，死人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信圣灵、我信圣洁的教会、我信罪得赦免、我信身体的复活。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roman Creed was expanded gradually by borrowing good phrases from other creeds over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马信经是通过多年来借用其他信经中的好词好句逐步扩展的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expanded Roman Creed gained wide acceptance throughout the Western Church because of its excellence and because of the commanding position of the Church of Rome.   It achieved special prominence in the 8th Century when the bishop of Rome and the Emperor pushed for liturgical uniformity in the Western Churches by adopting the Roman order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;扩展后的《罗马信经》在整个西方教会中获得了广泛的接受，因为它很出色的，也因为罗马教会的指导地位。  该信经在8世纪取得了特别突出的地位，当时罗马主教和皇帝通过采用罗马教规来推动西方教会的仪文统一。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pirminius, a Benedictine monk and founder of the Abbey of Reichenau in southern Germany, is the first to record the final version of the Apostles Creed.   He wrote it in his treatise, Scarapsus in 730 A.D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;皮尔米尼乌斯（Pirminius），本笃会修士，德国南部莱切诺修道院的创始人，是第一个记录《使徒信经》最终版本的人。  公元730年，他在他的论文《Scarapsus（皮尔米尼乌斯修道院院长的讲话，单行本的摘录）》中记载了该信经。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;d-a-challenging-interpretation一个解读的难题&#34;&gt;D. A Challenging Interpretation一个解读的难题&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most controversial and difficult phrase to understand in the Apostles’ Creed is the term translated “the communion of saints.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《使徒信经》中最有争议和最难理解的是翻译成 &amp;ldquo;圣徒相通&amp;quot;的那一句话。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original Latin has the words “sanctorum communion” and the Greek form uses the words “koinonia ton hagion”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;拉丁文原文是 &amp;ldquo;sanctorum communion&amp;rdquo;，希腊文则是 &amp;ldquo;koinonia ton hagion&amp;rdquo;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These words have traditionally been translated “the fellowship of the holy.”   This translation would refer to “the fellowship of holy people “, that is, the believers who are holy in Christ Jesus, both those who live on earth and those who have died and now live in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这些词传统上被翻译为 &amp;ldquo;神圣的团契（the fellowship of the holy ）&amp;quot;。  这种译法应该意指的是 &amp;ldquo;圣徒的团契（the fellowship of holy people ）&amp;quot;，即在基督耶稣里被分别为圣的信徒，包括那些生活在地上的人和那些已经死亡而在天堂的人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These words could also be translated “the participation in the holy” This translation would refer to “the participation in the holy things”, that is, the elements of Holy Communion.  People who favor this view question why the creed would include two phrases (“the Holy Christian Church, the communion of saints”) that say essentially the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这些词也可以翻译为 &amp;ldquo;在圣洁中有份的（the participation in the holy ）&amp;quot;，这种译法意指&amp;quot;在神圣的事物中有份的（the participation in the holy things ）&amp;quot;，即圣餐中所包含的事物。 赞成这种观点的人质疑为什么信经会用两个短语（&amp;ldquo;圣而公之教会，圣徒相同&amp;rdquo;）来认信从本质上来说的同一件事。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of scholars have favored the traditional translation and interpretation “communion of saints” or “the fellowship of the holy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;绝大多数学者都赞成传统的翻译和解释 &amp;ldquo;圣徒相通&amp;quot;或 &amp;ldquo;圣徒的团契&amp;rdquo;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;e-the-value-and-use-of-the-apostles-creed-使徒信经的价值和使用&#34;&gt;E. The Value And Use Of The Apostles’ Creed 《使徒信经》的价值和使用&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed offers basic instruction in the Gospel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经提供了关于福音的基本教导&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed is a helpful aid for public confession of faith in worship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经为在崇拜中公开表明信仰提供了有用的帮助&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed identifies the basis principles of Christian belief&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经确定了基督教信仰的基本准则&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed aids in personal examination and spiritual renewal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经有助于个人省察和灵里的更新&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed fosters unity and harmony in faith among Christians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信条促进了基督徒在信仰上的团结与和睦&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-v-review-questions--复习题&#34;&gt;Part V Review Questions  复习题&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is one of the outstanding features of the Apostles’ Creed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《使徒信经》的一个突出特点是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is the name “Apostles’ Creed” a good name for the creed, even though it was not written by the Apostles of Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么《使徒信经》这个名字对该信经来说是个好名字，尽管它并不是由基督的使徒们写的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what important purpose were simple, oral Trinity-confessing creeds developed in the early centuries after Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在基督之后的几个世纪里，简洁、用以口头承认三位一体的信经是为了什么重要目的而制定的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the name of the creed that served as the model for the Apostles’ Creed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《使徒信经》是以那个信经为底版写成的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is “the communion of saints” that we confess in the Apostles’ Creed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们在《使徒信经》中所认信的 &amp;ldquo;圣徒相通&amp;quot;是什么意思？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第六课 尼西亚信经</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/211/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/211/6/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;a-the-text-of-the-nicene-creed-尼西亚信经的文本&#34;&gt;A. The Text Of The Nicene Creed 尼西亚信经的文本&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in one God, the Father Almighty, maker of heaven and earth and of all things visible and invisible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in one Lord Jesus Christ, the only begotten Son of God, begotten of His Father before all worlds, God of God, Light of Light, very God of very God, begotten, not made, being of one substance with the Father, by whom all things were made; who for us men and for our salvation came down from heaven and was incarnate by the Holy Spirit of the virgin Mary and was made man; and was crucified also for us under Pontius Pilate.   He suffered and was buried.   And the third day He rose again according to the Scriptures and ascended into heaven and sits at the right hand of the Father.   And He will come again with glory to judge both the living and the dead, whose kingdom will have no end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I believe in the Holy Spirit, the Lord and Giver of life, who proceeds from the Father and the Son, who with the Father and the Son together is worshiped and glorified, who spoke by the prophets.   And I believe in one holy Christian and apostolic Church.   I acknowledge one Baptism for the remission of sins, and I look for the resurrection of the dead and the life of the world to come.  Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信独一上帝，全能的父，创造天地和有形无形万物的主。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信独一主耶稣基督，上帝的独生子，在万世以前为父所生，出于神而为神，出于光而为光，出于真神而为真神，受生而非被造，与父一体，万物都是借着他造的；&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为要拯救我们世人，从天降临，因着圣灵，并从童女马利亚成肉身，而为人；在本丢彼拉多手下，为我们钉于十字架上，受难，埋葬；照圣经第三天复活；并升天，坐在父的右边；将来必有荣耀再降临，审判活人死人；他的国度永无穷尽；&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信圣灵，赐生命的主，从父和子出来，与父子同受敬拜，同受尊荣，他曾借众先知说话。我信独一神圣大公使徒的教会；我认使罪得赦的独一洗礼；我望死人复活；并来世生命。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Characteristics Of The Nicene Creed尼西亚信经的特点&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed is similar in outline and content to the Apostles’ Creed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经在结构和内容上与《使徒信经》相似。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed is Trinitarian, confessing the three Persons of God and their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经是三位一体式的。分别认信上帝的三个位格和祂们的工作。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed emphasizes the eternal being of Christ and His activity before His incarnation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经强调基督的永恒性和祂在道成肉身前的作为。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed places the work of salvation in its cosmic context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经把救赎的事工放在宇宙的背景中。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed strongly emphasizes the divinity of Jesus, the Son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经强烈地强调了圣子耶稣的神性。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed was fashioned to address a doctrinal controversy about Jesus Christ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经的制定是为了解决关于耶稣基督的教义争论&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed is the most widely accepted creed in the Christian Church on earth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经是地上基督教会中最广泛接受的信条。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed is considered to be “the Creed of the communicant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经被认为是 &amp;ldquo;领受圣餐的圣徒的信经&amp;rdquo;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed is “conciliar.”  It is the product of an official Church Council that defines orthodox belief and possesses more than local authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经是由&amp;quot;教会大公会议发布的&amp;quot;。 它是一个正式的教会大公会议的产物，它定义了正统的信仰，拥有超过地方的权威。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;c-the-development-of-the-nicene-creed尼西亚信条的发展&#34;&gt;C. The Development Of The Nicene Creed尼西亚信条的发展&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed was produced by the Eastern Church (the part of the Church that developed in eastern part of the Roman Empire, primarily in eastern Europe. western Asia and eastern Africa)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信条由东方教会（在罗马帝国东部发展起来的教会部分，主要在东欧、西亚和非洲东部）产生。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Arian Conflict (320-360 A.D.) prompted the writing of the creed.   Arius, a priest of Alexandria, Egypt, developed a widely accepted heresy that the Son is not true God and is also not eternal.   Arius believed that Christ was an exalted, created being through whom God the Father created the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;阿里乌斯派之争（公元320-360年）促使了信条的撰写。  埃及亚历山大的牧师阿里乌斯提出了一个被广泛接受的异端，即圣子不是真神，也不是永恒的。  阿里乌斯认为，基督是一个高高在上的受造物，父神通过他创造了世界。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emperor Constantine called the first ecumenical Council in order to end division in the Christian church, to promote peace and unity in his empire, and to protect the reputation of the Christian religion by finding a formula to express clearly what the church believed about the Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;君士坦丁皇帝召集了第一次大公会议，以结束基督教会的分裂，促进其帝国的和平与团结，并通过找到一个公式来明确表达教会对主耶稣基督的信仰，从而保护基督教的声誉。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;318 bishops of the church met to form this Council in Nicea (a city near Constantinople, which is modern day Istanbul) during May and June of 325 A.D.  All the delegates were from Eastern churches, except for Hosius of Cordova, Spain who was sent by the bishop of Rome and served as chairman of the Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;公元325年5月和6月期间，教会的318位主教在尼西亚（君士坦丁堡附近的城市，也就是今天的伊斯坦布尔）开会组成了这个会议。所有代表都来自东方教会，只有西班牙科尔多瓦的霍修斯受罗马主教派遣，担任会议主席。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council rejected a creed proposed by the followers of Arius which denied Christ’s eternally begotten Sonship and His oneness in essence with the Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;大公会议否决了阿里乌斯的追随者提出的信经，该信经否认了基督的永生之子身份以及祂与天父在本质上的一体性。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council accepted a creed proposed by Eusebius of Caesarea as the basis for a new confession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;大公会议接受了凯撒利亚的尤西比乌斯提出的信条，作为新的信经的基础。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Model Oriental Creed 东方教会信经范本&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in one God, the Father Almighty, Maker of all things visible and invisible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in one Lord Jesus Christ, the only-begotten Son of God, begotten of His Father before all worlds, by whom all things were made, who for our salvation was made man.  He suffered, and the third day He rose again, and ascended into heaven, and He shall come again to judge both the living and the dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信独一真神，就是全能的父，是一切有形和无形事物的创造者。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信独一主耶稣基督，祂是神的独生子，在万世之前由祂的父所生，万物是祂所造，祂为救我们而作人。 祂受难，第三天复活，升到天上，祂要再来，审判活人和死人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信圣灵。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council debate centered on which of two Greek words “homoousious” (which means “of the same  essence” and was preferred by the orthodox church leaders) and “homoiousios” (which means “of a similar essence” and was preferred by some supporters of Arius) most accurately expressed the nature of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;大公会议的辩论集中在两个希腊词&amp;quot;homoousious&amp;quot;（意思是 &amp;ldquo;相同的本质&amp;rdquo;，正统的教会领袖倾向于这个词）和 &amp;ldquo;homoiousios&amp;rdquo;（意思是 &amp;ldquo;相似的本质&amp;rdquo;，被阿里乌斯的一些支持者倾向于这个词）中，哪个最准确地表达基督的本质。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council amended Eusebius’ creed to include the word “homoousios”, to affirm the full divinity of the Son, and to include a curse against those who held the view of the Arians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;大公会议更正了尤西比乌斯的信条，加入了 &amp;ldquo;homoousios &amp;ldquo;一词，肯定了圣子的完全神性，并加入了对持有亚流派观点的人的诅咒。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They gave approval to the original Nicene Creed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;他们批准了最初的《尼西亚信条》。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Original Nicene Creed of 325 A.D. 公元325年的《尼西亚信条》原文。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in one God, the Father Almighty, Maker of all things visible and invisible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in one Lord Jesus Christ, the Son of God, begotten of the Father (the only begotten; that is, of the essence of the Father, God of God, Light of Light, very God of very God, begotten, not made, being of one substance (homoousion) with the Father; by whom all things were made both in heaven and on earth; who for us men, and for our salvation, came down and was incarnate and was made man; He suffered, and the third day He rose again, ascended into heaven; from there He will come to judge the living and the dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But those who say: ‘There was a time when He was not;” and ‘He was not before He was made:’ and ‘He was made out of nothing.’ Or ‘He is of another substance’ or ‘essence,’ or ‘The Son of God is created,’ or ‘changeable’ or ‘alterable’ – they are condemned by the holy catholic and apostolic Church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们相信独一的神，全能的父，是一切有形和无形事物的创造者。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们相信独一的主耶稣基督，是神的儿子，由父所生（独生子；也就是与父的本质相同，出于神而为神，出于光而为光，出于真神而为真神，受生而非被造，与父同质（相同的本质）。天上地下万物都是由祂造的；祂为了我们这些人，为了救我们，降世为人；受难，第三天复活，升天，祂要从那里来审判活人和死人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们信圣灵。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;若有人说：‘祂不存在于某个时段中’；‘在祂被造之前，祂不存在’；‘祂是从无有中被造’或‘祂是另一种物质’或‘本质’，或‘上帝的儿子是被造的’，或‘是可改变的’或‘可变化的’ - 他们将被圣而公之、使徒教会咒诅。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arius and his followers were given the choice to accept the Nicene Creed as their confession by signing it or to be sent into exile.   Arius and his followers refused to accept the creed and chose exile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;阿里乌斯和他的追随者可以选择通过签署尼西亚信条来接受它作为他们的认信，或者被送去流放。  阿里乌斯和他的追随者拒绝接受该信条，选择了流放。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quarreling continued between the orthodox and Arian groups for many years after the Council of Nicea.   Athanasius of Alexandria (293-373 A.D.) emerged as the brave champion for orthodox, biblical teaching.   From 350-354 A. D., he wrote “Concerning the Decrees of the Council of Nicea” to refute the Arians, who had won the sympathies of emperors after Constantine with their weak and erring form of Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;尼西亚会议之后，正统派和阿里乌派之间的争论持续了许多年。  亚历山大的亚他那修（293-373 A.D.）成为正统的、符合圣经的教义的勇敢支持者。  公元350-354年，他写了《关于尼西亚会议的法令》来驳斥亚流派，当时亚流派以其式微的和错误的基督教信仰赢得了君士坦丁之后皇帝们的同情。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 381 A. D., Emperor Theodosius convened the second ecumenical Council in Constantinople to deal with the Pneumatomachians (who denied the divinity of the Holy Spirit) and other errors.   The 150 Eastern church bishops who met at the Council decided to address this and other doctrinal issues by using material that Cyril introduced from the Creed of Jerusalem of 348 A.D. to amend and enlarge the original Nicene Creed.   They made several minor changes in the articles that dealt with the Father and the Son, added several phrases to the third article about the Holy Spirit, and deleted the curse against the Arians to produce the Niceano-Constantinopolitan Creed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;公元381年，狄奥多西皇帝在君士坦丁堡召开了第二次大公会议，以处理Pneumatomachians（否认圣灵的神性）和其他错误。  参加大公会议的150位东方教会主教决定利用西里尔（Cyril）从公元348年的《耶路撒冷信经》中引入的材料来解决这个问题和其他教义问题，以修正和扩大原来的《尼西亚信经》。  他们对涉及圣父和圣子的条款做了一些细微的修改，在关于圣灵的第三条中增加了几个短语，并删除了对亚流派的诅咒，从而产生了《尼西亚-康斯坦丁堡信条（Niceano-Constantinopolitan Creed）》。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Niceano-Constantinopolitan Creed尼西亚-康斯坦丁堡信条（Niceano-Constantinopolitan Creed）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in one God, the Father Almighty, Maker of heaven and earth, and of all things visible and invisible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in one Lord Jesus Christ, the only begotten Son of God, begotten of the Father before all worlds, Light of light, very God of very God, begotten, not made, being of one substance with the Father; by whom all things were made; who for us men, and for our salvation, came down from heaven, and was incarnate by the Holy Spirit of the Virgin Mary, and was made man; He was crucified for us under Pontius Pilate, and suffered and was buried, and the third day He rose again, according to the Scriptures, and ascended into heaven, and sits on the right hand of the Father; from there He shall come again, with glory, to judge the living and the dead; whose kingdom shall have no end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the Holy Spirit, the Lord and Giver of life, who proceeds from the Father, who with the Father and the Son together is worshiped and glorified, who spoke by the prophets.  In one holy catholic and apostolic Church; we acknowledge one baptism for the remission of sins; we look for the resurrection of the dead, and the life of the world to come.  Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我等信独一之神，即全能之圣父，创造天地，及一切有形无形之万物之主。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我等信独一之主耶稣基督，上帝独生之圣子，是圣父在万世之先所生，是从神所出之神，从光所出之光，从真神所出之真神，是生非造，是与圣父同体，万物皆藉圣子而造；圣子为要拯救我等世人，从天降临，为圣灵感动之童贞女马利亚所生，成为人身，在本丢彼拉多手下，为我等钉十字架，被害而葬，照圣经之言，第三日复活，升天，坐在圣父之右；将来复必有荣耀而降临，审判生人死人，其国无穷无尽。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我等信圣灵即是主，是赐生命者，是从圣父、圣子所出，与圣父、圣子，同是当拜，当称颂者，众先知说预言，皆是被圣灵感动；我等信使徒所立独一圣而公之教会；我等信因为赦罪设立之独一洗礼；我等望死后复活，又望来世之永生。阿们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council of Chalcedon held in 451 A.D. officially recognized the Niceano-Constantinopolitan Creed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;公元451年举行的迦克墩会议（Council of Chalcedon）正式承认了《尼斯诺-康斯坦丁信条》。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Western Church added the word “filioque” (Latin for “and the Son” to the creed to express the co-equality of the Son with the Father in the procession of the Holy Spirit as Augustine had taught.  The Western Church also reinserted the words “God of God” and change the 1st person plural “we” to a first person singular “I.”   The Council of Toledo in 589 A.D. expressed these changes.   The altered creed gained gradual acceptance among the Western churches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;西方教会在信条中加入了 &amp;ldquo;filioque&amp;rdquo;（拉丁文，意为 &amp;ldquo;和圣子&amp;rdquo;）一词，以表达圣子与圣父在差遣圣灵中的共同地位，正如奥古斯丁所教导的。 西方教会还重新插入了 &amp;ldquo;是从神所出之神&amp;rdquo;，并将第一人称复数 &amp;ldquo;我们 &amp;ldquo;改为第一人称单数 &amp;ldquo;我&amp;rdquo;。  公元589年的托莱多会议明确的陈述了这些变化。  改变后的信条在西方教会中逐渐被接受。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eastern Church refused to accept the “filioque” addition.   This issue was a factor in the Great Schism of 1054 A.D. when the Eastern and Western Churches broke fellowship and went their separate ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;东方教会拒绝接受 &amp;ldquo;filioque &amp;ldquo;的补充。  这个问题是公元1054年大分裂的一个因素，当时东西方教会断绝关系，分道扬镳。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eastern Church recognized the Nicene Creed as its main confession of faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;东方教会承认尼西亚信条为其主要的信仰忏悔。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Western Church adopted the Nicene Creed as the “Creed of the Communicant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;西方教会采用尼西亚信经作为 &amp;ldquo;领受圣餐的圣徒的信经&amp;rdquo;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lutheran Church followed Martin Luther’s lead and changed the word “catholic” (which means “universal”) to “Christian” in its version of the Nicene Creed in order to avoid confusing the Roman Catholic denomination with the Holy Christian Church (which is made up of all those who believe in Christ as their Savior whatever their affiliation with an earthly church).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;路德宗追随马丁-路德的带领，将其版本的《尼西亚信经》中的 &amp;ldquo;大公教&amp;rdquo;（意为 &amp;ldquo;普世&amp;rdquo;）一词改为 &amp;ldquo;基督教&amp;rdquo;，以避免将罗马天主教教派与神圣的基督教会（由所有相信基督为救主的人组成，无论他们属于哪个地上教会）混淆。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lutheran Church adopted the Nicene Creed as one of its primary confessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;路德宗采用《尼西亚信经》作为其主要的认信文件之一。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;d-the-value-and-use-of-the-nicene-creed尼西亚信经的价值和用途&#34;&gt;D. The Value And Use Of The Nicene Creed尼西亚信经的价值和用途&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed serves as a test of correct Christian belief&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经是对正确的基督教信仰的一种检验。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed is a helpful aid for public confession of faith in worship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经是在崇拜中公开承认信仰的有用工具&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed identifies the basis principles of Christian belief&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经确定了基督教信仰的基本原则&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed aids in personal examination and spiritual renewal, especially for Communion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经有助于个人的省察和灵性的更新，特别是对领受圣餐而言。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed fosters unity and harmony in faith among Christians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经促进了基督徒在信仰上的团结与和睦&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-vi-review-questions-复习题&#34;&gt;Part VI Review Questions 复习题&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did the Nicene Creed get its name?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《尼西亚信经》的名字是如何来的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is one of the outstanding features of the Nicene Creed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《尼西亚信经》的突出特点是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What incorrect things was Arius teaching about Jesus Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;阿利乌斯对耶稣基督的教导有哪些不正确的地方？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who created the Council of Nicea and when did this council meet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;谁召集了尼西亚会议，这个会议是什么时候召开的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the significance of the two Greek words “homoousious” = “of the same essence” and “homoiousious” = “of a similar essence” in the conflict about the Christ that the Council addressed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在大公会议处理的关于基督的冲突中，两个希腊词 &amp;ldquo;homoousious&amp;rdquo;=&amp;ldquo;相同的本质 &amp;ldquo;和 &amp;ldquo;homoiousious&amp;rdquo;=&amp;ldquo;相似的本质 &amp;ldquo;的意义是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did the final part of the original Nicene Creed contain that was later dropped from the creed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最初的《尼西亚信经》的最后部分包含什么内容，后来被从信经中删除？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How were Arius and his followers dealt with at the Council of Nicea?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;尼西亚会议是如何处理阿里乌斯及其追随者的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which Council, held in 381 A.D., revised the Nicene Creed into its more complete form?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;公元381年举行的哪个会议将《尼西亚信经》修订为更完整的形式？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does one version of the Creed use the original word “we” and another version use the word “I”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么信经的一个版本使用原来的 &amp;ldquo;我们 &amp;ldquo;一词，而另一个版本使用 &amp;ldquo;我 &amp;ldquo;一词？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did the Lutherans change the original word “catholic” to the word “Christian” in the version of the creed they use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么路德宗在他们使用的信经版本中把原来的 &amp;ldquo;大公教 &amp;ldquo;改为 &amp;ldquo;基督教&amp;rdquo;？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第七课 亚他那修信经</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/211/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/211/7/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;a-the-text-of-the-athanasian-creed亚他拿修信经的文本&#34;&gt;A. The Text Of The Athanasian Creed亚他拿修信经的文本&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoever wishes to be saved must, above all else, hold to the true Christian faith. Whoever does not keep this faith pure in all points will certainly perish forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;任何人欲得救，首先当持守大公教会信仰。此信仰，凡守之不全不正者，必永远沉沦。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this is the true Christian faith: We worship one God in three persons and three persons in one God, without mixing the persons or dividing the divine being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;大公教会信仰即：我等敬拜一体三位，而三位一体之神。 其位不乱，其体不分。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each person – the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit – is distinct, but the deity of Father, Son, and Holy Spirit is one, equal in glory and coeternal in majesty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;父一位，子一位，圣灵亦一位。然而父子圣灵同一神性，同一荣耀，亦同一永恒之尊严。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the Father is, so is the Son, and so is the Holy Spirit.  The Father is uncreated, the Son uncreated, the Holy Spirit uncreated;  the Father is infinite, the Son infinite, the Holy Spirit infinite; the Father is eternal, the Son eternal, the Holy Spirit eternal; yet they are not three who are eternal, but there is one who is eternal, just as they are not three who are uncreated, nor three who are infinite, but there is one who in uncreated and one who is infinite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;父如何，子如何，圣灵亦如何。父不受造，子不受造，圣灵亦不受造。父无限，子无限，圣灵亦无限。父永恒，子永恒，圣灵亦永恒。非三永恒者，乃一永恒者。亦非三不受造者，非三无限者，乃一不受造者，一无限者。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same way the Father is almighty, the Son is almighty, the Holy Spirit is almighty; yet they are not three who are almighty, but there is one who is almighty.  So the Father is God, the Son is God, the Holy Spirit is God; yet they are not three Gods, but one God.  So the Father is Lord, the Son is Lord, the Holy Spirit is Lord; yet they are not three Lords, but one Lord.  For just as Christian truth compels us to confess each person individually to be God and Lord, so the true Christian faith forbids us to speak of three Gods or three Lords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如是，父全能，子全能，圣灵亦全能。然而，非三全能者，乃一全能者。如是，父是神，子是神，圣灵亦是神。然而，非三神，乃一神。如是，父是主，子是主，圣灵亦是主。然而，非三主，乃一主。依基督真道，我等不得不认三位均为神，均为主。依大公教，我等亦不得谓神有三，亦不得谓主有三。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Father is neither made nor created nor begotten of anyone. The Son is neither made nor created, but is begotten of the Father alone. The Holy Spirit is neither made nor begotten, but proceeds from the Father and the Son. So there is one Father, not three Fathers; one Son, not three Sons; one Holy Spirit, not three Holy Spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And within this Trinity none comes before or after; none is greater or inferior, but all three persons are coequal and coeternal, so that in every way, as stated before, all three persons are to be worshiped as one God and one God worshiped as three persons. Whoever wishes to be saved must have this conviction of the Trinity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;父非由谁作成：既非受造，亦非受生。子独由于父：非作成，亦非受造；而为受生。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣灵由于父与子：既非作成，亦非受造，亦非受生；而为发出。如是，有一父，非三父，有一子，非三子，有一圣灵，非三圣灵。25. 且此三位无分先后，无别尊卑。三位乃均永恒，而同等。由是如前所言，我等当敬拜一体三位，而三位一体之神。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is furthermore necessary for eternal salvation truly to believe that our Lord Jesus Christ also took on human flesh. Now this is the true Christian faith: We believe and confess that our Lord Jesus Christ, God’s Son, is both God and man. He is God, eternally begotten from the nature of the Father, and He is man, born in time from the nature of his mother, fully God, fully man, with rational soul and human flesh, equal to the Father as to his deity, less than the Father as to His humanity and though He is both God and man, Christ is not two persons but one, one, not by changing the deity into flesh, but by taking the humanity into God; one, indeed, not by mixture of the natures, but by unity in one person; for just as the rational soul and flesh are one human being, so God and man are one Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;所以凡欲得救者，必如是而思三位一体之神。再者，为求得永恒救赎，彼亦必笃信我等之主耶稣基督成为人身。依真正信仰，我等信认神之子我等之主耶稣基督，为神，又为人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;其为神，与圣父同体，受生于诸世界之先；其为人，与其母同体，诞生于此世界。全神，亦全人，具有理性之灵，血肉之身。依其为神，与父同等，依其为人，少逊于父。彼虽为神，亦为人，然非为二，乃为一基督。彼为一，非由于变神为血肉，乃由于使其人性进入于神。合为一；非由二性相混，乃由位格为一。如灵与身成为一人，神与人成为一基督。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He suffered for our salvation, descended into hell, rose the third day from the dead. He ascended into heaven, is seated at the right hand of God the Father almighty, and from there will come to judge the living and the dead. At His coming all people will rise with their own bodies to answer for their personal deeds. Those who have done good will enter eternal life, but those who have done evil will go into eternal fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;彼为救我等而受难，降至阴间，第三日从死复活。升天，坐于全能神父之右。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;将来必从彼处降临，审判活人死人。彼降临时，万人必具身体复活；并供认所行之事。行善者必入永生，作恶者必入永火。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the true Christian faith. Whoever does not faithfully and firmly believe this cannot be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;此乃大公教会信仰，人除非笃实相信，必不能得救。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;b-characteristics-of-the-athanasian-creed-亚他拿修信经的特点&#34;&gt;B. Characteristics Of The Athanasian Creed 亚他拿修信经的特点&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Athanasian Creed begins with a well-developed doctrine of the Triune God.  “If the mystery of the Trinity can be logically defined, it is done here (in the Athanasian Creed).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚他拿修信经以完善的三位一体神的教义开始。 &amp;ldquo;如果三位一体的奥秘可以在逻辑上加以定义，那么就在这里（在《亚他那斯信条》中）做到了。&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed continues with a second major part, a carefully fashioned statement on the Incarnation of Jesus Christ and His saving work for us.  It provides a valuable supplement to the Apostles’ and Nicene Creeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;紧随其后的是信经的第二个重要部分，即关于耶稣基督的道成肉身和祂为我们所做的救赎之功的精心设计的声明。 该信经为《使徒信经》和《尼西亚信经》提供了宝贵的补充说明。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed contains several “mandatory” (sometimes called “condemnatory”) clauses.   These clauses insist that a person must believe the truths expressed about a doctrine in the creed in order to be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经包含几个 &amp;ldquo;强制性&amp;rdquo;（有时称为 &amp;ldquo;谴责性&amp;rdquo;）条款。  这些条款坚持认为，人必须相信信经中所表达的关于某个教义的真理，才能得救。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed is doctrinally succinct, artistically arranged and rhythmically expressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经在教义上是简洁的，艺术地安排结构并且有节奏地呈现。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed employs abstract, metaphysical content in the technical language of philosophical schools.  It is “orthodoxy in technical language.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经采用抽象的、形而上学的内容，采用哲学流派的专门术语。 它&amp;quot;采用专门术语来表述正统信仰&amp;quot;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed summarizes the scriptural doctrinal positions taken at the first 4 Ecumenical Councils (Nicea – 325 A.D., Constantinople – 381 A.D., Ephesus – 431 A.D., and  Chalcedon – 451 A.D.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经总结了前四个大公会议（尼西亚&amp;ndash;公元325年，君士坦丁堡&amp;ndash;公元381年，以弗所&amp;ndash;公元431年，迦克墩&amp;ndash;公元451年）上的圣经教义立场。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed has been described as “a didactic creed of the clergy.”   It provides instruction to refute false teachings about the Trinity and Person of Christ that were prevalent in the 5th Century A.D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经被描述为 &amp;ldquo;神职人员的训导信经&amp;rdquo;。  它为驳斥公元5世纪盛行的关于三位一体和基督位格的错误教义提供了指导。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;c-the-development-of-the-athanasian-creed亚他拿修信经的产生&#34;&gt;C. The Development Of The Athanasian Creed亚他拿修信经的产生&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Athanasian Creed, sometimes called “Quicumque Vult” (after the first two words of the Latin original) is a purely Western Church creed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚他拿修信经，有时被称为 &amp;ldquo;Quicumque Vult&amp;rdquo;（取自拉丁文原文的前两个词），是一个纯粹的西方教会信经。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed was named after Athanasias, a defender of the scriptural faith against Arianism, but it was not written by him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信条以反对亚流主义的圣经信仰的捍卫者亚他拿修命名，但信经并不是由他写的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the adoption of the Niceano-Constantinopolitan Creed of 381 A.D. and its fine biblical confession of the person and work of Christ, a key Christological question remained to be answered.   The question was: “How did the eternal Son of God assume a human nature?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在公元381年的《尼西亚-康斯坦丁信经》及其对基督的位格和工作的美好的、合乎圣经的认信被通过后，一个关键的基督论问题仍有待回答。  这个问题是。&amp;ldquo;永恒的上帝之子是如何具有人性的？&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the effort to answer that question, three major heresies developed about the Person of Christ and needed to be addressed.   These false teachings were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在回答这个问题的过程中，出现了三个关于基督的位格的主要异端邪说，需要加以解决。  这些错误的教义是&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Apollinarianism:  Appollinaris of Laodicea (310-390 A.D.) had opposed the heretic Arias, but fell into the error of teaching that Christ did not have a human soul, but that Logos (the eternal reason or thought of God) took the place of the human soul.   By doing this Apollinarias claimed that the Son of God merely occupied a human body and denied that Jesus was a true human being.  (This teaching is a form of “Docetism” – the heresy that claims that Jesus was God, but that He only seemed to be a human being.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚波里拿留主义（Apollinarianism）。 老底嘉的亚波里拿留（Appollinaris of Laodicea）（公元310-390年）曾反对亚流派异端，但却陷入了教导基督没有人的灵魂的错误，而是由逻各斯（永恒中的理性或上帝的思想）来成为基督的灵魂。  通过这样做，亚波里拿留声称上帝的儿子只是占据了一个人的身体，并否认耶稣是一个真正的人。 （这种教导是一种 &amp;ldquo;幻影说（Docetism） &amp;ldquo;的形式—这种异端承认耶稣是上帝，但却认为耶稣只是看起来像是一个人（不是完全的人））&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Nestorianism: Nestorius, (380-451 A.D.) the patriarch of Constantinople, held the view that Jesus had two separate wills – one human and one divine.  He taught that the Son of God dwelled inside a full and complete human being, but that the human and divine natures did not have a true communion or joining together with each other.   He regarded the Virgin Mary as the “mother of Christ”, but not the “mother of God.”    (This teaching is a form of “Dualism” – the heresy that claims that Jesus had two separated natures.) Note: The followers of Nestorius spread his teaching far and wide and were likely the first to bring Christianity to India and China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;聂思托里主义（景教）。聂思托里（公元380-451年）是君士坦丁堡的牧首，他认为耶稣有两个独立的意志&amp;ndash;一个是人的意志，一个是神的意志。 他教导说，神的儿子居住在一个完整的人里面，但人的本性和神的本性并没有真正的共融或相互结合。  他认为圣母玛利亚是 &amp;ldquo;基督的母亲&amp;rdquo;，但不是 &amp;ldquo;上帝的母亲&amp;rdquo;。   (这一教义是 &amp;ldquo;二元论 &amp;ldquo;的一种形式—这种异端声称耶稣有两个分离的本性) 注：聂思托里的追随者将他的教导传播得很广，很可能是第一个将基督教带到印度和中国的人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Eutychianism: Eutyches, (378-454A.D.) the archimandrite (spiritual leader of the monasteries) of the Eastern Church in Constantinople, opposed Nestorianism.  He reacted to that false teaching by insisting that there were two natures in Christ before the incarnation, but only one nature after.  He taught that the human nature of Christ was absorbed or swallowed up in the divine nature.   In contrast to Nestorius, Eutyches insisted that the Virgin Mary was the “mother of God.”  (This teaching is form of “Monophysitism” – the heresy that claims that Jesus had only one nature.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;欧迪奇主义。欧迪奇（公元378-454年）是君士坦丁堡东方教会的大主教（修道院的精神领袖），他反对聂思托里主义（景教）。 他对这一错误的教导作出反应，坚持认为基督在道成肉身之前有两个本性，但在道成肉身之后只有一个本性。 他教导说，基督的人性被吸收或吞没在神性中。  与聂斯脱里相反，欧迪奇坚持认为圣母玛利亚是 &amp;ldquo;上帝之母&amp;rdquo;。 (这种教导是 &amp;ldquo;一元论 &amp;ldquo;的形式—这种异端声称耶稣只有一种本性)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council of Chalcedon (451 A.D.) addressed these controversies about the Person of Christ and responded to them with the production of the Chalcedonian Creed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;迦克墩会议（公元451年）讨论了这些关于基督位格的争议，并通过制定《迦克墩信经》对其做出回应。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chaledonian Creed迦克墩信经&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, then, following the holy fathers, all with one consent, teach people to confess one and the same Son, our Lord Jesus Christ, at once complete (perfect) in Godhead and also complete (perfect) in manhood; truly God and truly man, consisting also of a reasonable (rational) soul and body;  of one substance (co-essential) with the Father as regards His Godhead, and at the same time of one substance (co-essential) with us as regards His manhood; like us in all respects, apart from sin, as regards His Godhead, begotten of the Father before the ages, but yet as regards His manhood, born for us and for our salvation, of the Virgin Mary, the Mother of God (God-bearer); one and the same Christ, Son, Lord, Only-begotten, to be  acknowledged in two natures, without confusion, without division, without separation; the distinction of natures being in no way annulled (taken away) by the union, but rather the characteristics of each nature being preserved and coming together to form one Person and one Subsistence, not parted or separated into two persons, but one and the same Son and Only-begotten, God the Word, the Lord Jesus Christ; even as the prophets from earliest times &lt;spoke&gt; about Him, and our Lord Jesus Christ Himself taught us, and the creed of the fathers has handed down to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们跟随圣教父，同心合意教人认识同一位子，我们的主耶稣基督，是神性完全、人性亦完全者；祂真是上帝，也真是人，具有理性的灵魂，也具有身体；按神性说，祂与父同体，按人性说，祂与我们同体，在凡事上与我们一样，只是没有罪；&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;按神性说，在万世之前，为父所生，按人性说，在晚进时日，为求拯救我们，由上帝之母，童女马利亚所生；是同一基督，是子，是主，是独生的，具有二性，不相混乱，不相交换，不能分开，不能离散；二性的区别不因联合而消失，各性的特点反得以保存，会合于一个位格，一个实质之内，而非分离成为两个位格，却是同一位子，独生的，道上帝，主耶稣基督；正如众先知论到祂自始所宣讲的，主耶稣基督自己所教训我们的，诸圣教父的信经所传给我们的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The origins of the Athanasian Creed are somewhat vague: 亚他拿修信经的起源并不明确&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Some scholars believe that the creed was written between 381-428 A.D. by a church leader such as Vincent of Lerins or Ambrose, bishop of Milan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一些学者认为，该信经是在公元381-428年之间由一位教会领袖写的，如莱林的文森特或米兰的主教安布罗斯。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Other scholars believe that the creed was written between 430-500 A.D. in France by a member of the school of Lerins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;其他学者认为该信条是在公元430-500年间由法国的莱林学派成员写的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Still other scholars believe that the creed was developed somewhat later by the Augustinians in France or North Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;还有一些学者认为，该信条是由法国或北非的奥古斯丁修会会士稍后制定的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed appeared in its final form in the late 700’s.  At this time, it was being recited in church services, quoted in sermons and written about in commentaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经以其最终形式出现在公元700年代末。 此时，它在教堂仪式中被背诵，在布道中被引用，记载在解经书中。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed gave the church a well developed statement of Trinitarian and Christological orthodoxy in scholarly language to refute the heresies of Apollinarianism, Nestorianism, and Eutychianism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经以学术性的语言为教会提供了一个完善的三位一体和基督论的正统声明，以驳斥亚波里拿留主义（Apollinarianism）、聂思托里主义（景教）（Nestorianism）和欧迪奇亚主义（Eutychianism）等异端邪说。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roman Catholic Church makes limited official use of the creed, while the Orthodox Church makes limited unofficial use of the creed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马天主教会有限制的在正式场合中使用该信经，而东正教会有限制的在非正式场合中使用该信经&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lutherans adopted the creed as one of its major confessions, including it in the Book of Concord and in its hymnals for occasional use in worship.  Martin Luther praised the Athanasian Creed highly: “It is the most important and glorious composition since the days of the apostles.  Since the writing of the New Testament, nothing more weighty and grand has been written.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;路德宗将该信经作为其主要的认信文件之一，将其纳入《协和书》和其赞美诗中，以便在崇拜中不时的使用。 马丁-路德高度赞扬了《亚他拿修信经》。&amp;ldquo;这是自使徒时代以来最重要、最光荣的作品。 自《新约》写作以来，没有什么比它更有分量、更宏伟的著作了&amp;rdquo;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;d-a-puzzling-statement令人困惑的声明&#34;&gt;D. A Puzzling Statement令人困惑的声明&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most perplexing statement in the creed appears near the end of the creed.  These are the words in question: “At His coming all people will rise with their own bodies to answer for their personal deeds.  Those who have done good will enter eternal life, but those who have done evil will go into eternal fire.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;也许信条中最令人困惑的声明出现在信经的最后。 这些话就是问题所在。&amp;ldquo;彼降临时，万人必具身体复活；并供认所行之事。行善者必入永生，作恶者必入永火。&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statement seems to indicate that a person’s salvation depends on their works and that a person can earn his/her way into heaven on the basis of their good deeds.   This statement in the creed appears to conflict with the Bible’s teaching that salvation is a gift of God’s grace through Spirit-worked faith in the redeeming work of Jesus Christ.   (Romans 3:23-24, 28)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这句话似乎表明，一个人的得救取决于他们的行为，一个人可以根据他们的善行赢得进入天堂的机会。  信条中的这句话似乎与《圣经》的教导相冲突，即救恩是上帝的恩典，通过圣灵在耶稣基督的救赎工作中工作的信仰来实现的。  (罗马书3:23-24, 28)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These puzzling words of the Athanasian Creed are biblical.   They are based on John 5:28-29, where Jesus speaks about the Final Judgment and says: “Do not be amazed at this, for a time is coming when all who are in their graves will hear His voice and come out – those who have done good will rise to live, and those who have done evil will rise to be condemned.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚他拿修信经中这些令人困惑的话语是符合圣经的。  它们是基于约翰福音5:28-29，其中耶稣谈到最后的审判时说：&amp;ldquo;你们不要把这事看作希奇。时候要到，凡在坟墓里的，都要听见他的声音，就出来：行善的，复活得生；作恶的，复活定罪。&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When God speaks about people being judged on the basis of their works in the Bible (as He does in places such as John 5:28-29 and Matthew 25:31-46), He is not denying the truth that people are saved freely by faith in Jesus Christ as their Savior (see John 3:16 and 36, Ephesians 2:8-9).   What He is doing is indicating that a person expresses and reveals true faith in Christ by his/her good works, just as a person expresses and reveals their lack of faith by his/her evil deeds (see Matthew 7:16-20).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当上帝在《圣经》中谈到人们根据他们的行为被审判时（就像他在约翰福音5:28-29和马太福音25:31-46等地方所做的那样），他并不否认人们因相信耶稣基督是他们的救主而白白得救这一真理（见约翰福音3:16和36，以弗所书2:8-9）。  他所做的是表明，一个人通过他/她的善行来表达和显示对基督的真正信仰，正如一个人通过他/她的恶行来表达和显示他们缺乏信仰一样（见马太福音7：16-20）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way we are to understand the puzzling words of the creed is expressed in this sentence: “Those who have done good as an expression of true faith in Jesus Christ as their Savior will enter life, but those who have done evil as an expression of their lack of faith in/rejection of Jesus Christ as their Savior will rise to be condemned.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们用以下这句话的方式理解信经中这个令人困惑的部分。&amp;ldquo;行善者表达出他们相信耶稣基督为救主的真实信心，他们将必入永生，但那些行恶者表达出他们不信或拒绝耶稣基督为救主，他们将必入永火。&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;e-the-value-and-use-of-the-athanasian-creed亚那他修信经的价值和用途&#34;&gt;E. The Value And Use Of The Athanasian Creed亚那他修信经的价值和用途&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed provides a safe and needed summary of the orthodox faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经为正统的信仰提供了一个安全和必要的总结。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed gives clear instruction about the Triune nature of God and the Person of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经对上帝的三位一体性质和基督的人格给出了明确的指示。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed identifies and emphasizes fundamental doctrines that are essential to salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经确定并强调了对救赎至关重要的基本教义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creed offers useful help for Christian teaching and preaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;该信经为基督教的教导和证道提供有用的帮助。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-vii-review-questions-复习题&#34;&gt;Part VII Review Questions 复习题&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are two things we know for certain about the writing of the Athanasian Creed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;关于《亚他拿修信经》的文本，我们可以确实的知道哪两件事？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is one of the outstanding features of the Athanasian Creed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《亚他拿修信经》的最突出的特点是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What were the names of the three major false teachings that developed in an effort to answer the question: “How did the eternal Son of God assume a human nature?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在回答“永生的上帝之子是如何具有人性的”这个问题时产生了哪三个主要的错误教义？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which creed was written after the Nicene Creed and before the Athanasian Creed to refute the false teachings and to confess the true biblical teaching about the two natures of Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;哪个信经是在《尼西亚信条》之后、《亚他拿修信经》之前写的，用以驳斥错误的教义，并认信圣经中关于基督的两个本性的真实教导？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List two ways in which the Athanasian Creed is quite different from the Apostles’ and Nicene Creeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《亚他拿修信经》与《使徒信条》和《尼西亚信条》相比较有哪两个显著的不同之处，请列出。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What high regard did Martin Luther have for the Athanasian Creed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马丁-路德对《亚他拿修信经》有什么高度评价？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you answer the person who says: “The Athanasian Creed teaches salvation by works and not salvation by faith in Jesus Christ?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果有人说：&amp;quot;《亚他拿修信经》教人靠行为得救，而不是靠对耶稣基督的信仰得救&amp;rdquo;，你该如何回答？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are doctrinal errors about the Triune Nature of God and the Person and Work of Jesus Christ so dangerous to the Christian faith and so damaging to the spiritual welfare of people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么关于上帝的三位一体本性和耶稣基督的位格及工作的教义错误对基督教信仰如此危险，对人们的属灵福祉如此有害？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are the Apostles, Nicene and Athanasian Creeds regarded as the first three Lutheran Confessions and included in the Book of Concord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么《使徒信经》、《尼西亚信经》和《亚他拿修信经》被视为路德宗的前三份信经文件，并被列入《协同书》？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does a deeper knowledge of the contents and history of the main Christian creeds help Christians in their relationship with God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;深入了解基督教主要信经的内容和历史，对基督徒与上帝的关系有什么帮助？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does a deeper knowledge of the contents and history of the main Christian creeds help Christians in their confession of the Christian faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对基督教主要信经的内容和历史有更深入的了解，对基督徒对基督教信仰的认信有什么帮助？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share one valuable insight and/or encouragement you received from this study of Confessing the Faith and the Christian Creeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请分享你在学习《认信和基督教信经》课程的过程中得到的一个有价值的见解和/或鼓励。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
