<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grace Bible Institute – ROMANS 9-16</title>
    <link>/en/courses/111/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ROMANS 9-16 on Grace Bible Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:47:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/en/courses/111/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 5 Romans 13:1-14 Called To Respect Authority And To Love</title>
      <link>/en/courses/111/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/111/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;vii-practicing-gods-received-righteousness-romans-12-16&#34;&gt;VII. Practicing God’s Received Righteousness (Romans 12-16)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Believers Respond To God’s Grace By Using Their Gifts and Opportunities (12:1-21)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Believers Respect Authority And Pay The Debt Of Love (13:1-14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does the Christian owe obedience and loyalty to his government?  (verses 1-2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to verses 3-4, what role(s) has God assigned to government?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 4, Paul spoke of the government “bearing the sword.”  In what ways does the government “bear the sword” today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under what conditions does a government have God’s approval to use its power to go to war against others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List two blessings that you enjoy through your government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the two motivations Paul stated for a Christian to obey his government in verse 5?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which of the two motivations you identified in question 6 is more important for a Christian to follow?  (Explain your answer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What specific responsibilities does a citizen have toward his government according to verses 6-7?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martin Luther said that Christians live in two kingdoms.  The “kingdom of God’s right hand” is God’s rule through His grace in Jesus Christ and His Word in the Christian Church.  The ”kingdom of God’s left hand” is God’s rule through the authority exercised by the government and other organizations in the world.   What are some of the differences in being a citizen of these two kingdoms?&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;div class=&#34;data-table&#34;&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;| Category                | Christian Church  | Earthly Government  |
|------------------------ |------------------ |-------------------- |
| How one enters it       |                   |                     |
| What rules it           |                   |                     |
| What it commands        |                   |                     |
| One’s responsibilities  |                   |                     |
| One’s benefits          |                   |                     |
| When it ends            |                   |                     |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what sense is love a “debt we owe” to God and other people?  (verse 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agree or Disagree?  The debt to love others is one we can eventually pay off.  (Explain your answer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some opportunities you have had to love other people in this past week?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What special reason for showing self-giving love to others did Paul mention in verse 11?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What spiritual contrasts do the terms “day and light” and “night and darkness” express?  (verse 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the “armor of light” that God wants His believers to put on?  （verse 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do the 6 sins called the “deeds of darkness” in verse 13 contradict God’s command to love others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What two directives for living life did God give His Christians in verse 14?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In commenting on the closing verses of Romans 13, someone wrote: “As Christians we are to live our lives both with purpose and on purpose.”  What did this person mean by this statement?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 6 Romans 14:1-23 Living To Serve Others</title>
      <link>/en/courses/111/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/111/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;vii-practicing-gods-received-righteousness-romans-12-16&#34;&gt;VII. Practicing God’s Received Righteousness (Romans 12-16)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A.	Believers Respond To God’s Grace By Using Their Gifts and Opportunities (12:1-21)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B.	Believers Respect Authority And Pay The Debt Of Love (13:1-14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C.	Believers Live For The Benefit Of Others  (14:1-15:13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Romans 14:1-15:13, Paul addressed the matter of handling differences that arise when believers have a “strong” or “weak” faith about the way their believe they should conduct themselves?  (verses 2  and 14)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) What does Paul mean by a “strong” faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) What does Paul mean by a “weak” faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are “disputable” matters of the Christian faith different from “indisputable matters of the Christian faith?  (verse 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give three examples of “disputable” matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give 3 examples of “indisputable” matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does God want a Christian to regard and treat a fellow believer who is either “weak” or “strong” in one or more “disputable” matters? (verses 1, 3 and 4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does God want us to treat fellow believers in that way?  (verses 3b-4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What attitudes are to guide and motivate our conduct in the use of the things that God has neither commanded nor forbidden us to do or use (matters of adiaphora)?  (verses 5-9 and 13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verses 5-6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verses 7-9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How should the knowledge of God’s coming judgment help us in dealing with different views among Christians in matters of adiaphora?  (verses 10-12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agree or Disagree?  God’s commands to accept the weak in faith mean that the strong in faith should not try to strengthen the weak by instructing them from God’s Word.  (Explain your answer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can a strong in faith Christin harm a weak in faith Christian by his use of the things that God has neither commanded nor forbidden?  (verses 13-16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What important truths about God’s kingdom does Paul impress on us in verse 17?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give an example of how a believer might cause a fellow Christian to “stumble” by insisting on acting in a certain way in a matter in which God has declared free to do or not to do, but in which this weaker (less confident) fellow member might be misled or offended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some practical ways we can follow God’s command in verse 19 to pursue peace and mutual edification among fellow Christians?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agree or Disagree?  In verses 20-21, God is telling the strong Christian that the conscience of the weak Christian is to be his guide in the use of adiaphora.  (Explain your answer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Paul teach the strong in faith believer about his personal convictions in matters of adiaphora? (verse 22)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do we learn in verse 23 about the place of personal conviction and of following one’s conscience in matters of Christian conduct?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Romans 9-16 Final Exam</title>
      <link>/en/courses/111/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/111/9/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Student Name: __________________________________________     Grade:____________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;姓名: __________________________________________________     成绩: _____________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instructions:   The exam has 41 multiple choice questions that cover the important points from each chapter of Romans.  You are to elect the most correct answer to complete each statement and put the letter of that answer in the underlined blank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;说明：考试题目包含41道多项选择题。内容涵盖罗马书中每一章的要点。请选择每个选项中最恰当的一项，并将该选项前的字母填在题目中的下划线处。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-9-罗马书9章&#34;&gt;Romans 9 罗马书9章&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul had such a deep love for His fellow Jews that he was willing to ___ if only they would repent of their sins, believe in Jesus as their Savior and go to heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗深爱他的同胞犹太人，甚至愿意___只要他们能悔改自己的罪，相信耶稣基督为救主并进入天国。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. go to prison for the rest of his life   为他们在余生中坐监&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. be put to death for his faith   为信仰的缘故受死&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. give up his place in heaven and go to hell   放弃去天国的地位而去地狱&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul explained that the reason why many Jews were not saved was not because there was something wrong with God’s Word but because they ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗认为犹太人不得救的原因不是因为神的话语落了空，而是因为犹太人___&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. had never been told God’s Word    从来就不知道神的话&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. had too much knowledge of God’s Word   对神的话语知道的太多了&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. refused to believe God’s Word   拒绝相信神的话&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul also explained that salvation depends on ___ as Abraham did and not on the basis of being physically descended from Abraham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗阐明救恩取决于___，好像亚伯拉罕一样，而不是取决于肉身上是否为亚伯拉罕的后裔。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. believing God’s saving promises    相信神的救恩应许&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. leading a good life    生活中是人们的好榜样&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. obeying God’s call   遵行神的呼召&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul taught that because God is God, He cannot be accused of injustice if He is pleased to ____ as He wishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗教导说，因为神是神，人不能因为祂___而指责祂不公义&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. show mercy on people   怜悯人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. torment people    折磨人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. leave people without help   不管不顾人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason that God is patient with people who disobey and reject Him is ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神忍耐那些悖逆、抗拒祂的人是因为___&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. He needs time to decide how to punish them   祂需要时间来决定如何刑罚他们&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. He is very tolerant of sin.   祂对罪非常宽容&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. He is pleased to give sinners opportunity to repent and be saved 祂愿意给罪人机会好让他们悔改得救&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By quoting several Old Testament prophets at the close of the chapter, Paul demonstrated that God’s gracious plan of salvation is so save many Gentiles and ____ of the Jews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗在这章结束时引用了多处旧约中先知书的经文，以此证明神充满恩慈的救恩计划是要救赎许多的外邦人和___犹太人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. all    全部&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. the majority  大部分的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. some   一些&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-10---罗马书10章&#34;&gt;Romans 10   罗马书10章&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason so many Jews were not saved is because they incorrectly pursued righteousness by ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;很多犹太人没有得救的原因是因为他们用这种错误的方法称义：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. trying to create their own by their works   想要藉着自己的行为立自己的义&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. purchasing it with money   用钱财称义&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. thinking the faith of their ancestors protected them   以为他们的先祖的信心会保守他们&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Paul said that Christ is the end or fulfillment of the law, he meant that Jesus fulfilled all the prophecies of God’s Word about the Messiah and that He ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当保罗说基督是律法的总结或成全了律法时，他是指耶稣应验了所有神的话语中关于弥赛亚的预言，并且祂__&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. taught the law more completely than anyone ever had   比任何人更全面的教导律法&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. added several new commands to the law given in the Old Testament   在旧约中的律法上增加了些新的律法&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. obeyed all the law’s demands perfectly   完全的行全了律法中的要求&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul contrasted the way of righteousness by the law with the way of righteousness by faith.  He said that righteousness by the law requires people to do all the law says, while righteousness by faith was a ____ of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗对比了靠律法称义和靠信心称义的不同，他说靠律法称义要求人们行全律法中的要求，但靠信心称义则是神的___。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. brilliant idea   绝妙的主意&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. pure gift   完全的礼物&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. valuable possession   宝贵财产&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Paul said that God is the same Lord of both Jews and Gentiles, he meant that God has given both groups ____ way of salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当保罗说神既是犹太人的主也是万邦人的主时，他的意思是神赐给这两者的救恩是____&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. the same   同样的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. slightly different   有些许差别的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. completely different   完全不同的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul affirmed that in order for people to believe in Christ and be saved, they must first ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗肯定的说人想要信基督得救，就必须首先____。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. stop sinning    停止犯罪&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. pray for faith  祈求信心&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. hear God’s Word   听神的话&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people who were ultimately responsible for the tragedy of the Jews who did not believe were ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;从根本上来说____要为最终不信的犹太人负完全的责任。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. lazy Christians   懒惰的基督徒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. their spiritually blind parents   他们在灵里盲目的父母&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. themselves  他们自己&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-11--罗马书11章&#34;&gt;Romans 11  罗马书11章&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;13&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul affirmed the truth and gave several examples of it that God has not ____ His covenant to save Jewish people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗证实并且举例说明，神并没有____祂救赎以色列人的约。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. forgotten  忘记&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. renewed  更新&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. negated  取消&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God hardened the hearts of the Jews who persistently refused Him in unbelief so that they could ____ believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神使那些以不信的心定意拒绝祂的犹太人内心刚硬，以致于他们____相信。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. no longer  不再&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. later on  以后可以&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. help others  可以让别人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul held out the hope that some Jews who had initially rejected Jesus would later come to faith when they saw ____ believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗坚定的盼望有些起初拒绝耶稣的犹太人在看到____相信后，也会信主。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Jewish priests   犹太祭祀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Gentiles  外邦人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Roman officials  罗马官长&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the parable of the Cultivated Olive Tree, the wild olive branch grafted into the tree represents ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在嫁接橄榄枝的比喻中，野橄榄枝接在橄榄树上用以代表___。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. New Testament believers   新约的信徒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. believing Jews   犹太信徒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. believing Gentiles   外邦人信徒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Paul declared that “all Israel will be saved”, he likely meant that ____ will be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当保罗说“以色列全家都要得救”时，他可能是指____会得救。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. all Jewish people  所有的犹太人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. all God’s spiritual Israel – believing Jews and Gentiles   所有归于神的属灵的以色列人-犹太信徒和外邦人信徒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. all the elect Jewish people  所有被拣选的犹太人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the doxology Paul wrote to close the chapter, he specially praised God for His supreme ____ that surpasses all human understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗在本章结束的颂赞中，他尤其为神超越的、超乎众人之上的____献上赞美、。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. power and authority   能力和权柄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. grace and mercy  恩典和慈悲&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. wisdom and knowledge   智慧和知识&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-12--罗马书12章&#34;&gt;Romans 12  罗马书12章&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;19&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul called on those who know God’s saving mercies in Christ to offer ____ as living sacrifices to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗呼召那些明白神在基督里的救恩的人献上____作为活祭归给神。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. generous financial gifts  大笔的金钱财务&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. years of service   长久的服事&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. themselves   他们自己&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul urged believers to no longer be conformed to the world’s thoughts, but to be spiritually transformed in their minds so they can know and follow ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗催促信徒不再效法这个世界的样式，而是在灵里更新他们的心意，以使他们能明白并跟随____。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. their true feelings   他们真实的感受&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. more exalted thoughts  更加超越的样式&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. God’s perfect will   神纯全的旨意&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the human body has many members with difficult functions, so Christ’s Church has many members with different _____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如同人身体有很多器官并且各司其职，基督的教会也有很多肢体及不同的____。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. backgrounds  背景&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. gifts  礼物&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. levels of knowledge   不同等次的知识&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul directed believers to hate ____ and cling to what is good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗要信徒恨恶____亲近善。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. evil  恶&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. evil people  邪恶的人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. evil language  坏话&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul instructed Christians to live ____ others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗教导基督徒之间要彼此____。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. in a commune with  亲密&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. in harmony with  同心&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. cautiously with   谨慎&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul taught that Christians are to ____ when they are wronged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗教导基督徒在被伤害时要____。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. get revenge by themselves  自己报仇&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. let their family members get revenge for them   让家人为自己报仇&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. let God avenge them  让神为自己伸冤&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-13--罗马书13章&#34;&gt;Romans 13  罗马书13章&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;25&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul taught that all governments ultimately receive their authority to rule from ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗教导所有的政府的权柄在根本上出于____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. their citizens   他们的人民&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. strong-minded people   有主见的人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. God   神&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary work of earthly governments is to help the welfare of citizens by ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;地上政府的主要工作是通过____为人民服务。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. creating economic prosperity   创造经济的繁荣&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. maintaining good order   维持良好的秩序&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. defeating all its enemies  击败所有的敌人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul said that it is necessary for Christians to obey their earthly governments because they want to avoid punishment and they want to have clear _____ before God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗说基督徒需要顺服地上的掌权者，因为他们不要自取刑罚，同时他们想要在神面前有清洁的____。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. criminal records   犯罪记录&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. reputations   好名声&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. consciences  良心&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul explained that ____ is the fulfillment of God’s law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗说明____是完全了神的律法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. love   爱&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. obedience   顺服&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. sacrifice  牺牲&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul urgently appealed to believers to live morally good lives that oppose the desires of their sinful natures because ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗殷切的呼吁信徒过良好的道德生活、不可顺从他们的罪性，这是因为____。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. each day they are getting closer to the time of Jesus’ Second Coming 他们每一天都离耶稣二次再来的时候更近了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. they do not want to be an embarrassment to their families or themselves 他们不会想成为家人或自己的耻辱&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. punishments such as fines and prison sentences are painful and costly 罚款和坐监的刑罚非常痛苦并且代价巨大&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-14-罗马书14章&#34;&gt;Romans 14 罗马书14章&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;30&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Paul discussed the strong and weak Christians in this chapter, he was referring to a difference in ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗在本章中谈到软弱的和刚强的基督徒，他用____来区别两者。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. the degree of character   个人的不同&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. ability to endure persecution for the sake of Christ   为基督的名忍受迫害的能力&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. knowledge about the things God permits a Christian to do or not do   神许可基督徒去做哪些事、不许可去做哪些事的知识。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul told believers that they must answer to ___ for the judgments they make about matters God has neither commanded, nor forbidden them to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗告诉信徒，他们各人必要在___面前说明，自己是如何判断那些神没有明令禁止或不禁止的事的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. God   神&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. their pastor  他们的牧师&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. their family and friends   他们的家人和朋友&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul instructed that a strong Christian can ___ a weak Christian by insisting on using his freedom of choice and action in a way that disagrees with the conscience of the weaker person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗教导说，如果信心坚固的基督徒使用基督徒的自由所做的选择或行动会使软弱人的良心忧愁，那么信心大的基督徒就会___信心软弱的基督徒。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. educate   教育&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. spiritually offend   在灵里跌倒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. silence   压制&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul taught that it is ____ to destroy another person’s faith by using one’s freedom in an unloving way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗教导，不按爱人的道理而使用人的自由并毁坏别人的信心是____ 。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. permissible    可行的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. regrettable   很遗憾的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. wrong   错误的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul declared that in all matters a person must follow his ____ and decide and act on the basis of faith, not doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗宣称在任何事上人都不能违背自己的____，做任何事和任何决定要出于信心不要疑惑。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;a. feelings   感受

b. personal experiences  个人经验

c. conscience   良心
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-15--罗马书15章&#34;&gt;Romans 15  罗马书15章&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;35&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul directed believers to seek the good of others and not please themselves because ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗指教信徒要使别人得益处而不是求自己的喜悦，这是因为&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. people desperately need help   人们亟需帮助&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. it will make them feel good about themselves   这会使人自我感觉良好&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Jesus strove to please others and not Himself.   因为基督不求自己喜悦&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul announced that the Bible was written in order to _____ people so that they might gain patient endurance, spiritual encouragement, and eternal hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗宣告:所写的圣经是为_____我们，为使我们因圣经所生的忍耐和安慰可以得着盼望。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. distract   干扰&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. teach   教导&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. warn  警告&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul prayed that God would work a strong spirit of unity among the Jewish and Gentile believers in Rome so that ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗祈求神在罗马的犹太人和外邦人中建立彼此接纳的灵，从而使____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. they would have peace  他们之间有和平&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. they could accomplish more ministry   他们能够完成更多的事工&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. God would be glorified   神得荣耀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul rejoiced in what  ____ accomplished by bringing the gospel to many Gentile people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗因____所做成的事，把福音带给有多外邦人，而感到喜乐。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Jesus Christ    耶稣基督&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Paul himself   保罗自己&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. his co-workers, Titus and Timothy   他的同工，提多和提摩太&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul’s long-term goal was to preach the Gospel in ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗的长期目标是在____ 传福音。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. England   英国&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. France  法国&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Spain  西班牙&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-16--罗马书16章&#34;&gt;Romans 16  罗马书16章&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;40&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul warned Christians to watch out for and ____ those whose false teachings caused divisions in the church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗警告基督徒要留意并且____那些用假道理在教会中造成分裂的人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. keep away from  躲避&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. silence  压制&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. reason with   规劝&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul concluded the Book of Romans with a beautiful doxology that praised God for ____.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗用美好的颂赞来总结罗马书并为____而颂赞神。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. showing mercy to the Roman believers   向罗马的信徒施怜悯&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. revealing the saving gospel to the world  向世界启示救赎人的福音&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. ruling over all things in love and justice  用爱和公义掌管万事&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
