<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grace Bible Institute – ministry</title>
    <link>/en/tags/ministry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ministry on Grace Bible Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:53:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/en/tags/ministry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Christian Counseling</title>
      <link>/en/courses/405/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/405/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;course-descriptionobjective&#34;&gt;Course Description/Objective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wherever we look in this world, we find people in desperate need of help. This course is the first part in a series which goal is to provide Christians with an overview of the variety of issues that people may face as they remind others of God’s redeeming love in Christ (Psalm 34:18 – The Lord is close to the brokenhearted and saves those who are crushed in spirit). Christian Counseling, Part 1 primarily focuses on cognitive/mood disorders as addressed in Scripture. Part 2 will emphasis family structure disorders. A course listing of these topics is provided elsewhere in this material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-objective-of-this-course-is-to-provide-a-resource-for-others-in-a-christian-counseling-ministry-it-will-help-you-to&#34;&gt;The objective of this course is to provide a resource for others in a Christian counseling ministry. It will help you to&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand and accurately assess a person’s struggle;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guide discussion and provide helpful suggestions;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember key principles in the process of moving people from problem to resolution;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lay the foundation of God’s Word, so that proper use of law and gospel directs the counseling setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-teaching-format-will-provide-a-collaborative-learning-experience-which-focuses-on-the-following-goals-of-touching-the-head-heart-and-hands-of-the-learner-since-all-learning-is-meant-to-affect-the-intellect-emotion-and-volition-this-will-be-the-teaching-philosophy-of-this-course&#34;&gt;The teaching format will provide a collaborative learning experience, which focuses on the following goals of touching the head, heart, and hands of the learner. Since all learning is meant to affect the intellect, emotion, and volition this will be the teaching philosophy of this course&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each topic will generally be divided into an outlined format as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Case Study – Every topic begins with an example that relates a story about people struggling with a particular issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Terms – Important definitions will be provided, so that the student will have a better understanding of the issue under discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Causes/Character – A series of statement or questions are provided to help the student understand a particular struggle. These are also used to help determine if referral to a physician or other professional is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Counseling Advice– Students will learn to structure their counseling so that biblical concepts are applied in the most helpful way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steps to Follow – These steps will give the student an idea of how to identify the problem and bring it to resolution in a counseling setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light on the Path – Bible passages and brief commentary will aid the student in learning how to place a counseling session into a biblical framework, so the power of the Holy Spirit offers true, spiritual direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Mindful Questions – these are questions that a counselor may ask as part of an in-take interview or simply as a Christian friend talking with another friend about a struggle. These are meant to be “open” and “closed” questions so as to expose the student to information-gathering questions, which encourage further, deeper discussion about the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, It’s Your Turn – Students are given an opportunity to apply the principles discussed in each lesson to the case studies that are provided. This allows the student to gain practical experience as well as to apply collaborative learning in the class setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Please note that not every lesson will follow this outline exactly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-list-of-topics-discussed-in-christian-counseling-part-1&#34;&gt;A list of topics discussed in Christian Counseling, Part 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addictions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Envy/Jealousy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grief/Loss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fear/Anxiety&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guilt/Shame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;expectations-and-outcomes&#34;&gt;Expectations and Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructor-responsibilities&#34;&gt;Instructor Responsibilities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be an 8 – week course. Each session is to be 90-minutes. During this course, the instructor will work with the students (through a translator, as necessary). The instructor will be prepared to teach each session in the time allowed. The instructor will give a final assessment at the end this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;teaching-materials&#34;&gt;Teaching Materials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provided in the class notes and also as handouts by the instructor, if needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-length&#34;&gt;Course Length&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course will generally take between 12-14 hours of instruction time to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rubrics-for-credit&#34;&gt;Rubrics for Credit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For satisfactory completion of the course, the student will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;● Be in attendance for at least 75% of the instruction periods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;● Actively participate in class discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;● Review all notes and prepare all assignments in preparation for each lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;● Complete any assessments and/or tests given by the instructor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*All Scripture references are taken from the New International Version, 2011&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Preaching</title>
      <link>/en/courses/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/404/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Introduction of Preaching （讲道学概要）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important Ideas to consider as we speak about Preaching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be a speaker of the Word before God’s people or any people is to be an ambassador of Christ Jesus. Any preacher who is more interested in themselves or earning money than in telling people about Jesus and his Word, is a mockery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the call of a preacher to proclaim God’s Word. We are not free to substitute our own ideas. Even though we use all of our life experiences and knowledge in our sermons, even though we think of good ways from modern life to illustrate what God’s Word is saying all those tools are meant to communicate the Word better not change the Word. The message of Jesus, the gospel and all of God’s will in the Bible must be central to all we proclaim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proclaiming God’s Word is an awesome opportunity. Those who are best able to do it are those on whom the Gospel has had an impact. Those who proclaim it well are those for whom the Gospel is an exciting and marvelous gift of God. We proclaim God’s Word for the sake of people with a focus on the Gospel. In preaching we apply what God has given each of us – our personality, our experiences, our faith. Get EXCITED about the opportunity to share God’s Word with people. If proclaiming God’s Word is not exciting to you, then you may better serve the Lord and his kingdom in a different way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central point of Jesus is the Gospel. So in our preaching the central point needs to be the Gospel. Certainly each sermon will have law (some more than others). Each sermon will have sanctification (some more than others). Yet to proclaim both law and sanctification best the Gospel must be central. The Law and sanctification without the Gospel many times turn into legalism. The Holy Spirits words in the book of Galatians show what happens when someone turns back to the law. If sermons lose the Gospel, then we do the same as the circumcision party in Galatians. Without the Gospel the law strangles the spirit. Without the Gospel, sanctification turns into an extension of the law. The Gospel is the power of the Christian faith and of the Christian faith in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strictly speaking, the modern preacher is not a prophet, for the real prophets received direct revelation from God. We hear from them in both the Old and New Testaments. The modern preacher does speak the Word of God to people and so we do carry on the prophetic ministry of what has already been revealed in the Word of God in the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Christian Worship</title>
      <link>/en/courses/304/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/304/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;An Introduction to Biblical Worship 简介圣经的敬拜&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CONTENTS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is worship?
什么是敬拜？&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worship is both a personal and group activity
敬拜是个人和集体的属灵生活&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In worship we give ourselves to God, but more ————————importantly God gives his Word and Sacraments to us.
在敬拜中我们将自己献给上帝，————————更重要的是籍着道和圣礼上帝将恩典赐给我们。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The God of heaven is with us everywhere,————————but in a special way in group worship.
天父上帝无处不与我们同在，————————集体敬拜是上帝与我们同在的一种特殊方式。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worship can be spontaneous, but planned ————————structured worship has advantages.
敬拜可以是自发的，而有准备的————————敬拜有很多益处&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is pleased with our humble worship, but worship is ————————a gift to God and therefore should be the best we can offer.
上帝喜悦我们谦卑的敬拜，但是敬拜也是————————我们献给上帝的礼物， 因此我们应当献上最好的。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worship is a universal experience but should ————————reflect a Christian&amp;rsquo;s culture.
敬拜是普世性的经验，但应该————————反映基督徒的文化&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When we worship we fellowship with God ————————and fellowship with other Christians
敬拜是我们与上帝之间的交通,————————也是基督徒之间的团契&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appendix 1: Brief overview and explanation ————————of the main liturgies in Christian Worship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appendix 2: The Church Year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appendix 3: Colors and their Meaning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appendix 4: Symbols and Art&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appendix 5: The Pastor: His Clothing and Actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Christian Stewardship</title>
      <link>/en/courses/302/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:51:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/302/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Course Syllabus
课程大纲&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life With Our Lord (Stewardship-Discipleship)
与主同在的生活（管家职份—门徒职份）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description: A comprehensive introduction to the basic matters of Christian stewardship and discipleship.
简介：这门课程是对基督徒管家职份和门徒职份的基础知识的综合介绍。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Course Objectives: The objectives of this course are to help students
课程目标：这门课程的目标是帮助学生们：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain a clear, biblical understanding of whole life Christian stewardship and discipleship
1）对基督徒管家职份和门徒职份的整体生活获得清晰的、基于圣经的理解。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To lead students to make thoughtful, grace-led decisions regarding the Christian use of their time, abilities, possessions, money and the Gospel.
2）在有关基督徒使用时间、能力、财产、金钱与福音上，引导学生做出深思熟虑的、由恩典引导的决定。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To prepare students to equip others to be faithful Christian managers of their lives for God.
3）使学生们预备好去装备他人成为为神而活的、忠实的基督徒管家。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To help students grow in their ability to apply the Law and Gospel to themselves and to others in matters of Christian stewardship and discipleship.
4）帮助学生们在管家职份和门徒职份方面的事物上，能更好地对他们自己或别人运用律法和福音。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline:
大纲：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lesson 1: Answering The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Call To Life
第一课：回应主对生命的呼召
Lesson 2: Fighting The Battle For Life
第二课：为生命征战
Lesson 3: Managing Life For Our Lord
第三课：为主管理生活
Lesson 4: Gaining Strength From Our Lord&amp;rsquo;s Word
第四课：从主的话语中获得力量
Lesson 5: Communicating Personally With Our Lord
第五课：个人与主交通
Lesson 6: Making Disciples For Our Lord (Part 1)
第六课：领人作主的门徒（第一部分）
Lesson 7: Making Disciples For Our Lord (Part 2)
第七课：领人作主的门徒（第二部分）
Lesson 8: Managing Spiritual Gifts For Our Lord (Part 1)
第八课：为主管理我们的属灵恩赐（第一部分）
Lesson 9: Managing Spiritual Gifts For Our Lord (Part 2)
第九课：为主管理我们的属灵恩赐（第二部分）
Lesson 10: Managing Life Resources For Our Lord
第十课：为主管理生活资源
Lesson 11: Living To Live A Holy Life For Our Lord
第十一课：为主过圣洁的生活
Lesson 12: Serving People For Our Lord
第十二课：为主服侍人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching Procedures:
教学过程：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructor will work with the students (through a translator, if necessary) to carefully go through the teaching material and exercises for each lesson. The instructor will give the final exam at the conclusion of the class.
教师会与学生一起（如有需要，通过翻译）认真地学习每一课的学习资料和练习。在课程结束的时候，教师会进行期末考试&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching Materials:
教学资料：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Life With Our Lord” (bilingual edition) 
与主同在的生活（双语版）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Course Length:
教程：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course will generally take between 18-24 hours of instruction time to complete.
完成这门课程大概需要18到24小时的课时。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements For Credit:
学分要求：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to get credit for the completion of a course, the student must do the following:
课程结束后想要获得学分的学生必须做到以下几点：
• Be in attendance for at least 75% of the instruction periods
• 至少应参加75%的课时
• Actively participate in the instruction periods when present
• 课堂中积极参与
• Complete on time and in a satisfactory manner any assignments and/or tests given by the instructor
• 按时并令人满意地完成教师布置的作业和/或者测试 　　　 　　　&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Evangelism</title>
      <link>/en/courses/301/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/301/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Syllabus of Evangelism 
福音传道课程大纲&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Course Title: Evangelism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description: During this course we will review key Biblical doctrines that will help prepare students to do the work of evangelism. We will study several methods for sharing the good news of God’s Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;课程描述：我们在本课程中将回顾基要圣经教义，帮助学生为传福音事工做准备。我们将学习几种分享神话语中的福音的方法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Course Objectives: The objectives of this course are to help students&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;课程目标：该课程旨在帮助学生&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gain a clear understanding of Bible teachings related to evangelism
获得关于圣经对福音传道的教导的清楚理解&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand that the work of sharing God’s Word is given to all God’s people
明白分享神的话语是所有神的子民的工作&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn several methods for sharing God’s Word.
学习分享神的话语的几种方法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Course Outline:
课程大纲：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lesson 1 – What is Evangelism?
第一课—— 什么是福音传道？
Lesson 2 – Natural and Revealed Knowledge of God
第二课—— 对神的自然认知和启示认知
Lesson 3 – Our Triune God, His Creation, and the Fall into Sin
第三课—— 我们三位一体的神，神的创世，和人坠入罪中
Lesson 4 – Christ, His Work and It’s Results
第四课——基督，他的事工和果效
Lesson 5 – The Work of the Holy Spirit: Justification by Faith Alone
第五课——圣灵的工作：因信称义
Lesson 6 – Faith Walk, Faith Talk
第六课——行走的信心，传讲的信心
Lesson 7 – Some Ways to Share
第七课——分享的方法
Appendix 1 – Explanation of “Our Dilemma, God’s Solution”
附录1——解释“我们的困境，神的良策”
Appendix 2 – Explanation of “A Handy Way to Witness”
附录2——解释“作见证的捷径”
Appendix 3 – Spiritual Mentoring: A Primer for Christians
附录3—— 灵性的辅导： 基督徒入门&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching Procedures:
教学程序：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructor will work with the students through a translator to carefully go through the materials in each lesson. A final exam will be given at the conclusion of the class.
教师每节课将通过翻译，与学生一起认真完成教材的学习。课程结束时进行期末考试。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements for Credit:
确立学分要求：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to get credit for the completion of a course, the student must do the following
学完课程为了获得学分，学生必须达到以下标准：
Be in attendance for at least 75% of the instruction periods
参加至少75%教程的学习
Actively participate in the instruction periods when present
上课时积极参与
Complete on time and in a satisfactory manner any assignments and/or tests given by the instructor
对于教师分配作业或测试准时完成，令人满意。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
