<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>恩典圣经学院 – 事工</title>
    <link>/zh-cn/tags/%E4%BA%8B%E5%B7%A5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 事工 on 恩典圣经学院</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:43:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/zh-cn/tags/%E4%BA%8B%E5%B7%A5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 基督徒心理辅导</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/405/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:43:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/405/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;课程介绍目标&#34;&gt;课程介绍/目标&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们观察这个世界的任何地方，都会发现人们迫切需要帮助。本课程是心理辅导系列课程的第一部分，目的是向基督徒概述当他们提醒别人神在基督里的救赎大爱时，人们可能面临的各种问题。（诗篇34:18耶 和 华 靠 近 伤 心 的 人 ， 拯 救 灵 性 痛 悔 的 人）。基督徒心理辅导 ，第一部分 主要讨论圣经中如何解决认知/情绪失调 的问题。第二部分将着重于家庭结构失调的问题。大家可以参看讲义中提供的课程主题目录。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;本课程的目的是为基督徒心理辅导人员提供资源它将提供如下帮助&#34;&gt;本课程的目的是为基督徒心理辅导人员提供资源。它将提供如下帮助&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;理解并准确评估个人的争战；&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;带领讨论并提供有效建议；&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;记住使人的问题得以解决的过程中的关键原则；&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以神的话语为根基，正确使用律法与福音来指导心理辅导方案。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;本课程的教导模式将提供协作形式的学习体验以触摸学生的思想内心和决策为目的本课程的教学理念旨在通过所有的学习影响人的智力感情和意志&#34;&gt;本课程的教导模式将提供协作形式的学习体验，以触摸学生的思想，内心和决策为目的。本课程的教学理念旨在通过所有的学习影响人的智力，感情和意志&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;每个主题通常被分成下面的纲要格式：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;案例研究– 每个主题以叙述人在具体的事情上争战的实例开始，。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;关键词– 提供重要定义，以便学生更好地理解讨论的问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;原因/特征–以一系列陈述或提问帮助学生理解一个具体的争战。这同样有助于决定是否需要转交给医生或其他专业人士。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;心理辅导建议— 学生要学习制定辅导方案，以便应用圣经的观念达到最佳果效。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;遵循步骤— 这些步骤将使学生知道如何分辨问题并找到心理辅导的解决方案。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;路上的灯— 圣经经文和简洁评论将有助于学生学习怎样将心理辅导置于圣经的框架中，因此籍着圣灵的力量给以真正的，灵性的指导。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;思考题—辅导员可以问这些问题作为谈话的切入口，或仅作为基督徒和另一个朋友讨论争战的话题。这些有意“敞开的”和“非公开的”问题使学生在辅导中便于提问采集信息，从而对情况进一步深入讨论。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;实例练习— 给学生机会应用每课案例学习中讨论的原则。这使学生获得实际经验，并在课堂里应用协作学习的方法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*请注意并非每节课都要完全按照该纲要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;基督徒心理辅导第一部分的主题讨论目录&#34;&gt;基督徒心理辅导第一部分的主题讨论目录&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;上瘾&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;抑郁&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;羡慕/ 嫉妒&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;悲痛/ 损失&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;害怕/焦虑&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;愧疚/羞耻&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;愤怒&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;决心&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;期望和结果&#34;&gt;期望和结果&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;教师责任&#34;&gt;教师责任&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;课程设置为8周。每节课90分钟。本课程由教师与学生合作完成（必要时通过翻译）。教师在时间允许的情况下准备教授每一课。教师在课程结束时将给予最终评估。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;教学材料&#34;&gt;教学材料&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;教师提供讲课笔记或讲义：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;课时&#34;&gt;课时&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本课程通常需要花12-14课时完成。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;学分评估准则&#34;&gt;学分评估准则&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圆满完成本课程学习，学生要达到以下要求：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;至少75%的课堂出席率。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;积极参加课堂讨论。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;做好每课复习和预习工作。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;完成教师布置的作业/测试。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*所有圣经参考源自2011年新国际版本。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 讲道学概要</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Introduction of Preaching （讲道学概要）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important Ideas to consider as we speak about Preaching alt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be a speaker of the Word before God’s people or any people is to be an ambassador of Christ Jesus. Any preacher who is more interested in themselves or earning money than in telling people about Jesus and his Word, is a mockery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the call of a preacher to proclaim God’s Word. We are not free to substitute our own ideas. Even though we use all of our life experiences and knowledge in our sermons, even though we think of good ways from modern life to illustrate what God’s Word is saying all those tools are meant to communicate the Word better not change the Word. The message of Jesus, the gospel and all of God’s will in the Bible must be central to all we proclaim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proclaiming God’s Word is an awesome opportunity. Those who are best able to do it are those on whom the Gospel has had an impact. Those who proclaim it well are those for whom the Gospel is an exciting and marvelous gift of God. We proclaim God’s Word for the sake of people with a focus on the Gospel. In preaching we apply what God has given each of us – our personality, our experiences, our faith. Get EXCITED about the opportunity to share God’s Word with people. If proclaiming God’s Word is not exciting to you, then you may better serve the Lord and his kingdom in a different way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central point of Jesus is the Gospel. So in our preaching the central point needs to be the Gospel. Certainly each sermon will have law (some more than others). Each sermon will have sanctification (some more than others). Yet to proclaim both law and sanctification best the Gospel must be central. The Law and sanctification without the Gospel many times turn into legalism. The Holy Spirits words in the book of Galatians show what happens when someone turns back to the law. If sermons lose the Gospel, then we do the same as the circumcision party in Galatians. Without the Gospel the law strangles the spirit. Without the Gospel, sanctification turns into an extension of the law. The Gospel is the power of the Christian faith and of the Christian faith in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strictly speaking, the modern preacher is not a prophet, for the real prophets received direct revelation from God. We hear from them in both the Old and New Testaments. The modern preacher does speak the Word of God to people and so we do carry on the prophetic ministry of what has already been revealed in the Word of God in the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
