<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>恩典圣经学院 – 婚姻的意义</title>
    <link>/zh-cn/courses/303/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 婚姻的意义 on 恩典圣经学院</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 03:29:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/zh-cn/courses/303/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第一课	预备婚姻(1)</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/303/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/303/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;以下这些婚前问题是为帮助即将结婚的夫妇而设计的。回答这些问题时，就像你自己正准备结婚一样。在你完成问题后，老师会引导全班讨论问题和答案。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preparing For Marriage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;婚前准备&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;讨论问题&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following questions have been developed to help you think through some important aspects of marriage with your intended spouse. You are to answer each question by checking the Yes or No column after each statement. After you have answered the questions, you will discuss them with your future spouse and the pastor to help prepare you for a strong, healthy married life. Be prepared to explain your answers as we discuss them. Feel free to add  notes as we work through the questions together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以下的问题帮助你思考与你未来的配偶建立婚姻的一些重要内容。在每一个问题后回答“是”，或“否”。答完后与你未来的配偶以及牧师讨论，以帮助你建立一个坚固健康的婚姻。在我们讨论这些问题时，请做好准备解释你的答案。也欢迎随时对你的答案作补充。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A.My Relationship With My Spouse 我与配偶的关系&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes 是&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No 否&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next to God, my spouse is the most important person in the world to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;除了神，我的配偶是我生命中最重要的人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can expect that the feelings my spouse and I have for each other will remain basically the same throughout our marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我可以期待，我和配偶对彼此的感情在整个婚姻中基本保持不变。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not fully know either myself or my spouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我对自己或我的配偶都不完全了解。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that my spouse and I do and will agree on most of the issues that we will face in our marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我相信我和配偶，对我们婚姻中将要面对的问题意见会或将会一致。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more familiar I become with my spouse, the less time I will need to take to communicate with him/her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我对配偶越熟悉与他/她沟通所花的时间越少。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not think that it is wise or helpful for my spouse and I to keep secrets from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我认为配偶相互保留秘密不是明智或有益的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My growth in faith in Christ will be very helpful to the quality of my relationship with my spouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我在基督里信心的长进，对改善我与配偶关系的品质有很大的帮助。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In marriage, forgiveness for each other is understood and does not need to be verbally requested or granted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在婚姻中，彼此的饶恕是理解不需要口头请求和承诺。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is foolish for me to assume that I know what my spouse is feeling or thinking about something without me asking him/her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;假定我没有问他/她就知道配偶的感受或想法，这是愚蠢的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a problem develops in my marriage, it will be helpful to determine who is at fault and then assign the proper amount of blame to each individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我的婚姻出现问题时，判断是谁的责任然后对各人给予适当的责备是有必要的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider divorce to be a permissible action to take if things do not work out the way I would like them to between my spouse and me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我认为离婚在我和配偶之间可允许的行为，如果事情不按我期望的方式解决。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be times in my marriage when it would be helpful to seek the counsel of my pastor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12.在我的婚姻中有时寻求牧师忠告是有益的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B.Our Home And Family Life 我们的家及家庭生活&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes 是&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No 否&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I believe that children are a precious gift of God and desire to have children, if God grants them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我相信孩子是神所赐的珍贵礼物，我渴望有孩子如果神赐给我。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God permits couples to use means of preventing pregnancies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神允许夫妻使用节育措施。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christian freedom,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒的自由，&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1Cor. 10: 23-24, 31, 23“I have the right to do anything,” you say—but not everything is beneficial. “I have the right to do anything”—but not everything is constructive.24No one should seek their own good, but the good of others. 31So whether you eat or drink or whatever you do, do it all for the glory of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;林前 10: 23-24, 31, 凡事都可行，但不都有益处。凡事都可行，但不都造就人。无论何人，不要求自己的益处，乃要求别人的益处。
31 所以，你们或吃或喝，无论做什么，都要为荣耀 神而行。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Peter 3:7 Husbands, in the same way be considerate as you live with your wives, and treat them with respect as the weaker partner and as heirs with you of the gracious gift of life, so that nothing will hinder your prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;彼前 3:7 你们作丈夫的也要按情理（原文作“知识”）和妻子同住；因她比你软弱（“比你软弱”原文作“是软弱的器皿”），与你一同承受生命之恩的， 所以要敬重她。这样，便叫你们的祷告没有阻碍。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problems with infertility are something to suffer in silence and keep to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;无生育能力是一件只能默默忍受、不能告诉别人的事。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aborting a pre-born child when the life of the mother is not in danger&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is a sinful taking of human life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在母亲没有生命危险的情况下，堕胎是杀害生命的有罪行为。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children will have a rather small impact on our marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;孩子对我们婚姻的影响将会非常小。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important need a child has is to have a saving relationship with God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一个孩子最重要的需要是与救主建立关系。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husbands are to be the spiritual heads and leaders of their families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;丈夫应该是这个家庭的属灵领导和头。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary duties of a wife and mother are to love her husband and children and to look after their well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一个妻子和母亲的基本责任是爱她的丈夫和孩子，照顾他们的安康。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My spouse and children can expect that their greatest joys in life will come from the family itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我的配偶和孩子可以期望，他们生命中最大的喜乐将来自家庭本身。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very important for the happiness of my family that we always reach agreement on the matters that deeply concern us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在我们深切关心的问题上常常达成协议，对我家庭的幸福非常重要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can hurt my family members by being too absorbed in their lives and by ignoring my individual needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我太专注于家人的生活而忽略我个人的需要就会造成对家人的伤害。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will probably learn the greatest lessons about human sin and God’s grace in the experiences I have with my family members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12.在与我家人的经历中我将学到最好的功课关于人的罪和神的恩典。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial Matters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;财务问题&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making money is one of the most worthwhile goals we can strive to reach in our lives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在我们的生活中，挣钱是我们可以努力达到的最有价值的目标之一。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God is really the Owner of all we have and He gives us the job of managing these things to serve His purposes in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神其实是我们一切所有的主人，他赐给我们工作去管理事务，是为他对我们生命的计划服务。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To save money at first, it is best for newlyweds to live with one set of parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为了省钱新婚夫妇最好先与父母住在一起。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spouse who best manages money should be the handler of the family finances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;善于理财的配偶应该作家庭经济的管理者。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Budgeting for family expenses is not very practical because spending priorities can easily lead to arguments and because unexpected expenses always seem to arise anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;家庭开支预算不太实际，因为优先要花的部分很容易导致争吵，还因为不可预料的开支似乎总会出现。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “I-have-to-have-it-now” philosophy is the biggest problem families face with their finances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“我现在就得要”的哲学，是家庭经济面对的最大问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving a generous portion of my income for my God and His work is the first obligation I have with the income I receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;把我收入的大部分献给神及他的事工，是我收入的首要责任。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saving and investing money for future needs are disciplines that couples should begin early in their marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;攒钱或用于未来的投资，是婚姻中的夫妇尽早开始的财务纪律。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a will and/or other estate plans are matters that a young family does not have to be concerned about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.立遗嘱或其它财产计划，是年轻家庭不需要关注的事情。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spiritual Life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;属灵生活&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My relationship with God is something that I deeply care about and am devoting a good deal of my time and energy to develop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;与神的关系是我深切关心的事情。我奉献大量的时间和经历来发展和神的关系。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am confident that I will go to heaven when I die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我确信当我离开这个世界时我会去天堂。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently attend worship services regularly with my future spouse and am encouraging him/her to grow spiritually by my actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我现在经常与未来的配偶定期地参加崇拜聚会，通过我的行动鼓励他/她在灵里成长。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am regularly involved in an organized study of God’s Word in my church or Christian fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我定期参加教会或基督徒团契组织的圣经学习。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally read the Bible and pray to God regularly and intend to do that with my spouse when we are married.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我经常自己读圣经向神祷告。打算结婚以后也与我的配偶这样做。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand the teachings of the Bible fairly well and am able to explain them clearly to other people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我能够相当好地明白圣经的教导，能够清楚地向他人讲解。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since religion is such a personal matter, I think that it is wise not to discuss religious differences that I may have with my spouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因为宗教是个极私人化的事情，我认为明智的做法是不要与配偶谈论宗教上的不同。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For good or bad, parents have a tremendous influence on the spiritual life of their children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;无论好坏，父母对孩子的属灵生活都有极大的影响。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My actions in obedience to Jesus Christ are just as important as the words I speak to confess and praise Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我顺服耶稣基督的行动，与我承认他的名和赞美他同样重要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Babies are born sinful and should be baptized as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.婴儿自出生就有罪，因此需要尽早地给他们施洗。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E. Love And Sex 爱与性&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes 是&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No 否&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good sexual relationship with my spouse is the key factor in having a fulfilling marriage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;与配偶良好的性关系，是拥有一个美满婚姻的关键因素。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God loves me unselfishly and wants me to love my spouse in the same self-giving way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神无私地爱我也想让我以这种无私舍己的方式爱我的配偶。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexual relations before marriage or outside of marriage are permissible as long as the people involved genuinely care about each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;只要两人彼此真诚地关心，婚前或在婚外性行为是允许的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God will forgive people who sincerely repent of their sins of sexual immorality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝会赦免那些真心悔改其罪及淫乱罪的人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot possibly love my intended spouse any more than I do right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我不可能比现在更爱我的未婚配偶了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My faith in God will have a strong influence in my love life with my
spouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我对神的信心将会对我和配偶的爱情生活产生有力的影响。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexual relations should be a pleasurable experience for both the husband and wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;性关系对夫妻双方都应该是一种很愉悦的经历。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My spouse and I should be ready to respond to each other’s desire for sexual relations at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我和配偶都应该随时准备好回应对方的性需要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a good marriage, the sexual aspect will generally take care of itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.在一个好的婚姻中，都会普遍地照顾性生活。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F. Social Life 社交生活&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes 是&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No 否&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to get along with my intended spouse’s family is very important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;与我未来配偶的家人和睦相处对我很重要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since a married couple have each other’s companionship, they do not need much contact with other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因为已婚夫妇有彼此的陪伴，他们不太需要和他人联系。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long separations for the sake of getting an education or advancing one’s career have very little impact on a marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为了受教育或晋升事业而造成的长期分居，对婚姻造成的影响非常小。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some Christian friends and family members who can and will be a wholesome influence on my marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有一些基督徒的朋友和家人，他们能够对我的婚姻产生健康有益的影响。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第二课	预备婚姻 (2)</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/303/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/303/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Complete the discussion of the Preparing For Marriage statement introduced in Lesson 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;完成讨论第一课中关于婚前准备的陈述介绍&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第三课	婚姻的奥秘 (第一章)</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/303/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/303/3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Pre-Reading Questions:预读问题&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you read this chapter, answer these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你读本章之前请回答这些问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offer 3 reasons why people want to be married.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;给出人想要结婚的三个理由。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offer 3 reasons why people do not want to be married or stay married.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;给出人不愿结婚或维持婚姻的三个理由。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 1 – The Secret Of Marriage Questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第一章&amp;mdash;-婚姻的奥秘 问题：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer these questions as you read or after you read the chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在你阅读或读完本章后回答这些问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The Decline Of Marriage)  婚姻日渐衰微&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the opening section of the chapter, what reasons does the author present for a decline in marriage?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在本章的开篇，作者提出了婚姻衰微的原因是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What reasons for the decline of marriage are especially applicable to China?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;结婚率下降的原因有哪些尤其适用于中国？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;（ The Search For A Compatible “Soul Mate” ） 找一个合得来的“心灵伴侣”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;( Making Men Truly Masculine) 让男人成为真男人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the author say about the idea of finding an ideal “soul mate”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;关于寻找理想心灵伴侣的想法，作者说什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The Irony Of Pessimistic Idealism) 悲观理想主义的讽刺&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does the belief in a marriage based on a self-centered idealism (“Me- Marriage”) lead to a pessimistic attitude toward marriage?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对婚姻信仰以自我为中心的理想主义(以我为本的婚姻)为基础，是如何导致对婚姻的悲观态度？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What valuable insights about love does the quotation from C.S. Lewis reveal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;引用C.S.刘易斯的这句话关于爱揭示了什么宝贵见解？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(You Never Marry The Right Person)你从未嫁/娶对人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does Professor Stanly Hauerwas contend that “we never marry the right person”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么斯坦利·豪厄尔斯教授主张“我们从未嫁/娶对人”？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your opinion, how big a factor is a person’s natural sinfulness, that is selfish, rebelliousness against God and His will, and unloving toward others, in the problem of incompatibility with a spouse in marriage?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在你看来，一个人天生的罪性就如自私、违背神和他的旨意、不爱他人、在婚姻中与配偶不和谐等问题有多大的因素？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Apocalyptic Romance) 世界末日的爱情&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite its critics why is marriage necessary for most people and for society?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;即有批评，为什么婚姻对大多数人和社会是必要的?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;（The Great Secret ） 极大的奥秘&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;（No False Choices) 无错的选择&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the great secret that God reveals through Paul’s writing about marriage in Ephesians 5?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神通过保罗在以弗所书 5 中所写的婚姻揭示了什么极大的奥秘？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggest two ways in which marriage can be painful for a person in a good and helpful way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请给出两种方式，说明婚姻对人来说既是痛苦的又好且有益的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggest two ways in which marriage can be wonderful for a person as God intends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请列举两种方式，说明婚姻对人来说既是奇妙的又如神所愿那样。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第四课	圣经关于婚姻的教导</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/303/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/303/4/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Introduction 引言:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this lesson we will explore some of the primary sections of the Bible that address the topic of marriage. These precious passages from God’s Word will give us a better understanding of God’s plan to bless people in marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在本课我们将探讨圣经中有关婚姻的一些主要章节。来自神宝贵的话语将使我们更好地明白神的计划和对人婚姻的祝福。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-ephesians-522-33&#34;&gt;A. Ephesians 5:22-33&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;bible&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;h6&#34;&gt;Ephesians 5:22–33&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Wives, submit yourselves to your own husbands as you do to the Lord. For the husband is the head of the wife as Christ is the head of the church, his body, of which he is the Savior. Now as the church submits to Christ, so also wives should submit to their husbands in everything. Husbands, love your wives, just as Christ loved the church and gave himself up for her to make her holy, cleansing her by the washing with water through the word, and to present her to himself as a radiant church, without stain or wrinkle or any other blemish, but holy and blameless. In this same way, husbands ought to love their wives as their own bodies. He who loves his wife loves himself. After all, no one ever hated their own body, but they feed and care for their body, just as Christ does the church—for we are members of his body. “For this reason a man will leave his father and mother and be united to his wife, and the two will become one flesh.” This is a profound mystery—but I am talking about Christ and the church. However, each one of you also must love his wife as he loves himself, and the wife must respect her husband.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;small class=&#34;text-muted float-right mt-n3&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;i&gt;The New International Version.&lt;/i&gt; 2011.
        &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;bible&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;h6&#34;&gt;以弗所书 5：22–33&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;你们作妻子的，当顺服自己的丈夫，如同顺服主。因为丈夫是妻子的头，如同基督是教会的头；他又是教会全体的救主。教会怎样顺服基督，妻子也要怎样凡事顺服丈夫。你们作丈夫的，要爱你们的妻子，正如基督爱教会，为教会舍己。要用水借着道把教会洗净，成为圣洁，可以献给自己，作个荣耀的教会，毫无玷污、皱纹等类的病，乃是圣洁没有瑕疵的。丈夫也当照样爱妻子，如同爱自己的身子；爱妻子便是爱自己了。从来没有人恨恶自己的身子，总是保养顾惜，正像基督待教会一样，因我们是他身上的肢体。为这个缘故，人要离开父母，与妻子连合，二人成为一体。这是极大的奥秘，但我是指着基督和教会说的。然而，你们各人都当爱妻子，如同爱自己一样。妻子也当敬重她的丈夫。&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;small class=&#34;text-muted float-right mt-n3&#34;&gt;
        
        《中文圣经和合本－神版》
        &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of what great spiritual relationship does God intend the marriage of a man and a woman to be a reflection? ( see verses 23-27, 32)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神想要男人和女人的婚姻反映了什么伟大的属灵关系? (参看 23- 27,32 节)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When God addresses the wife’s role in marriage in verses 22-24, He calls on the wife to submit to her husband. The word “submit” in this context is often misunderstood to mean “to give the slavish, unquestioning obedience of an inferior person to one who is superior.” Actually, the word “submit” as used here means “to willingly surrender one’s self-interests and accept the responsibility to live for the benefit of the one God has placed in authority over you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当神在 22-24 节谈到妻子在婚姻中的角色时，他呼吁妻子顺服她的丈夫。“服从”这个词在文中经常被误解为“上级对下级盲从和绝对的服从”。事实上，“顺服”用在这的意思是“甘愿放弃自己的利益去承担责任，就为那赐给你力量的神而活”。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what ways is the Church’s (all Christian believers’) submission to Jesus Christ a model for a wife to follow as she relates to her husband? (see verses 22-24)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;教会(所有基督徒)以何种方式顺服耶稣基督，成为妻子遵循她与丈夫关系的榜样? (见第 22 - 24 节)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What great responsibility does God give the husband in his relationship to his wife in verses 25-27?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在 25-27 节中，在丈夫与妻子的关系中神赋予了丈夫什么重大的责任？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what ways is Christ’s love for the Church (all Christian believers) a model for the husband to follow as he relates to his wife? (verses 25-27)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督对教会(所有基督教信徒)的爱在哪方面是丈夫在与妻子相处时应该遵循的榜样? (第 25 - 27 节)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What additional point is God making in verses 28-31 when He calls on husbands to love their wives as they love themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在 28-31 节中神呼吁丈夫爱妻子就像爱他们自己一样，这额外说明了什么?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What important understanding about what happens in marriage does God give when Paul quotes Genesis 2:24 in verse 31?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;保罗在 31 节引用创世记 2:24，神对婚姻中发生的事给了什么重要的领悟？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do phrases such as “Christ is the head of the church, his body, of which he is the Savior,” (verses 23b) and “just as Christ loved the church and gave himself up for her to make her holy, cleansing her by the washing with water through the word, and to present her to himself as a radiant church, without stain or wrinkle or any other blemish, but holy and blameless,” (verses 25b-27) teach us about what motivates Christians to fulfill the roles God gives them in marriage?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诸如“基督是教会的头；他又是教会全体的救主。”(23 节下),“正如基督爱教会，为教会舍己。 要用水藉着道把教会洗净，成为圣洁， 可以献给自己， 作个荣耀的教会， 毫无玷污、皱纹等类的病， 乃是圣洁没有瑕疵的。”(25 节下-27 节) 这些话语教导我们什么去激励基督徒履行神给他们在婚姻中的角色？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;b-1-peter-31-7&#34;&gt;B. 1 Peter 3:1-7&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;bible&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;h6&#34;&gt;1 Peter 3:1–7&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Wives, in the same way submit yourselves to your own husbands so that, if any of them do not believe the word, they may be won over without words by the behavior of their wives, when they see the purity and reverence of your lives. Your beauty should not come from outward adornment, such as elaborate hairstyles and the wearing of gold jewelry or fine clothes. Rather, it should be that of your inner self, the unfading beauty of a gentle and quiet spirit, which is of great worth in God’s sight. For this is the way the holy women of the past who put their hope in God used to adorn themselves. They submitted themselves to their own husbands, like Sarah, who obeyed Abraham and called him her lord. You are her daughters if you do what is right and do not give way to fear. Husbands, in the same way be considerate as you live with your wives, and treat them with respect as the weaker partner and as heirs with you of the gracious gift of life, so that nothing will hinder your prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;small class=&#34;text-muted float-right mt-n3&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;i&gt;The New International Version.&lt;/i&gt; 2011.
        &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;bible&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;h6&#34;&gt;彼得前书 3：1–7&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;你们作妻子的要顺服自己的丈夫；这样，若有不信从道理的丈夫，他们虽然不听道，也可以因妻子的品行被感化过来；这正是因看见你们有贞洁的品行和敬畏的心。你们不要以外面的辫头发，戴金饰，穿美衣为妆饰，只要以里面存着长久温柔、安静的心为妆饰；这在　神面前是极宝贵的。因为古时仰赖　神的圣洁妇人正是以此为妆饰，顺服自己的丈夫，就如撒拉听从亚伯拉罕，称他为主。你们若行善，不因恐吓而害怕，便是撒拉的女儿了。 你们作丈夫的也要按情理和妻子同住；因她比你软弱，与你一同承受生命之恩的，所以要敬重她。这样，便叫你们的祷告没有阻碍。&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;small class=&#34;text-muted float-right mt-n3&#34;&gt;
        
        《中文圣经和合本－神版》
        &lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to what God teaches in Ephesians 5, what does God expect of wives in relation to their husbands? (verse 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;类似于神在以弗所书 5 章所教导的，神期望妻子与丈夫有什么关系? (1 节)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does God state as the primary way for Christian wives to influence their non-Christian husbands to embrace the Christian faith? (verses 1-2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神教导基督徒妻子影响非基督徒丈夫接受基督教信仰的主要方式是什么? (1 - 2 节)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In light of what God teaches in verses 1-2, comment on the quotation: “Love that is only talked about is easily turned aside, but love that is demonstrated is almost irresistible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据神在 1-2 节中的教导，评价这句话:“挂在嘴边上的爱情很容易放到一边；表现在行动上的爱情则不可抗拒。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does God teach us about the essence of true beauty in a woman in verses 3-5a?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在 3-5 节中上帝教导我们关于女人真正美丽的实质是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify two ways in which the beauty that comes from outward adornment and the beauty of a godly, inner self are different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;辨别两种方式的不同，来自外在修饰的美和来自自我敬虔内在的美。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some things that might cause a Christian wife to give way to fear and so fail to do what is right in her marriage and in her life before God? (verse 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在神面前，什么事情会使一个基督徒妻子她的婚姻和生活中屈于惧怕而不能做对的事情? (6 节)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean for a husband to respect his wife as “the weaker partner” in their marriage relationship? (verse 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在婚姻关系中，丈夫尊重妻子“因她比你软弱”这意味着什么? (7 节)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean for a husband to respect his wife as “heirs with him of the gracious gift of life” in their marriage relationship? (verse 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在婚姻关系中，丈夫尊重他的妻子“与你一同承受生命之恩的”，这意味着什么? (7 节)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain the connection between the way a husband treats his wife and the way God responds to his prayers? (verse 7)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;解释丈夫对待妻子的方式和上帝回应他的祷告方式之间的关系? (7 节)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第五课	婚姻的力量(第二章)</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/303/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/303/5/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Pre-Reading Questions: 预读问题:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you read this chapter, answer these questions. 你读本章之前请回答这些问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of his novels, the French writer, Albert Camus, has one of his characters declare: “People say that I am cold and unloving. This is not true. There is one great love that I have conceived in my life – a love of which I am always the object.” List 3 problems that you can envision this kind of love causing in a marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在法国作家阿尔贝·加缪的一部小说中，他笔下的一个人物宣称:“人们说我冷酷无情。这不是真的。在我的一生中我认定了一种伟大的爱&amp;mdash;我总是以这种爱为对象。”列举三个你能想象到的，这种爱情在婚姻中会导致的问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share your belief on where a person can acquire the ability to love a marriage partner in an unselfish way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;分享你的信仰，在哪里一个人可以获得能力无私的去爱婚姻伴侣。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 2 – The Power For Marriage Questions:  第二章&amp;mdash;-婚姻的力量 问题：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer these questions as you read or after you read the chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当你阅读或读完本章后回答这些问题。&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


    ( Be Filled With The Spirit ) 被圣灵充满

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What roles do Jesus Christ and the Holy Spirit play in a person’s ability to follow God’s plan for marriage?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在个人遵行神婚姻计划的能力中，耶稣基督和圣灵扮演什么角色?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


    （Submit To One Another） 彼此顺服

&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


    （The Problem Of Self-Centeredness ) 自我为中心的问题

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give 2 examples of how a person’s self-centeredness can interfere with a close, loving relationship between marriage partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;举两个例子说明以自我为中心的人，是如何影响婚姻配偶之间亲密相爱关系的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does God call on married people to put aside their selfish interests and willing seek the interest of their spouses?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么神要呼吁已婚的人放下私心自愿去寻求配偶的利益?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


    (The Wounds We Carry) 伤痕累累

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give an example you are familiar with of how unhealed emotional wounds a person has experienced in the past have harmed or destroyed a marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;举一个你熟悉的例子，说明一个人过去经历中未治愈的情感创伤是如何伤害或破坏了婚姻的。&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


    (Confronting Our Self-Centeredness) 面对私心

&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;(It Only Takes One To Begin Healing） 从我开始&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How resolved are you to work on dealing with your own self-centeredness in your marriage and other relationships?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;怎样解决和处理你自己在婚姻和人际关系中以自我为中心的问题?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should you be willing to work on improving yourself as a marriage partner even if your spouse is not interested in improving himself/herself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;即使你的配偶对改善自己不感兴趣，为什么你还愿意为改善自己而努力呢?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(The Fear Of Christ) 敬畏基督
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Growing In The Fear Of The Lord) 在敬虔中成长（更加敬畏主）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the author mean when he says we should have a proper “fear of the Lord”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;作者说我们应该完全地“敬畏主”是什么意思?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What difference does it make if a person lives by the principle of loving one’s spouse because of God’s grace in Jesus Christ and not because the spouse is deserving of love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果一个人生活中爱配偶的原则是因为神在耶稣基督里的恩典而不是因为配偶值得被爱，这有什么不同呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第六课	婚姻的精髓(第三章)</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/303/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/303/6/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Pre-Reading Questions: 预读问题:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you read this chapter, answer these questions. 你读本章之前请回答这些问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agree or Disagree? It is possible for a person to truly be in love with another person even if they do not have loving feelings toward that person. (Explain why your answered as you did)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意或不同意? 一个人有可能真正爱上另一个人即使他们对那个人没有爱的感觉。(解释你为什么这样回答)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agree or Disagree? In marriage, it is fair for a person to think that he/she should be able to at least get as much out of the relationship as he/she has put into it. (Explain why you answered as you did.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意或不同意? 在婚姻中一个人认为他/她至少应该从这段关系中得到和他/ 她投入的一样多，这是公平的。(解释你为什么那样回答。)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 2 – The Essence Of Marriage Questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第 2 章 婚姻的本质问题:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer these questions as you read or after you read the chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在你阅读或读完后回答这些问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


    ( Love and the “Piece Of Paper ) 爱情与那张纸

&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;(The Overly Subjective View Of Marriage) 过于主观的婚姻&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your opinion, what motivates a person to think that “marriage is just a piece of paper”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在你看来，什么会促使一个人认为“婚姻只是一张纸”？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is wrong with the view many hold that love is about having romantic feelings for someone without a sense of responsibility or obligation toward  that person?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;许多人认为爱情就是对某人产生浪漫的感觉却没有责任感或义务，这种观点有什么错呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;( Consumer Or Covenant ) 消费或盟约
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(The Vertical And Horizontal ) 垂直与平行
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;( Love And Law ) 爱和法律
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain what a “consumer relationship” is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;解释什么是消费关系。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain what a “covenant relationship” is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;解释什么是盟约关系。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the author means when he says that there are both vertical and horizontal aspects to the marriage relationship?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;作者说婚姻关系既有垂直也有平行两个方面，这是什么意思？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does making a solemn, binding agreement (a covenant) to a person in marriage increase rather than decrease intimacy for the married couple?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么对已婚的人订立一个庄严的、有约束力的协议(盟约)会增加而不是减少已婚夫妇的亲密感？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;( The Promise Of Future Love） 对未来爱情的承诺
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;（ The Power Of Promising） 承诺的力量
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;（The Freedom Of Promising） 承诺的自由
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;（Promise And Passion )承诺与激情
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give 3 reasons why the solemn promise of life-long faithfulness to serve one’s spouse is essential for a fulfilling marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请给三个理由说明为什么承诺终生忠诚地去服事配偶是美满婚姻的本质。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(Helping Romantic Love Fulfill Itself) 浪漫的爱情有助实现自我
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is the person who is guided only by romantic feelings not actually “free” to love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么仅仅被浪漫感情所引导的人实际上不能自由地去爱？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;( Emotion And Action） 情感与行为
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Actions Of Love Lead To Feelings Of Love） 爱的行为引发爱的感觉
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;（ Deciding To Love ) 决定去爱
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do feelings of love for another person and decisions to take loving actions for another person work together to benefit spouses in marriage?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对一个人爱的感觉和对一个人采取爱的行动是如何共同决定已婚夫妇受益的呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you advise a person who tells you: “I know that I should not, but I no longer have loving feelings for my spouse.”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果有人告诉你:“我知道我不应该，但我对我的配偶已不再有爱的感觉了。” 你会怎么建议呢?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;（The Bargain） 讨价还价
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-primary&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;（He Stayed ) 他从未没离开我们
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;11&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does the blessed truth that Jesus Christ willingly refused to abandon us in our worthless wickedness and endured all God’s punishing anger for us to win our salvation help us when we are tempted to quit on our marriages?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们想要放弃婚姻的时候，主耶稣基督甘意拒绝放弃我们在我们无用的罪恶中，并且忍受了神为我们所做的惩罚和愤怒来赢得我们的救恩，这个神圣的真理怎样帮助我们呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
