<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>恩典圣经学院 – 创世纪 12-25</title>
    <link>/zh-cn/courses/106/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 创世纪 12-25 on 恩典圣经学院</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 03:28:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/zh-cn/courses/106/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第一课 神呼召亚伯拉罕并且在埃及慈爱地保护他</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/106/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/106/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;简介&#34;&gt;简介&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本课程研习创世纪第12-25章，亚伯拉罕的故事。亚伯拉罕是神的救恩计划当中最为重要的人物之一。他的故事表明了，神如何借着福音的应许来生发信心并且建立信心。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯拉罕的故事就是信心伟人的故事。虽然他的信心也起起落落，但是他因着神的应许在自己身上的成就而学到功课，那就是，主耶和华所告诉我们的事情无论看起来多么奇妙或者不可能，我们都要有信心。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创12是亚伯拉罕故事的开始，那时他大概70-75岁。创12开始神呼召他的时候，亚伯拉罕的名字还是亚伯兰。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在创11:26-30，我们得到关于亚伯兰的几个重要信息：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;他是他拉的儿子，是诺亚儿子闪的后裔。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;他有两个哥哥——拿鹤和哈兰。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;他们全家住在迦勒底的吾珥。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;亚伯兰的哥哥哈兰很年轻地时候便在吾珥去世，他有一个儿子叫罗得。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;亚伯兰的妻子叫撒莱，撒莱不能生育——没有孩子。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;迦勒底的吾珥&#34;&gt;迦勒底的吾珥&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经说亚伯兰和他的家人本来住在迦勒底的吾珥。创15:7当中，耶和华对亚伯兰说：“我是耶和华，曾领你出了迦勒底的吾珥，为要将这地赐你为业。”旧约当中四次提到这个地方（创11:28；11:31；15:7；尼9:7），徒7:2-4也提到这个地方，就是司提反说吾珥是在“米所波大米……迦勒底人之地。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;很多学者认为，迦勒底的吾珥位于下美索不达米亚的幼发拉底河上。十九世纪二十到三十年代，英国考古学家伦纳德·伍利爵士(Sir Leonard Wooley) 假定那是亚伯拉罕的出生地，挖掘了这个令人难忘的遗址。发掘工作表明，在亚伯拉罕时期（约公元前2000年），该城市的文化已经相当繁荣先进。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;考古学家发掘出的遗址包括大型庙宇、皇家陵地以及城市街道上的房屋遗迹。陵地当中有很多珍宝——包括用金银宝石制成的令人惊叹的物品——这些物品可以和古代埃及著名墓葬中发现的珍宝相媲美。吾珥的居民似乎相当富有，可能是因为该城市毗邻波斯湾，他们可以与其他民族贸易往来。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;吾珥有冷热自来水、下水道系统、多层建筑、铺好的道路、大型寺庙、华丽的家具和各种金属乐器。吾珥人发明了一种方法，把一小时分为六十分钟，一分钟分为六十秒，并且把圆分为三百六十度——我们今天仍旧使用这种划分方法。那时也有非常发达的法律制度，以及标准度量体系。还有一个运河系统，连接底格里斯河和幼发拉底河的峡谷，用来控制洪水和提供灌溉，这样农耕可以全年进行。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;还有一座巨大的金字塔神庙被发掘出来，是一座类似金字塔的泥砖塔，建于公元前2100年，是献给吾珥月亮神祗的。这个金字形神庙基底约135英尺x 200英尺，神庙高65英尺。神庙有三个平台，每个平台一个颜色。神庙顶部有一个银质神龛。吾珥大金字塔是献给月亮神祗南纳的。人们敬拜月亮之神，因为其乃是控制天堂和地上生命循环的力量。在米索不达米亚的诸神当中，南纳是至高无上的，因为他乃是庄稼、牲畜和家庭生育的来源。人们给月亮献上祈祷和祭品，以此求得祝福。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这里是亚伯兰和他的家族曾经生活的地方，周围满是不信的人。然而，主耶和华呼召亚伯兰离开那里，去到一个新的地方，在那里他要使得亚伯兰的后裔成为大国。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;亚伯拉罕的宗教背景&#34;&gt;亚伯拉罕的宗教背景&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;关于亚伯拉罕的前75年，圣经几乎完全没有提到。约书亚记给我们提供了关于那个时代的信息：“古时你们的列祖，就是亚伯拉罕和拿鹤的父亲他拉，住在大河那边事奉别神”（约24:2）。从创31:30当中我们可以得知，拉班（亚伯拉罕哥哥拿鹤的孙子）家中供有“神像”（偶像），拉结偷了神像，去迦南的时候给带走了。显然，这些家供的神像对拉班和拉结都非常重要。因此，我们知道亚伯兰家族曾经也拜偶像。但是亚伯拉罕拜不拜呢？亚伯拉罕是在什么时候开始知道并且相信耶和华，这位独一真神的呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;关于亚伯拉罕在迦勒底吾珥时期，有很多传说（圣经当中没有记载）。有一个传说非常有意思，其中提到亚伯兰被邪恶的宁录王所害，逃去诺亚和闪那里住了很多年。1 该传说提到，诺亚教导了亚伯兰关于耶和华的事，因此，亚伯兰并不像他的父亲他拉和其他族人那样拜偶像。圣经当中并没有提到这个传说，但是这个传说解释了，为什么尽管他居住在拜偶像的人中间，亚伯兰仍旧是个敬畏神的人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;事实真相到底如何，我们并不清楚。很有可能亚伯兰知道诺亚。根据创世纪第十一章记载的家谱，诺亚950岁去世的时候，亚伯兰58岁。实际上，在亚伯拉罕的前半生，从诺亚开始到他父亲他拉的十代人都还活着。所以，亚伯兰很有可能认识诺亚，也有可能是诺亚教导他，真神如何拯救诺亚和他的家人脱离洪水。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;创世纪有关亚伯拉罕的记录总结&#34;&gt;创世纪有关亚伯拉罕的记录总结&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;下面是我们研经课程每一章的简单小结。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创12——神呼召亚伯兰并在埃及保护他&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创13——亚伯兰和罗得分开&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创14——亚伯兰营救罗得&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创15——神重申他对亚伯兰的应许&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创16——撒莱干涉，以实玛利出生&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创17——和亚伯拉罕的割礼之约&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创18——三位天使到访亚伯拉罕&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创19——所多玛、蛾摩拉覆灭&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创20——亚伯拉罕和亚米比勒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创21——以撒出生&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创22——亚伯拉罕信心受试炼&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创23——撒拉死亡埋葬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创24——亚伯拉罕为以撒娶妻&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创25——亚伯拉罕死亡&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;亚伯拉罕生平时间表&#34;&gt;亚伯拉罕生平时间表&lt;/h2&gt;







&lt;div class=&#34;data-table&#34;&gt;
  &lt;table class=&#34;table table-hover&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year/时间 BC(公元前)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;年龄&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;事件&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;地点&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;圣经经文&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2297&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;他拉出生&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;迦勒底的吾珥&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;创11:32；12:4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2227&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;亚伯拉罕的哥哥拿鹤、哈兰出生&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;迦勒底的吾珥&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;创11:26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2167&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;亚伯兰出生（其父他拉130岁）&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;迦勒底的吾珥&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;创11:32,12:4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2157&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Birth of Sarai  (Abram’s future   wife) 撒莱出生（亚伯兰未来的妻子）&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ur of the Chaldeans 迦勒底的吾珥&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cf Genesis 17:17 参创17:17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Death of Abram’s   brother Haran (father of Lot) 亚伯兰哥哥哈兰（罗得之父）去世&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ur of the Chaldeans 迦勒底的吾珥&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 11:28 创11:28&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Abram marries Sarai 亚伯兰娶撒莱&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ur of the Chaldeans 迦勒底的吾珥&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 11:29 创11:29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2097&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Terah, Abram,   Sarai, and Lot relocate 他拉、亚伯兰、撒莱和罗得搬家&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ur to Haran 吾珥到哈兰&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 11:31 创11:31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2092&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;75?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Death of Terah (age   205) in Haran 他拉在哈兰去世（年205岁）&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Haran 哈兰&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 11:32 创11:32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2092&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;75&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;God calls Abram to   go to Canaan 神呼召亚伯兰去迦南&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Haran to Shechem,   Bethel, the Negev 哈兰到示剑、伯特利、南地&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 12:1-9 创12:1-9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Abram goes to Egypt   during the famine 大饥荒时亚伯兰去到埃及&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Egypt 埃及&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 12:10-20 创12:10-20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Abram rescues Lot/Melchizadek 亚伯兰营救罗得/麦基洗德&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sodom 所多玛&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 14:1-24 创14:1-24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2082&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;85&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Abram conceives   child with Hagar 亚伯兰由夏甲得子&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Negev 南地&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 16:3 创16:3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2081&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Birth of Ishmael  以实玛利出生&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Negev 南地&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 16:16；17:24-25 创16:16；17:24-25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2068&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Abraham is   circumcised; God appears to Abram promising him a son Abram renamed   Abraham 亚伯拉罕受割礼；神向亚伯兰显现，应许他会生一个儿子，神改亚伯兰名为亚伯拉罕&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Negev, near Mamre 南地，临近幔利&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 17:24；18:14 创17:24；18:14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2068&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sodom and Gomorrah 所多玛和蛾摩拉&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 19:24 创19:24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2068&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Abraham lives with   Philistines 亚伯拉罕住在非利士人中&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gerar 基拉耳&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 20:1-18 创20:1-18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2067&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Birth of Isaac 以撒出生&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Negev 南地&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 21:1-5 创21:1-5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;110-120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Isaac spared by   Angel of the Lord 耶和华的使者不杀以撒&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mt. Moriah   (Jerusalem) 摩利亚山（耶路撒冷）&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 22:1-19 创22:1-19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2030&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;137&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Death of Sarah (age   127) 撒拉去世（年127岁）&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hebron 希伯仑&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 23:1-2 创23:1-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2027&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;140&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Isaac marries   Rebekah 以撒娶利百加&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Negev 南地&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 24 and   25:20 创24；及创25:20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2007&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;160&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Birth of Jacob and   Esau 雅各、以扫出生&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Beer Lahai Roi 庇耳拉海莱&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 25:26 创25:26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Marriage to Keturah 娶基土拉&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mamre 幔利&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 25:1 创25:1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1992&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;175&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Death of Abraham 亚伯拉罕去世&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mamre 幔利&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genesis 25:7 创25:7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;阅读创121-9&#34;&gt;阅读创12:1-9&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神为什么让亚伯兰离开本地本族，去往一个新的地方？（第1-2节）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神给了亚伯兰哪七个应许，鼓励他遵行神的呼召？（第2-3节）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第3节最后一个应许就是应许使万族得福的救主。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对此，新约当中的下列经文说得非常清楚：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 加3:6-9——正如，亚伯拉罕信神，这就算为他的义。所以你们要知道那以信为本的人，就是亚伯拉罕的子孙。并且圣经既然预先看明，神要叫外邦人因信称义，就早已传福音给亚伯拉罕，说，万国都必因你得福。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• “从撒母耳以来的众先知，凡说预言的，也都说到这些日子。你们是先知的子孙，也承受神与你们祖宗所立的约，就是对亚伯拉罕说，地上万族，都要因你的后裔得福。神既兴起他的仆人，就先差他到你们这里来，赐福给你们，叫你们各人回转，离开罪恶。”（徒3:24-26）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神给我们很多应许，正如他给亚伯拉罕很多应许一样。神并没有应许说，只要我们相信他，我们就可以富有、出名，或者子孙兴旺；而是应许我们，只要遵行他的话，就会蒙福。他应许赦免我们的罪。他应许会聆听并且回应我们的祷告。他应许会在末日的时候让我们的身体复活。他应许会在新的地方给我们一个家——就是我们天上的迦南地，天上的房屋。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神能够成就他的应许吗？他会吗？当然会！神应许了就会成就。他成就了向亚伯拉罕所作的应许，他也会成就向我们所作的应许！我们可以相信神对我们的应许，就像亚伯拉罕相信神一样。他并不知道神要让他去到哪里，也不知道神为什么要那么做，但是他知道神的应许是真的，是可信的，这令他信心十足。我们也可以向亚伯拉罕一样信靠顺服。主带领我们所走的道路，尽管有时候看起来崎岖难行，却仍旧是正确的道路。尽管危机四伏，我们慈爱的父却与我们同在。他让我们离弃罪的道路，应许说他会祝福我们带领我们道新的地方，我们可以确信，他一定会一路祝福我们、保守我们，并且带领我们平安到达永恒的家。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意或不同意？神对亚伯兰的呼召，与其说是邀请他相信并且忠心，不如说是要求他顺服。（请对你的回答进行解释）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们为什么可以说亚伯兰相信神对他的应许？（见来11:8）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰为什么要在他在迦南地所停留的前两个地方（示剑和伯特利）给耶和华筑坛？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第9节提到了“南地”，那是亚伯兰要去的地方。南地是迦南地的南部，位于死海的西南。那地乃是沙漠地带，雨水非常稀少，温度很高。那是迦南地最不好的地方。亚伯兰为什么要去那里？或许是因为住在那里的人非常少，十分开阔。他能够在那里找到地方安顿下来。在南地的别示巴，有一口井，亚伯兰似乎就住在井附近。那口井成为他家的人口和牲口的饮用水源。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们想到亚伯拉罕的时候，就会想到他是大有信心的人，是信徒的父，甚至是信心的伟人。在前面的经文当中，我们看到了他有信心的诸多凭据。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但是在接下来的经文当中，我们知道，亚伯兰的信心也不是完全的。下面是一段令人伤心失望的记载，那段日子亚伯兰允许其他男人娶他的妻子。更为糟糕的是，亚伯拉罕这么做不仅一次，而是两次，我们将会在接下来的课程中看到。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰的行为令人失望，但是神是信实的，是有怜悯的，哪怕我们的所作所为令人失望。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;阅读创1210-20&#34;&gt;阅读创12:10-20&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;迦南地有饥荒。迦南地雨水很少，人和牲畜都靠着春雨和秋雨才能存活。如果雨没有按时降下或者没有降雨，就会发生饥荒。那时，就有这样的饥荒。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;然而，哪怕是在雨水很少的时候，在埃及，尼罗河仍旧有充沛的水源来进行灌溉。埃及地有粮食，这促使亚伯兰举家带着牲畜挪移帐朋到那里去，这样才能在患难之时得以存活。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;什么促使亚伯兰和撒莱对他们的关系撒谎（创12:10-13）？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;耶稣和他的门徒在一起的时候，湖上起了风暴，门徒十分害怕，他们大喊“夫子，夫子，我们丧命啦!”耶稣平静风浪之后，斥责他们说：“你们的信心在哪里呢？”（路8:24-25）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;彼得信中教导基督徒妻子的时候（彼前3:1-6），他用撒拉作为榜样：“做妻子的……只要以里面存着长久温柔安静的心为妆饰。这在神面前是极宝贵的。因为古时仰赖神的圣洁妇人，正是以此为妆饰，顺服自己的丈夫。就如撒拉听从亚伯拉罕，称他为主。你们若行善，不因恐吓而害怕，便是撒拉的女儿了。”我一直好奇彼得所想的“害怕”是什么。害怕顺服男人吗？或者彼得认为，亚伯兰和撒莱害怕去到埃及？或者彼得是在说“不要（像撒拉一样）害怕”？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;还有一节经文：罗8:15——“你们所受的不是奴仆的心，仍旧害怕。所受的乃是儿子的心，因此我们呼叫阿爸，父。”主啊，帮助我们信靠你，不要害怕。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;关于在撒莱的事情上为什么要向埃及人撒谎，亚伯兰给了三个理由，是哪三个？（创12:11-13）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意或不同意？亚伯拉罕计划蒙骗埃及人，是一种不信的行为。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神拯救亚伯兰（和撒莱）因为欺骗的罪而招致的后果，为什么神要那么做？（第17-18节）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰和撒莱被赶出埃及一事提醒我们，亚当和夏娃也被赶出伊甸园。亚伯兰和撒莱，正如亚当和夏娃一样，对神的应许心存怀疑，他们经历了不信神的话所带来的后果。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;从亚伯兰的这次事件，我们学到什么功课？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;尽管亚伯兰是一个真的信徒，有的时候他的信心依旧软弱、不成熟。神也会继续对亚伯兰施恩典，以圣约来确认他的应许，并且试验洁净亚伯兰的信心。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;下一课（第13课）中，我们会继续学习亚伯兰对他侄子罗得的爱心关切。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第二课 亚伯兰和罗得分开——创13</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/106/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/106/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION 简介&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As chapter 12 ended, Abram and his family had been expelled from Egypt because of his shameful attempt to deceive the Pharaoh. In spite of his conduct in Egypt, Abram returned to Canaan as a very wealthy man, with many flocks and herds and both male and female servants (see Genesis 12:16). God had kept his promise to bless Abram (12:2) and this promise was being kept, even though Abram had done nothing to deserve God’s rich blessings. It is clear that God was being gracious to Abram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在第十二章结尾的时候，亚伯兰和他的家人被赶出埃及，因为他想要欺骗法老，那种做法不大光荣。然而，尽管他在埃及的行为不体面，亚伯兰回到迦南地的时候十分富有，带着许多牲畜和奴隶（见创12:16）。神成就了他的应许，大大祝福了亚伯兰（创12:2）。哪怕亚伯兰的所作所为不配得到神的祝福，神也依旧信守他的承诺。显而易见，神对亚伯兰满有恩典。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not know whether the famine was over or not as Abram’s family returned to Canaan, but they traveled north to the places where they had pitched their tents before. We read in verses 3-4 that the family returned to the middle of Canaan where Abram had previously built an altar and confessed his faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们不知道，当亚伯兰家回到迦南的时候，饥荒有没有结束；不过，他们沿路北上回到他们曾经支搭帐棚的地方。阅读第3-4节，我们就知道，他们一家回到了迦南中部，就是亚伯兰曾经筑坛认信的地方。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;READ GENESIS 13:1-4 阅读创13:1-4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/1. What was Abram’s purpose in building an altar and proclaiming the name of the Lord (vs. 4)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰筑坛求告耶和华的名，他的目的是什么（第4节）？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;READ GENESIS 13:5-13 阅读创13:5-13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 7 reminds us that the land of Canaan was still occupied by the Canaanites, and so Abram’s group and Lot’s group had only the less desirable part of the land (the part not already occupied by the Canaanites) as grazing land for their large flocks and herds. Though Canaan was a land “flowing with milk and honey,” with a fertile soil that would support life, there was simply not enough space for both groups to provide ample grazing for their animals. On the surface, that may seem to be the reason for the separation. However, there was something else happening through this event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第7节提醒我们，迦南地仍旧由迦南人占据；所以亚伯兰的人和罗得的人只能住在别人不想住的地方（迦南人没有占据的地方），以此来作为他们诸多牲畜的放牧之地。虽然迦南地是“流奶与蜜之地”，土地肥沃滋养生命，只不过没有那么多地方供两大群人来牧养牲畜。表面看来，这是他们分开的原因。然而，造成这个结果的还有其他原因。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God had previously separated Abram from most of his relatives, but his nephew Lot had remained part of his traveling group. Lot may have been an orphan, the son of Abram’s brother Haran who had died in Ur of the Chaldeans (Genesis 11:28), and it seems that Abram and Sarai had committed to caring for Lot and keeping him as part of their family. But the Lord had promised that Abram and Sarai would have a family of their own, and so now the Lord would arrange for Abram to also separate from Lot and his family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;之前，神带领亚伯兰离开他的大多数亲族，但是他的侄子罗得一直与他同行。罗得是个孤儿，是亚伯兰的哥哥哈兰的儿子。哈兰死在迦勒底的吾珥（创1:28）。亚伯兰和撒莱似乎承诺要照顾罗得，把他当做自己家的一员。然而，耶和华应许亚伯兰和撒莱会有自己的家。现在，耶和华安排亚伯兰和罗得、罗得的家人分开。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there was another part of God’s promise to Abram (“To your offspring I will give this land” – Genesis 12:7) that was involved in this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神对亚伯兰的应许还包括另外一部分（“我要把这地赐给你的后裔”——创12:7），也和这一事件有关。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/2. Agree or disagree: Since the Lord had promised the land of Canaan to Abram and his offspring (12:7), it was not a good thing that Abram would offer to give it to Lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意或不同意：耶和华已经应许要把迦南地赐给亚伯兰和他的后裔（12:7），亚伯兰要把这地给罗得，这样并不是好事。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our text describes the place to which Lot and his group re-located. It was in the direction of the “plain of the Jordan … toward Zoar” (v. 10). In verse 12 we read that eventually Lot and his group settled near the city of Sodom, a city that would eventually place his family in great trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;经文描述了罗得和他的牧人迁移的地方，是在“约旦河的全平原，直到锁珥”（第10节）。在第12节，我们得知，最终罗得和他牧人们在所多玛附近安家。他的家最终在那里遭遇了大麻烦。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two possible locations for the city of Sodom. For many years, most Bible scholars believed that the best possible location was at the southeastern end of the Dead Sea. But recently some archaeologists have suggested that the preferred location was at the northeastern end of the Dead Sea because that location was closer to the Jordan River.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;下一页的地图显示，所多玛可能的位置有两处。有许多年，大多数圣经学者认为所多玛最有可能位于死海的东南部。但是近年来，有些考古学家认为其更有可能位于死海的东北部，因为那里离约旦河更近。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A solution to this situation is that it is possible that Lot’s group first moved toward the area where the Jordan River flows into the Dead Sea, and then migrated further south toward Zoar, which was at the southern end of the Dead Sea. That theory would fit with the location of Sodom and Gomorrah closer to the southeastern end of the Dead Sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;要想解释这一情况，可能就是，罗得一行人首先迁移到了约旦河流入死海的地方，然后继续南移，到了锁珥，也就是死海的南部。这个说法能够解释所多玛和蛾摩拉靠近死海东南部的情形。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter which location we choose, the important fact is that Lot’s group located at the far edge of Canaan, and eventually outside of the borders of Canaan altogether. That would leave the entire land of Canaan to the offspring of Abram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;不论我们认为所多玛位置在哪里，最重要的事实是，罗得一行人先是在迦南的边缘，最终移到了迦南以外。这样，整个迦南就归亚伯兰的后裔所有。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later (Genesis 19:37–38) we learn that Lot became the ancestor of the Ammonites and the Moabites. Abram almost handed over the Promised Land to the same people who, in the author’s own day (e.g., Numbers 22–25) and throughout Israel’s subsequent history (Deuteronomy 23:3–6; Ezra 9:1), were the primary obstacle to the fulfillment of the promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们知道，稍后（创19:37-38）罗得成为了亚扪人和摩押人的祖先。亚伯兰差一点就亲手把应许之地交给了阻碍应许成就的那群人，他们在作者的年代（如民22-25）和以色列历史上（申23:3-6；拉9:1）都是应许成就的主要障碍。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/3. What do we learn from the fact that Lot chose to relocate to the east, leaving the land of Canaan for Abram and his family?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗得迁移到东边，把迦南地留给了亚伯兰及其家族。从这一事实我们学到了什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verses 10-13, Moses mentions what we will read about in chapter 19 – the destruction of Sodom and Gomorrah because of the great wickedness within those cities. Did Lot realize the spiritual danger that would come upon him and his family when he pitched his tents near Sodom? We don’t know. But we do know that eventually he ended up living not just near the city, but within the gates of the evil city itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在第10-13节，摩西提到了所多玛和蛾摩拉的毁灭，它们毁灭是因为城内的大恶之事，这在第19章当中会提到。当罗得渐渐挪移帐棚到所多玛的时候，他有没有意识到他和家人所面临的属灵危险？我们不得而知。但是我们的确知道，最终，他不仅仅是住得离那城很近而已，而是住到了那个罪恶之城的里面。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;READ GENESIS 13:14-18 阅读创13:14-18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/7. Why did God renew and expand his promise to give Abram’s offspring the land of Canaan? (vs. 14-16)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么神要更新并且扩展他对亚伯兰的应许，把迦南地赐给他的后裔？（第14-16节）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/9. Agree or Disagree? In verse 15, God promised that Abram&amp;rsquo;s descendants would be entitled to possess the land of Canaan for all time. (see Deuteronomy 28:63, 10:17-18) (Explain your answer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意或不同意？在第15节，神应许亚伯兰的后裔将永远拥有迦南地。（见申28:63,0:17-18）。（请解释你的回答）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/10. How did Abram give proof/evidence that he believed God&amp;rsquo;s promise? (vs. 17-18)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰如何表明他相信神的应许？（第17-18节）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/11. Identify at least three things we might do to show that we believe God’s promise that He will give us full possession of the promised land of heaven in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果我们相信神的应许，即将来我们要承受天上的应许之地，我们需要做些什么才能证明我们真的相信。请举出至少三件我们可以做的事情。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第三课 亚伯兰营救罗得——创14</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/106/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/106/3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-简介&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION 简介&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In chapter 13 we read that Lot and his family moved near Sodom, a very wicked city. Eventually, Lot and his family moved into Sodom itself and were living among the unbelievers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们在第十三章读到，罗得和家人迁移到了邪恶之城所多玛附近。最终，罗得和家人搬进了所多玛城，和不信的人住在了一起。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The king of Sodom had made an alliance with four other kings in the area. For 12 years all five of those city-kings had been under the rule of a powerful king from the north named Kedorlaomer. The political tension of this situation resulted in warfare that would involve both Lot and Abram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;所多玛王和当地的其他四个王结盟。十二年来，这五个城的王都要事奉北方一个强大的王，名叫基大老玛。这一情况导致的政治紧张局势最终发展成了战争，使得罗得和亚伯兰都牵涉其中。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The historical event described in this chapter would become an example of the ways that God was keeping his promises to Abram. It will also introduce us to a new king who would become a pattern of Jesus himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本章所描述的历史事件成为神向亚伯兰守信的例子。这次事件也向我们介绍了一个新的王，他预示了耶稣自己。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-genesis-14112-阅读创141-12&#34;&gt;READ GENESIS 14:1–12 阅读创14:1-12&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four Canaanite kings mentioned here were on a rampage across the territory that is now within the nation of Jordan, on the east side of the Jordan River valley. They swept south and defeated …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;此处所提及的四个横冲直撞的迦南地的王，他们的领地在今天约旦国境内，在约旦河谷地的东岸。他们横扫南部，并且打败了……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• the Rephaites 利乏音人
• the Zuzites 苏西人
• the Emites 以米人
• the Horites 何利人
• the Amalekites 亚玛力人
• the Amorites 亚摩利人
• the five kings in the valley of Siddim 西订谷的五王&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sweeping military victories of these 4 kings indicate that their combined armies were a formidable force, able to overpower one tribe of people after another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;四王压倒性的军事胜利表明，他们的联军是一股强大的力量，能够征服一个又一个部族。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to escape capture or death at the hands of Kedorlaomer’s army, the kings of Sodom and Gomorrah and some of the other leaders of those cities fled to the tar pits and the hills bordering the valley (v.10). The Hebrew word translated as “fell” into the tar pits may also indicate that they “jumped” into the tar pits in order to escape the invading army. The picture is one of desperation. Thus, even though their cities were captured and the inhabitants led away as prisoners of war, the kings themselves survived by running and hiding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为了逃避被基大老玛俘获或者死亡的命运，所多玛王和蛾摩拉王以及其他几个城的王逃到了石漆坑和山谷附近的山上（第10节）。被翻译为“掉”在坑里的希伯来文词语可能也意味着他们是“跳进”石漆坑，以此来逃避追兵。这是一幅绝望的画面。因此，尽管他们的城被占领，居民被掳为战俘，君王自己却因着逃跑和躲藏幸存了下来。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-genesis-141316-阅读创1413-16&#34;&gt;READ GENESIS 14:13–16 阅读创14:13-16&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time that the term “Hebrew” is used in the Bible (verse 13). Why was Abram called “the Hebrew”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是圣经当中第一次出现“希伯来人”这个词（第13节）。亚伯兰为什么被称为“希伯来人”？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Abram come to be an ally of three Amorites (Mamre, Eshcol, Aner)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰为什么会和三个亚摩利人（幔利，以实各，亚乃）联盟？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 14 says that Abram had 318 trained men born in his household. This would indicate that these men had all been trained in warfare and knew how to fight. This also indicates how large Abram’s group was. He had his own private army, so to speak. These men were a significant force, able to defend Abram’s group against any who would attack them. It must have taken a large amount of food and drink to sustain a group so large. This is an indication of Abram’s great wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第14节提到，亚伯兰有在他家里生养的精壮丁三百一十八人。这暗示着这些人都受过军事训练，并且知道如何打仗。这也表明亚伯兰的队伍很壮大。可以说，他有自己的私人军队。这些人是一股很强的力量，能够在有人想要攻击他们的时候护卫亚伯兰的军队。他们可能带着大量的食物和水来供养这么大的军队。这也表明了亚伯兰拥有巨大财富。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abram’s group was able to do what the five kings of the Valley of Siddim could not do, and they defeated the army of four kings and recovered all of the people and possessions that had been taken. This was a testimony to the power of Abram’s group. But even more than that, it was a testimony to the Lord’s blessing upon Abram. Abram had already become a great nation blessed by God, just as the Lord had promised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰的军队能够完成西订谷五王无法完成的事情，他们打败了四王的军队，夺回了被掳去的人和财物。这也证明了亚伯兰军队的力量。然而更为重要的是，这证明了耶和华对亚伯兰的祝福。亚伯兰已经因着神的祝福而成为大国，就像耶和华所应许的那样。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What were the factors that led to Abram’s victory over the four Canaanite kings?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;是哪些原因让亚伯兰赢了迦南的四个王？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the lesson of this event?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这次事件让我们学到什么功课？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;READ GENESIS 14:17–24 阅读创14:17-24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Abram’s group returned from defeating the four kings and rescuing all of the captives including Lot and his family, we read that the king of Sodom had crawled back out of the tar pit in which he had taken refuge (v.10) and came north to meet Abram’s victorious group. They met in the Valley of Shaveh (v.17 which was also known as “the King’s Valley.”  The exact location of this valley is unknown, but many believe that it was somewhere near Salem (another name for the city of Jerusalem (see Psalm 76:2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰打败四王，把被掳掠的人都夺了回来，包括罗得及其家人。我们读到所多玛王从他躲藏的石漆坑（第10节）里爬了上来，并且到北方来迎接亚伯兰胜利归回。他们在沙微谷（第17节，沙微谷也称为“王谷”。我们不清楚这个谷的准确位置，但是很多人相信其在撒冷[耶路撒冷的另一个名字&amp;lt;见诗76:2&amp;gt;]附近）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the king of Sodom, we read that the king of Salem also came to meet Abram in that valley. The king of Salem was Melchizedek, a beautiful name that in Hebrew means “king of righteousness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;除了所多玛王，撒冷王也到谷里来迎接亚伯兰。撒冷王是麦基洗德，这是一个很美的名字，在希伯来文当中的意思是“公义之王”。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is Melchizedek described in verse 18? What two roles did he have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第18节所描述的麦基洗德是怎么样的？他有哪两个角色？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is Melchizedek described in Hebrews 7:1-3?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;来7:1-3如何描述麦基洗德？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several important things that the Bible teaches us about this man. First of all, we read in verse 18 that he was a “priest of God Most High.” This is the same thing that Abram called the Lord in verse 22: “the LORD, God Most High, Creator of heaven and earth.”  Thus, both he and Abram believed in the one true God, in contrast to all of the other Canaanites. The fact that Melchizedek was a priest of the Lord and that he offered sacrifices to the Lord as an act of worship, meant that he practiced his faith in the city of Salem where he was king. How did Melchizedek come to know and worship the one true God? We do not know. But it is noteworthy that here in the middle of all of the Canaanite idolatry was a man who knew the Lord and openly worshiped Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;关于这个人，圣经教导了我们很重要的几件事。首先，在第18节当中，他是“至高神的祭司”。而第22节当中，亚伯兰正是如此称呼耶和华“天地的主至高的神耶和华”。所以，麦基洗德和亚伯兰都相信独一的神，和其他的迦南人不同。麦基洗德是耶和华的祭司并且他献祭给耶和华作为敬拜的形式，这表示他在自己做王的城里践行他的信仰。麦基洗德如何认识独一真神并且敬拜他的呢？我们不知道。但是值得注意的是，在迦南地拜偶像的风气当中，有一个人认识耶和华，并且公开敬拜他。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What two things did Melchizedek do to honor Abram? (verses 18-19)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;麦基洗德做了哪两件事表示对亚伯兰的尊敬？（第18-19节）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Melchizedek’s blessing (verses 19-20) teach Abram (and everyone else who heard the blessing)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;麦基洗德的祝福（第19-20节）教给亚伯兰（以及所有听到这个祝福的人）什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did Abram give Melchizedek a tenth of everything (v. 20)? See Hebrews 7:6–7 for the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰把所得的十分之一给麦基洗德（第20节），为什么？回答见来7:6-7。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his promises to Abram in Genesis 12:2-3, God had said, “I will bless those who bless you.” God richly blessed Melchizedek by designating this man as a picture or type of Jesus Christ. In Psalm 110:4 we read that the Messiah would be “a priest forever, in the order of Melchizedek.” And in Hebrews 5:10 we read that Jesus “was designated by God to be high priest in the order of Melchizedek.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在创12:2-3给亚伯兰的应许当中，神说：“为你祝福的，我必赐福给你。”神大大祝福了麦基洗德，以他作为耶稣基督的预表。在诗110:4里面我们知道，弥赛亚会“照着麦基洗德的等次，永远为祭司。” 在来5:10当中我们知道，耶稣“照着麦基洗德的等次称他为大祭司。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melchizedek was not like the other priests of Israel, who were all descended from Aaron and inherited a priesthood by virtue of their lineage. Melchizedek was also different from all the other Old Testament priests in that he was also a king. Kings were descended from the tribe of Judah. Priests were descended from the tribe of Levi. But Melchizedek was both a king and priest, and in that sense he was like Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;麦基洗德与其他的以色列祭司不同，其他祭司都是来自亚伦家族，是因着血缘继承成为祭司。麦基洗德同旧约当中其他的祭司也不一样，因为他也是君王。君王是来自犹大支派。祭司来自利未支派。但是麦基洗德既是君王又是祭司，所以从这一点来说，他像耶稣一样。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer to the Hebrews explains this. He writes: “For it is clear that our Lord descended from Judah, and in regard to that tribe Moses said nothing about priests. And what we have said is even more clear if another priest like Melchizedek appears, one who has become a priest not on the basis of a regulation as to his ancestry but on the basis of the power of an indestructible life. For it is declared: “You are a priest forever, in the order of Melchizedek.” (Hebrews 7:14–17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;给希伯来人写信的作者对此做出了解释。他写到：“我们的主分明是从犹大出来的。但这支派，摩西并没有提到祭司。倘若照麦基洗德的样式，另外兴起一位祭司来，我的话更是显而易见的了。他成为祭司，并不是照属肉体的条例，乃是照无穷之生命的大能。因为有给他作见证的说，你是照着麦基洗德的等次永远为祭司”（来7:14-17）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not told why the king of Sodom made the extremely generous offer to let Abram keep all of Sodom’s property that he had recovered. Most likely, the offer was not because the king of Sodom was a generous man but because he wanted to sort of bribe Abram into making an alliance with him. He obviously recognized Abram’s power and capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;经文没有告诉我们为什么所多玛王那么大方，让亚伯兰把夺回来的财物都收着。很有可能，这把这些给亚伯兰不是因为他大方，而是想以此贿赂亚伯兰和他结盟。显然，他知道了亚伯兰的军力和能力有多强大。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his response to the king of Sodom Abram used the same terms for the Lord (“God Most High, Creator of heaven and earth”) that Melchizedek had used. Abram was now acknowledging the truth that Melchizedek had spoken about in his blessing: The Lord had blessed Abram with this victory and the recovery of all the people and goods. Thus Abram was giving testimony to the king of Sodom regarding his faith in the one true God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在回复所多玛王的时候，亚伯兰使用了耶和华的同一个称呼（“天地的主至高的神耶和华”），和麦基洗德一样。亚伯兰现在明白麦基洗德对他的祝福：耶和华祝福亚伯兰，让他得胜，并且夺回了被掳的人和财物。所以，亚伯兰在此是在为相信独一的神而向所多玛王做见证。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What parts of God’s promise to Abram in Genesis 12:2-3 were kept in this chapter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在本章当中，创12:2-3当中神对亚伯兰的应许有哪些部分得以成就？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter illustrates that God is faithfully keeping his promises. Abram would experience this and learn that he could trust in all that God had told him. We can believe that the event described in this chapter must have strengthened Abram’s confidence in the Lord’s promises to him. And as we study this chapter, we pray that the events described here will strengthen our trust in the Lord, God Most High, who keeps his promises to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本章表明，神信守承诺。亚伯兰经历了这些，他知道自己可以相信神对他所说的一切话。我们相信，本章所描述的事件增强了亚伯兰对耶和华应许的信心。学习本章的时候，我们祷告，此处所描述的事件也能够增强我们对主的信心，至高的神恪守他的应许。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第四课 神重申他对亚伯兰的应许——创15章</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/106/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/106/4/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;GOD AFFIRMS HIS PROMISES TO ABRAM – GENESIS 15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION 简介&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abram and Sarai had never been able to have children because Sarai was barren. But when Abram was 75 years old (and Sarai was 65) the Lord promised him, “I will make you into a great nation” (Genesis 12:2). Abram correctly understood this to mean that he would have many descendants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰和撒莱没有孩子，是因为撒莱无法生育。但是当亚伯兰75岁（撒莱65岁）的时候，耶和华应许他说“我必叫你成为大国”（创12:2）。亚伯兰的理解是对的，就是他会有很多后裔。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now 10 years had passed (Genesis 16:3) and Abram and Sarai had no children. What God had said seemed humanly impossible. Everything was against the promise He had given Abram. He and Sarai were old, infertile (“as good as dead”), and childless. But “nothing is impossible with God” (Luke 1:37). Though human reason might consider it impossible for Abram and Sarai to have many descendants, God can do all things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但是十年过去了（创16:3），亚伯兰和撒莱还是没有孩子。神说的话在人似乎行不通。所有的事情都和他给亚伯兰的应许相悖。他和撒莱都老了，不能生育（“如同已死”），没有孩子。但是“因为出于神的话，没有一句不带能力的”（路1:37）。虽然在人看来，亚伯兰和撒莱不可能有很多后裔，但是在神凡事都能。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some things that God has told you in the Bible that human reason would regard as impossible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经告诉你的一些事情，在人看来是不可能的。这些事情有哪些？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though Abram believed the Lord’s promises to make of him a great nation, as the years passed Abram began to wonder, “HOW God would do this?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;尽管亚伯兰相信耶和华给他的应许，就是他会成为大国。但是多年过去了，亚伯兰也开始犯嘀咕“神会如何成就呢？”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;READ GENESIS 15:1-6 阅读创15:1-6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In v. 1 the Lord tells Abram: “Do not be afraid, Abram. I am your shield, your very great reward.” A shield is a protection device. God is Abram’s protector. Abram had just returned from defeating the four kings with his servants (Genesis 14). Abram and his group had been involved in warfare and had made enemies to the north. He was living in a foreign land, surrounded by unbelieving Canaanites. His great wealth and his vulnerable position made him nervous. He was a prime target for attack by foreign powers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在第1节当中，耶和华对亚伯兰说“亚伯兰，你不要惧怕，我是你的盾牌，必大大地赏赐你。”盾牌是用来保护的工具。神是亚伯兰的保护者。亚伯兰刚刚带领他的仆人打败四王回来（创14）。亚伯兰和他的军队参加了争战，成为了北方的仇敌。他住在一个陌生的地方，周围都是不信的迦南人。巨大的财富和脆弱的地位使他如履薄冰。他是这些外国强敌的的主要攻击目标。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the Lord appeared to him in a vision to reassure him. Melchizedek had reminded him that the Lord was with him in the victory over the four kings when he said, “Blessed be God Most High who delivered your enemies into your hand” (Genesis 14:20). Now the Lord himself reminds Abram that He was his “shield.” Abram could trust in God to protect him against his enemies. The Lord would not let his promises of blessing fail. However, could Abram also trust that God would keep his promise to make of him a great nation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;所以耶和华在异象当中向他显现，使他安心。麦基洗德已经提醒了他，耶和华与他同在，使他战胜四王，他说“至高的神把敌人交在你手里，是应当称颂的”（创14:20）。现在，耶和华自己提醒亚伯兰说，他是他的“盾牌”。亚伯兰可以相信神会保护他，不受仇敌侵扰。耶和华的应许不会落空。可是，亚伯兰也相信神应许他成为大国的应许吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Abram begin to think that God’s plan might be for making him into a great nation? (v. 2-3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰开始认为神可能使用什么方式使他成为大国（第2-3节）？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did God say to Abram that his plan would actually be? (verses 4-5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神告诉亚伯兰他的计划是什么？（第4-5节）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God’s answer to Abram was to strengthen his faith. Not only would he and Sarai have a child, but through an object lesson, God made it clear that they would have more descendants than they could count.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神回应亚伯兰是为了加强他的信心。他和撒莱不仅会有儿子，而且通过比喻，神清楚地告诉他，他们会有数不清的后裔。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astronomers say that more than 2,000 stars are visible with the naked eye at any one time. The promise of God that Abram’s descendants would be more numerous than the stars had a double fulfillment. Abram’s physical descendants were more numerous than the visible stars: “The LORD your God has increased your numbers so that today you are as many as the stars in the sky.” (Deuteronomy 1:10) And Abram’s spiritual descendants number many more than the visible stars: “If you belong to Christ, then you are Abraham’s seed, and heirs according to the promise.” (Galatians 3:29)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;天文学家告诉我们，任一时间肉眼可见的星星大概有2000颗。神应许亚伯兰他的后裔数算不尽是双重应验。亚伯兰肉身的后裔要比可见的星星还要多：“耶和华你们的神使你们多起来。看哪，你们今日像天上的星那样多”（申1:10）。亚伯兰属灵的后裔更是比星星还要多数倍：“你们既属乎基督，就是亚伯拉罕的后裔，是照着应许承受产业的了”（加3:29）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 15:6 must be a very important verse because it is quoted several times in the New Testament:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创15:6这节经文肯定非常重要，因为新约引用了好几次：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• “Does God give you his Spirit and work miracles among you because you observe the law, or because you believe what you heard? Consider Abraham: “He believed God, and it was credited to him as righteousness.”” (Galatians 3:5–6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“那赐给你们圣灵，又在你们中间行异能的，是因你们行律法呢？是因你们听信福音呢？正如，亚伯拉罕信神，这就算为他的义”（加3:5-6）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• If, in fact, Abraham was justified by works, he had something to boast about—but not before God. What does the Scripture say? “Abraham believed God, and it was credited to him as righteousness.” Now when a man works, his wages are not credited to him as a gift, but as an obligation. However, to the man who does not work but trusts God who justifies the wicked, his faith is credited as righteousness.” (Romans 4:2–5)
“倘若亚伯拉罕是因行为称义，就有可夸的。只是在神面前并无可夸。经上说什么呢？说，亚伯拉罕信神，这就算为他的义。作工的得工价，不算恩典，乃是该得的，惟有不作工的，只信称罪人为义的神，他的信就算为义”（罗4:2-5）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• “The words “it was credited to him” were written not for him alone, but also for us, to whom God will credit righteousness—for us who believe in him who raised Jesus our Lord from the dead. He was delivered over to death for our sins and was raised to life for our justification.” (Romans 4:23–25)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“算为他义的这句话，不是单为他写的，也是为我们将来得算为义之人写的。就是我们这信神使我们的主耶稣从死里复活的人。耶稣被交给人，是为我们的过犯，复活是为叫我们称义”（罗4:23-25）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• “And the scripture was fulfilled that says, “Abraham believed God, and it was credited to him as righteousness,” and he was called God’s friend. You see that a person is justified by what he does and not by faith alone.” (James 2:23–24)
“这就应验经上所说，亚伯拉罕信神，这就算为他的义。他又得称为神的朋友。这样看来，人称义是因着行为，不是单因着信”（雅2:23-24）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let’s consider the fact that Abram believed God’s amazing promise to him. The apostle Paul says that Abram understood the facts of his situation: “He faced the fact that his body was as good as dead—since he was about a hundred years old—and that Sarah’s womb was also dead” (Romans 4:19-20). Yet in spite of all of these factors that seemed to make it impossible for God to keep his promise, Paul writes: “Against all hope, Abraham in hope believed and so became the father of many nations, just as it had been said to him, “So shall your offspring be.” Without weakening in his faith, he faced the fact that his body was as good as dead—since he was about a hundred years old—and that Sarah’s womb was also dead. Yet he did not waver through unbelief regarding the promise of God but was strengthened in his faith and gave glory to God, being fully persuaded that God had power to do what he had promised” (Romans 4:18-21).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;首先，我们知道亚伯兰相信神的奇妙应许。使徒保罗说，亚伯兰明白他的处境：“他自己的身体如同已死——因为他将近百岁——撒拉的生育已经断绝”（罗4:19-20）。但是尽管这些情况似乎说明神无法实现他的应许，保罗写到：“他在无可指望的时候，因信仍有指望，就得以做多国的父，正如先前所说：“你的后裔将要如此。” 他将近百岁的时候，虽然想到自己的身体如同已死，撒拉的生育已经断绝，他的信心还是不软弱， 并且仰望神的应许，总没有因不信心里起疑惑，反倒因信心里得坚固，将荣耀归给神， 且满心相信神所应许的必能做成”(罗马书 4:18-21)。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain the phrase, “he (God) credited it to him (Abram) as righteousness” (verse 6).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请解释短语：“耶和华就以此为他（亚伯兰）的义”（第6节）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apostle Paul explains that this means that Abram was saved through faith. He believed what God had told him. And the promises he believed included this one: “and all peoples on earth will be blessed through you” (Genesis 12:3). In other words, he believed the promise of a Messiah, a Savior, who would bless all people on earth by his work of salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;使徒保罗解释说，这表明亚伯兰因信得救。他相信神告诉他的话。他所相信的应许其中包括“地上的万族都要因你得福”（创12:3）。换而言之，他相信弥赛亚救主的应许，世上所有的人都要因他救赎的工而蒙福。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these chapters we have been studying have the continual theme of God’s faithfulness to his promises. God has been keeping his promises to Abram, and he will keep this one also. Abram’s future glory and ours is tied up in that Son, the holy child of Mary, Jesus Christ, who will bring the blessing of forgiveness of sins and eternal salvation to all who share in the faith of Abram. The way of salvation is the same for us as it was for Abram &amp;ndash; through faith. Jesus once told the Jews, “Abraham saw my day and was glad” (John 8:56). In other words, Abram embraced Jesus as the Savior, trusting not in his own obedience or goodness, but in the Savior that God would send.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们学习的这些章节都有个一贯的主题，就是神对应许的信实。神一直遵守他对亚伯兰的应许，他也会遵守这个应许。亚伯兰将来的荣耀和我们的荣耀都和圣子相连，就是马利亚的圣婴、耶稣基督，他会赐给那些和亚伯兰一样有信心的人赦罪和永恒救恩的福分。我们得救的方式和亚伯兰得救的方式一样——通过信心。耶稣曾经告诉犹太人：“亚伯拉罕欢欢喜喜地仰望我的日子。既看见了，就快乐”（约8:56）。换而言之，亚伯兰拥抱耶稣做为救主，不仅相信他的顺服和良善，也相信他就是神所差遣的救主。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;READ GENESIS 15:7–21 (NIV84) 阅读创15:7-21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Abram first arrived in Canaan many years earlier God had promised him, “To your offspring I will give this land” (Genesis 12:7). Now Abram had been living in Canaan for a number of years, and the land was still occupied by the Canaanites. So now, as God repeated the promise to him that he would possess the land of Canaan, Abram was wondering how that would all happen (v.8).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰到迦南地之前很多年，神就已经应许他说“我要把这地赐给你的后裔”（创12:7）。现在亚伯兰已经住在迦南地很多年，那地却仍然被迦南人所占据。所以这次，当神再次应许他，他会拥有迦南地，亚伯兰想知道那怎么才能发生（第8节）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Abram asked, “How can I know that I will gain possession of it?” God responded by directing Abram to take part in a solemn ritual, the making or cutting of a covenant. Verse 18 says, “On that day the LORD made a covenant with Abram.” This was a solemn ritual that Abram would understand. It was something that was part of the culture of those times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰问：“我怎能知道必得这地为业呢？”神对亚伯兰的回应就是让他举行一个严肃的仪式，即立（切）约。第18节说，“当那日，耶和华与亚伯兰立约。” 亚伯兰明白这是个严肃的仪式，因为那时当时的文化。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE MAKING (CUTTING) OF THE COVENANT 立（切）约&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/course-file/106/106-4-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CUTTING COVENANT（切）约&#34; title=&#34;CUTTING COVENANT（切）约&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hebrew word for “make” a covenant in Genesis 15:18 is actually the word that means “cut”. The covenant was “cut” when animals were sliced in half. Though this may sound like a very strange thing to us, in that culture it was an accepted way for two groups to enter into a solemn and binding agreement. In this solemn ceremony, God entered into a covenant with Abraham and by doing so bound himself to keep his promises. This covenant, which we call the “Abrahamic Covenant” is God’s assurance that he will not break his promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创15:18当中“立”约的希伯来文词语是“切”。动物被劈成两半，约就“切”了。虽然在我们看来这很奇怪，但是在那种文化下，双方都认同以这种方式来达成严肃有效力的合约。在这个严肃的仪式当中，神和亚伯拉罕立约，并且以此来约束自己守约。这个约我们称之为“亚伯拉罕之约”，即神确保他不会破坏他的应许。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God gave the instructions for the covenant. Abram was to slaughter 3 animals and divide their bodies in half. Two birds were also to be sacrificed as part of the covenant ceremony. The animals and birds were to be arranged so that the covenant participants could pass between them. This would indicate that the covenant into which they were entering would be a matter of life and death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神说明了如何立约。亚伯兰要取三种动物，并且把它们劈成两半。也要献上两只鸟为祭，作为立约仪式的一部分。动物和鸟都要放好，这样立约双方可以从中走过。这表明他们所立的约事关生死。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then there was a delay before the covenant was completed. The delay was so long that Abram had to drive away some birds of prey that were trying to consume part of the sacrificial animals. The delay lasted even until the end of the day when the exhausted Abram fell into a deep and troubling sleep. It seems as if God was using this pause to teach Abram that before the covenant promises would be fulfilled, there would be a “pause” when his family would not be living in the promised land of Canaan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但是在约得以成立之前发生了迟延。迟延了很久，亚伯兰不得不把一些觊觎祭品的鸟赶走。甚至推迟到了日落的时候，亚伯兰过于疲惫而沉沉睡去。似乎神使用这个迟延来教导亚伯兰一个功课，就是约的应许成就之前会有“迟延”，那段时间他的后裔不会住在迦南地。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Genesis 15:13-14 what future historical “pause” was God revealing to Abram concerning his family’s occupation of the land of Canaan?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创15:13-14当中，神启示亚伯兰导致他的后裔取得迦南地“迟延”的历史事件是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God wanted Abram and all of us to know that this “pause” in the occupation of Canaan was not a surprise to the Lord and would not invalidate the covenant that was being made. God would indeed give this land to Abram’s family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神希望亚伯兰和我们都明白，取得迦南地“迟延”对耶和华来说不是什么吃惊的事情，也不会令他的约失效。神肯定会把那地赐给亚伯兰的后裔。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What comforting announcement did God make to Abram regarding his personal future in the land of Canaan (verse 15)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;关于亚伯兰在迦南地未来的情形（第15节），神给了他什么欣慰的宣告？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 16 the Lord told Abram that the delay in possessing the land of Canaan would take place because “the sin of the Amorites has not yet reached its full measure” (Genesis 15:16). Who are the Amorites? What does it mean that their sin has “not yet reached its full measure”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第16节当中，耶和华告诉亚伯兰他们取得迦南地有些迟延，是因为“亚摩利人的罪孽还没有满盈”（创15:16）。亚摩利人是谁？他们的罪孽“还没有满盈”是什么意思？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, after a long pause and the darkness of night had fallen, God completed the covenant ritual with Abram. A smoking firepot with a blazing torch appeared and passed between the animal parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最终，经过了长时间的迟延，黑夜降临，神完成了和亚伯兰的约。冒烟和炉和烧着的火把从那些肉块当中经过。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the significance of this firepot and blazing torch that passed between the severed animal parts? (v. 17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有冒烟的炉并烧着的火把从那些肉块中经过，这有什么重要性？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We notice that Abram did not speak or promise anything or walk between the animal parts, but only the Lord. Why? Because this covenant promise was the work of the Lord. Only the Lord could make the promise and only the Lord could keep it. God was binding himself to keep this promise so that Abram would be sure that this promise would be kept. Yes, there would be a pause when the Hebrews lived in Egypt, but the land would be given to Abram and his descendants because this was the place that the Lord had chosen to bring the Messiah into the world. When Christ would come, he would have a place – this land of Canaan. God binds himself to do what he had promised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们注意到，亚伯兰没有说什么，没有应许什么，也没有从肉块中经过，只有耶和华那么做了。为什么呢？因为这个约的应许是耶和华的工作。只有耶和华才能立约，只有耶和华才能守约。神约束自己守约，这样亚伯兰才能确定神会守约。是的，会有迟延，希伯来人会住在埃及，但是这地会赐给亚伯兰和他的后裔，因为耶和华已经拣选了那地是弥赛亚来到世界出生的地方。当基督来临的时候，他会有一个地方——迦南地。神约束自己来成就他的应许。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God’s promises to Abram included both a nation and a land. In this chapter God worked to strengthen Abram’s faith in the promise of a land. In the next chapter, God will work to strengthen Abram’s faith in the promise of a nation, a promise that seemed more and more impossible as the years passed by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神对亚伯兰的应许包括一个国和一块地。本章当中，神增强了亚伯兰对应许之地的信心。下一章中，神会增强亚伯兰对应许之国的信心，虽然随着年岁渐长，这个应许变得越来越不可能。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第五课 夏甲和以实玛利——创16章</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/106/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/106/5/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第六课 割礼之约——创第17章</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/106/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/106/6/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第七课 亚伯拉罕的访客—创世纪18章</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/106/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/106/7/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第八课 所多玛和蛾摩拉——创世记第19章</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/106/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/106/8/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-介绍&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION 介绍&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In chapter 18 Abraham had three visitors. One of them was the Lord himself. The other two were angels, as we discover in chapter 19:1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在第18章中，亚伯拉罕有三个访客。其中一个是耶和华本人，另外两个是天使，正如我们在第19：1章中发现的那样。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the angels left Abraham’s tent, they traveled to the city of Sodom. In Genesis 13:13 we were told: “Now the men of Sodom were wicked and were sinning greatly against the LORD.” In this chapter we find out how deeply their morals had sunk, and the depths of their perversions are revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;天使离开亚伯拉罕的帐篷后，去了所多玛城。在创世纪13：13中说：“所多玛人在耶和华面前罪大恶极。”在这一章中，我们发现他们的道德沦陷得有多深，而且这种沦陷的深度被揭示了出来。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-genesis-19114-读创世记19114&#34;&gt;READ GENESIS 19:1–14 读创世记19:1–14&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apostle who wrote the book of Hebrews may have been referring to this account when he wrote: “Do not forget to entertain strangers, for by so doing some people have entertained angels without knowing it.” (Hebrews 13:1–2). Lot showed loving hospitality to the two strangers he met at the city gate. However, Lot also showed how life in Sodom had affected his judgment and character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;写希伯来书的使徒在提到下面这句话时说的可能就是这种情况：“不可忘记用爱心接待客旅；因为曾有接待客旅的，不知不觉就接待了天使。”（希伯来书第13章1-2节）。罗得热情接待了他在城门口遇到的两个陌生人。然而，所多玛城的生活方式对他的判断力和性格的影响也同样表现了出来。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did Lot insist strongly that the two men not spend the night in the city square? See 1 Peter 2:7-8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗得为什么强烈坚持说这两个人不能在城市广场上过夜？见彼前2：7-8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The depravity and lust of the men of Sodom is shocking. But Lot’s suggestion in verse 8 is also shocking. How could he say such a thing? Why would he make such a terrible offer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;所多玛人的堕落和贪欲令人震惊，但罗得在第8节中的建议也令人震惊。他怎么能  说出这样的话，提出如此糟糕的提议呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LORD had told Abraham, “The outcry against Sodom and Gomorrah is so great and their sin so grievous that I will go down and see if what they have done is as bad as the outcry that has reached me. If not, I will know.” (Genesis 18:20–21) Now, when we see what happened at Lot’s door, we also see for ourselves the evidence of the sinful condition of Sodom and Gomorrah. The time for God’s judgment against these people has come. There are not even ten righteous people left in Sodom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;耶和华曾经告诉亚伯拉罕说：“所多玛和蛾摩拉的罪恶甚重，声闻于我。我现在要下去，查看他们所行的，果然尽像那达到我耳中的声音一样吗？若是不然，我也必知道。”（创世纪18：20-21）现在，当我们看到在罗得的门口发生的事情时，我们也就亲自看到了所多玛和蛾摩拉罪恶深重的证据。上帝审判这些人的时候已经来了。所多玛甚至连十个义人都没有了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two men of Sodom who were engaged to marry Lot’s daughters were given a chance to leave the city and escape the Lord’s judgment. But they treated the warning of impending judgment as a joke. How many times do the people in our own generation also treat the Lord’s warnings and call to leave a life of sin as a joke?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;与罗得的两个女儿订了婚的两个所多玛男子被赐予了离开这座城的机会，使他们可以逃避主的审判，但他们却把即将到来的审判警告看成了笑柄。我们这个时代的人也有多少次把主的警告和召唤，把离开有罪的生活看成了玩笑？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Lord’s judgment is not a joke. When that day of judgment comes for the world, there will be no more warnings. So now is the time for repentance. Now is the time to believe what the Lord says, turn from sin, and flee to the saving grace of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但主的审判不是玩笑。当世界接受审判的日子到来时，将不会再有警告。所以现在就是悔改的时候，现在就是相信耶和华所说的话、脱离罪、逃进耶稣救赎恩典中的时候！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-genesis-1915-23-读创世记1915-23&#34;&gt;READ GENESIS 19:15-23 读创世记19：15-23&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lot’s future sons-in-law regarded the warning of judgment as a joke. Now we see that even Lot himself was hesitant to leave the city. Didn’t he understand what was going to happen? The angels had told him plainly: “We are going to destroy this place. The outcry to the LORD against its people is so great that he has sent us to destroy it.” But Lot still hesitated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗得未来的女婿们认为，那些审判的警告是一个笑话。现在我们看到，就连罗得自己也在犹豫是否要离开这座城市。难道他不明白会发生什么事吗？天使们已经清楚地告诉了他：“我们要毁灭这地方；因为城内罪恶的声音在耶和华面前甚大，耶和华差我们来，要毁灭这地方。”（创19:13）但罗得迟延不走（第16节）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did Lot hesitate to leave (verse 16) when he understood that Sodom would be destroyed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗得明白所多玛要被摧毁了，但为什么还迟延不走？（第16节）？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of his hesitation to leave, the Lord showed great kindness to him and his family. The Lord would not punish the righteous with the unrighteous. The angels took the hands of Lot, his wife, and his two daughters, and led them out of the city. In spite of their hesitancy to leave, “the Lord was merciful to them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;尽管罗得迟延不走，但神对他和他的家人仍然非常仁慈。耶和华不会因为不义的人而惩罚义人。天使们抓住罗得、他妻子和两个女儿的手，把他们从城里拉了出来。尽管他们犹豫着不想离开，但“耶和华怜恤他们。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How has the Lord been merciful to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;耶和华神是怎样怜恤你的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why was Lot afraid to flee to the mountains?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗得为什么害怕逃到山上去？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small town to which Lot and his family fled was called Zoar, which literally means “tiny town.” The Lord spared that tiny town from the coming destruction only because Lot and his family went there. The location of Zoar is uncertain, but many feel it was location south of the Dead Sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗得和他的家人逃往的小镇名叫琐珥（Zoar），字面意思是“小的”。主免去对这个小镇的毁灭，只因为罗得和他的家人逃到了那里。琐珥的位置尚不确定，但许多人认为它位于死海以南。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-genesis-1924-29-读创世记1924-29&#34;&gt;READ GENESIS 19:24-29 读创世记19：24-29&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus once spoke about the day that God destroyed Sodom and Gomorrah. In Luke 17:28-30 Jesus said: “… in the days of Lot. People were eating and drinking, buying and selling, planting and building. But the day Lot left Sodom, fire and sulfur rained down from heaven and destroyed them all. It will be just like this on the day the Son of Man is revealed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;耶稣曾提到过上帝毁灭所多玛和蛾摩拉的那个日子。在路加福音 17:28-30中，耶 稣说：“…又好像罗得的日子；人又吃又喝，又买又卖，又耕种又盖造。到罗得出 所多玛的那日，就有火与硫磺从天上降下来，把他们全都灭了。人子显现的日子也 要这样。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What day will be like the day that Sodom and Gomorrah were destroyed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;将来的什么日子会像所多玛和蛾摩拉被毁灭的日子一样？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T
he apostle Jude wrote: “Sodom and Gomorrah and the surrounding towns gave themselves up to sexual immorality and perversion. They serve as an example of those who suffer the punishment of eternal fire.” (Jude 6–7) As we read this account, we must understand that it has been written down for us so that we can be prepared ahead of time for the final day of judgment when the city in which we live, along with the entire world in which we live, will be destroyed. Let us live in daily repentance and forsake the sin of this world, putting our trust in Christ alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;使徒犹大曾写道：“又如所多玛、蛾摩拉和周围城邑的人，也照他们一味地行淫，随从逆性的情欲，就受永火的刑罚，作为鉴戒。”（犹大6-7）当我们读到这些记述时，我们必须明白，这些事情为我们写下来，是要使我们为末日的审判提前做好准备。我们生活的城市，连同整个世界都将被毁灭。让我们在活着的每一天中悔改，离弃这个世界的罪恶，唯独依靠基督。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord had warned Lot’s family that they should not look back when Sodom and Gomorrah were destroyed. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主曾警告罗得的家人，在所多玛和蛾摩拉被毁灭的时候不要回头看。这是为什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of his teaching about judgment day, Jesus told us to, “Remember Lot’s wife!” (Luke 17:32) What should we remember about her? (see Luke 17:33)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;作为他对审判日的一部分教导，耶稣曾告诉我们：“你们要回想罗得的妻子。”（路加福音17:32）我们应该记住有关她的什么？（见路加福音17：33）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The apostle Peter wrote down the lesson God wants us to learn from this event. Here is the lesson: “If [the Lord] condemned the cities of Sodom and Gomorrah by burning them to ashes, and made them an example of what is going to happen to the ungodly; and if he rescued Lot, a righteous man, who was distressed by the filthy lives of lawless men (for that righteous man, living among them day after day, was tormented in his righteous soul by the lawless deeds he saw and heard)— if this is so, then the Lord knows how to rescue godly men from trials and to hold the unrighteous for the day of judgment, while continuing their punishment.” (2 Peter 2:6–9, NIV84)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;使徒彼得曾写下了上帝希望我们从这个事件中学到的教训。这个教训是：“又判定所多玛、蛾摩拉，将二城倾覆，焚烧成灰，作为后世不敬虔人的鉴戒；只搭救了那常为恶人淫行忧伤的义人罗得。因为那义人住在他们中间，看见听见他们不法的事，他的义心就天天伤痛。主知道搭救敬虔的人脱离试探，把不义的人留在刑罚之下，等候审判的日子。”（彼后2：6-9，NIV84）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different theories have been proposed for the “burning sulfur” that turned those cities of the plain to ash. Some have suggested that there was a volcano. However, there is no evidence of lava and other things associated with volcanoes. God did not need to use a naturally occurring event such as a volcano in order to overthrow those cities. It could have simply been a miraculous event of judgment. In any case, a careful search of the area today has not turned up any remains of those cities. They were simply wiped off the face of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;关于把平原上的城市烧为灰烬的“燃烧的硫磺”有不同的说法。一些人提议说有一座火山。然而，并没有熔岩和其它与火山有关的证据。上帝不需要用火山等自然发生的事件来倾覆那些城市，而可能只是一个奇迹般的审判事件。不管怎样，今天对该地区的仔细搜索还没有发现那些城市的任何遗迹。它们只是从地球上被抹去了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-genesis-193038-读创世记1930-38&#34;&gt;READ GENESIS 19:30–38 读创世记19：30-38&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seeing God’s fiery judgment fall on the other cities of the plain, Lot did not feel safe even in the tiny town of Zoar. So he finally left the plain of sin and shame and went where the Lord told him to go – the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;看到上帝的愤怒审判降临到平原的其它城市后，罗得即使待在琐珥那个小镇也没有感到安全。于是他最后离开了充满罪恶和羞耻的平原，去了主叫他去的地方——高山上。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dead Sea is in a deep depression in the earth and it surrounded by mountains or high cliffs which contain many caves. (The Dead Sea caves are in that area.) Those cool caves provide shelter from the heat of that dry and hot climate, and so Lot and his daughters took shelter among the caves. We can’t help but observe that Lot, who was once a very wealthy man with great possessions, has now been reduced to living in a cave with just his two daughters (and a good supply of wine). It reminds us of the runaway son in Jesus’ parable (Luke 15) who lost everything when he turned away from his father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;死海位于地球的深洼地，周围是山脉或高悬崖，里面有许多洞穴。(死海洞穴就在那个地区。）这些凉爽的洞穴提供了躲避了干燥炎热气候的庇护所，所以罗得和他的女儿们也躲进了洞穴里。我们不禁注意到，罗得，一个曾经非常富有，拥有大量财富的人，现在却只落得和他的两个女儿（还有大量的酒）住在一个洞穴里。这让我们想起了耶稣寓言（路加15）中的浪子，在他离开父亲之后失去了一切。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was wrong with the plan of Lot’s daughters to have children and preserve the family line?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗得的女儿们试图要生孩子并延续家庭血脉的计划有什么错误？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verses 37 and 38 make it clear why this disgraceful behavior is recorded in the Bible. Here we learn of the origin of two groups of people – the Moabites and the Ammonites – that will be an important part of the story of God’s people in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第37节和38节清楚地说明了这种可耻的行为为什么被记录在圣经中的原因。我们在这里了解到两族人的起源——摩押人和亚扪人，他们将是未来上帝子民故事的重要组成部分。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;moabites-摩押人&#34;&gt;MOABITES 摩押人&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Moabite people lived east of the Dead Sea, not far from where Lot and his family once lived. From the time that the Israelites came out of Egypt on their journey to Canaan, until the end of the Old Testament record, the Moabites were enemies of the children of Israel who worshiped idols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;摩押人住在死海以东，离罗得和他的家人曾经居住的地方不远。自从以色列人从埃及出来一路到迦南的时间起，到旧约所记事件的结束，摩押人都是以色列后代的敌人，一直在拜偶像。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the Moabites are significant for another reason. Ruth, the great-grandmother of King David, and an ancestor of Jesus, was a Moabite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;然而，摩押人之所以重要的另一个原因还有路得，她是大卫王的曾祖母，是耶稣的祖先，她是一个摩押人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A search of the Old Testament will reveal frequent references to the Moabites, and in this account of Lot’s daughters we have the record of their origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;搜索《旧约》你就会发现，摩押人经常被提到。从这里对罗得女儿的叙述中，我们就知道了他们的起源。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ammonites-亚扪人&#34;&gt;AMMONITES 亚扪人&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ammonites also lived east of the Dead Sea, north of the kingdom of Moab. They were also hostile toward the people of Israel from the time of Moses until the time of the great kings of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚扪人也住在死海以东，摩押王国的北部。他们从摩西时代到以色列的列王时代，也对以色列人怀有敌意。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the Moabites, the Ammonites worshiped idols in horrifying ways that involved human sacrifice. The Lord warned the people of Israel to remain separate from them: “No Ammonite or Moabite or any of his descendants may enter the assembly of the LORD, even down to the tenth generation.” (Deuteronomy 23:3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;与摩押人一样，亚扪人拜偶像的方式极其可怕，包括用活人献祭。耶和华曾警告过以色列人要与他们分开：“亚扪人或是摩押人不可入耶和华的会；他们的子孙，虽过十代，也永不可入耶和华的会。”（申命记23：3）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Solomon married both Moabite and Ammonite wives and out of a desire to please them, built worship places for their idols near Jerusalem. Those worship places stood until the God-fearing king Josiah finally destroyed them once and for all: “King Josiah also desecrated the high places that were east of Jerusalem on the south of the Hill of Corruption—the ones Solomon king of Israel had built for Ashtoreth the vile goddess of the Sidonians, for Chemosh the vile god of Moab, and for Molech the detestable god of the people of Ammon.” (2 Kings 23:13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;然而，所罗门娶了摩押人和亚扪人的妻子，而且为了取悦她们，在耶路撒冷附近为她们的偶像建造了崇拜场所。这些崇拜的地方一直存留到敬虔的王约西亚最后将它们彻底摧毁：“从前以色列王所罗门在耶路撒冷前、邪僻山右边为西顿人可憎的神亚斯他录、摩押人可憎的神基抹、亚扪人可憎的神米勒公所筑的邱坛，王都污秽了（毁坏或亵渎了）”（王下23：13）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the Biblical record will have much to say about the Moabites and Ammonites, this is the last time that we read of Lot. He now disappears from the Biblical record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;虽然圣经对摩押人和亚扪人还有很多记录，但这是我们最后一次读到罗得。从现在起，圣经对他的记录就停止了。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第九课 亚伯拉罕和亚米比勒-创20章</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/106/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/106/9/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-简介&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION 简介&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In chapter 20 the focus of the account returns to Abraham and Sarah. When the events described in this chapter took place, Sarah may have already been pregnant, because the Lord had told them in Mamre, “I will surely return to you about this time next year, and Sarah your wife will have a son” (Genesis 18:10).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第二十章的焦点重新回到亚伯拉罕和撒拉。本章描述的事件发生的时候，撒拉可能已经怀孕，因为耶和华在幔利已经告诉他们：“到明年这时候，我必要回到你这里。你的妻子撒拉必生一个儿子”（创18:10）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abraham and his family had lived near Mamre for about 20 years. But now something led them to relocate. Perhaps there was a famine. Perhaps there was simply a need to move to new pastureland. Whatever the case may have been, Abraham eventually came to live near Gerar in the land of the Philistines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯拉罕一家住在幔利附近已经大概二十年。但是现在，他们需要重新安家。或许是由于发生了饥荒，也或许仅仅是为了搬到新的牧地。不论原因为何，最终，亚伯拉罕寄居在非利士地的基拉耳附近。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/course-file/106/106-9-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;亚伯拉罕寄居在基拉耳&#34; title=&#34;亚伯拉罕寄居在基拉耳&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-genesis-20113-阅读创201-13&#34;&gt;READ GENESIS 20:1–13 阅读创20:1-13&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second time that something like this happened. The first time Abraham lied about his wife was in Genesis 12:10-20, when Abram and Sarai agreed to lie to the Egyptians. Now the same sin is repeated again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;类似事件这是第二次。第一次是在创12:10-20，亚伯拉罕在妻子的事情上说谎，那时亚伯兰和撒莱商量好对埃及人撒谎。现在则是再一次犯同样的罪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What motivated Abraham and Sarah to lie about their relationship (20:11)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;什么促使亚伯拉罕和撒莱在二人的关系上说谎（20:11）？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 3 God told Abimelech that he was as good as dead if would touch Sarah. Then he told Abimelech. “I have kept you from sinning against me. That is why I did not let you touch her. Now return the man’s wife, for he is a prophet, and he will pray for you and you will live. But if you do not return her, you may be sure that you and all yours will die.” (verses 6-7). 
在第三节中，神告诉亚米比勒，如果他胆敢亲近撒拉，就是个死人。然后他告诉亚米比勒：“我也拦阻了你，免得你得罪我，所以我不容你沾着她。现在你把这人的妻子归还他。因为他是先知，他要为你祷告，使你存活。你若不归还他，你当知道，你和你所有的人都必要死”（第6-7节）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why was God so intent on keeping Abimelech away from Sarah?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神为什么要让亚米比勒远离撒拉？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What four excuses did Abram offer for his plan to deceive Abimelech? (20:11-13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰找了哪四个理由为欺骗亚米比勒开脱？（创20:1）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 20:12 Abraham explains that Sarah was actually his half-sister, the daughter of his father, Terah, by another wife. Was marrying your half-sister allowed? Look at these verses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;亚伯拉罕在创20:12节当中解释说，撒拉是他的父亲他拉的女儿，是他同父异母的妹妹。和同父异母的姐妹结婚可以吗？请看下列经文：
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Ezekiel 22:11 - “In you one man violates his sister, his own father’s daughter.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 结22:11-“还有玷辱同父之姐妹的。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Leviticus 18:3, 9 - “You must not do as they do in Egypt, where you used to live, and you must not do as they do in the land of Canaan, where I am bringing you. Do not follow their practices. Do not have sexual relations with your sister, either your father’s daughter or your mother’s daughter, whether she was born in the same home or elsewhere.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 利18:3,9-“你们从前住的埃及地，那里人的行为，你们不可效法，我要领你们到的迦南地，那里人的行为也不可效法，也不可照他们的恶俗行。你的姐妹，不拘是异母同父的，是异父同母的，无论是生在家生在外的，都不可露她们的下体。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s remember that the commandments God gave to Moses were hundreds of years after the time of Abraham. As the human race began to re-populate the world after the flood, marrying those who were related to you was often necessary and not as awful as it came to be later. We do not know for sure whether Terah was married before or after he was married to Abraham’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们知道，亚伯拉罕之后几百年，神才给摩西的律法。洪水之后，人类重新繁衍在世上居住，那时，近亲结婚是有必要的，不像后来那么不好。我们不知道他拉娶撒拉的母亲是在娶亚伯拉罕的母亲之前还是之后。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-genesis-201418-阅读创2014-18&#34;&gt;READ GENESIS 20:14–18 阅读创20:14-18&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is clear that Abraham and Sarah were lying and deceiving Abimelech. So why did they prosper as a result of it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;显然，亚伯拉罕和撒拉在撒谎欺骗亚米比勒。那么，为什么他们却因此而发达呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s analyze the lie/half-truth that Abraham and Sarah engaged in. Was it a lie or not? Is telling a half-truth a lie? Is telling only part of the truth the same as lying? And if they were lying, why weren’t they punished for it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们来分析一下亚伯拉罕和撒拉所说的谎言/半真实的话。那是不是谎言？只说一半的真话是撒谎吗？只说部分真话是撒谎吗？如果他们在撒谎，为什么他们没有受到惩罚呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Scripture contains several incidents when people told lies and were not punished for it, but even commended for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经记载了几次事件，人们撒谎了，但是不仅没有因之受到惩罚，反而甚至得到赞许。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hebrew midwives Shiphrah and Puah lied about (Exodus 1:15-21) the birth of the baby boys and God blessed them for it. Rahab lied about the spies that she hid in her house (Joshua 2:4-7) and the New Testament even commends her for what she did. (“In the same way, was not even Rahab the prostitute considered righteous for what she did when she gave lodging to the spies and sent them off in a different direction?” &amp;ndash; James 2:25)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;希伯来收生婆施弗拉和普阿在男婴出生一事上撒谎（出1:15-21），神因此厚待她们。喇合在把探子藏在房子里的事情上撒谎（书2:4-7），新约甚至因此表扬她所做的事情。（ 妓女喇合接待使者，又放他们从别的路上出去，不也是一样因行为称义吗？-雅2:25）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Bible clearly condemns lying as a sin. “Do not lie. Do not deceive one another” (Leviticus 19:11). “The LORD detests lying lips, but he delights in men who are truthful” (Proverbs 12:22). “Do not lie to each other, since you have taken off your old self with its practices” (Colossians 3:9). And Ananias and Sapphira were struck dead when they told a lie (Acts 5).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但是圣经明确谴责撒谎是罪。“不可欺骗，也不可彼此说谎”（利19:11）。“说谎言的嘴，为耶和华所憎恶。行事诚实的，为他所喜悦”（箴12:22）。“不要彼此说谎，因你们已经脱去旧人和旧人的行为”（西3:9）。而亚拿尼亚和撒非喇因为撒谎被击杀（徒5）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does God approve of lying in some (exceptional) cases? Where do we draw the line? For example, if you were applying for a job and they asked you, “What religion are you?” If you answer “Christian” then you will not get the job. What should you do?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在一些（例外）情况下，神允许人撒谎吗？那么该如何界定这条线呢？例如如果你申请一个工作，他们问你，“你信什么教？”如果你回答“基督教”，你就得不到这份工作。那么你会怎么做？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did this event serve to advance the fulfillment of God’s promises to Abraham?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这一事件如何促使神向亚伯拉罕的应许成就？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again the events of this chapter reinforce God’s grace and faithfulness. In spite of Abraham’s failure to act in faith, God blessed him and turned what could have been a disaster into a way to bring even more blessings to Abraham and Sarah. It was as Abraham’s servant later declared: “Praise be to the LORD, the God of my master Abraham, who has not abandoned his kindness and faithfulness to my master.” (Genesis 24:27)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本章的事件再次强调了神的恩典和信实。尽管亚伯拉罕没能凭着信心行事，神还是祝福了他，并且把本来的灾难化为了对亚伯拉罕和撒拉更多的祝福。正如后来亚伯拉罕的仆人宣告的那样：“耶和华我主人亚伯拉罕的神是应当称颂的，因他不断地以慈爱诚实待我主人”（创24:27）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our next lesson we will see how God kept one of his most important and seemingly impossible promises to give Abraham and Sarah a son in their old age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;下一课，我们会看到神如何成就他最重要的、看起来似乎不可能成就的应许，就是在亚伯拉罕和撒拉年老的时候赐给他们一个儿子。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
