<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>恩典圣经学院 – 敬拜学</title>
    <link>/zh-cn/courses/304/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 敬拜学 on 恩典圣经学院</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/zh-cn/courses/304/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第一课 什么是敬拜？</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/304/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/304/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is worship?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;什么是敬拜？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worship is both a personal and group activity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬拜是个人和集体的属灵生活&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In worship we give ourselves to God, but more importantly God gives his Word and Sacraments to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在敬拜中我们将自己献给上帝，更重要的是籍着道和圣礼上帝将恩典赐给我们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The God of heaven is with us everywhere, but in a special way in group worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;天父上帝无处不与我们同在，集体敬拜是上帝与我们同在的一种特殊方式。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worship can be spontaneous, but planned structured worship has advantages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬拜可以是自发的，而有准备的敬拜有很多益处&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God is pleased with our humble worship, but worship is a gift to God and therefore should be the best we can offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝喜悦我们谦卑的敬拜，但是敬拜也是我们献给上帝的礼物， 因此我们应当献上最好的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worship is a universal experience but should reflect a Christian’s culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬拜是普世性的经验，但应该反映基督徒的文化&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we worship we fellowship with God and fellowship with other Christians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬拜是我们与上帝之间的交通, 也是基督徒之间的团契&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/course-file/304/Worship-Appendix-1-Liturgies.docx&#34;&gt;Appendix 1: Brief overview and explanation of the main liturgies in Christian Worship 简要概览基督教敬拜中的仪文&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/course-file/304/Worship-Appendix-2-Church-Year.docx&#34;&gt;Appendix 2: The Church Year 教会节期&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/course-file/304/Worship-Appendix-3-Colors.docx&#34;&gt;Appendix 3: Colors and their Meaning 色彩及其含义&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/course-file/304/Worship-Appendix-4-Symbols.docx&#34;&gt;Appendix 4: Symbols and Art 符号和艺术&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/course-file/304/Worship-Appendix-4-Symbols.docx&#34;&gt;Appendix 5: The Pastor: His Clothing and Actions 牧师：着装和动作&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-worship-什么是敬拜&#34;&gt;What is worship? 什么是敬拜？&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 22:5 &amp;ndash; Abram said to his servants, &amp;ldquo;Stay here with the donkey while I and the boy go over there. We will worship and then we will come back to you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创世纪22:5 – 亚伯拉罕对他的仆人说：“你们和驴在此等候，我与童子往那里去拜一拜，就回到你们这里来。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did Abram and Isaac do &amp;ldquo;over there&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亚伯兰和以撒“在那里”做了什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;9-aspects-of-worship-in-the-bible-圣经中关于敬拜的9个观点&#34;&gt;9 Aspects of worship in the Bible 圣经中关于敬拜的9个观点&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- Psalm 100:2 诗篇 100:2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- Matthew 4:9 马太福音 4:9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- Joshua 22:27 约书亚记 22:27&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- Luke 2:37 路加福音 2:37&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- 2 Kings 17:34 列王记下 17:34&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- Ezra 7:19 以斯拉记 7:19&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- Matthew 14:33 马太福音 14:33&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- Romans 12:1罗马书 12:1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- Luke 4:8 路加福音 4:8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: Worship is our humble and obedient approach to the true God in prayer, praise and offerings. Worship takes place through special acts and in our entire daily life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Bible, the word worship emphasizes one or more of the meanings just given. Already in the early church, however, the word worship came to be used in the narrower meaning of our church service &amp;ndash; our praise and offerings to God and the proclamation of God to us in Word and Sacrament. In this course we will use the term A worship service when we are thinking of this narrower meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬拜是我们在祷告、赞美和奉献中以谦卑和顺服的心靠近真神——上帝。我们可以通过特别的仪式来敬拜,也可以通过我们日常的生活来敬拜上帝。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;其实,在《圣经》里,“敬拜”一词强调的意思远不止上述的含义。在初期教会中,“敬拜”一词就专指教会礼拜仪式— —会众赞美上帝并向上帝献上奉献同时上帝藉着道和圣礼与我们相交。因此，在这一课中我们提到“敬拜”狭义的含义时，我们会用到“礼拜仪式”这个词。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discussion-questions-讨论题&#34;&gt;Discussion Questions 讨论题&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When many Christians think of &amp;ldquo;worship&amp;rdquo;, they first think of the Sunday church service. What parts of our Sunday service would fit the Biblical description of worship?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;许多基督徒一提到敬拜,首先想到的就是主日教会礼拜仪式。那么我们主日教会礼拜仪式中哪些内容是符合《圣经》对敬拜的描述的呢?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What parts of the Sunday service would not be &amp;ldquo;worship&amp;rdquo; in its narrowest sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主日教会礼拜仪式的哪些内容不符合“敬拜”狭义的含义呢 ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What aspects of worship mentioned above are usually not part of our worship services on Sunday?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上述提到的敬拜的含义中,有哪些通常不属于我们主日教会礼拜仪式的范围?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we pray, we &amp;ldquo;talk to&amp;rdquo; God &amp;ndash; thanking him, praising him, and often requesting things from him. What makes prayer important is the fact that God hears us and answers our prayers. Thus we might say that prayer is a 2-way conversation &amp;ndash; our talking to God, and his answering us. In what ways is worship also 2-way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们祷告时,我们与上帝“交通”——感恩、赞美并常常向上帝祈求。祷告对于我们来说非常重要的原因是上帝垂听和回应我们的祷告。因此我们说祷告是双向对话——我们和上帝交通,他回应我们。敬拜中，还有哪些方面也是双向的呢?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what ways is our Sunday church service 2-way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们主日教会礼拜仪式中，哪些方面是双向的交通?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read John 4: 19-24. How does Jesus&amp;rsquo; understanding of worship differ from that of the woman at the well?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;阅读约翰福音 4:19-24。耶稣理解的敬拜和井边妇人理解的敬拜有什么不同?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;homework-作业&#34;&gt;Homework 作业&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At your worship this weekend, take notes on the service – the order followed, mark what is technically ‘worship’ and what parts are not. If not, why do we have them in the service? Bring your notes to discuss next week in class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在你们这周末的礼拜仪式中，做礼拜仪式中以下内容的记录——仪式遵循的顺序、标出哪些部分是严格意义上的“敬拜”，哪些不是。如果不是，为什么我们在仪式中保留这些部分？下周上课时，请将你们所做的记录带来进行讨论。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第二课 敬拜是个人和集体的属灵生活</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/304/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/304/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;worship-is-both-a-personal-and-group-activity&#34;&gt;Worship is both a personal and group activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬拜是个人和集体的属灵生活&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Christians can worship God individually and personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒都可以单独地和私下地敬拜上帝。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Peter 2:5 – You also, like living stones, are being built into a spiritual house to be a holy priesthood, offering spiritual sacrifices acceptable to God through Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;彼得前书2:5 –你们来到主面前，也就像活石，被建造成为灵宫，作圣洁的祭司，藉着耶稣基督奉献神所悦纳的灵祭。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is often called the universal priesthood of all believers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;编者按：这常被称为信徒皆祭司。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians worship individually in their hearts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒可以独自在心里敬拜上帝&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Alone 独自地&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 26:36 – Then Jesus went with his disciples to a place called Gethsemane, and he said to them, “Sit here while I go over there and pray.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音26:36 – “耶稣同门徒来到一个地方，名叫客西马尼，就对他们说：‘你们坐在这里，等我到那边去祷告’。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our every breath should be prayer and praise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们要不住地祷告，常常地赞美。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 10:31 – So whether you eat or drink or whatever you do, do it all for the glory of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;哥林多前书10:31 “所以你们或吃或喝，无论做什么，都要为荣耀神而行。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we also are moved to worship God for special blessings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但是我们也会因为得到了特别的祝福而敬拜上帝。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 24:48 – And I bowed down and worshiped the LORD. I praised the LORD, the God of my master Abraham, who has led me to get the granddaughter of my master’s brother [as a husband] for his son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创24:48 －我们要为领受了特别的祝福而敬拜上帝。“随后我低头向耶和华下拜，称颂耶和华我主人亚伯拉罕的神，因为他引导我走合适的道路，使我得着我主人兄弟的孙女，给我主人的儿子为妻。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians also worship in groups (as the Church)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒聚集在一起（作为教会）敬拜上帝&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. As part of our fellowship – 成为团契的一员。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acts 2:46 – Every day they continued to meet together in the temple courts. They broke bread in their homes and ate together with glad and sincere hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;使徒行传2:46 — “他们天天同心合意恒切地在殿里，且在家中擘饼，存着欢喜、诚实的心用饭。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. To encourage each other – 当互相勉励，彼此扶持。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebrews 10:25 – Let us not give up meeting together, as some are in the habit of doing, but let us encourage one another– and all the more as you see the Day approaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;希伯来书10:25 －“你们不可停止聚会，好像那些停止惯了的人，倒要彼此劝勉。既知道那日子临近，就更当如此。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. As a witness and proclamation to others 向别人做见证。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 102:21-22 – So the name of the LORD will be declared in Zion and his praise in Jerusalem when the peoples and the kingdoms assemble to worship the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇102:21-22 －“使人在锡安传扬耶和华的名，在耶路撒冷传扬赞美他的话，就是在万民和列国聚会侍奉耶和华的时候。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christ is with us in group worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们聚会时基督临在我们中间。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Jesus says so– 耶稣这样说：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 18:20 – For where two or three come together in my name, there am I with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音18:20－ “因为无论在哪里，有两三个人奉我的名聚会，那里就有我在他们中间。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Group worship is a natural expression of faith -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;聚会是基督徒信心的自然体现。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 102:22 – ….when the peoples and the kingdoms assemble to worship the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇102:22－ “就是在万民和列国聚会侍奉耶和华的时候。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Christian family has a special opportunity to grow and worship together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒家庭具有信心共同成长和一同敬拜的特殊机会。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 12:25-27 When you enter the land that the LORD will give you as he promised, observe this ceremony. And when your children ask you, ‘What does this ceremony mean to you?’ then tell them, ‘It is the Passover sacrifice to the LORD….”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;出埃及记12:25-27： “日后，你们到了耶和华按着所应许赐给你们的那地，就要守这礼。你们的儿女问你们说：‘行这礼是什么意思？’你们就说：‘这是献给耶和华逾越节的祭。当以色列人在埃及的时候，他击杀埃及人，越过以色列人的房屋，救了我们各家。’于是百姓低头下拜。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Timothy 3:15 – And how from infancy you have known the holy Scriptures, which are able to make you wise for salvation through faith in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;提摩太后书3:15： “并且知道你是从小明白圣经，这圣经能使你因信基督耶稣有得救的智慧。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discussion-questions-问题讨论&#34;&gt;Discussion Questions 问题讨论&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some ways Christians might worship individually today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如今的基督徒有哪些独自敬拜的方式？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides our Sunday services, what ways might Christians jointly worship today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如今除了主日礼拜仪式，基督徒还有哪些集体敬拜的方式？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there ways that you worship individually while taking part in a Sunday service?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在参加主日礼拜仪式时，你有独自敬拜的部分吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Acts 2:46, what joint activities went along with joint worship?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据使徒行传2:46节，什么样的集体活动和集体敬拜有关？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we all can worship God individually, why do we need to meet together?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;既然我们都能独自敬拜上帝，为什么我们还需要聚会呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all Christians can worship God individually, why do we need pastors?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;既然所有基督徒都能独自敬拜上帝，为什么我们还需要牧师呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a saying, “The family that prays together, stays together.” Does the Bible agree with this? List several different ways that a family can pray together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有人说，“家庭成员之间一起祷告，能使家人团结在一起。”这和圣经中的教导一致吗？列举几个家庭成员可以一起祷告的不同方式?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Give some examples from the Bible of individual worship and prayer and public worship in the temple.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;从圣经里找出几个独自敬拜神和祷告以及会众在圣殿里敬拜的例子。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第三课 敬拜中的两个方向</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/304/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/304/3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In worship we give ourselves to God, but more importantly God gives his grace to us through the Word and Sacraments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在敬拜中我们将自己献给上帝，更重要的是籍着道和圣礼上帝将恩典赐给我们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the church service God gives us his greatest gifts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在礼拜仪式中，上帝将最好的赐给我们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. —————————————-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 1:7 以弗所书1:7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. —————————————-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 1:16 罗马书1:16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. —————————————-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 26:28 马太福音26:28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. —————————————-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Timothy 4:2 提摩太后书4:2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the worship service we have opportunities to give our best to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在礼拜仪式中我们有机会将最好的献给上帝。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Praise 赞美:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 9:1 – For the director of music. To the tune of “The Death of the Son.” A psalm of David. I will praise you, O LORD, with all my heart; I will tell of all your wonders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇9:1－（大卫的诗，交与伶长。调用慕拉便。）我要一心称谢耶和华；我要传扬你一切奇妙的作为！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Prayer 祷告&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 17:1 – Hear, O LORD, my righteous plea; listen to my cry. Give ear to my prayer– it does not rise from deceitful lips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇17:1－（大卫的祈祷。）耶和华啊，求你听闻公义，侧耳听我的呼吁！求你留心听我这不出于诡诈嘴唇的祈祷。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Offerings 奉献&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numbers 18:29 – You must present as the LORD’s portion the best and holiest part of everything given to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;民数记18:29－奉给你们的一切礼物，要从其中将至好的，就是分别为圣的，献给耶和华为举祭。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. Repentance 悔改&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 1:9 – If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书1:9－我们若认自己的罪，神是信实的，是公义的，必要赦免我们的罪，洗净我们一切的不义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we worship, we want to ensure that God’s gifts to us remain at the center of our worship services and that all worshipers have an opportunity to offer God their humble “thank you” in return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在礼拜仪式中，我们要确保将上帝的恩赐作为我们礼拜仪式的重点，同时所有敬拜上帝的人也有机会向上帝献上他们谦卑的“感恩”作为回报。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discussion-questions-问题讨论&#34;&gt;Discussion Questions 问题讨论&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examine the following order of Service, how does it acomplish this goal of worship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;看下面礼拜仪式的步骤，它怎么达到敬拜的目的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order of Worship for the Festival of Pentecost五旬节（圣灵降临节）礼拜礼文&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;赞美为开端： 欢呼欣逢喜乐日 #181 (Hail This Joyful Day)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众请起立 (please stand)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;呼召&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：恳求圣灵充满信众的心，&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众：在我们里面燃起你的爱火！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：愿主耶稣基督的恩典、天父上帝的慈爱、圣灵的团契，与你们同在！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众：也与你同在!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;呼召&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：弟兄姐妹！就如经上所记，“我们若说自己无罪，便是自欺，真理不在我们心里了。我们若认自己的罪，神是信实的，是公义的，必要赦免我们的罪，洗净我们一切的不义。”来吧！我们当奉主耶稣基督的名祈求天父上帝的赦免。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;认罪文&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众：全能慈悲的天父上帝啊！我向你承认我生来就是不义的。我的思想，言语，行为都亏欠了神又得罪了人。你吩咐我去做的我反倒没有做，而不该做的倒去做了。我没有尽心、尽意、尽性地爱上帝，和爱我的邻居。我本不配做天父上帝的儿女。但是，我愿意真心悔改我的罪过，相信耶稣基督为我的救主。我恳切地祈求：主啊！你是满有怜悯的神，求你洗尽我的罪孽，赦免我的过犯。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主啊！眷顾我们(Kyrie)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众齐唱：主啊！眷顾我们。基督啊！眷顾我们。主啊！眷顾我们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;赦罪文&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼: 满有慈爱、全知全能的天父上帝已经赦免了我们的罪。因耶稣基督替我们钉死在十字架上，他为我们的罪付了赎价。凡信他名的人，他就赐给他们权柄，做上帝的儿女。愿天父上帝坚固你们在真信心里，顺服他的旨意，荣耀他的圣名。奉圣父、圣子、圣灵的名！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众: 阿们！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本日共祷文&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼: 我们在平安中向主祷告。 上帝啊，你在这日曾经发出圣灵的光来教导你信众的心，求你今日也赐下同一的灵给我们，使我们凡事都有正确的认识，永久因他神圣的安慰而喜乐；奉靠你的儿子，我们的主，耶稣基督，他与你和圣灵联合，同是一位上帝，活着掌权，从今时直到永远。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众: 阿们！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众请坐 (please be seated)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第一段经文&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约珥书 2:28-32 (Joel 2:28-32)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇经文&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇51 (Psalm 51)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第二段经文&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;使徒行传 2:1-21 (Acts 2:1-21)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众请起立 (please stand)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;备福音词&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼:哈利路亚！哈利路亚！恳求圣灵充满信众的心，在他们里面燃起你的爱火。哈利路亚！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;福音经文&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰福音14:23-31 (John 14:23-31)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;福音启应&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众齐唱：哈利路亚！哈利路亚！哈利路亚！我们信圣经都是神的话，耶稣是救赎主，道成肉身的神。哈利路亚！哈利路亚！哈利路亚！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;使徒信经&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我信上帝,全能的父,创造天地的主。我信我主耶稣基督,上帝的独生子,因圣灵感孕,由童贞女马利亚所生;在本丢·比拉多手下受难,被钉于十字架,受死, 埋葬;降在阴间,第三天从死人中复活;後升天,坐在全能父上帝的右边;将来必从那里降临,审判活人死人。我信圣灵;我信圣而公之教会;我信圣徒相通;我信罪得赦免;我信身体复活;我信永生。阿们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众请坐 (please be seated)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;唱圣诗：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神光显赫主圣灵 #10 (Holy Spirit, Light Divine)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;讲道&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;祷告&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主祷文&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众：我们在天上的父，愿人都尊你的名为圣。愿你的国降临；愿你的旨意行在地上，如同行在天上。我们日用的饮食，今日赐给我们。免我们的债，如同我们免了人的债。不叫我们遇见试探；救我们脱离凶恶。因为国度、权柄、荣耀全是你的，直到永远。阿门。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Lord’s Supper we receive the true body and blood of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ along with the bread and wine. In this communion Jesus gives us forgiveness that we can touch and taste. It’s the same forgiveness that I pronounced to you at the beginning of the service. You are forgiven! The Lord’s Supper makes a second statement. It says, “We are one in all that we confess!” We don’t know if this type of bond exists with our guests, so we ask that you observe the Lord’s Supper today and meet personally with our pastor or deacons if you desire to receive the Sacrament in the future. Thank you. (See 1 Corinthians 10:17; and 11:27-29)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;下面进行圣餐礼&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在圣餐礼中，我们不仅领受了面包和红酒，同时还领受了我们救主耶稣基督的真身体和宝血。在这种联合里，耶稣给我们可以摸到和尝到的赦免，就如同我在礼拜开始的时候向你们宣布的赦免一样。你们的罪得赦免了！我们一起领受圣餐礼也说明我们在信心里合一。我们不能确定我们和来宾有这种合一的联系，因此我们邀请你们今天先观摩圣餐礼，礼拜之后你们也可以和牧师或执事单独的交流是否愿意在以后接受这种圣礼，谢谢。（参看：哥林多前书 10:17及11:27-29）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;唱圣诗：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;行近圣坛前 #263 (Draw Near and Take the Body of the Lord)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：主耶稣与你们同在！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众：也与你同在！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：你们的心要仰望主。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众：我要一心仰望主。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：我们要感谢主，我们的上帝！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众：上帝是圣洁的，他有永远的慈爱！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：主啊！圣洁的天父、全能和永在的上帝。你是实实在在的。我们应该常常地感谢你！奉主耶稣基督的名。他实现了他的承诺，赐下圣灵使教会有能力传福音给万民。阿们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;设立圣餐文&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：我们的主耶稣基督，在他被卖的那一夜，拿起饼来，祝谢了，就掰开，递给他的门徒说：“你们拿着吃；这是我的身体，为你们舍的。你们应当如此行，为的是记念我。” 饭后，也照样拿起杯来，祝谢了，递给他们说：“你们都拿着喝；这杯是用我的血所立的新约，就是为你们流出来的，使罪得赦。你们每逢喝的时候，要如此行，为的是纪念我。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：愿从主耶稣而来的平安常与你们同在！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众：阿们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;分发圣餐&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼分饼：拿着吃，这是你救主耶稣基督的身体，为你的罪而舍的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼分杯：拿着喝，这是你救主耶稣基督的宝血，为赦免你的罪而流的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：愿主耶稣圣体宝血坚固保守你们在真信心里，直到永生。平安地去吧！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;称谢&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：我们要称谢主，因他本为善！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众：他的慈爱永远长存。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：我们感谢你，全能的上帝，藉着圣餐使我们重新得力，並坚固我们在真信心里，赐给我们信心和爱心。求主继续保守看顾我们，並使我们彼此更加真诚相爱。奉靠耶稣基督，你的儿子，我们的主，他与你和圣灵是一位上帝，活着掌权，从今时直到永远。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;会众：阿们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;祝福&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;主礼：愿上帝保护你们，赐恩给你们！愿上帝的脸光照你们！愿上帝向你们仰脸，赐给你们平安！ 会众齐唱：阿们，阿们，阿们！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;唱圣诗：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;真神羔羊 #26 (Lamb of God)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicate whether the listed parts of the Sunday worship service are predominantly God giving to us, we giving to God, or are both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;简要说明以下所列的主日礼拜仪式的内容中，哪些是上帝赐给我们的、哪些是我们献给上帝的或者是双向的：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;下面进行圣餐孔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在圣餐孔中，我们不仅领受ア面包和酒。同还领受我们救主耶稣基督的身体和宝血。在这种联合里，耶稣给我们可似摸到和尝到的&lt;strong&gt;赦免&lt;/strong&gt;。就如同我在礼拜开始的时候向你们宣布的赦免一样。你们的罪得赦免了！我们一起领受圣餐礼也说明我们在信心里合一。我们不能确定我们和来访客这种合一的联系，因此我们邀请你们今天先观看圣餐孔，礼拜之后你们可以和牧师或执事单独的交流，是否愿意在以后接受这样的圣礼，谢谢。(参看：哥林多前书10:17及11:27-29)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some churches the worship service consists mostly of praise songs and a sermon which tells Christians how they should live. Where is the emphasis in those services – on what God gives us or what we give God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有些教会的礼拜仪式主要由赞美诗和一篇关于教导基督徒怎样过合乎主意的生活的讲道组成。这样的礼拜重点是什么——是上帝所赐给我们的还是我们所献给上帝呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some Pentecostal services, much time is given to speaking in tongues (non-human languages). Where do you think the emphasis would be in such services?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有些灵恩教会在礼拜仪式中，用很多时间来说方言（不是人通常用的语言）。你认为这样的礼拜仪式的重点是什么？为什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been said, “Christians need to go to church to learn about God.” Is that a good description of why we go to church? Explain your answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有人说：“基督徒要去教会学习有关上帝的事”。这是否完整地解释了我们为什么去教会？谈谈你的看法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;homework-作业&#34;&gt;HOMEWORK 作业&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AT WORSHIP THIS WEEK, EXAMINE THE ORDER OF SERVICE YOUR CHURCH USES. HOW DOES IT ACCOMPLISH THE GOALS FOR WORSHIP WE STUDIED TODAY? WRITE YOUR ANSWER BELOW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在本周的敬拜中，看看你们教会礼拜仪式的步骤。它是怎样达到我们今天所学的敬拜的目的的？把你的答案写在下面。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第四课 上帝在集体敬拜中与我们同在</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/304/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/304/4/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The God of heaven is with us everywhere, but in a special way in group worship.
天父上帝无处不与我们同在，集体敬拜是上帝与我们同在的一种特殊方式。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God is the Lord of Heaven and above all creation and thus deserves our worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝是天地万物的主宰，他在万有之上，是配得我们敬拜的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Ephesians 1:18-21    以弗所书1:18-21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Malachi 1:6    玛拉基书1:6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet God is also present with us personally in worship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在敬拜中上帝也与我们每个人同在。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. 2 Corinthians 6:16     哥林多后书6:16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Matthew 18:20     马太福音18:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group worship can also take place anyplace where people can meet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;集体敬拜的地点可以不受限制。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. 2 Samuel 15:32 – When David arrived at the summit, where people used to worship God, Hushai the Arkite was there to meet him, his robe torn and dust on his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;大卫到了山顶敬拜神的地方，见亚基人户筛衣服撕裂头蒙灰尘来迎接他。”（撒母耳记下15:32）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. “Exodus 29:42 – “For the generations to come this burnt offering is to be made regularly at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting before the LORD. There I will meet you and speak to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这要在耶和华面前、会幕门口，作你们世世代代常献的燔祭。我要在那里与你们相会，和你们说话。”（出埃及记29:42）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: God does not give a similar command in the New Testament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;编者按：在新约里上帝没有给类似的命令。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Romans 16:3,5 – Greet Priscilla and Aquila…. Greet also the church that meets at their house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“问百基拉和亚居拉安。……又问在他们家中的教会安。”（罗马书16:3,5）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;——————–we worship is not as important as ———————-we worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;————————–敬拜要比————————–敬拜更重要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Some worship methods and places are associated with false gods and thus are not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;acceptable for worship of the true God&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有些敬拜方式和地点会使人联想到假神，因此这些方式和地点是不适合敬拜真神上帝的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deuteronomy 12:2-5    申命记12:2-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Unplanned worship can lead to disorder and disagreements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;没有准备的礼拜仪式容易导致混乱和纷争。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 11:18    哥林多前书11:18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Planned worship can ensure a useful experience for all worshipers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;准备充分的礼拜仪式能确保所有敬拜的上帝的人获得有益的经历。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 14:26    哥林多前书14:26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. We should worship the God of the Universe with proper humility, dignity and honor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们应该以谦卑、敬虔、尊敬的心敬拜这位宇宙万物的上帝。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Chronicles 16:29    历代志上16:29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebrews 12:28    希伯来书12:28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our worship imitates heavenly worship&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们的敬拜也是照着天上的样式&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nehemiah 9:6    尼希米记9:6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revelation. 5:8-14     启示录5:8-14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important aspect of worship is that God shares with us his Word and Sacrament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬拜中最重要的是上帝和我们分享他的道和圣礼。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Psalm 119:105     诗篇119:105&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. 1 Corinthians 11:26     哥林多前书11:26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discussion-questions--讨论问题&#34;&gt;Discussion Questions  讨论问题&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The God of all creation comes down from heaven to be with us in our Sunday services. What effect should that have on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;天地万物的上帝从天上临到我们中间，在主日礼拜仪式中时与我们同在。这会对以下行为产生什么影响？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. the way we take care of our church building?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们维护教堂建筑的方式？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. our preparation for each service?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们为每次礼拜仪式所做的准备？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. our conduct during church services?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们在礼拜仪式中的表现？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. our attendance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们的参与？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Rev. 5:8-14. Here John receives a glimpse of a worship service around God’s throne in heaven. Compare it with our Sunday services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;读启示录5:8-14。在这一部分约翰看见了天堂里围绕上帝宝座敬拜景象的一瞥。与我们的主日礼拜仪式相比：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. How is the music the same or different?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;天上的音乐有何相似与不同之处？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. How is leadership and participation similar or different?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;天上带领礼拜仪式的人和参与的人有何相似与不同？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. How is “body language” similar or different?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在天上他们用的肢体语言有何相似和不同之处？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what ways are our Sunday services a “taste of heaven”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在哪些方面我们的主日礼拜仪式具有“天堂的味道”？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we knew a famous person would be attending our church some Sunday, how might our preparations and actions be different? How does this relate to God’s presence in church each Sunday?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果我们得知某个主日有位著名人士要来参加我们教会的礼拜，我们的准备和表现会有什么不同？这与上帝在每一个礼拜时与我们同在有什么关联？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people think everyone should dress up in their “Sunday best” for church since they are going to God’s house. Others think it is best to dress more normal so that everyone will feel comfortable and so that nobody will stay home because they don’t have good enough clothes. With which attitude do you agree?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有些人认为每个人在主日礼拜时都应该穿着 “盛装”，因为他们是去上帝的家。还有些人认为最好是穿着普通，这样每个人都会觉得舒服而且也不会有人因为没有足够好的衣服穿而呆在家里。你是认同哪种看法呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people stress that we should use the CUV version of the Chinese Bible when we worship, others say that we should use a new, easier to understand version. Which do you think is fitting to use? Talk about your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有些人强调我们敬拜时应该用中文和合本《圣经》，还有些人说应该用较新的，更易懂的译本。你认为用哪个版本更合适？谈谈你的看法？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you answer a person who says he doesn’t need to go to church to worship God, because he goes to the forest or mountains and feels closer to God there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你怎么看，有人说他不需要去教堂敬拜上帝，因为他觉得到森林里或者到山上去与上帝更亲近？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Exodus 29:42 (3b above) what is the importance of the word regularly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在出埃及记29:42(本课3b中提到的)中，“常”这个词有什么重要意义？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the advantages or disadvantages of having a special church building as the place where one normally meets others for worship?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有一座特别的教堂作为经常礼拜聚会的地点的优点和缺点是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Christians meet together for worship, is their main job listening to the pastor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒聚在一起敬拜上帝的主要目的是听牧师讲道吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does going to church differ from going to the movies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;去教堂和去电影院有什么不同？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第五课 敬拜可以是自发的，而有准备的敬拜有很多益处</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/304/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/304/5/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Worship can be spontaneous, but planned structured worship has advantages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬拜可以是自发的，而有准备的敬拜有很多益处&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything a Christian does is worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒要将所做的一切当成是敬拜。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 12:1 罗马书12:1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But certain aspects of worship can be taught&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但是需要正确地教导敬拜的某些要素。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Kings 17:28 &amp;ndash; So one of the priests who had been exiled from Samaria came to live in Bethel and taught them how to worship the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;列王记下17:28 &amp;ndash; “于是有一个从撒玛利亚掳去的祭司回来，住在伯特利，指教他们怎样敬畏耶和华。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 29:13 &amp;ndash; The Lord says: &amp;ldquo;These people come near to me with their mouth and honor me with their lips, but their hearts are far from me. Their worship of me is made up only of rules taught by men.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以赛亚书29:13 &amp;ndash; “主说：因为这百姓亲近我，用嘴唇尊敬我，心却远离我。他们敬畏我，不过是领受人的吩咐。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worship can be planned to include a variety of body language&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们预备的敬拜可以包括丰富的肢体语言。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 33:10 &amp;ndash; Whenever the people saw the pillar of cloud standing at the entrance to the tent, they all stood and worshiped, each at the entrance to his tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;出埃及记33:10 &amp;ndash; 众百姓看见云柱立在会幕门前，就都起来，各人在自己帐棚的门口下拜。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 24:48 &amp;ndash; And I bowed down and worshiped the LORD. I praised the LORD, the God of my master Abraham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创世记24:48 “随后我低头向耶和华下拜，称颂耶和华我主人亚伯拉罕的神；因为他引导我走合式的道路，使我得着我主人兄弟的孙女，给我主人的儿子为妻”。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: To differentiate themselves from worshipers of pagan statues, early Christians do not seem to have &amp;ldquo;bowed down&amp;rdquo; in worship after Jesus&amp;rsquo; ascension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;编者按：为区别与异教徒的不同，早期信徒在耶稣升天后的敬拜中不再行跪拜礼。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Chronicles 29:29 &amp;ndash; When the offerings were finished, the king and everyone present with him knelt down and worshiped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;历代志下29:29 &amp;ndash; 献完了祭，王和一切跟随的人都俯伏敬拜。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Chronicles 29:30 &amp;ndash; King Hezekiah and his officials ordered the Levites to praise the LORD with the words of David and of Asaph the seer. So they sang praises with gladness and bowed their heads and worshiped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;历代志下29:30 &amp;ndash; 希西家王与众首领又吩咐利未人用大卫和先见亚萨的诗词颂赞耶和华。他们就欢欢喜喜地颂赞耶和华，低头敬拜。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worship can be planned for different times and occasions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬拜可以在不同时间为不同的事情而预备。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. 1 Samuel 1:19 &amp;ndash; Early the next morning they arose and worshiped before the LORD and then went back to their home at Ramah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;撒母耳记上1:19 “次日清早，他们起来，在耶和华面前敬拜，就回拉玛。到了家里，以利加拿和妻哈拿同房，耶和华顾念哈拿。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Luke 1:10 &amp;ndash; And when the time for the burning of incense came, all the assembled worshipers were praying outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;路加福音1:10 &amp;ndash; “烧香的时候，众百姓在外面祷告。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worship can be planned as a complete experience emphasizing Christ&amp;rsquo;s message to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;敬拜还可以预备成强调对基督给我们信息的完整经历。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God’s invitation for us to worship him&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝邀请我们敬拜他&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Confession of sins to God&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们向上帝的认罪；&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s announcement of forgiveness to us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;聆听上帝宣告赦免了我们的罪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s message to us in the Scriptures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝藉着《圣经》赐给我们真道；&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our response in prayer and song&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们用祷告和诗歌作回应。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s encouragement to us in the sermon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝通过讲道来鼓励我们；&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our confession of faith in God in the creeds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们以信经作为在上帝里的认信。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our gifts to God in the offering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们以奉献作为给上帝的礼物；&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s gifts to us in the Sacraments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝通过圣礼给我们恩赐&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three important benefits of using a liturgy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;礼文礼拜的三个主要好处：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. The use of a liturgy is a good way of ensuring a complete worship experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;采用礼文的好处之一是确保完整的敬拜经历。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Except for the sermon, the liturgy can be conducted even without a highly trained leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;除了讲道以外，礼文可以用来作为那些没有受过专门训练的带领礼拜的人的引导。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Children and adults who can&amp;rsquo;t read or can&amp;rsquo;t read well can memorize parts of the liturgy and still take part in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;采用礼文可以方便那些不会阅读或阅读能力不强的小孩和成人记住礼拜程序并参与进来。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discussion-questions问题讨论&#34;&gt;Discussion Questions问题讨论&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give examples of when you or Christians you know were moved to spontaneous worship of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;举例说说你或你所认识的基督徒在什么时候会自发地敬拜上帝？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give examples of special occasions (besides Sundays) when planned group worship might be appropriate in your church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;举几个特殊情况时的例子（主日除外），什么时候适合在你们的教会安排集体敬拜。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name and explain any different worship postures used in your church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;说出你们教会中不同的敬拜肢体语言的名称并进行解释。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there some postures that are inappropriate in your culture?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有没有一些敬拜的肢体语言不符合你们的文化？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do worship styles and postures vary between different Christian denominations? Are there important reasons why ours differs from others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;不同教派之间的敬拜方式和肢体语言有什么差异？是什么重要的原因使我们和别人有这些差异？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your church, how are children or new members taught how to worship？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在你们的教会中，是怎样教导小孩和新会友参与礼拜的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we avoid the improper worship which God criticizes in Isaiah 29:13?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们怎样才能避免以赛亚书29：13中上帝所批判的那种不合宜的敬拜呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read again point 5, then answer these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;再阅读一下第五点，然后回答下列问题：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. If we did not use a liturgy, which important parts of the worship experience might we forget? (You might think of different kinds of services in different churches.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果我们不用礼文，礼拜仪式过程中哪些部分有可能被忘记？（你也可以思考不同教会的不同礼拜仪式）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. What are the advantages of having a pastor conduct the entire liturgy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;由牧师来带领整个礼文有什么好处？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Would there be advantages to having lay people assist in conducting the liturgy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果让义工辅助带领礼文是否有好处？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What parts of your congregation&amp;rsquo;s liturgy could non-readers learn and take part in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你们教会的礼文中哪些部分是不会阅读的人也能学会和参与的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第六课(lesson 6) 上帝喜悦我们谦卑的敬拜，但是敬拜也是我们献给上帝的礼物，因此我们应当献上最好的</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/304/christian-worship-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/304/christian-worship-6/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第六课(lesson #6) 上帝喜悦我们谦卑的敬拜，但是敬拜也是我们献给上帝的礼物，因此我们应当献上最好的
分类：基督徒敬拜 Christian Worship
作者：Dr. Glen L. Thompson
点击数：2104
God is pleased with our humble worship, but worship is a gift to God and therefore should be the best we can offer.
上帝喜悦我们谦卑的敬拜，但是敬拜也是我们献给上帝的礼物，因此我们应当献上最好的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is pleased with our most humble worship and offerings.
上帝喜悦我们最谦卑的敬拜和奉献。
Luke 18:13-14 &amp;ndash; But the tax collector stood at a distance. He would not even look up to heaven, but beat his breast and said, &amp;ldquo;God, have mercy on me, a sinner. I tell you that this man, rather than the other, went home justified before God. For everyone who exalts himself will be humbled, and he who humbles himself will be exalted.&amp;rdquo;
“那税吏远远地站着,连举目望天也不敢,只捶着胸说:‘神啊,开恩可怜我这个罪人!’我告诉你们:这人回家去比那人倒算为义了。因为凡自高的,必降为卑;自卑的,必升为高。”(路加福音18:13-14)
Mark 12:42-43 &amp;ndash; But a poor widow came and put in two very small copper coins, worth only a fraction of a penny. Calling his disciples to him, Jesus said, &amp;ldquo;I tell you the truth, this poor widow has put more into the treasury than all the others.
“有一个穷寡妇来,往里投了两个小钱,就是一个大钱。耶稣叫门徒来,说:‘我实在告诉你们,这穷寡妇投入库里的,比众人所投的更多’。” (马可福音12:42-43)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet God is not pleased with improper worship
但是上帝不喜悦不恭敬的敬拜。
a. Worship is improper when it is just empty words
只是空话的敬拜是不恭敬的:
&amp;ndash; Matthew 15:8-9 &amp;ndash; These people honor me with their lips, but their hearts are far from me. They worship me uselessly; their teachings are but rules taught by men.
“这百姓用嘴唇尊敬我,心却远离我;他们将人的吩咐当作道理教导人,所以拜我也是枉然。”(马太福音15:8-9)
b. Worship is improper when it is directed to a false God
把人引向假神的敬拜是不恭敬的:
&amp;ndash; Deuteronomy 12:31 &amp;ndash; You must not worship the LORD your God in their way, because in worshiping their gods, they do all kinds of detestable things the LORD hates. They even burn their sons and daughters in the fire as sacrifices to their gods.
“你不可向耶和华你的神这样行,因为他们向他们的神行了耶和华所憎嫌、所恨恶的一切事, 甚至将自己的儿女用火焚烧,献与他们的神。”(申命记12:31)
c. Worship is improper when it contains afalse message
参差了错误信息的敬拜是不恭敬的:
&amp;ndash; Colossians 2:23 &amp;ndash; Such regulations indeed have an appearance of wisdom, with their self-imposed worship, their false humility and their harsh treatment of the body, but they lack any value in restraining sensual indulgence.
“这些规条使人徒有智慧之名,用私意礼拜,自表谦卑,苦待己身,其实在克制肉体的情欲上是毫无功效。”(歌罗西书2:23)
d. Worship is improper when the worshiper is leading an ungodly life.
把人引向不圣洁生活的敬拜是不恭敬的:
&amp;ndash; Amos 5:21-24 &amp;ndash; I hate, I despise your religious feasts; I cannot stand your assemblies. Even though you bring me burnt offerings&amp;hellip;, I will not accept them&amp;hellip;. But let justice roll on like a river, righteousness like a never-failing stream!
“我厌恶你们的节期,也不喜悦你们的严肃会。你们虽然向我献燔祭和素祭,我却不悦纳;也不顾你们用肥畜献的平安祭;要使你们歌唱的声音远离我,因为我不听你们弹琴的响声。惟愿公平如大水滚滚,使公义如江河滔滔。”(阿摩司书5:21-24)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Therefore we should worship carefully:
因此我们应该用心敬拜上帝:
1)so that we worship the true God only
我们应该敬拜独一真神
2)so that everything said and done conveys a biblical message,
我们所说的和所做的都应当传达《圣经》的信息
3)so that our worship is not disrespectful or just empty words
我们的敬拜不应当是不敬虔的或只是空话
4)so that our lives reflect our love and praise of God.
我们的生活要彰显对上帝的爱和赞美&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God asks us to give our best gifts to Him as a sign of our love. Therefore, our worship should be giving God our best in preparation, music, sermons, prayers, offerings and attention.
上帝要求我们献上最好的礼物作为爱的标记。因此,我们应当在敬拜的准备、音乐、讲道、祷告、奉献和关注中献上我们最好的。
Malachi 1:8 &amp;ndash; When you bring blind animals for sacrifice, is that not wrong? When you sacrifice crippled or diseased animals, is that not wrong? Try offering them to your governor! Would he be pleased with you? Would he accept you?&amp;rdquo; says the LORD Almighty.
“你们将瞎眼的献为祭物,这不为恶吗?将瘸腿的、有病的献上,这不为恶吗?你献给你的省长,他岂喜悦你,岂能看你的情面吗? 这是万军之耶和华说的。”(玛拉基书 1:8)
Discussion Questions问题讨论：&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some churches do not plan their services. They simply meet and &amp;ldquo;let the Holy Spirit lead them.&amp;rdquo; Is this a more &amp;ldquo;spiritual&amp;rdquo; approach than planning worship ahead of time?
有些教会不为礼拜仪式做准备。只要大家聚集在一起“让圣灵来带领”就行了。你认为这样的礼拜是否比有准备的礼拜更 “属灵”?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our worship services follow a plan and usually contain most of the following elements. Number them to show the order in which they usually occur in your church. Then tell why each is planned into the service and why it is done in that order.
我们的主日礼拜有一个程序并且通常包括以下所列的大多数内容。请将以下内容进行排序以显示出通常他们在你们教会礼拜仪式进行的顺序。然后说明为什么这些内容中的每一项要被包括在仪式中以及为什么要以这样的顺序来安排。
Confession of Faith (Creed) 认信 (按照信经)
Prayers 祷告
Blessing 祝福
Lord&amp;rsquo;s Supper 圣餐
Confession of Sins 认罪文
Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer 主祷文
Sermon 讲道
Scripture Readings 读经
Absolution (forgiveness of sins) 赦罪
Offering 奉献
Praise 赞美&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From time to time your congregation probably has worship services that are &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; and do not come straight from the prepared services in the hymnal. Can you remember how you reacted to such services? What things did you like or not like about them?
有时你们的教会可能会有“特殊的”礼拜仪式不是直接来自赞美诗集中已经预备好的仪式。你还记得你对这样的礼拜仪式的反应是怎样的吗？这样的仪式中的哪些部分是你所喜欢的，哪些是你所不喜欢的？&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People sometimes complain that the worship services in our hymnals becomes boring because we use them again and again. Can you think of ways that churches can keep that from happening and still have well planned worship?
有时人会抱怨重复使用赞美诗集里的礼拜仪式太枯燥了。你想到消除这种抱怨并保持有序的礼拜仪式的方法吗？&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第七课(lesson 7) 敬拜是普世性的经验，但应该反映基督徒的文化</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/304/christian-worship-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/304/christian-worship-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第七课(lesson #7) 敬拜是普世性的经验，但应该反映基督徒的文化
分类：基督徒敬拜 Christian Worship
作者：Dr. Glen L. Thompson
点击数：2084
Worship is a universal experience but should reflect a Christian&amp;rsquo;s culture.
敬拜是普世性的经验，但应该反映基督徒的文化&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worship changed over the course of Bible history
历史的进程改变了礼拜模式
a. Worship in Old Testament times was done with the music and instruments of Jewish culture
旧约时代的敬拜融合了犹太人的文化及乐器。
&amp;ndash; Psalm 81:2 &amp;ndash; Begin the music, strike the tambourine, play the melodious harp and lyre.
“唱起诗歌，打手鼓，弹美琴与瑟。”（诗篇81：2）
b. Worship in New Testament times was changed to fit the language and culture of that time
新约时期的敬拜转变为适应时代的语言和文化需要。
&amp;ndash; Acts 2:4 &amp;ndash; All of [the apostles] were filled with the Holy Spirit and began to speak in other tongues as the Spirit enabled them.“
他们就都被圣灵充满，按着圣灵所赐的口才，说起别国的话来”（使徒行传2：4）。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God taught the Jewish Christians that their culture was no better than other cultures.
上帝教导犹太基督徒他们的文化并不比别人的好
&amp;ndash; Acts 10:28 &amp;ndash; Peter said to Cornelius: &amp;ldquo;You are well aware that it is against our law for a Jew to associate with a Gentile or visit him. But God has shown me that I should not call any man impure or unclean.“
就对他们说：‘你们知道，犹太人和别国的人亲近来往，本是不合例的，但神已经指示我，无论什么人都不可看作俗而不洁净 的。”（使徒行传10：28）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul makes it clear that worship benefits people only if it is conducted in a language that people understand.
使徒保罗明确地指出敬拜必须使用人容易懂的语言才能造就人
1 Corinthians 14:4,9,19 &amp;ndash; He who speaks in a tongue edifies himself, but he who prophesies edifies the church&amp;hellip;. So it is with you. Unless you speak intelligible words with your tongue, how will anyone know what you are saying? You will just be speaking into the air&amp;hellip;. But in the church I would rather speak five intelligible words to instruct others than ten thousand words in a tongue.
“说方言的，是造就自己；作先知讲道的，乃是造就教会。你们也是如此，舌头若不说容易明白的话，怎能知道所说的是什么呢？这就是向空说话了。但在教会中，宁可用悟性说五句教导人的话，强如说万句方言。”（哥林多前书14：4，9，19）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bible pictures worship in heaven in ways that were understood to people of ancient times. However, the Bible makes it clear that people from every culture and language will worship God in heaven.
《圣经》用古人能明白的方式将天上的敬拜描绘出来。同样地，《圣经》也明确地指出有着不同文化背景和语言的人要一同在天上敬拜上帝。
Revelation 7:9 &amp;ndash; After this I looked and there before me was a great multitude that no one could count, from every nation, tribe, people and language, standing before the throne and in front of the Lamb. They were wearing white robes and were holding palm branches in their hands. And they cried out in a loud voice: &amp;ldquo;Salvation belongs to our God, who sits on the throne, and to the Lamb.&amp;rdquo;
“此后，我观看，见有许多的人，没有人能数过来，是从各国、各族、各民、各方来的，站在宝座和羔羊面前，身穿白衣，手拿棕树枝，”（启示录7：9）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since God normally influences the mind and emotions of Christians most intimately through the language and music with which they grow up, worship should, whenever possible, be conducted in that language and with culturally appropriate music.
上帝通过伴随我们成长的语言和音乐潜移默化地影响基督徒的思想和情感，因此，我们也应该用适合我们文化的语言和音乐来带领我们的敬拜。
Acts 2:7-11 &amp;ndash; Utterly amazed, they asked: &amp;ldquo;Are not all these men who are speaking Galileans? Then how is it that each of us hears them in his own native language? Parthians, Medes and Elamites; residents of Mesopotamia, Judea and Cappadocia, Pontus and Asia, Phrygia and Pamphylia, Egypt and the parts of Libya near Cyrene; visitors from Rome (both Jews and converts to Judaism); Cretans and Arabs&amp;ndash; we hear them declaring the wonders of God in our own tongues!&amp;rdquo;
“都惊讶希奇说，看哪，这说话的不都是加利利人吗？我们各人，怎么听见他们说我们生来所用的乡谈呢？我们帕提亚人，玛代人，以拦人，和住在米所波大米，犹太，加帕多家，本都，亚西亚，弗吕家，旁非利亚，埃及的人，并靠近古利奈的吕彼亚一带地方的人，从罗马来的客旅中，或是犹太人，或是进犹太教的人，革哩底和亚拉伯人，都听见他们用我们的乡谈，讲说神的大作为。”（使徒行传2：7-11）
Corinthians 9:20-22 &amp;ndash; [Paul says:] To the Jews I became like a Jew, to win the Jews. &amp;hellip;.I became like one under the law&amp;hellip;I became like one not having the law&amp;hellip;I became weak, to win the weak. I have become all things to all men so that by all possible means I might save some.
“向犹太人，我就作犹太人，为要得犹太人；向律法以下的人，我虽不在律法以下，还是作律法以下的人，为要得律法以下的人。向没有律法的人，我就作没有律法的人，为要得没有律法的人。其实我在神面前，不是没有律法；在基督面前，正在律法之下。向软弱的人，我就作软弱的人，为要得软弱的人。向什麽样的人，我就作什麽样的人。无论如何总要救些人。”（哥林多前书9：20-22）
Discussion Questions问题讨论：&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name some musical instruments of the Jewish culture which were used in Bible times as part of worship.
列举几个旧约时代用于敬拜的犹太民族乐器&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there some musical instruments which would be inappropriate to use in your worship services today?
是否有某些乐器不适合于我们今天的礼拜仪式？&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every language continues to change. Some words are no longer used and understood. New words are added. What affect might this have on the Bible translations and other language which we use in our worship?
每一种语言都在不断演变。有些词语已渐渐不被使用和了解，新的词语被添加进来。这对《圣经》的翻译和我们在敬拜中使用的其他语言有何影响？&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would St. Paul include speaking in tongues (unknown languages) as part of a worship service? Explain your answer.
使徒保罗是否把说方言（无法理解的语言）作为为礼拜仪式的一部分？谈谈你的理解。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point 4 says that the Bible pictured heaven in a way that Hebrew and Greek people could identify with. Luther once pictured heaven to his son as a place where children played, rode ponies and ate good things all days. How would you picture heaven to an 80-year old in your culture? To a child?
第四点说《圣经》用希伯来人和希腊人能明白的方式将天上的敬拜描绘出来。马丁·路德曾给他的儿子描绘天堂是孩子们整体玩耍、骑小马、吃美食的地方。在你们的文化背景中你怎样向一个80岁的老人或一个孩子描绘天上的景象？&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much of the liturgies in our hymn book reflect the culture of Western Europe. Most Lutheran congregations also use music, art and social customs which reflect European and American culture. Choose several of the following and describe in what ways they are or could be used in your church to reflect your culture?
我们用的赞美诗本中很多礼文反映的是西欧文化。大多数路德教会也使用的是反映欧洲和美国文化的音乐和艺术。从下列选项中选择几个并描述一下它们在哪些方面反映了你们的文化或是可以在你们的教会中使用？
musical tunes 音乐曲调
musical instruments 乐器
the way the pastor, choirs, or worshipers dress 牧师、诗班及敬拜者的服装
the length of the service 礼拜仪式的时间长短
the design of the church building 教堂建筑的设计
the art used in the church building 教堂中使用的艺术品
the way the Scriptures are read 读经方式&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Christianity enters a new culture, it will change and purify parts of that culture. What does this mean about the use of traditional music and arts in Christian worship?
当基督教传入一种新的文化处境中，它有可能改变和净化部分的本土文化。使用传统音乐和艺术对基督徒的敬拜有什么意义？&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第八课(lesson 8) 敬拜是我们与上帝之间的交通,也是基督徒之间的团契</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/304/christian-worship-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/304/christian-worship-8/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;第八课(lesson #8) 敬拜是我们与上帝之间的交通,也是基督徒之间的团契
分类：基督徒敬拜 Christian Worship
作者：Dr. Glen L. Thompson
点击数：2069
When we worship we fellowship with God and fellowship with other Christians.
敬拜是我们与上帝之间的交通,也是基督徒之间的团契&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worship is foremost a communion or fellowship with God.
敬拜是与上帝最重要的交通。
Exodus 24:5 &amp;ndash; Then he sent young Israelite men, and they offered burnt offerings and sacrificed young bulls as fellowship offerings to the LORD.
又打发以色列人中的少年人去献燔祭，又向耶和华献牛为平安祭。”（出埃及记24:5）
Deuteronomy 27:7 &amp;ndash; Sacrifice fellowship offerings there, eating them and rejoicing in the presence of the LORD your God.
“又要献平安祭，且在那里吃，在耶和华你的神面前欢乐。”（申命记27:7）
1 Corinthians 1:9 &amp;ndash; God, who has called you into fellowship with his Son Jesus Christ our Lord, is faithful.
神是信实的，你们原是被他所召，好与他儿子，我们的主耶稣基督，一同得分。”（哥林多前书1:9）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the same time, we share our fellowship with God by enjoying fellowship with other believers.
同时，我们通过与基督徒一起享受团契生活来与上帝交通。
1 John 1:3 &amp;ndash; We proclaim to you what we have seen and heard, so that you also may have fellowship with us. And our fellowship is with the Father and with his Son, Jesus Christ.
“我们将所看见、所听见的传给你们，使你们与我们相交，我们乃是与父并他儿子耶稣基督相交的。”（约翰一书1:3）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That fellowship with God and other believers becomes very personal in our joint worship services.
与上帝的交通和与其他基督徒的团契成为我们集体礼拜仪式中非常个人的一部分。
1 John 1:7 &amp;ndash; But if we walk in the light, as he is in the light, we have fellowship with one another, and the blood of Jesus, his Son, purifies us from all sin.
“我们若在光明中行，如同神在光明中，就彼此相交，他儿子耶稣的血也洗净我们一切的罪。”（约翰一书1:7）
NOTE: Sharing our Lord&amp;rsquo;s body and blood in Holy Communion is one of the most intimate types of fellowship we have. That is one reason for our caution in sharing the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Supper with people who are not members of our own church body (group of churches that are in full agreement with each other).
编者按：我们在圣餐中共同分享主的身体和宝血是一项最亲密的团契生活。这也是为什么我们对于与非本教团（彼此间完全认同所信的教会群体）的基督徒分享圣餐要非常谨慎的原因。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Those who do not have true fellowship with God cannot have fellowship with us either.
我们也不能与那些与上帝没有真正相交的人有团契关系。
2 Kings 17:41 &amp;ndash; Even while these people were worshiping the LORD, they were serving their idols.
“如此这些民又惧怕耶和华，又侍奉他们的偶像。他们子子孙孙也都照样行，效法他们的祖宗，直到今日。”（列王记下17:41）
John 1:6 &amp;ndash; If we claim to have fellowship with him yet walk in the darkness, we lie and do not live by the truth.
“我们若说是与神相交，却仍在黑暗里行，就是说谎话，不行真理了。”（约翰一书1:6）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our common worship and fellowship should only take place with other believers.
我们通常的敬拜和团契只应在信徒中进行。
2 Corinthians 6:14 &amp;ndash; Do not be yoked together with unbelievers. For what do righteousness and wickedness have in common? Or what fellowship can light have with darkness?
“你们和不信的原不相配，不要同负一轭。义和不义有什么相交呢？光明和黑暗有什么相通呢？”（哥林多后书6:14）。
1 Corinthians 5:2 &amp;ndash; And you are proud! Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t you rather have been filled with grief and have put out of your fellowship the [unrepentant] man who did this [public sin]?
“你们还是自高自大，并不哀痛，把行这事的人从你们中间赶出去。” （哥林多前书5:2）
Discussion Questions问题讨论：&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the Old Testament regulations for the fellowship offering in Lev. 7:11-22. Between which two parties is this offering to establish or maintain fellowship? What cause the breaking of fellowship so that an offering was necessary to restore it?
读旧约《利未记》7:11-22中关于关于平安祭的条例。平安祭在哪两部分中使信徒与上帝建立或保持与上帝相交的关系？什么使得信徒与上帝相交的关系破裂从而使信徒需要平安祭来修复这种关系？&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of the following would you enjoy doing with your closest friends?.
下面哪一项是你想与你最亲密的朋友一起要做的？
a. singing songs 唱歌
b. eating a meal 聚餐
c. praying 祷告
d. doing things together 彼此合作
How do your answers apply to worship services in your church?
这些跟教会的礼拜仪式有何关系？&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Communion&amp;rdquo; is another word meaning &amp;ldquo;fellowship.&amp;rdquo; In what way is Holy Communion or the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Supper such an important form of fellowship?
“圣餐”的另一层意思是“团契”。从哪方面说圣餐是如此重要的团契方式？&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A church that is practicing ‘closed communion’ or ‘member only communion’ will allow unbelievers or people from other churches to come to worship services, sing songs, etc., but not to have Holy Communion with us? (1 Corinthians 11:27 gives another reason from that mentioned above.)
一个执行“严密圣餐”或者“会友圣餐”的教会允许非信徒或其他教会的信徒来参加礼拜仪式、唱赞美诗等等，但是不能领圣餐。（哥林多前书11:27中告诉我们为什么要这样做的另一个原因）。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
