<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>恩典圣经学院 – 律法与福音</title>
    <link>/zh-cn/courses/205/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 律法与福音 on 恩典圣经学院</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/zh-cn/courses/205/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 引言</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/205/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/205/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. 来自于神的两大真理&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;律法驱策疾跑&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;却未赐我手脚&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;福音甘美悠扬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;予翼辅我翱翔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在这首短诗中，Ernest Reisinger生动形象地介绍了圣经的两大教导——律法与福音。我们从中得知，律法与福音各自传达不同的信息，成就不同的目的。在本课程中，你将详尽地学习圣经中的两项神圣教导，从而充分掌握、恰当应用此教导。神以律法与福音两大真理转变人心，带给人救恩与奇妙的祝福。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;律法与福音是基督徒必须学习领会与应用的极为重要与绝对基要的教导。愿神——他的话语的亲授者——帮助你认识真理。愿神让你透彻理解、全然相信、以感恩的心颂扬律法与福音。在你服事神的过程中，为着他人属灵的与永恒的福分，忠实地宣扬律法与福音。&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第一课 律法与福音的主要内容</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/205/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/205/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;a----the-true-god-speaks-to-us-in-his-word-the-bible-圣经真神向我们讲述他的道&#34;&gt;A.    The True God Speaks To Us In His Word, The Bible 圣经：真神向我们讲述他的道&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of His great love for us, God has spoken to us and revealed the things that are essential for us to know about Him and His will so that we can have a close, loving relationship with Him.  The Bible is God&amp;rsquo;s Spirit-given, absolutely true, and dynamically powerful word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因着对我们的大爱，神以话语来启示我们，他显明万事让我们从中认识他，明了他的旨意，从而更亲近他。圣经是神赐给我们的属灵礼物，是永生神的权威话语，是绝对真理。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No mind has conceived what God has prepared for those who love Him, but God has revealed it to us by His Spirit.” （1 Corinthians 2:9b-10）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“神为爱他的人所预备的，是人心未曾想到的。只有　神藉著圣灵向我们显明了。”（哥林多前书2:9b-10）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All Scripture is God-breathed.” （2 Timothy 3:16a）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“圣经都是神所默示的。” （提摩太后书3:16a）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Your Word is truth.” （John 17:17b）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“你的道就是真理。”（约翰福音17:17b）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The word of God is living and active. Sharper than any two-edged sword, it penetrates even to dividing soul and spirit, joints and marrow, it judges the thoughts and attitudes of the heart.”（Hebrews 4:12）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神的道是活泼的，是有功效的，比一切两刃的剑更快，甚至魂与灵、骨节与骨髓，都能刺入、剖开，连心中的思念和主意都能辨明。（希伯来书4:12）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s Word is effective in accomplishing the important things God wants it to do in our hearts and lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神的话语卓有成效地在我们的生命与心中成就大事。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So is My word that goes out from My mouth: It will not return to Me empty, but will accomplish what I desire and achieve the purpose for which I sent it.” （Isaiah 55:11）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“我口所出的话也必如此，决不徒然返回，却要成就我所喜悦的，在我发它去成就的事上必然亨通。”（以赛亚书55:11）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You have known the holy Scriptures, which are able to make you wise for salvation through faith in Christ Jesus. All Scripture is God-breathed and is useful for teaching, rebuking, correcting and training in righteousness, so that the man of God may be thoroughly equipped for every good work.” （2 Timothy 3:15-17）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“并且知道你是从小明白圣经；这圣经能使你因信基督耶稣有得救的智慧。圣经都是　神所默示的，于教训、督责、使人归正、教导人学义都是有益的，”（提摩太后书3:15-17）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God reveals his primary will for people in His two great truths, the two major teaching of the Bible: the law and the gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神在两大真理中向人显明他的根本旨意。圣经的主要教导——律法与福音。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For the Lord is our judge, the Lord is our lawgiver, the Lord is our king” （Isaiah 33: 22a）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“因为耶和华是审判我们的，耶和华是给我们设律法的，耶和华是我们的王。”（以赛亚书33: 22a）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am the Lord your God. Follow My decrees and be careful to obey My laws, and you will live safely in the land.” （Leviticus 25:17-18）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“因为我是耶和华你们的　神。我的律例，你们要遵行，我的典章，你们要谨守，就可以在那地上安然居住。”（利未记 25:17-18）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For in the gospel a righteousness from God is revealed, a righteousness that is by faith from first to last, just as it is written: ”The righteous will live by faith.“ （Romans 1:17）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”因为　神的义正在这福音上显明出来；这义是本于信，以至于信。如经上所记：‘义人必因信得生。’“（罗马书 1:17）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God wants people to hold to and proclaim His Word （including its teachings of law and gospel） faithfully and correctly as they apply it to their lives and the lives of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神要我们在个人与他人的实际生活应用中，正确、忠实地掌握与宣扬他的道（包括律法与福音的教导）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”He must hold firmly to the trustworthy message as it has been taught, so that he can encourage others by sound doctrine and refute those who oppose it.“ （Titus 1:9）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”坚守所教真实的道理，就能将纯正的教训劝化人，又能把争辩的人驳倒了。“（提多书1:9）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”Let the one who has My word speak it faithfully.“ （Jeremiah 23:28b）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”得我话的人，可以诚实讲说我的话。“（耶利米书23:28b）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”Do your best to present yourself to God as one approved, a workman who does not need to be ashamed and who correctly handles the word of truth.“ （2 Timothy 2:15）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”你当竭力在　神面前得蒙喜悦，作无愧的工人，按著正意分解真理的道。“（提摩太后书2:15）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b----the-basic-aspects-of-the-law-and-the-gospel-律法与福音的几个基本方面&#34;&gt;B.    The Basic Aspects Of The Law And The Gospel 律法与福音的几个基本方面&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;The Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;The Gospel&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;种类&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;律法&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;福音&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Definition&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s holy will, His moral requirements of us&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The ”Good News“, God&amp;rsquo;s gracious will of what He does to save us&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;定义&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;上帝神圣的旨意，他对我们的道德要求&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;”好消息“,上帝充满恩典的旨意，救赎我们。&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Revelation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Written in people&amp;rsquo;s hearts Revealed in God&amp;rsquo;s Word&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Naturally unknown to people Revealed in God&amp;rsquo;s Word&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;启示&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;书写在人心中，显明于神话语中&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;人非天生知晓福音，显明于神话语中&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Messages&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Love God and your neighbor&lt;br&gt;Do all God wants perfectly&lt;br&gt;You have sinned &amp;amp; are lost&lt;br&gt;God will justly punish you&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;God lovesyou&lt;br&gt;God has done it all foryou&lt;br&gt;God has forgiven you &amp;amp; savedyou&lt;br&gt;God will freely bless you&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;信息&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;完美无缺地履行神的旨意：爱神，爱人。&lt;br&gt;你犯罪迷失，神将行使他公义的惩罚&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;神爱你，他已为你成就一切，&lt;br&gt;神宽恕、拯救你，祝福你&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Commands &amp;amp; demands&lt;br&gt;Warnings and threats&lt;br&gt;Rewards to earn by obedience&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Announcements &amp;amp; invitations&lt;br&gt;Comforts &amp;amp; encouragements&lt;br&gt;Gifts from God to receive&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;形式&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;命令与要求，警告与威赫&lt;br&gt;靠顺服得奖赏&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;通告与邀请，安慰与鼓励，&lt;br&gt;收取来自神的礼物&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;God- Intended Effects&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Genuine sorrow for sin&lt;br&gt;Restricts sinful behavior&lt;br&gt;Gives guidance for living&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Creates faith in Jesus Christ &lt;br&gt;Makes confident of salvation&lt;br&gt;Empowers to live spiritually&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;神预期的效果&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;真诚悔罪，约束罪恶行为&lt;br&gt;指导生活&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;在耶稣基督里建立信心，&lt;br&gt;坚信神的救赎，健全属灵生命&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Results Of Rejection&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Creates more hatred for God&lt;br&gt;Increases sin and rebellion&lt;br&gt;Works to harden heart&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Regarded as offensive &amp;amp; foolish&lt;br&gt;Taken as permission to sin&lt;br&gt;Spiritual arrogance or despair&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;拒绝的后果&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;更加怨恨神，&lt;br&gt;更多的罪恶与悖逆，内心刚硬&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;视福音为唐突无礼、愚蠢可笑的信息&lt;br&gt;纵容罪，灵里的傲慢与绝望&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Major Applications&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sinners who are not contrite&lt;br&gt;Believers who need guidance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sinners who are contrite&lt;br&gt;Believers who need strength&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;主要应用&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;不思悔改的罪人&lt;br&gt;偏离正路的基督徒&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;悔过的罪人&lt;br&gt;需要汲取力量的基督徒&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;c----identify-law-and-gospel-确认律法与福音&#34;&gt;C.    Identify Law And Gospel 确认律法与福音&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following passages, indicate whether they contain Law and/or Gospel and explain your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;指出以下经文包含：1 律法与福音，2律法或福音，并解释你的选择。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音22:37-39是 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因为&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰3:16 是 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因为&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音Matthew 5:48 是 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因为&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;希伯来书 9:28 是&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因为&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;加拉太书 3:10 是&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因为&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音9:2 是 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因为&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;希伯来书 3:12 是 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因为&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书 5:13 是&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因为&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音 23:13 是 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因为&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书 4:11 是&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因为&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;d----reviewing-the-lesson-本课回顾&#34;&gt;D.    Reviewing The Lesson 本课回顾&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill in the blanks to correctly complete the following sentences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;填空，正确完成下列句子。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two great teachings of the Bible are the law and the &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经的两大教导是：律法和&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The law is written both in the &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; of people and in the Bible, while the gospel is written only in the &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;律法书写在圣经里和人的&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;,而福音只书写在&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the law God demands that we &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; Him and our neighbor perfectly.  Because we do not do this, the law reveals that we have sinned and deserve to be &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在律法中，神命令我们完美无缺地&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;神和他人。由于我们没有做到这一点，律法显明：我们应该受&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the gospel God announces the good &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; that He loves us and that He has saved us from our sins through the perfect, redeeming work of &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在福音中，神向我们宣告”好&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;“:神爱我们，靠着完美的救主&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-   &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;神把我们从罪恶中拯救出来。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God presents the law to us in the form of commands, demands, warnings, and &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神以命令、要求、警告以及&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;的形式向我们显明律法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God presents the gospel to us in the form of announcements, &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;, comforts, and encouragements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神以通告、&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;、安慰与鼓励的形式向我们显明福音。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The law promises spiritual blessings as &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; for one&amp;rsquo;s perfect obedience; while the gospel promises spiritual blessings as &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; from God&amp;rsquo;s undeserved love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;律法应许，靠着完全的顺服我们将得到属灵的祝福，以此作为&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;;福音却将属灵的祝福作为&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;赐给我们，是我们所不配得的、来自神的爱。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God intends and empowers the law&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a） to work contrition or genuine &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; for sin in people&amp;rsquo;s hearts,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b） to restrict the sinful behavior of people and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c） to provide Christians with &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; for living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神预期律法能够使人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1）真诚&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2）约束自己的罪恶行为&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3）为基督徒的生活提供&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God intends and empowers the gospel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a） to create &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; in Jesus Christ in people&amp;rsquo;s hearts,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b） to make people confident of their &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c） to empower Christians to live spiritually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神预期福音能够使人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1）在耶稣基督里建立&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2）坚信神的&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3）健全基督徒的属灵生活&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sinful nature of a person responds to the message of the law with hatred and &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因着罪性，人以怨恨和&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;回应律法信息。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sinful nature of a person considers the gospel to be an offensive and &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因着罪性，人认为福音信息唐突无礼，&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people who especially need to hear the law are sinners who are not genuinely sorry for their sins and believers who need &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; for Christian living; while the people who especially need to hear the gospel are sinners who are genuinely &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; for their sins and believers who need strength for Christian living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;不真诚悔罪的人和&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-的基督徒，尤其需要神的律法。真诚&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;的人和需要汲取生活力量的基督徒，尤其需要神的福音。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第二课 律法来自神的严酷消息</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/205/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/205/3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;a----the-great-truth-of-the-law-and-its-primary-meaning-律法的伟大真理与基本意义&#34;&gt;A.    The Great Truth Of The Law And Its Primary Meaning 律法的伟大真理与基本意义&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In His Word, God has revealed the two great truths of His Law and Gospel.  The law is a truth that contains very hard news for us to receive.  God&amp;rsquo;s law sends an exceedingly strong, stern, demanding and difficult message to us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神在他的话语中向我们显明律法与福音两大真理。律法承载着极为严酷的消息，是来自神的强烈、严厉、苛求、难以遵循的信息。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The two primary words that are translated “law” in the Bible are the Old Testament Hebrew word, “torah”, and the New Testament Greek word, “nomos.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“律法”一词有两个最初的译法，一个是旧约中的希伯来语“教导”,一个是新约中的希腊语“法律”.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of the time, God uses the word “law” in the Bible in a specific, primary sense to refer to “God&amp;rsquo;s holy, moral demands of all people that they be perfect and God&amp;rsquo;s condemnation and punishments for those who disobey Him.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;多数情况下，神在圣经中以“律法” 一词专指“神的圣洁，神对人类完美的道德要求，神对悖逆者的定罪与惩罚。”

“Be holy because I am the Lord your God. Keep My decrees and follow them.” （Leviticus 20:7b-8a）

所以你们要自洁成圣，因为我是耶和华你们的　神。你们要谨守遵行我的律例，我是叫你们成圣的耶和华。（利未记20:7b-8a）

“The soul who sins is the one who will die.” （Ezekiel 18:4b）

犯罪的他必死亡。（以西结书18:4b）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When we speak about God&amp;rsquo;s teachings of the law and gospel, we are using this specific, primary definition/sense of the law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;当我们讲到关于神的律法与福音的教导时，我们就是在应用律法这一基本的、专门的定义。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b-----the-revelation-of-the-law-律法的启示&#34;&gt;B.     The Revelation Of The Law 律法的启示&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has revealed His law to people in two places:  神在两个地方向人类启示他的律法：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God has written His holy, moral demands on the minds and souls of people at the time of their creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神早在创世之初就已将他的圣洁、他的道德要求书写在人类的头脑与心灵里。

“They show that the requirements of the law are written on their hearts, their consciences also bearing witness, and their thoughts now accusing, now even defending them.” （Romans 2:15）

这是显出律法的功用刻在他们心里，他们是非之心同作见证，并且他们的思念互相较量，或以为是，或以为非。（罗马书2:15）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entrance of sin into people&amp;rsquo;s lives has blurred this once perfect knowledge of the law.  So now, when people are created, they have a limited and flawed understanding of God&amp;rsquo;s requirements of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;罪恶进入人类生活，玷污了这一曾经完美的、对神律法的认知。如今，人类在这方面的知识已相当有限且残缺不全。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In order to help people know His moral demands of them clearly and fully, God lovingly revealed His law in a second way.  He had it written and recorded in various places in the Bible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;为了使人充分清楚地了解神对人的道德要求，神充满慈爱地以第二种方式向我们显明他的律法——将律法书写记录在圣经的诸多地方。

“The secret things belong to the Lord our God, but the things revealed belong to us and to our children forever, that we may follow all the words of His law.” （Deuteronomy 29:29）

隐秘的事是属耶和华我们　神的；惟有明显的事是永远属我们和我们子孙的，好叫我们遵行这律法上的一切话。“（申命记29:29）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;c----the-messages-of-the-law-律法的信息&#34;&gt;C.    The Messages Of The Law 律法的信息&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the law, God makes great and important demands of people:  神在律法中向人类提出重大要求：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God commands people to love Him and all other people with their whole being at all times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神命令人毕生全身心地爱神、爱所有的人。

”Jesus replied, &#39;Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind . . . and love your neighbor as yourself.‘“ （Matthew 22:37, 39b）

耶稣对他说：”你要尽心、尽性、尽意，爱主你的　神… 要爱人如己。“（马太福音22:37, 39b）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God instructs people to carry out this command to love in many different ways:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神教导人在诸多方面执行这一爱的指令。

”You shall have no other gods before Me. You shall not make for yourself an idol. You shall not bow down to worship them. You shall not misuse the name of the Lord your God. Remember the Sabbath day by keeping it holy. Honor your father and your mother. You shall not murder. You shall not commit adultery. You shall not steal. You shall not give false testimony against your neighbor. You shall not covet your neighbor&#39;s wife . . . or anything that belongs to your neighbor.“ （Exodus 20:3-17） （See also Leviticus 19 and Romans 12:9-13:1）

除了我以外，你不可有别的神。不可为自己雕刻偶像；不可跪拜那些像；不可妄称耶和华你　神的名；当记念安息日，守为圣日。当孝敬父母。不可杀人。不可奸淫。不可偷盗。不可作假见证陷害人。不可贪恋人的妻子。 . . 并他一切所有的。（出埃及记20:3-17）（另见利未记 19及罗马书 12:9-13:1）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God requires that people keep his law perfectly （100%） in all that they are and think and say and do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神要求人的一切思想言行都完美无缺（100%）地符合他的律法。

”Be holy, because I the Lord your God, am holy.“ （Leviticus 19:2）

”你们要圣洁，因为我耶和华你们的　神是圣洁的。“（利未记 19:2）

”Be perfect, therefore, as your heavenly Father is perfect.“ （Matthew 5:48）

所以你们要完全，像你们的天父完全一样。（马太福音5:48）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God will not change or alter any part of His law&amp;rsquo;s demands and punishments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神不会更改他律法中的任何诫命及惩罚。

”I the Lord do not change.“ （Malachi 3:6）

”因我耶和华是不改变的。“（马拉基书3:6）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the law, God promises blessing for those who perfectly obey it and curses for those who disobey it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神在律法中应许：完全遵行律法的人将得祝福，违背律法的人将遭诅咒。

”He answered, &#39;Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your strength and with all your mind and, Love your neighbor as yourself.&#39; &#39;You have answered correctly,&#39; Jesus replied, &#39;Do this and you will live.’“ （Luke 10:27-28）

他回答说：”你要尽心、尽性、尽力、尽意爱主你的　神；又要爱邻舍如同自己。“耶稣说：”你回答的是。你这样行，就必得永生。“（路加福音10:27-28）

”All who rely on observing the law are under a curse, for it is written: &#39;Cursed is everyone who does not continue to do everything written in the Book of the Law.“ （Galatians 3:10）

凡以行律法为本的，都是被咒诅的，因为经上记著：”凡不常照律法书上所记一切之事去行的，就被咒诅。“（加拉太书3:10）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the law, God declares the just and convicting truth that all people have failed to keep His law and have sinned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神在律法中宣告公正确凿的事实——世人犯了罪，未能遵守神的律法。

”There is no one righteous, not even one; there is no one who understands, no one who seeks God. All have turned away, they have together become worthless; there is no one who does good, not even one . . . All have sinned and fall short of the glory of God.“ （Romans 3:10-12, 23）

就如经上所记：”没有义人，连一个也没有！没有明白的，没有寻求　神的。 . . 都是偏离正路，一同变为无用。没有行善的，连一个也没有！“. . .因为世人都犯了罪，亏缺了　神的荣耀。（罗马书3:10-12, 23）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the law, God delivers the just and terrifying truth that all sinners are under His just condemnation and must suffer His earthly and eternal wrath and punishment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神在律法中传达了公正可怕的事实——所有罪人都在神公义的审判之下，必将承受神现世与永恒的烈怒和惩罚。

”But your iniquities have separated you from your God. Your sins have hidden His face from you. （Isaiah 59:2）

但你们的罪孽使你们与神隔绝，你们的罪恶使他掩面不听你们。（以赛亚书 59:2）

“The wages of sin is death.” （Romans 6:23）

罪的工价乃是死。（罗马书 6:23）

“Then Jesus said to those on His left, &#39;Depart from Me, you who are cursed, into the eternal fire prepared for the devil and his angels.” （Matthew 25:41）

王又要向那左边的说，你们这被咒诅的人，离开我，进入那为魔鬼和他的使者所豫备的永火里去。（马太福音25:41）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;d----the-forms-of-the-law-律法的形式&#34;&gt;D.    The Forms Of The Law 律法的形式&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God uses a variety of forms to deliver the true, powerful messages of His law:  神以多种方式传达真实、权威的律法信息。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God gives commands or orders. 神发布命令。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“The Lord your God commands you this day to follow these decrees and laws; carefully observe them with all your heart and with all your soul. （Deuteronomy 26:16）

耶和华你的神今日吩咐你行这些律例典章，所以你要尽心尽性谨守遵行。（申命记26:16）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God makes demands or authoritative claims. 神提出要求。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;”He said to them, &#39;Give to Caesar what is Caesar&#39;s, and to God what is God&#39;s.“ （Matthew 22:21）

耶稣说，这样，该撒的物当归给该撒，神的物当归给神。（马太福音22:21）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God issues warnings. 神发出警告。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;”Know that for all these things God will bring you to judgment.“ （Ecclesiastes 11:9）

却要知道，为这一切的事，神必审问你。（传道书11:9）  

”Repent! Turn away from all your offenses; then sin will not be your downfall.“ （Ezekiel 18:30b）

你们当回头离开所犯的一切罪过。这样，罪孽必不使你们败亡。（以西结书18:30b）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God makes threats. 神发出威吓&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;”Cursed is the man who does not uphold the words of this law by carrying them out.“ （Deuteronomy 27:26）

不坚守遵行这律法言语的，必受咒诅。（申命记27:26）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God makes valid accusations of sin and wrongdoing. 神指控罪与恶行。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;”Hear the word of the Lord, you Israelites, because the Lord has a charge to bring against you who live in the land: &#39;There is no faithfulness, no love, no acknowledgement of God in the land. There is only cursing, lying and murder, stealing and adultery; they break all bounds, and bloodshed follows bloodshed.“ （Hosea 4:1-2）

以色列人哪，你们当听耶和华的话。耶和华与这地的居民争辩，因这地上无诚实，无良善，无人认识神。但起假誓，不践前言，杀害，偷盗，奸淫，行强暴，杀人流血，接连不断。 （何西阿书4:1-2）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God makes just condemnations of sin and unbelief. 神对罪与悖逆发出公义的责难。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;”Their sin engulfs them; they are always before Me . . . He does not return to the Lord his God or search for Him. . . Woe to them, because they have strayed from Me! Destruction to them, because they have rebelled against Me! （Hosea 7:2b, 10b, 13a）

他们所行的现在缠绕他们，都在我面前…他们仍不归向耶和华他们的神，也不寻求他…他们因离弃我，必定有祸，因违背我，必被毁灭。（何西阿书7:2b, 10b, 13a）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God pronounces punishments for sin. 神宣告罪得惩罚。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“On that day I will become angry with them and forsake them; I will hide My face from them, and they will be destroyed. Many disasters and difficulties will come upon them, and on that day they will ask, &#39;Have not these disasters come upon us because our God is not with us?&#39; And I will certainly hide My face on that day because of all their wickedness in turning to other gods.” （Deuteronomy 31:17-18）

那时，我的怒气必向他们发作。我也必离弃他们，掩面不顾他们，以致他们被吞灭，并有许多的祸患灾难临到他们。那日他们必说，这些祸患临到我们，岂不是因我们的神不在我们中间吗？那时，因他们偏向别神所行的一切恶，我必定掩面不顾他们。 （申命记31:17-18）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God promises rewards for complete obedience. 神应许完全的顺服得奖赏。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“If you fully obey the Lord your God and carefully follow all His commands I give you today, the Lord your God will set you high above all the nations on the earth. All these blessings will come upon you and accompany you if you obey the Lord your God.” （Deuteronomy 28:1-2）

一切诫命，就是我今日所吩咐你的，他必使你超乎天下万民之上。你若听从耶和华你神的话，这以下的福必追随你，临到你身上，（申命记28:1-2）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;e----the-purposes-of-the-law-神律法的目的&#34;&gt;E.    The Purposes Of The Law 神律法的目的&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of His great love, God has given people His law for a number of important reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神爱世人且为人设立律法，有以下几个重要理由。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Originally, God gave the law as a means by which people could gain salvation for themselves.  They could earn salvation by perfectly obeying the law.  （The Law as a Stairway to heaven）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;律法原本是神为那些能够靠着完美无缺地遵行律法而为自己赢得救恩的人设立的。（律法如同通往神国的天梯）

Keep My decrees and laws, for the man who obeys them will live by them. I am the Lord.“ （Leviticus 18:5）

所以，你们要守我的律例典章，人若遵行，就必因此活着。我是耶和华。（利未记18:5）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the Fall into sin and the spiritual corruption of the human race, all people are sinful and fail to keep the law perfectly.  Now no one is able to save himself/herself by obeying the law.  （The Law is a Dead End as a means of salvation）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;由于人类陷入罪及灵魂的堕落，没有人能完美无缺地遵行律法，没有人可以靠着顺从律法而自救/得救。（靠律法得救赎是一条死胡同）

”All have turned aside, they have together become corrupt; there is no one who does good, not even one.“ （Psalm 14:3）

他们都偏离正路，一同变为污秽。并没有行善的，连一个也没有。（诗篇14:3）

”Therefore no one will be declared righteous in His sight by observing the law.“ （Romans 3:20a）

所以凡有血气的没有一个，因行律法，能在神面前称义。（罗马书3:20a）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God now uses the law for the primary purpose of causing people to realize and be genuinely sorry for their sins and to be afraid of God and His judgment on their sins.  The name we give to this spiritual condition is contrition.  （The Law as a Photograph that reveals our sin and punishment）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神律法的根本目的是令人认罪悔过，敬畏神、惧怕神对罪的公义审判。我们将这一属灵状况称为悔悟。（律法如同一帧照片显明我们的罪与神的惩罚）

a.     The law makes people aware of their sin and guilt.

律法使人知罪。

”I would not have known what sin was except through the law.“ （Romans 7:7b）

只是非因律法，我就不知何为罪。 （罗马书7:7b）

”Through the law we come conscious of sin.“ （Romans 3:20b）

因为律法本是叫人知罪。（罗马书3:20b）

b.    The law works in people a spirit of sincere regret for their sins.

律法令人在灵魂深处真诚悔过。

”I confess my iniquity. I am troubled by me sin.“ （Psalm 38:18）

我要承认我的罪孽。我要因我的罪忧愁。（诗篇38:18）

”Father, I have sinned against Heaven and against you. I am no longer worthy to be called your son.“ （Luke 15:21）

父亲，我得罪了天，又得罪了你，从今以后，我不配称为你的儿子。（路加福音 15:21）

c.    The law crushes the sinful pride of people and kills their false hopes of avoiding or escaping God&#39;s condemnation of their sins.

律法击碎人类的傲慢，无人能够侥幸回避与逃脱神对罪的审断。

”My guilt has overwhelmed me like a burden too heavy to bear…I am feeble and utterly crushed; I groan in anguish of heart.“ （Psalm 38:4, 8）

我的罪孽高过我的头，如同重担叫我担当不起…我被压伤，身体疲倦。因心里不安，我就唉哼。（诗篇38:4, 8）

”Once I was alive apart from law; but when the commandments come, sin sprang to life and I died.“ （Romans 7:9）

我以前没有律法是活着的，但是诫命来到，罪又活了，我就死了。（罗马书7:9）

d.    The law leads people to despair of saving themselves and to be prepared to look to God to save them.

律法让人意识到自救无望，转而指望神的拯救。

”Out of the depths I cry to You, O Lord; O Lord, hear my voice. Let Your ears be attentive to my cry for mercy.“ （Psalm 130:1-2）

耶和华啊，我从深处向你求告。主啊，求你听我的声音。愿你侧耳听我恳求的声音。 （诗篇130:1-2）

”What a wretched man I am! Who will rescue me from this body of death?“ （Romans 7:24）

我真是苦啊，谁能救我脱离这取死的身体呢。 （罗马书7:24）

”I said, &#39;O Lord, have mercy on me; heal me, for I have sinned against You.“ （Psalm 41:4）

我曾说，耶和华啊，求你怜恤我，医治我。因为我得罪了你。（诗篇41:4）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By giving people the law to work contrition in their hearts, God uses the law in the service of the Gospel.  People who are properly alarmed by their sin and afraid of God&amp;rsquo;s judgment are prepared to receive and appreciate the saving comfort God gives in the Gospel.   People who are secure in their sin and not afraid of God&amp;rsquo;s judgment feel no need and have no interest in the Gospel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;凭借律法在人内心所做的认罪悔改的工作，神将律法应用于福音事工。凡被罪警醒，畏惧神公义审判的人，即得着福音救赎信息的安慰，并为此而感恩。凡心安理得沉溺于自己的罪，不惧怕神公义审判的人，不会在乎也不认为自己需要福音信息。

”Is the law, therefore, opposed to the promises of God? Absolutely not! For, if a law had been given that could impart life, then righteousness would certainly have come by the law. But the Scripture declares that the whole world is a prisoner of sin, so that what was promised, being given through faith in Jesus Christ, might be given to those who believe. Before this faith came, we were held prisoners by the law, locked up until faith should be revealed. So the law was put in charge to lead us to Christ that we might be justified by faith.“ （Galatians 3:21-24）

这样，律法是与神的应许反对么。断乎不是。若曾传一个能叫人得生命的律法，义就诚然本乎律法了。但圣经把众人都圈在罪里，使所应许的福因信耶稣基督，归给那信的人。但这因信得救的理，还未来以先，我们被看守在律法之下，直圈到那将来的真道显明出来。这样律法是我们训蒙的师傅，引我们到基督那里，使我们因信称义。（加拉太书3:21-24）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God also uses the law to restrict the sinful behavior of people so that there is relative peace and order in the world.  （The law as a Fence to restrain sin）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神用律法约束人的犯罪行为，这个世界从而有了相对的和平与秩序。（律法如同制约罪恶的围栏）

”We also know that the law is made not for the righteous but for lawbreakers and rebels, the ungodly and the sinful, the unholy and irreligious; for those who kill their fathers or mothers, for murderers, for adulterers and perverts, for slave traders and liars and perjurers – and for whatever else is contrary to the sound doctrine.“ （1 Timothy 1:9-10）

因为律法不是为义人设立的，乃是为不法和不服的，不虔诚和犯罪的，不圣洁和恋世俗的，弑父母和杀人的，行淫和亲男色的，抢人口和说谎话的，并起假誓的，或是为别样敌正道的事设立的。（提摩太前书1:9-10）

”For rulers hold no terror for those who do right, but for those who do wrong. . . He is God&#39;s servant to do you good. But if you do wrong, be afraid, for he does not bear the sword for nothing. He is God&#39;s servant, an agent of wrath to bring punishment on the wrongdoer.“ （Romans 13:3a, 4）

作官的原不是叫行善的惧怕，乃是叫作恶的惧怕…因为他是神的用人，是与你有益的。你若作恶，却当惧怕。因为他不是空空的佩剑。他是神的用人，是伸冤的，刑罚那作恶的。（罗马书13:3a, 4）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God also uses the law to give Christians guidance for living a God-pleasing, obedient life of good works.  （The law as a Guide to show the way to live）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神用律法指导基督徒的善行，让他们过蒙神喜悦的顺服生活。（律法如同生活向导）

”How can a young man keep his way pure? By living according to Your word.“ （Psalm 119:9）

少年人用什么洁净他的行为呢。是要遵行你的话。（诗篇119:9）

”Whoever has my commands and obeys them, he is the one who loves Me.“ （John 14:21）

有了我的命令又遵守的，这人就是爱我的。（约翰福音14:21）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;f----sinful-efforts-to-interfere-with-gods-purposes-in-the-law-人类的罪恶努力抵挡神实现律法的目的&#34;&gt;F.    Sinful Efforts To Interfere With God&amp;rsquo;s Purposes In The Law 人类的罪恶努力抵挡神实现律法的目的&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All people, by nature, know God&amp;rsquo;s law and have consciences that witness to their keeping or breaking of the law （Romans 2:14-15）。 However, their sinful natures hate the powerful, strict and difficult message of the law, refuse to accept it, and fight against the law accomplishing God&amp;rsquo;s good purposes in their lives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;人的天性知晓神的律法，道德良心可以见证人或遵行或违背了律法（罗马书2:14-15）。然而他们的罪性（罪恶天性）厌恶并拒绝接受神权威、严苛、难以照办的律法信息，阻挠律法在他们的生命中实现神美好的目的。

”The sinful mind is hostile to God. It does not submit to God&#39;s law, nor can it do so.“ （Romans 8:7）

原来体贴肉体的，就是与神为仇。因为不服神的律法，也是不能服。（罗马书8:7）

”The law brings wrath.“ （Romans 4:15a）

因为律法是惹动忿怒的。（罗马书 4:15a）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In their opposition to God and His law, the sinful natures of people lead them to rebel against the law in such ways as:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;人的罪性（罪恶天性）以这样的方式悖逆神与神的律法。

a.     Refusing and ignoring the law&#39;s authority over them.

拒绝与忽视神的律法至高无上的权威。

”In his pride the wicked does not seek Him; in all his thoughts there is no room for God. . . . He is haughty and Your laws are far from him . . . He says to himself, &#39;Nothing will shake me; I&#39;ll always be happy and never have trouble“ （Psalm 10:4, 5b, 6）

恶人面带骄傲，说，耶和华必不追究。他一切所想的，都以为没有神…凡他所作的，时常稳固。你的审判超过他的眼界。他心里说，我必不动摇，世世代代不遭灾难。（诗篇10:4, 5b, 6）

b.    Declaring the law to be evil and sins against it to be good things.

宣称神的律法只有消极意义没有积极意义。

”Woe to those who call evil good and good evil, who put darkness for light and light for darkness, who put bitter for sweet and sweet for bitter. Woe to those who are wise in their own eyes and clever in their own sight.“ （Isaiah 5:20-21）

祸哉，那些称恶为善，称善为恶，以暗为光，以光为暗，以苦为甜，以甜为苦的人。祸哉，那些自以为有智慧，自看为通达的人。 （以赛亚书 5:20-21）

c.    Insisting that the law is for other people, but not for them.

认为律法只针对他人，不针对自己。

”They do not practice what they preach. They tie up heavy loads and put them on men&#39;s shoulders, but they themselves are not willing to lift a finger to move them.“ （Matthew 23:3b-4）

他们能说不能行。他们把难担的重担，捆起来搁在人的肩上。但自己一个指头也不肯动。 （马太福音23:3b-4）

d.    Accepting some parts of the law and neglecting others

部分接受部分忽略。

”Woe to you, teachers of the law and Pharisees, you hypocrites! You give a tenth of your spices – mint, dill and cumin. But you have neglected the more important matters of the law – justice, mercy and faithfulness. You should have practiced the latter, without neglecting the former.“ （Matthew 23:23-24）

你们这假冒为善的文士和法利赛人有祸了。因为你们将薄荷，茴香，芹菜，献上十分之一。那律法上更重的事，就是公义，怜悯，信实，反倒不行了。这更重的是你们当行的；那也是不可不行的。（马太福音23:23-24）

e.     Insisting that the law only needs to be kept in outward actions and not also in the inner attitudes of the heart.

执意认为只有人的外在行为需要遵行律法，内心世界不必如此。

”You are like whitewashed tombs, which look beautiful on the outside, but on the inside are full of dead men&#39;s bones and everything unclean. In the same way, on the outside you appear to people as righteous but on the inside you are full of hypocrisy and wickedness.“ （Matthew 23:27b-28）

你们好像粉饰的坟墓，外面好看，里面却装满了死人的骨头，和一切的污秽。 你们也是如此，在人前，外面显出公义来，里面却装满了假善和不法的事。 （马太福音23:27b-28）

f.     Assuming that God is not really serious about the law and is either unwilling and/or unable to enforce it.

以为神并不真正在意他的律法，神要么不情愿要么没能力执行他的律法。

”He says to himself, &#39;God has forgotten; He covers His face and never sees.“ …… ”Why does the wicked man revile God? Why does his say to himself, &#39;He won&#39;t call me to account?‘“ （Psalm 10:11, 13）

他心里说，神竟忘记了。他掩面，永不观看……恶人为何轻慢神，心里说，你必不追究。 （诗篇 10:11, 13）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All these and other forms of rebellion against the law reveal the foolish, sinful stubbornness of the human heart.  People who persist in this unbelieving rebellion against God only succeed in incurring more sin and punishment for themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;所有这类及其它悖逆神律法的方式都表明了人心的愚蠢、邪恶与冥顽。一意孤行不信与背叛神的人，只能招致更严重的罪，加剧神对他们的惩罚。

”But because of your stubbornness and your unrepentant heart, you are storing up wrath against yourself for the day of God&#39;s wrath, when His righteous judgment will be revealed.“ （Romans 2:5）

你竟任着你刚硬不悔改的心，为自己积蓄忿怒，以致神震怒，显出他公义审判的日子来到。（罗马书 2:5）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;g----reviewing-the-lesson-本课回顾&#34;&gt;G.    Reviewing The Lesson 本课回顾&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-fill-in-the-blanks-to-correctly-complete-the-following-sentences-填空正确完成下列句子&#34;&gt;1. Fill in the blanks to correctly complete the following sentences. 填空，正确完成下列句子。&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We call the law, God&amp;rsquo;s extremely hard news for us because its message is strong, stern, demanding and &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; for us to receive and follow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;我们称律法为”来自神的极为严酷的消息“,因为它强烈、严厉、苛求和---------.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The specific, primary  meaning of God&amp;rsquo;s law is God&amp;rsquo;s &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;, moral demands of all people that they be perfect along with God&amp;rsquo;s condemnations and punishments for those who &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; Him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;”律法“一词专指”神的--------,神对人类完美的道德要求，神对-------者的定罪与惩罚。“
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One reason God lovingly chose to reveal His law by writing it in the &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; was that God&amp;rsquo;s original writing of the law in human hearts had become &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; after sin entered people&amp;rsquo;s lives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神充满慈爱地在---------中以书面形式向我们显明他的律法，是因为他起初写在我们心中的律法因着罪恶进入人类生活而变得-------------------.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The primary requirements God has for us in the law is that we &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- both God and all other people without failing even &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神在律法中对我们的根本要求是-------------------地---------神和所有的人。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The law also announces to us that tragic news that we have &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; against God and that we must suffer His earthly and eternal &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神在律法中向我们宣布悲剧性的消息：我们----------背离神，必将遭受神现世与永恒的-------------------.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God delivers the messages of the law to us in the forms of &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;, demands, warnings and &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;.  He also makes valid &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; and condemnations and pronounces &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; for our sins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神以--------、要求、警告和----------的形式向我们传达律法信息。他责难我们的罪，并宣告罪得----------.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because of our sinfulness, the law is no longer a ”&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;“ we can climb to reach heaven.  Attempting to gain salvation by our own &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- is now a useless and frustrating ”dead end.“&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;因着我们的罪，律法已不再是我们攀爬而进入神国的”--------------“.试图靠着我们自己----------------而赢得救赎是一条无望的”--------------“.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s primary purpose in giving us the law is to work &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; in our hearts, that is, a genuine sorrow for our sins and a &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; of God and His judgment on our sins.  In this way, the law serves as a spiritual ”photograph“ to reveal our sin and punishment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神设立律法的根本目的是在我们心中做--------------的工作，让我们真诚悔罪，令我们---------神，---------神对罪的公义审判。从这个意义上讲，律法如同一帧属灵的”照片“显明我们的罪及神对罪的惩罚。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God also uses the law as a spiritual ”fence“ to restrain the sinful &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; of people and as a spiritual ”guide“ for the Christian to show him/her how to live a God- &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神把律法当作属灵的”围栏“,用来制约人的----------行为。神把律法当作基督徒属灵的”向导“,指引他们过-----------------的生活。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God seeks to accomplish His good purposes of His law in our lives against the wicked, rebellious efforts of our sinful &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;针对人类罪------（罪恶--------）中恶意反叛的努力，神要在我们的生活中实现他律法的美好目的。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-analyze-these-scripture-verses-经文分析&#34;&gt;2. Analyze These Scripture Verses 经文分析&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The house of Israel says, &amp;lsquo;The way of the Lord is not just.&amp;rsquo; Are My ways unjust, O house of Israel? Is it not your ways that are unjust? Therefore, O house of Israel, I will judge you, each one according to his ways, declares the Sovereign Lord. Repent! Turn away from all your offenses; then sin will not be your downfall. Rid yourselves of all the offenses you have committed, and get a new heart and a new spirit. Why will you die, O house of Israel! For I take no pleasure in the death of anyone, declares the Sovereign Lord, Repent and live! （Ezekiel 18:29-32）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以色列家还说，主的道不公平。以色列家阿，我的道岂不公平么。你们的道岂不是不公平么。所以主耶和华说，以色列家阿，我必按你们各人所行的审判你们。你们当回头离开所犯的一切罪过。这样，罪孽必不使你们败亡。你们要将所犯的一切罪过尽行抛弃，自作一个新心和新灵。以色列家阿，你们何必死亡呢。主耶和华说，我不喜悦那死人之死，所以你们当回头而存活。 （以西结书 18:29-32）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What forms does God uses to present the law in these verses?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在这段经文中，神以何种形式显明律法？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What purpose（s） does God want to accomplish through the law in these verses?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在这段经文中，神要通过律法实现什么目的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第三课 福音神赐予我们的绝佳消息</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/205/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/205/4/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;a----the-great-truth-of-the-gospel-and-its-primary-meaning-福音的伟大真理及其根本意义&#34;&gt;A.    The Great Truth Of The Gospel And Its Primary Meaning 福音的伟大真理及其根本意义&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In His Word, God has revealed the two great truths of His law and gospel.  The gospel is a truth that contains very good news for people.  God&amp;rsquo;s gospel sends a specially beautiful, loving, generous and pleasing message to us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神在他的话语中向我们们显明福音与律法两大真理。福音为人类带来充满神的爱与丰盛、无比美好、令人欢欣鼓舞的信息。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The word “gospel” is a combination of two old English words “good” and “spell” that mean “good news.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“福音”是一个合成词，由古英语“好”和“消息”合二而一，意为“好消息”.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The primary word that is translated “gospel” in the Bible is the New Testament Greek word “euangelion.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;圣经中“福音”一词最初译自新约希腊语“euangelion”.“eu”意为“好”,“angelion”意为“信息”.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of the time, God uses the word “gospel” in a specific, primary sense to refer to “God&amp;rsquo;s loving work to save people from sins and give them eternal salvation and all its blessings through the redeeming work of Jesus Christ.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;多数情况下，神以“福音” 一词专指“神的爱，神拯救人于罪恶，赐予人类永恒的救恩，通过耶稣基督的救赎大业带给人祝福。”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When we speak about God&amp;rsquo;s teachings of law and gospel, we are using this specific, primary definition of the gospel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;当我们讲到关于神的律法与福音的教导时，我们就是在应用福音这一基本的、专门的定义。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b----the-revelation-of-the-gospel-福音的启示&#34;&gt;B.    The Revelation Of The Gospel 福音的启示&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has revealed the good news of His saving love in Jesus Christ only in His Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神只在他的话语里显明耶稣基督救恩的好消息。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Now to Him who is able to establish you by my gospel and the proclamation of Jesus Christ, according to the revelation of the mystery hidden for long ages past, but now revealed and made known through the prophetic writings by the command of the eternal God, so that all nations might believe and obey Him.” （Romans 16:25-26）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;惟有　神能照我所传的福音和所讲的耶稣基督，并照永古隐藏不言的奥秘，坚固你们的心。这奥秘如今显明出来，而且按着永生　神的命，藉众先知的书指示万国的民，使他们信服真道。（罗马书 16:25-26）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“From infancy you have known the holy Scriptures, which are able to make you wise for salvation through faith in Jesus Christ.” （2 Timothy 3:15）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;并且知道你是从小明白圣经；这圣经能使你因信基督耶稣，有得救的智慧。（提摩太后书 3:15）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;c----the-messages-of-the-gospel-福音信息&#34;&gt;C.    The Messages Of The Gospel 福音信息&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the gospel, God reveals His great giving and saving love for people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在福音中，神显明他赐予人类救恩的大爱。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He tells them He loves them and desires their salvation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神让人知道他的爱，希望他们得救。

“The Lord appeared to us in the past saying: &#39;I have loved you with an everlasting love; I have drawn you with loving kindness.‘” （Jeremiah 31:3）

古时（或作“从远方”）耶和华向以色列（原文作“我”）显现，说：“我以永远的爱爱你，因此我以慈爱吸引你。（耶利米书 31:3）

”This is good and pleases God our Savior who wants all men to be saved and to come to a knowledge of the truth.“ （1 Timothy 2:3-4）

这是好的，在　神我们救主面前可蒙悦纳。他愿意万人得救，明白真道。（提摩太前书 2:3-4）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He announces that His love has moved Him to send His Son Jesus Christ to save people and give them eternal life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神宣告，因着爱，他差遣他的儿子耶稣基督救赎人类并赐给他们永生。

”This is how God showed His love among us. He sent His one and only Son into the world that we might live through Him.“ （1 John 4:9）

神差他独生子到世间来，使我们藉着他得生，　神爱我们的心在此就显明了。（约翰壹书 4:9）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He declares that Jesus Christ has done everything that He requires and has paid everything that sinners owe to save all people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神宣告，耶稣基督已成就神所要求的一切，替罪人偿还了一切债务，拯救人类。

”But now He has appeared once for all at the end of the ages to do away with sin by the sacrifice of Himself. （Hebrews 9:26b）

但如今在这末世显现一次，把自己献为祭，好除掉罪。（希伯来书 9:26b）

“By that will we have been made holy through the sacrifice of the body of Jesus Christ once for all.” （Hebrews 10:10）

我们凭这旨意，靠耶稣基督只一次献上他的身体，就得以成圣。（希伯来书 10:10）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He assures people that He forgives all their sins because of what Jesus Christ has done for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神让人确信，他已因着耶稣基督为人类所成就的一切而宽恕了他们所有的罪。

In Him we have redemption through His blood, the forgiveness of sins, in accordance with the riches of God&#39;s grace that He lavished on us with all wisdom and understanding. （Ephesians 1:7）

我们藉这爱子的血，得蒙救赎，过犯得以赦免，乃是照他丰富的恩典。这恩典是　神用诸般智慧聪明，充充足足赏给我们的（以弗所书 1:7-8）

“The blood of Jesus Christ, His Son, purifies us from all sin.” （1 John 1:7b）

他儿子耶稣的血也洗净我们一切的罪。（约翰壹书 1:7b）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He announces that He grants sinners salvation freely out of His mercy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神宣告，因着他的怜悯，他无偿地将救恩赐给罪人。

“But when the kindness and love of God our Savior appeared, He saved us, not because of righteous things we had done, but because of His mercy.” （Titus 3:4-5）

（Titus 2:4-5）

但到了　神我们救主的恩慈和他向人所施的慈爱显明的时候，他便救了我们，并不是因我们自己所行的义，乃是照他的怜悯。（提多书 3:4-5）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He declares that He freely gives His blessings to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神宣告，他无偿地赐予他们祝福。

“To the praise of His glorious grace, which He freely gives us in the One He loves.” （Ephesians 1:6）

使他荣耀的恩典得着称赞；这恩典是他在爱子里所赐给我们的。（以弗所书 1:6）

“Praise the Lord, O my soul, and forget not all His benefits – who forgives all your sins and heals all your diseases, who redeems your life from the pit and crowns you with love and compassion, who satisfies your desires with good things . . . The Lord is compassionate and gracious, slow to anger, abounding in love…… He does not treat us as our sins deserve or repay us according to our iniquities.” （Psalm 103:2b-5a, 8, 10）

我的心哪！你要称颂耶和华，不可忘记他的一切恩惠。他赦免你的一切罪孽，医治你的一切疾病。他救赎你的命脱离死亡，以仁爱和慈悲为你的冠冕。他用美物，使你所愿的得以知足…… 耶和华有怜悯，有恩典，不轻易发怒，且有丰盛的慈爱…… 他没有按我们的罪过待我们，也没有照我们的罪孽报应我们。（诗篇103:2b-5a, 8, 10）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;d----the-forms-of-the-gospel-福音的形式&#34;&gt;D.    The Forms Of The Gospel 福音的形式&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God uses a variety of forms to deliver the true, love-filled message of the gospel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神以多种方式传达真实的、充满爱的福音信息。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God makes announcements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神发布通告。

“But the angel said to them, ”Do not be afraid. I bring you good news of great joy that will be for all the people. Today in the town of David a Savior has been born to you, He is Christ the Lord.“ （Luke 2:10-11）

那天使对他们说：”不要惧怕！我报给你们大喜的信息，是关乎万民的；因今天在大卫的城里，为你们生了救主，就是主基督。（路加福音 2:10-11）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God makes promises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神承诺。

“I tell you the truth, he who believes has everlasting life.” （John 6:47）

我实实在在地告诉你们，信的人有永生。（约翰福音 6:47）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God extends invitations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神广发邀请。

“Come to me, all you who are weary and burdened, and I will give you rest.” （Matthew 11:28）

凡劳苦担重担的人，可以到我这里来，我就使你们得安息。（马太福音 11:28）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God makes urgent pleas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神迫切恳求。

“Why will you die, O house of Israel?  For I take no pleasure in the death of anyone, declares the Sovereign Lord.  Repent and live!” （Ezekiel 18:31b-32）以色列家啊！你们何必死亡呢？主耶和华说：我不喜悦那死人之死，所以你们当回头而存活。“（以西结书 18:31b-32）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God speaks comforting messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神讲宽慰人的信息。

”Comfort, comfort, my people, says your God.   Speak tenderly to Jerusalem and proclaim to her that her hard service has been completed, that her sin has been paid for, that she has received from the Lord&#39;s hand double for all her sins.“  （Isaiah 40:1-2）

你们的　神说：”你们要安慰，安慰我的百姓。要对耶路撒冷说安慰的话，又向他宣告说，他争战的日子已满了，他的罪孽赦免了，他为自己的一切罪，从耶和华手中加倍受罚。“ （以赛亚书  40:1-2）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God offers encouragements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神鼓舞激励人。

Let us fix our eyes on Jesus, the author and perfecter of our faith, who for the joy set before Him endured the cross, scorning its shame, and sat down at the right hand of the throne of God.  Consider Him who endured such opposition from sinful men, so that you will not grow weary and lose heart.”  （Hebrews 12:2-3）

仰望为我们信心创始成终的耶稣（或作“仰望那将真道创始成终的耶稣”），他因那摆在前面的喜乐，就轻看羞辱，忍受了十字架的苦难，便坐在　神宝座的右边。那忍受罪人这样顶撞的，你们要思想，免得疲倦灰心。（希伯来书  12:2-3）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;e----the-purposes-of-the-gospel-福音的目的&#34;&gt;E.    The Purposes Of The Gospel 福音的目的&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a gift of His lavish love, God has given the gospel for a number of important reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;作为爱的礼物，神赐给人类福音有以下重要理由：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God gives the gospel to bring people to saving faith in Jesus Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神的福音使人信靠耶稣基督。

“If you confess with your mouth, ”Jesus is Lord,“ and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved. . .  Consequently, faith comes from hearing the message, and the message is heard through the word of Christ.”  （Romans 10:9, 17）

你若口里认耶稣为主，心里信　神叫他从死里复活，就必得救。 . . 可见信道是从听道来的，听道是从基督的话来的。（罗马书  10:9, 17）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God gives the gospel to make contrite sinners confident of salvation and eternal life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神的福音使悔过的罪人对救恩与永生充满信心。

“God chose you to be saved through the sanctifying work of the Spirit and through belief in the truth.  He called you to this through our gospel.” （2 Thessalonians 2:13b-14a）

因为他从起初拣选了你们，叫你们因信真道，又被圣灵感动，成为圣洁，能以得救。神藉我们所传的福音召你们到这地步。（帖撒罗尼迦后书   2:13b-14a）

“And this is the testimony that God has given us eternal life, and this life is in His Son.  He who has the Son has life; he who does not have the Son of God does not have life.  I write these things to you who believe in the name of the Son of God so that you may know that you have eternal life.”  （1 John 5:11-13）

这见证就是　神赐给我们永生，这永生也是在他儿子里面。人有了　神的儿子就有生命；没有　神的儿子就没有生命。我将这些话写给你们信奉　神儿子之名的人，要叫你们知道自己有永生。（约翰壹书  5:11-13）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God gives the gospel to give Christians the spiritual desire and strength to live a life of obedience to His law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神的福音使基督徒有意志力，渴望过遵从神的律法的生活。

“I have been crucified with Christ and I no longer live, but Christ lives in me.  The life I live in the body, I live by faith in the Son of God, who loved me and gave Himself for me.”  （Galatians 2:20）

我已经与基督同钉十字架，现在活着的，不再是我，乃是基督在我里面活着；并且我如今在肉身活着，是因信　神的儿子而活，他是爱我，为我舍己。（加拉太书  2:20）

“It is God who works in you to will and to act according to His good purpose.” （Philippians 2:13）

因为你们立志行事，都是　神在你们心里运行，为要成就他的美意。（腓力比书2:13）

“We love because He first loved us.”  （1 John 4:19）

我们爱，因为　神先爱我们。（约翰壹书  4:19）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;f----sinful-efforts-to-interfere-with-gods-purposes-in-the-gospel-人类的罪恶努力抵挡神实现福音的目的&#34;&gt;F.    Sinful Efforts To Interfere With God&amp;rsquo;s Purposes In The Gospel 人类的罪恶努力抵挡神实现福音的目的&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All people, by nature, are spiritually dead to God and are unable to understand and accept the gospel and are opposed to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;因着本性，人类天生与神隔绝——灵里的死亡。他们无法理解与接受福音，反而背离福音。

“As for you, you were dead in your transgressions and sins.”  （Ephesians 2:1）

你们死在过犯罪恶之中，他叫你们活过来。（以弗所书  2:1）

“The man without the Spirit does not accept the things that come from the Spirit of God, for they are foolishness to him, and he cannot understand them, because they are spiritually discerned.”  （1 Corinthians 2:14）

然而，属血气的人不领会　神圣灵的事，反倒以为愚拙，并且不能知道；因为这些事惟有属灵的人才能看透。（哥林多前书   2:14）

“For, as I have often told you before and now say again even with tears, many live as enemies of the cross of Christ.” （Philippians 3:18）

因为有许多人行事是基督十字架的仇敌。我屡次告诉你们，现在又流泪地告诉你们；（腓力比书  3:18）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In their opposition to God and His gospel, the sinful natures of people lead them to oppose the gospel in such ways as:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;人的罪性（罪恶天性）使人在以下方面背离福音：

a.     Rejecting the gospel as an unimpressive, repulsive and foolish message.

拒绝福音，把福音当作无聊、愚昧、令人厌烦的信息。

“Jews demand miraculous signs and Greeks look for wisdom, but we preach Christ crucified: a stumbling block to Jews and foolishness to Gentiles.”  （1 Corinthians 1:22-23）

犹太人是要神迹，希腊人是求智慧；我们却是传钉十字架的基督，在犹太人为绊脚石，在外邦人为愚拙；（哥林多前书  1:22-23）

b.    Adding law conditions to the gospel.

给福音附加律法条件。

“Since you died with Christ to the basic principles of the world, why, as though you still belonged to it, do you submit to its rules: ”Do not handle!  Do not taste!  Do not touch!  These are all destined to perish with use, because they are based on human commands and teachings.“  （Colossians 2:20-22）

你们若是与基督同死，脱离了世上的小学，为什么仍象在世俗中活着，服从那”不可拿、不可尝、不可摸“等类的规条呢？这都是照人所吩咐、所教导的。说到这一切，正用的时候就都败坏了。（歌罗西书 2:20-22）

c.    Rejecting and attacking the Bible&#39;s teaching about the person and work of Jesus Christ.

拒绝、攻击圣经中关于耶稣生平事迹的教导。

”They will secretly introduce destructive heresies, even denying the sovereign Lord who bought them – bringing swift destruction on themselves.“  （2 Peter 2:1b）

自引进陷害人的异端，连买他们的主他们也不承认，自取速速的灭亡。（彼得后书  2:1b）

”Every spirit that does not acknowledge Jesus is not from God.  This is the spirit of the antichrist, which you have heard is coming and even now is already in the world.“ （1 John 4:3）

凡灵不认耶稣，就不是出于　神，这是那敌基督者的灵。你们从前听见他要来，现在已经在世上了。（约翰一书  4:3）

d.    Inventing and promoting false gospels.

自行发明与推销伪福音。

”I am astonished that you are so quickly deserting the one who called you by the grace of Christ and are turning to a different gospel – which is really no gospel at all.“  （Galatians 1:6-7a）

我希奇你们这么快离开那藉着基督之恩召你们的，去从别的福音–那并不是福音，（加拉太书   1:6-7a）

e.     Asserting that the gospel is divine permission to continue in sin.

把福音当作继续犯罪的神圣许可证。

”They are godless men who change the grace of God into a license for immorality and deny Jesus Christ our only Sovereign and Lord.“  （Jude 4）

因为有些人偷着进来，将我们　神的恩变作放纵情欲的机会，并且不认独一的主宰我们（”我们“或作”和我们“）主耶稣基督。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-review-the-lesson-本课回顾&#34;&gt;I. Review The Lesson 本课回顾&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-fill-the-blank-填空&#34;&gt;1. Fill the blank 填空&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We call the gospel, God&amp;rsquo;s extremely &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; news for us because its message is  beautiful,  loving, generous, and &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; to us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;我们把福音称作-------------,因为福音是无比美好、充满神的爱与丰盛和-------------的信息。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The English word ”gospel“ comes from two old English words that mean ”&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;   &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;.“&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;英语”福音“一词来自两个古英语：”--------  “和”--------  “.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The specific, primary meaning of God&amp;rsquo;s gospel is ”God&amp;rsquo;s loving work to save people from their &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; and to give them eternal &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; and all its blessings through Jesus Christ.“&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神的福音专指”神的爱，神拯救人于-----------,赐予人类永恒的-----------,通过耶稣基督的救赎大业带给人祝福。“
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God has revealed and recorded the gospel for us only in the &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神只在-----------中为我们显明与记录福音。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the gospel, God tells us that He &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; us and has sent Jesus Christ to do &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; necessary to save us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神在福音中告诉我们，因着---------,他差遣他的儿子耶稣基督来成就神所---------------,拯救人类。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the Gospel God assures us that He &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; all our sins and gives us His blessings &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; through the saving work of Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;在福音中，神让我们确信，他已----------了我们所有的罪，并通过基督的救赎大业将他的祝福-----------地赐给我们。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God delivers the message of the gospel to us in the forms of announcements, &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;, invitations, and urgent pleas.  He also speaks comforting and encouraging &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; to us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神以通告、-----------、邀请与迫切恳求的形式向我们传达福音，并讲宽慰与鼓舞激励人的----------.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God gives us the gospel so that He can create and strengthen saving &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; in Christ in our hearts and make contrite &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; confident of their &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神的福音使人在内心----------耶稣基督。神的福音让真心悔过的-----------对---------------充满信心。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God give us the gospel also so that he can give believers the desire and &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; they need to live a life of &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- to His law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神的福音使基督徒有-----------,渴望过-----------神的律法的生活。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God seeks to overcome the natural &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; to His gospel that comes from the sinful hearts of people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;人类的罪性使人天生/本能地-----------福音。神会胜过人类的这一罪恶努力。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-analyze-these-scripture-verses-经文分析&#34;&gt;2. Analyze These Scripture Verses 经文分析&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said to her, &amp;lsquo;I am the resurrection and the life.  He who believes in Me will live, even though he dies; and whoever lives and believes in Me will never die.  Do you believe this? （John 11:25-26）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;耶稣对她说：”复活在我，生命也在我，信我的人，虽然死了，也必复活。凡活着信我的人，必永远不死。你信这话吗？“ （约翰福音  11:25-26）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What forms does God uses to present the gospel in these verses?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在这段经文中，神以何种形式显明福音？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What purpose（s） does God want to accomplish through the gospel in these verses?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在这段经文中，神要通过福音实现什么目的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最后更新于 2014年2月22日 星期六 11:39&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第四课 福音在神的话语与圣礼中 神的恩典的传达方式</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/205/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/205/5/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;a----gods-gospel-delivery-system-福音的传达系统&#34;&gt;A.    God&amp;rsquo;s Gospel Delivery System 福音的传达系统&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In His great love for sinful people, God has not only sent Jesus Christ to fulfill the holy demands of the law and pay the full penalty of sin for all.  He has also developed special ways through which He imparts this “good news” to people and give them the wonderful benefits of Jesus&amp;rsquo; redeeming work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;因着神伟大的爱，他不仅差遣耶稣基督来实现律法的神圣要求，为人类罪有应得的惩罚付上完全的代价，而且以特殊的方式向人类传达这个“好消息”,传递耶稣的救赎带给人类的奇妙祝福。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God causes the gospel to come to people in the forms of the Word （as it is read, heard, or remembered） and the two Sacraments （Holy Baptism and Holy Communion）。  We call the Gospel as it comes in the form of the Word and Sacraments “the means or paths of God&amp;rsquo;s grace” because they are the ways or routes by which God brings His saving grace in Jesus Christ into our lives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神以话语的形式（读经、听道、记忆）和圣礼的形式（圣洗礼与圣餐）将福音传达给人类。我们将神的话语与圣洗礼称为“神的恩典的传达方式或途径。”通过这两个途径，神把他在耶稣基督里救赎的恩典带入我们的生活。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Holy Spirit works through the Gospel in these forms to bring people to and preserve and strengthen them in saving faith in Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;圣灵通过这样的形式在人的心里做福音的工作，带领人归向耶稣，保守坚固在耶稣基督里的信心。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b----the-gospel-in-gods-word-神话语中的福音信息&#34;&gt;B.    The Gospel In God&amp;rsquo;s Word 神话语中的福音信息&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has the Gospel come to people through His Word in several ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神通过他的话语使福音临到人类，有以下几种方式：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gospel comes in the spoken Word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;传讲话语的方式

“Now brothers I want to remind you of the gospel I preached to you, which you received and on which you have taken your stand.”  （1 Corinthians 15:1）

“弟兄们，我如今把先前所传给你们的福音，告诉你们知道；这福音你们也领受了，又靠着站立得住；”（ 哥林多前书15:1）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gospel comes in the written Word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;书面话语的方式

“But these are written that you may believe that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of God, and that by believing you may have life in His name.”  （John 20:31）

“但记这些事，要叫你们信耶稣是基督，是　神的儿子，并且叫你们信了他，就可以因他的名得生命。” （约翰福音  20:31）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gospel comes in the learned and remembered Word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;学习与记忆的方式

“But as for you, continue in what you have learned and have become convinced of, because you know those from whom you learned it, and how from infancy you have known the holy Scriptures, which are able to make you wise for salvation through faith in Christ Jesus.”  （2 Timothy 3:14-15）

“但你所学习的，所确信的，要存在心里；因为你知道是跟谁学的，并且知道你是从小明白圣经；这圣经能使你因信基督耶稣，有得救的智慧。”  （提摩太后书 3:14-15）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;c----the-sacraments-圣礼&#34;&gt;C.    The Sacraments 圣礼&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has the Gospel come to people through the Sacraments of Baptism and Communion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神通过圣礼——圣洗礼与圣餐使福音临到人类。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The word “sacrament” comes from the Latin word “sacramentum,” which means “a solemn, sacred pledge.”  In the sacraments, God is the One who makes a solemn, sacred pledge to bless people because of Jesus Christ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;“圣礼”一词源自拉丁语“sacramentum”,意为“一个庄严神圣的誓约”.因耶稣基督，神在圣礼中以庄严神圣的誓约祝福人们。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We define a sacrament as:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;我们把圣礼定义为：

a.     A sacred act – in which God is at work, giving something to us;

神在一个庄严神圣的仪式上做工，赐予；

b.    Instituted by Jesus Christ – established and commanded by Jesus for us to do;

由耶稣基督确立、命令我们举行的仪式；

c.    Which uses earthly elements – physical substances （water, bread, wine）；

使用世上的物质（水，饼、酒）；

d.    Connected with God&#39;s Word – which gives the sacraments their power;

与神的话语相连接，被赋予神的能力；

e.    through which God offers, gives and assures forgiveness of sins, eternal life and salvation.

神以此形式提供、给予、让我们确信罪得赦免，永生与救恩。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sacraments are not empty symbols, sacrifices offered to God or church ceremonies.  They are Gospel instruments by which God actually gives His spiritual blessings to people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;圣礼不是空泛的象征，也不是向神献祭或教会的典礼，而是福音传递的方式，由神实实在在地赐予人们属灵的祝福。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;d----the-gospel-in-baptism-圣洗礼中的福音&#34;&gt;D.    The Gospel In Baptism 圣洗礼中的福音&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus Christ instituted Baptism as part of His “Great Commission” to the Church to reach all people just before His ascension.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;耶稣基督在升天之前将圣洗礼作为 “大使命”的一部分赋予教会，让他们将此祝福送达万民。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Baptism, a person receives the application of God&amp;rsquo;s Word and water for their blessing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;在圣洗礼中，一个人收到的是来自神的话语及水的祝福。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Baptism, God gives the following Gospel blessings to people:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;在圣洗礼中，神赐予人以下祝福：

a.     God lovingly claims a person to be His disciple and enjoy His spiritual favor.

神宣告一个人成为他的门徒，享有他赐予的属灵的恩惠。

“Go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit.”  （Matthew 28:19）

“所以，你们要去使万民作我的门徒，奉父子圣灵的名，给他们施洗”  （马太福音 28:19）

b.    God brings spiritually separated people into spiritual union with Christ and makes them God&#39;s children.

神让他所拣选的人在灵里与基督合为一体，使他们成为神的儿女。

“You are all sons of God through faith in Christ Jesus, for all of you who were baptized into Christ have been clothes with Christ.” （Galatians 3:26-27）

“所以，你们因信基督耶稣，都是　神的儿子。你们受洗归入基督的，都是披戴基督了。” （加拉太书  3:26-27）

c.    God grants them the forgiveness of sins and the Holy Spirit.

神恩准他们罪得赦免，赐予他们圣灵。

“Peter replied, &#39;Repent and be baptized everyone of you, in the name of Jesus Christ for the forgiveness of your sins.  And you will receive the gift of the Holy Spirit.‘” （Acts 2:38）

“彼得说：’你们各人要悔改，奉耶稣基督的名受洗，叫你们的罪得赦，就必领受所赐的圣灵；‘” （使徒行传2:38）

d.    God saves people and spiritually cleanses them.

神拯救人，使他们灵里洁净。

“And this water symbolizes baptism that now saves you also – not the removal of dirt from the body, but the pledge of a good conscience toward God.  It saves you by the resurrection of Jesus Christ.”  （1 Peter 3:21）

“这水所表明的洗礼，现在藉着耶稣基督复活也拯救你们；这洗礼本不在乎除掉肉体的污秽，只求在　神面前有无亏的良心。”  （彼得前书  3:21）

e.     God creates new spiritual life and gives a place in God&#39;s kingdom.

神为他们建造全新的属灵生命，将神的国度赐予他们。

“Jesus answered, &#39;I tell you the truth, no one can enter the kingdom of God unless he is born of water and the Spirit.’” （John 3:5）

“耶稣说：‘我实实在在地告诉你，人若不是从水和圣灵生的，就不能进　神的国。’”（约翰福音  3:5）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;e----the-gospel-in-communion-the-lords-supper-圣餐中的福音&#34;&gt;E.    The Gospel In Communion, The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Supper 圣餐中的福音&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus instituted Holy Communion at a Passover meal on the night before He died on the cross.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;耶稣在临刑（死于十字架）前的那个逾越节的夜晚设立了圣餐礼。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Holy Communion, a person receives the earthly elements of bread and wine along with the spiritual elements of the true body and blood of Christ.  （The Real Presence）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;在圣餐礼上，一个人接受的是世间的物质——饼和酒，与属灵的赐予——基督真实的身体与血。（真实的同在）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Communion, God gives the following Gospel blessings to people:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;在圣餐礼上，神赐予人以下的福音祝福：

a.     God gives the forgiveness of sins.

神使人罪得赦免。

“While they were eating, Jesus took bread, gave thanks and broke it, and gave it to His disciples, saying, &#39;Take and eat; this is my body.”  Then He took the cup, gave thanks and offered it to them, saying, &#39;Drink from it, all of you.  This is my blood of the covenant, which is poured out for many for the forgiveness of sins.“  （Matthew 26:26-28）

”他们吃的时候，耶稣拿起饼来，祝福，就掰开，递给门徒，说：‘你们拿着吃，这是我的身体。’又拿起杯来，祝谢了，递给他们，说：‘你们都喝这个，因为这是我立约的血，为多人流出来，使罪得赦。’“（马太福音26:26-28）

b.    Jesus gives the blessings of God&#39;s new covenant （solemn agreement）： forgiveness for all sins and intimate fellowship with Him.

耶稣赐下神新约的祝福，那就是饶恕世人所有的罪，与神建立亲密的关系。

”This cup is the new covenant in my blood, which is poured out for you.“   （Luke 22:20b）

”这杯是用我血所立的新约，是为你们流出来的。 “（路加福音  22:20b）

”The time is coming, declares the Lord, when I will make a new covenant with the house of Israel and with the house of Judah. . . This is the covenant I will make with the house of Israel after that time, declares the Lord.  No longer will a man teach his neighbor, or a man his brother, saying, &#39;Know the Lord,&#39; because they will all know Me, from the least of them to the greatest.  For I will forgive their wickedness and will remember their sins no more.“  （Hebrews 8;8b, 10a, 11-12）

”日子将到，我要与以色列家和犹大家另立新约。 . . 主又说：“那些日子以后，我与以色列家所立的约乃是这样：…他们不用各人教导自己的乡邻和自己的弟兄，说：‘你该认识主；’因为他们从最小的到至大的，都必认识我。我要宽恕他们的不义，不再记念他们的罪愆。”  （希伯来书  8;8b, 10a, 11-12）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God intends that believing, instructed, and prepared Christians received Communion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神要基督徒首先相信并真正懂得圣餐礼的意义、真正预备好他们的心，再来接受圣餐。

“A man ought to examine himself before he eats of the bread and drinks of the cup.  For anyone who eats and drinks without recognizing the body of the Lord eats and drinks judgment on himself.”  （1 Corinthians 11:28-29）

“人应当自己省察，然后吃这饼、喝这杯。因为人吃喝，若不分辨是主的身体，就是吃喝自己的罪了。（哥林多前书  11:28-29）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;f----review-the-lesson-本课回顾&#34;&gt;F.    Review The Lesson 本课回顾&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-agree-and-disagree-statements-判断题&#34;&gt;1. Agree And Disagree Statements 判断题&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark each statement A （agree） or D （disagree）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;正确的划”V“,错误的划”X“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 1.   Both the law and the gospel are imparted to us through God&amp;rsquo;s ”means of grace.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 律法与福音通过神恩典的传递方式传授给我们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 2.   Without God&amp;rsquo;s delivery system of the means of grace, Jesus&amp;rsquo; redeeming work would be of no help to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 没有神的恩典传递系统，耶稣的救赎大业便无助于我们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 3.   The Holy Spirit regularly brings unbelievers to faith by directly reaching their hearts apart from the gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 对于那些远离福音的非信徒，圣灵会直接触及他们的心，将他们带回到信心中。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 4.   A person can be spiritually strengthened by the gospel, even if he/she has not heard it or read it for some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 一个人可以靠着福音在灵里得坚固，即使他们有一段时间未曾聆听或阅读福音信息。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 5.   In the administration of the sacraments, God solemnly pledges to bless us and we gratefully pledge to serve and obey God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 在圣礼中，神庄严地应许赐福予我们；我们满怀感恩地起誓服事、顺从神。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 6.   It is God&amp;rsquo;s Word of the gospel that gives the sacraments their power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神福音的话语赐予圣礼权能。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 7.   God wants everyone to be baptized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神要万民受洗。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 8.   The body and blood of Jesus are powerfully symbolized, but not actually present, with bread and wine in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Supper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 在圣餐中，饼与酒强有力地象征了耶稣的身体与血，却没有耶稣真实的同在。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 9.   The blessings of God&amp;rsquo;s new covenant include the forgiveness of all our sins and intimate fellowship with God Himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神新约的祝福包括罪得赦免和与神建立亲密的关系。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 10.  God invites all people to partake of Holy Communion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神邀请所有的人都来领受圣餐。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-reflection-questions-思考题&#34;&gt;2. Reflection Questions 思考题&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Christian emperor, who lived centuries ago, once said: ”The three handfuls of water poured over my head in baptism are worth more to me than the crown that sits on my head.“  What did he mean by that comment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;几个世纪前有一位基督徒皇帝曾经说：”洗礼仪式中浇在我头上的三捧水，比我头上的皇冠更宝贵。“他这样的评价有什么含义？
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is it important for us to prepare carefully for the reception of Holy Communion?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;为领受圣餐而慎重地预备好我们的身心为什么很重要？
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最后更新于 2013年3月23日 星期六 10:04&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第五课 律法与福音促成罪人的转变</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/205/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/205/6/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;a----gods-teachings-of-law-and-gospel-work-together-to-convert-people-to-saving-faith-in-jesus--christ-神律法与福音的教导共同作用使人转而相信耶稣基督&#34;&gt;A.    God&amp;rsquo;s Teachings Of Law And Gospel Work Together To Convert People To Saving Faith In Jesus  Christ 神律法与福音的教导共同作用，使人转而相信耶稣基督&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God uses His two great truths of law and gospel to work in harmony to accomplish the great miracle of bringing sinful people to a saving faith in Jesus Christ in which they enjoy the forgiveness of their sins and the gift of eternal life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神使律法与福音两大真理和谐运作，一同完成转变罪人的人间奇迹。在耶稣基督里的信心令他们尽情享受罪得赦免的喜悦与永生的礼物。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both the law and gospel play important, but different and complementary, roles in accomplishing the conversion of unbelieving sinners into believing Christians.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;在转变罪人的过程中，律法与福音具有同等重要的地位、各不相同的角色，二者相辅相成。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s Holy Spirit works through the law to terrify the hearts of people who are naturally sinful, hostile and spiritually dead to God.   Through the law, the Holy Spirit leads people to realize that they are spiritually lost and guilty of great sins against God.  The Spirit also leads them to dread God&amp;rsquo;s fierce punishment and to desire His help to deliver them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神的圣灵通过律法来震慑罪人的心，使他们意识到自己灵魂的迷失，意识到他们天然的罪性，他们悖逆神，与神隔绝。圣灵且引导他们敬畏神，渴求神的帮助与救赎。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s Holy Spirit works through the gospel to comfort the hearts of people who are made contrite through the law and to make them confident that God has saved them by His grace in Jesus Christ.   The Spirit assures them that God has forgiven them all their sins, accepts them as His dear children and assures them of everlasting life with Him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神的圣灵通过福音来抚慰罪人的心，使那些因律法而知罪悔过的人坚信，靠着神在耶稣基督里的恩典，他们已得救赎。圣灵使罪人确信神已赦免了他们所有的罪过，并接纳他们为自己的儿女，与神同享永生。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b----the-law-leads-sinners-to-the-point-of-genuine-sorrow-over-their-sins-and-despair-over-gods-punishment-神的律法使罪人真诚悔过并且惧怕神的惩罚&#34;&gt;B.    The Law Leads Sinners To The Point Of Genuine Sorrow Over Their Sins And Despair Over God&amp;rsquo;s Punishment 神的律法使罪人真诚悔过并且惧怕神的惩罚&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the Holy Spirit&amp;rsquo;s blessing, the law does a number of things to create sinners who are contrite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;蒙圣灵的祝福，律法多方引导罪人悔过。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The law teaches people that God requires them to live an absolutely perfect life in which they obey all His moral commands whole-heartedly, completely, all the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;律法教导人，神要求他们过绝对完美的生活，全心全意、完美无缺、时时刻刻遵行他全部的道德例律。

You must obey my laws and be careful to follow my decrees.  I am the Lord your God.  Be holy because I, the Lord your God am holy. Keep all my decrees and all my laws and follow them.  （Leviticus 18:4; 19:2, 37）

你们要遵我的典章，守我的律例，按此而行。我是耶和华你们的　神。“你晓谕以色列全会众说：你们要圣洁，因为我耶和华你们的　神是圣洁的。（利未记 18:4; 19:2, 37）

I am the Lord. Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your strength.  （Deuteronomy 6:5）

你要尽心、尽性、尽力爱耶和华你的　神。（申命记 6:5）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The law declares to people that they and all others have failed to live the absolutely perfect life that God requires of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;律法宣告，所有的人都没有达到神对他们的要求——过绝对完美的生活。

There is no one righteous, not even one; there is no one who understands, no one who seeks God.  All have turned away and become worthless; there is no one who does good, not even one.  No one will be declared righteous in His sight by observing the law.   （Romans 3:11, 12, 20a）

没有明白的，没有寻求　神的；都是偏离正路，一同变为无用；没有行善的，连一个也没有。所以凡有血气的，没有一个因行律法能在　神面前称义。（罗马书 3:11, 12, 20a）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The law announces to people that they are guilty of sin against God and deserving of His eternal punishment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;律法宣布，人们犯罪悖逆神，应受神永恒的惩罚。

All have sinned and fall short of the glory of God.  （Romans 3:23）

因为世人都犯了罪，亏缺了　神的荣耀；（罗马书3:23）

The wages of sin is death. （Romans 6:23a）

因为罪的工价乃是死；惟有　神的恩赐，在我们的主基督耶稣里，乃是永生。（罗马书6:23a）

Depart from me, you who are cursed into the eternal fire prepared for the devil and his angels. （Matthew 25:41）

王又要向那左边的说：‘你们这被咒诅的人，离开我！进入那为魔鬼和他的使者所预备的永火里去！（马太福音25:41）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The law extends God&amp;rsquo;s call to people to admit their sin and turn to Him for help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;律法将神对众人的呼召延伸扩展，使他们悔改，转向神寻求帮助。

Repent!  Turn away from all your offenses; then sin will not be your downfall.  Rid yourselves of all the offenses you have committed, and get a new heart and a new spirit.  Why will you die?  For I take no pleasure in the death of anyone, declares the Sovereign Lord.  Repent and live! （Ezekiel 18 30b-32）

你们当回头离开所犯的一切罪过；这样，罪孽必不使你们败亡。你们要将所犯的一切罪过，尽行抛弃，自作一个新心和新灵。以色列家啊！你们何必死亡呢？主耶和华说：我不喜悦那死人之死，所以你们当回头而存活。” （以西结书18:30b-32）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The law leads people to sincerely regret their sins and to seek God&amp;rsquo;s mercy to save them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;律法引导人们衷心悔过，寻求神的怜悯与救赎。

Have mercy on me, O God, according to Your unfailing love; according to Your great compassion blot out my transgressions.  Wash away all my iniquity and cleanse me from my sin.  For I know my transgressions; and my sin is always before me.  Against you, you only, have I sinned and done what is evil in your sight. Hide Your face from my sins and blot out all my iniquity （Psalm 51:1-4a, 9）

神啊！求你按你的慈爱怜恤我，按你丰盛的慈悲涂抹我的过犯。求你将我的罪孽洗除净尽，并洁除我的罪。因为我知道我的过犯，我的罪常在我面前。我向你犯罪，惟独得罪了你，在你眼前行了这恶；求你掩面不看我的罪，涂抹我一切的罪孽。（诗篇51:1-4a, 9）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;c----the-gospel-leads-contrite-sinners-to-believe-in-jesus-christ-as-their-savior-from-sin-and-eternal-death&#34;&gt;C.    The Gospel Leads Contrite Sinners To Believe In Jesus Christ As Their Savior From Sin And Eternal Death&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;福音带领悔过的罪人相信耶稣基督为他们的救主，救他们脱离罪恶与永恒的死亡&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the Holy Spirit&amp;rsquo;s blessing, the gospel does a number of things to create believing Christians out of contrite sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;蒙圣灵的祝福，福音多方引导悔过的罪人信靠耶稣基督。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gospel teaches people that God loves sinners apart from their deserving and graciously desires to deliver them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;福音教导人们，神爱一切不配得此厚爱的罪人，神以宽容与仁慈救助罪人。

With everlasting kindness I will have compassion on you, says the Lord your Redeemer. （Isaiah 54:8b）

要以永远的慈爱怜恤你。这是耶和华你的救赎主说的。（以赛亚书54:8b）

The Lord, the Lord, is the compassionate and gracious God, slow to anger, abounding in love and faithfulness, maintaining love to thousands, and forgiving wickedness, rebellion and sin. （Exodus 34:6b-7a）

耶和华，耶和华，是有怜悯有恩典的　神，不轻易发怒，并有丰盛的慈爱和诚实。为千万人存留慈爱，赦免罪孽、过犯和罪恶；（出埃及记34:6b-7a）

Turn to Me and be saved, all you ends of the earth; for I am God, and there is no other. （Isaiah 45:22）

地极的人都当仰望我，就必得救；因为我是　神，再没有别神。（以赛亚书45:22）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gospel announces that Jesus Christ has come to save them by living a perfect life of obedience to God&amp;rsquo;s laws for them and dying on the cross to pay for their sins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;福音宣布，耶稣基督降世拯救罪人，他全然顺服神的律法，活出完美无瑕的生命，在十字架上受难，为世人的罪付清赎价。

But when the time had fully come God sent His Son, born of a woman, born under law, to redeem those under law, that we might receive the full rights of sons.  （Galatians 4:4-5）

及至时候满足，　神就差遣他的儿子为女子所生，且生在律法以下，要把律法以下的人赎出来，叫我们得着儿子的名分。（加拉太书4:4-5）

Do not think that I have come to abolish the Law and Prophets; I have not come to abolish them, but to fulfill them. （Matthew 5:17）

莫想我来要废掉律法和先知；我来不是要废掉，乃是要成全。（马太福音5:17）

You see, at just the right time, when we were still powerless, Christ died for the ungodly.  While we were still sinners, Christ died for us. （Romans 5:6,9）

因我们还软弱的时候，基督就按所定的日期为罪人死。惟有基督在我们还作罪人的时候为我们死， （Romans 5:6,8b）

Christ died for our sins. （1 Corinthians 15:3b）

就是基督照圣经所说，为我们的罪死了。 （ 哥林多前书15:3b）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gospel relates that God justifies all sinners, that is, He declares all people in the world to be innocent of their sin and righteous in His sight because of Jesus&amp;rsquo; ransoming work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;福音与神的赦免相联系——神宣告世人无罪，在他的眼中成为公义，完全是因着耶稣基督的救赎大业。

Jesus is the atoning sacrifice for our sins, and not only for ours, but also for the sins of the whole world.  （1 John 2:2）

他为我们的罪作了挽回祭，不是单为我们的罪，也是为普天下人的罪。（约翰一书2:2）

All are justified freely by His grace through the redemption that came by Christ Jesus.  （Romans 3:24）

如今却蒙　神的恩典，因基督耶稣的救赎，就白白地称义。（罗马书3:24）

The result of one act of righteousness was justification that brings life for all men.  （Romans 5:18b）

因一次的义行，众人也就被称义得生命了。（罗马书5:18b）

The blood of Jesus, His Son, purifies us from all sin. （1 John 1:7b）

他儿子耶稣的血也洗净我们一切的罪。（约翰一书 1:7b）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gospel extends the invitation to people that they receive God&amp;rsquo;s free gift of forgiveness and salvation by faith in Jesus Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;福音广发邀请，人们凭着在耶稣基督里的信心无偿地得到神赐予的罪得宽恕与救恩的礼物。

Seek the Lord while He may be found; call on Him while He is near.  Let the wicked forsake his way and the evil man his thoughts,  Let him turn to the Lord, and He will have mercy on him, and to our God, for He will freely pardon. （Isaiah 55:6-7）

当趁耶和华可寻找的时候寻找他，相近的时候求告他。恶人当离弃自己的道路，不义的人当除掉自己的意念。归向耶和华，耶和华就必怜恤他；当归向我们的　神，因为　神必广行赦免。（以赛亚书55:6-7）

Believe in the Lord Jesus and you will be saved. （Acts 16:31）

当信主耶稣，你和你一家都必得救。（使徒行传16:31）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gospel itself creates faith so a person believes in Jesus as his/her Savior and receives God&amp;rsquo;s gift of pardon and new life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;福音本身建造信心，一个相信耶稣为救主的人会得到神的宽恕与新生命。

Our gospel came to you not simply with words, but also with power, with the Holy Spirit and with deep conviction.  （1 Thessalonians 1:5a）

我们的福音传到你们那里，不独在乎言语，也在乎权能和圣灵，并充足的信心。（帖撒罗尼迦前书 1:5a）

No one can say, “Jesus is Lord” except by the Holy Spirit.  （1 Corinthians 12:3b）

若不是被圣灵感动的，也没有能说耶稣是主的。（哥林多前书  12:3b）

For it is by grace you have been saved through faith – and this not from yourselves, it is the gift of God, not by works, so that no one can boast. （Ephesians 2:8-9）

你们得救是本乎恩，也因着信，这并不是出于自己，乃是　神所赐的；也不是出于行为，免得有人自夸。（以弗所书2:8-9）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;d----the-law-and-gospel-work-to-produce-a-proper-cautious-yet-confident-assurance-of-salvation-in-the-christian&#34;&gt;D.    The Law And Gospel Work To Produce A Proper “Cautious-Yet-Confident” Assurance Of Salvation In The Christian&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;律法与福音使人 “谨慎却又自信”,确信基督的救恩&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God uses His powerful teachings of the law and gospel not only to bring people to saving faith in Christ.  He also uses them to keep people in saving faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神运用律法与福音独具权能的教导带领人们相信基督，并且使他们信心坚固持久。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You through faith are shielded by God&amp;rsquo;s power until the coming of the salvation that is ready to be revealed in the last time. （1 Peter 1:5）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你们这因信蒙　神能力保守的人，必能得着所预备，到末世要显现的救恩。（彼得前书 1:5）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because Christians have both a sinful nature that strives to lead them to fall away from Christ and a believing nature that trustingly clings to Christ, they need both the law and the gospel to remain in faith.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;在基督徒的身心当中，罪性（罪恶天性）与新生命共存。罪性力图引诱他们背离基督；新生命使他们一心信靠追随基督。因而他们需要律法与福音共同作用，以保守他们的信心。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God uses the strong warnings of the law to speak to the sinful natures of Christians so that they do not become proud or careless and fall from faith.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神以律法向基督徒的罪性发出严正警告，使他们远离傲慢与不洁，保守他们的信心。

So, if you think you are standing firm, be careful that you don&#39;t fall! （1 Corinthians 10:12）

所以，自己以为站得稳的，须要谨慎，免得跌倒。（哥林多前书 10:12）

We must pay more careful attention, therefore, to what we have heard, so that we do not drift away. （Hebrews 2:1）

所以，我们当越发郑重所听见的道理，恐怕我们随流失去。（希伯来书 2:1）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God uses the comforting promises of the gospel to speak to the believing natures of Christians so that they do not despair over their sinful weakness, but cling in faith to Jesus for salvation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神以福音安慰的应许看顾保守基督徒的新生命，驱散他们的绝望与软弱，让他们靠着耶稣得救恩。

I give them eternal life, and they shall never perish.  No one can snatch them out of My hand.  My Father, who has given them to Me, is greater than all; no one can snatch them out of My Father&#39;s hand.  （John 10:28-29）

我又赐给他们永生；他们永不灭亡，谁也不能从我手里把他们夺去。我父把羊赐给我，他比万有都大，谁也不能从我父手里把他们夺去。（约翰福音10:28-29）

Being confident of this, that He who began a good work in you, will carry it on to completion until the day of Christ Jesus.  （Philippians 1:6）

我深信那在你们心里动了善工的，必成全这工，直到耶稣基督的日子。（腓利比书 1:6）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christians are confident of their salvation because of God&amp;rsquo;s gospel promises in Christ.  Yet they are cautious and guard against the efforts of the sinful nature to cause them to fall away from faith in Jesus and lose their salvation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;因着神在福音中的应许，基督徒对自己必得神的救恩充满自信。然而他们也时刻谨慎警惕，严防罪性引诱他们丧失对耶稣基督的信心从而失去神的救恩。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;e----review-the-lesson-本课回顾&#34;&gt;E.    Review The Lesson 本课回顾&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;agree-and-disagree-statements-判断题&#34;&gt;Agree And Disagree Statements 判断题&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark each statement A （agree） or D （disagree）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;正确的划“V”,错误的划“X”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 1.   A person can follow either the teaching of the law or the gospel to gain salvation from sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 一个人可以靠着或者律法或者福音二者中的任何一项教导而得救恩。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 2.   Before God can make people certain of their salvation, He must make them certain of their damnation,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神在使人确信自己必得救恩之前，先使他们懂得自己因着罪而必遭毁灭的事实。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 3.   In the law God tells us that we must live a very good life, a life that is far better than the average person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神在律法中告诉我们，必须过一个远高于常人标准的美好生活。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 4.   The law delivers to us the devastating message that we are spiritual failures who are lost and doomed because of our sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 律法向我们传达严酷的信息：我们是属灵的败亡者，因着罪，我们失丧遭毁灭。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 5.   Through the message of the law, God encourages us to keep fighting to earn our salvation by striving to keep His commandments better than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神通过律法鼓励我们靠着不断努力遵行他的诫命，艰苦奋斗来赢得他赐予我们的救恩。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 6.   In the gospel God announces the pleasing message that He loves us because we are such good and loving beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神在福音中宣告他对我们的爱，是因为我们美善而可爱。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 7.   The central message of the gospel is that Jesus Christ has won salvation for us by His perfectly obedient life and sin-removing death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 福音的中心信息是，耶稣基督在世上活出完全顺服的生命，替我们的罪受死，从而为我们赢得神的救恩。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 8.   In the gospel, God not only invites us to believe in Jesus, but He also creates faith in us so we do believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 在福音中，神不仅鼓励带领我们相信耶稣，而且为我们建立、坚固这样的信心。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 9.   A person who has come to saving faith in Jesus never has to worry about losing that faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 一个相信耶稣的人再不用担心自己会丧失这样的信心。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 10.  God graciously brings us to faith in Jesus, but after that, it is entirely up to us to continue in that faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神带领我们相信耶稣基督，从此以后全靠我们自己去保守这样的信心。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reflection-questions-思考题&#34;&gt;Reflection Questions 思考题&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What things must a person know and believe in order to have eternal life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;一个人必须知道并相信什么，才能享有永生？
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A believer once said: “I believe that I am saved by works, but not by my own works.”  What do you think he meant by that statement?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一个基督徒说：“我相信我是靠行为而得救，但并非我个人的作为。”你如何理解他的这一说法？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最后更新于 2012年8月25日 星期六 08:50&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第六课 律法与福音使基督徒圣洁</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/205/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/205/7/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;a----gods-teachings-of-law-and-gospel-work-together-to-sanctify-believers-in-jesus-christ-神律法与福音的教导共同作用使基督徒靠着主耶稣而圣洁&#34;&gt;A.    God&amp;rsquo;s Teachings Of Law And Gospel Work Together To Sanctify Believers in Jesus Christ 神律法与福音的教导共同作用，使基督徒靠着主耶稣而圣洁&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God uses His two great truths of law and gospel to work in harmony to accomplish the vital work of enabling believers in Jesus Christ to live the new spiritual life the Holy Spirit creates in them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神的律法与福音两大真理和谐运作一同完成伟业——使基督徒能够在主耶稣里活出圣灵已建构于他们内心的全新的属灵生命。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this new life, the Holy Spirit sanctifies people.  When He sanctifies, the Holy Spirit sets people apart further from sin and brings them nearer to God and His holy purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;在这个新生命中，圣灵使人圣洁，使人远离罪恶，使人更加靠近神及他神圣的目的。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both the law and gospel play very different, but very important roles in accomplishing the sanctification of Christians.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;在使基督徒圣洁的过程中，律法与福音具有同等重要的地位、各不相同的角色。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s Holy Spirit works through the law to lead Christians to be aware of the dangers of sin, to continue to be genuinely sorry for their sins and to know the good things that God wants them to be and to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神的圣灵通过律法带领基督徒意识并警惕罪恶之凶险，继续真诚悔过，明白什么是神要他们去做的美善事工。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s Holy Spirit works through the gospel to lead Christians to be strong to fight against the power of sin, to be confident that God continues to forgive them for their sins and to have the proper spiritual desire and strength to  produce God-pleasing good works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神的圣灵通过福音带领基督徒勇敢无畏地与罪恶权势抗争，使他们对神的宽恕充满信心，具有属灵的力量与渴望去做蒙神喜悦的事。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b----the-law-and-gospel-work-to-assist-christians-to--fight-against-the-power-of-sin-in-their-lives-律法与福音辅助基督徒与他们生命中的罪恶权势抗争&#34;&gt;B.    The Law And Gospel Work To Assist Christians To  Fight Against The Power Of Sin In Their Lives 律法与福音辅助基督徒与他们生命中的罪恶权势抗争&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God uses His teachings of law and gospel to help believers in Christ to make progress in their fight against the efforts of their sinful nature and other spiritual enemies to lead them to sin against God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神以律法与福音的教导帮助信靠耶稣基督的人在与自己的罪性及任何引诱他们背离神的一切属灵之敌的抗争中不断进取得胜。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God uses the alarming message of the law to warn believers against giving in to temptations to sin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神以律法警示基督徒，不要被罪恶引诱。

The acts of the sinful nature are obvious: sexual immorality, impurity and debauchery, idolatry and witchcraft, hatred, discord, jealousy, fits of rage, selfish ambition, dissentions, factions and envy, drunkenness, orgies and the like.  I warn you, as I did before, that those who live like this will not inherit the kingdom of God.  （Galatians 5:19-21）

情欲的事都是显而易见的；就如奸淫、污秽、邪荡、拜偶像、邪术、仇恨、争竞、忌恨、恼怒、结党、纷争、异端、嫉妒（有古卷在此有“凶杀”二字）、醉酒、荒宴等类，我从前告诉你们，现在又告诉你们，行这样事的人，必不能承受　神的国。（加拉太书5:19-21）

Therefore do not let sin reign in your mortal body so that you obey its evil desires.  Do not offer the parts of your body to sin, as instruments of wickedness.  （Romans 6:12-13a）

所以不要容罪在你们必死的身上作王，使你们顺从身子的私欲。也不要将你们的肢体献给罪作不义的器具。（罗马书6:12-13a）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God uses the life-giving message of the gospel to strengthen believers to resist temptations to sin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神以福音坚固基督徒，拒绝罪恶的试探。

We died to sin, how can we live in it any longer?  Or don&#39;t you know that all of us who were baptized in Christ Jesus were baptized into His death?  We were therefore buried with Him through baptism into death in order that, just as Christ was raised from the dead through the glory of the Father, we too may live a new life.…… In the same way, count yourselves dead to sin, but alive to God in Christ Jesus……Offer yourselves to God, as those who have been brought from death to life……For sin shall not be your master, because you are not under law, but under grace.  （Romans 6:2-4, 11, 13b, 14）

我们在罪上死了的人，岂可仍在罪中活着呢？岂不知我们这受洗归入基督耶稣的人，是受洗归入他的死吗？所以我们藉着洗礼归入死，和他一同埋葬，原是叫我们一举一动有新生的样式，象基督藉着父的荣耀从死里复活一样…… 倒要象从死里复活的人，将自己献给　神，并将肢体作义的器具献给　神。……也不要将你们的肢体献给罪作不义的器具；罪必不能作你们的主，因你们不在律法之下，乃在恩典之下。（罗马书 6:2-4, 11, 13b, 14）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;c----the-law-and-gospel-work-to-produce-in-christians-a-continued-contrition-for-sin-and-a-continued-assurance-of-forgivness-律法与福音使基督徒持久地悔过持久地坚信神的宽恕&#34;&gt;C.    The Law And Gospel Work To Produce In Christians A Continued Contrition For Sin and A Continued Assurance Of Forgivness 律法与福音使基督徒持久地悔过，持久地坚信神的宽恕。&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God uses His teachings of law and gospel to keep believers in Christ repentant for their sins and confident of God&amp;rsquo;s forgiveness for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神以律法与福音的教导使基督徒保持一颗认罪悔改的心，同时也让他们对神的宽恕充满信心。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God uses the convicting message of the law to show believers their sins and to keep them sincerely sorrowful for their sins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神以律法定罪审判的信息昭示基督徒的罪，使他们保持一颗真诚悔过的心。

Yet, I hold this against you.  You have forsaken your first love.  Remember the height from which you have fallen!  Repent, and do the things you did at first.  If you do not repent, I will come to you and remove your lamp stand from its place. （Revelation 2:4-5）

然而有一件事我要责备你，就是你把起初的爱心离弃了。所以应当回想你是从哪里坠落的，并要悔改，行起初所行的事。你若不悔改，我就临到你那里，把你的灯台从原处挪去。（启示录 2:4-5）

I know your deeds, that you are neither cold nor hot.  I wish you were one or the other!  So because you are lukewarm – neither hot, nor cold – I am about to spit you out of my mouth. . . Those whom I love I rebuke and discipline.  So be earnest, and repent. （Revelation 3:5-6, 19）

我知道你的行为，你也不冷也不热；我巴不得你或冷或热。你既如温水，也不冷也不热，所以我必从我口中把你吐出去。凡我所疼爱的，我就责备管教他；所以你要发热心，也要悔改。（启示录 3:15-16, 19）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God uses the comforting message of the gospel to assure contrite Christians that God forgives their sins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神以福音安慰体恤的信息使真心悔过的基督徒确信，神宽恕他们的罪。

If we confess our sins, He is faithful and just and will forgive us our sins and purify us from all unrighteousness. （1 John 1:9）

我们若认自己的罪，　神是信实的，是公义的，必要赦免我们的罪，洗净我们一切的不义。（约翰一书 1:9）

But if anybody does sin, we have one who speaks to the Father in our defense – Jesus Christ, the Righteous One.  He is the atoning sacrifice for our sins, and not only for ours but also for the sins of the whole world. （1 John 2:1b-2）

若有人犯罪，在父那里我们有一位中保，就是那义者耶稣基督，他为我们的罪作了挽回祭，不是单为我们的罪，也是为普天下人的罪。（约翰一书 2:1b-2）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;d----the-law-and-gospel-work-to-enable-christians-to-produce-god-pleasing-good-works-律法与福音使基督徒有能力做蒙神喜悦的事&#34;&gt;D.    The Law And Gospel Work To Enable Christians To Produce God-Pleasing Good Works 律法与福音使基督徒有能力做蒙神喜悦的事&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God uses His teachings of law and gospel to produce good works in the lives of Christians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;神律法与福音的教导在基督徒的生命中成就美善的事工。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God uses the instructive message of the law to give Christians guidance to know the good things God wants them to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神以律法启发性的信息引导基督徒了解神要他们去做的美善事工。

Be joyful always; pray continually; give thanks in all circumstances, for this is God&#39;s will for you in Christ Jesus.  Do not put out the Spirit&#39;s fire; do not treat prophecies with contempt.  Test everything.  Hold on to the good.  Avoid every kind of evil. （1 Thessalonians 5:16-22）

要常常喜乐，不住地祷告，凡事谢恩，因为这是　神在基督耶稣里向你们所定的旨意。不要消灭圣灵的感动，不要藐视先知的讲论。但要凡事察验，善美的要持守；各样的恶事要禁戒不作。（帖撒罗尼迦前书 5:16-22）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God uses the empowering message of the gospel to give Christians the desire and strength to do the good works that God desires.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神以福音独具权能的信息赐予基督徒属灵的力量与渴望去做蒙神喜悦的事。

But the grace of God that brings salvation has appeared to all men.  It teaches us to say “No” to ungodliness and worldly passions, and to live self-controlled, upright and godly lives in this present age, while we wait for the blessed hope – the glorious appearance of our great God and Savior, Jesus Christ, who gave Himself for us to redeem us from all wickedness and to purify for Himself a people who are His very own, eager to do what is good.  （Titus 2:11-14）

因为　神救众人的恩典已经显明出来，教训我们除去不敬虔的心和世俗的情欲，在今世自守、公义、敬虔度日，等候所盼望的福，并等候至大的　神和我们救主耶稣基督的荣耀显现。他为我们舍了自己，要赎我们脱离一切罪恶，又洁净我们，特作自己的子民，热心为善。（提多书 2:11-14）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;e----review-the-lesson-本课回顾&#34;&gt;E.    Review The Lesson 本课回顾&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;agree-and-disagree-statements-判断题&#34;&gt;Agree And Disagree Statements 判断题&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark each statement A （agree） or D （disagree）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;正确的划“V”,错误的划“X”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 1.   When God sanctifies Christians, He sets them apart spiritually from the power of sin and the practice of wickedness for dedication to God and the practice of holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神使基督徒灵魂圣洁远离罪恶权势，使他们在实际生活中圣洁、杜绝邪恶行为， 一心向神。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 2.   God uses the law and gospel to bring people to saving faith in Christ, but uses other sacred teachings to sanctify His believing people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神以律法与福音带人信靠基督，却以另外的神圣教导使他们圣洁。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 3.   The law not only tells Christians what to do in their sanctified life, but it also gives them the desire to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神的律法不仅告诉基督徒应该如何过圣洁的生活，也让他们内心渴望去这样做。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 4.   The gospel alone makes Christians willing and able to live a sanctified life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 只有福音使基督徒甘愿并有能力过圣洁的生活。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 5.   Once a person becomes a believer in Christ, he/she is not seriously troubled by temptations to sin any longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 一个人一旦成为基督徒，他/她从此再不会遇到罪的试探与诱惑。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 6.   Because the Holy Spirit sanctifies Christians through the law and gospel, they are able to life a sin-free life of love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 因为圣灵通过律法与福音使基督徒圣洁，所以他们能够过一个充满爱的无罪的生活。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 7.   If Christians stop repenting of their sins, they will also stop believing in Jesus Christ as their Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 基督徒如果停止认罪悔改，他们便停止相信耶稣基督是他们的救主。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 8.   Good works are an important, but not an essential part of the Christian&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 善工固然重要，但不是基督徒生活的本质部分。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 9.   Without gospel motivation, our works are not truly good or God-pleasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 不以福音为动因的一切工作不是真正的善工，不会蒙神喜悦。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 10.  Because Christians need so much instruction in God&amp;rsquo;s will, God employs the law as the greater power than the gospel in their sanctification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 由于基督徒需要在神的旨意中接受诸多指导，所以在使人圣洁的过程中，神让律法具有高于福音的权能。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;recognizing-how-god-uses-the-law-and-gospel-辨别题神如何使用律法与福音&#34;&gt;Recognizing How God Uses The Law And Gospel 辨别题：神如何使用律法与福音&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify the way God uses the law and gospel to sanctify Christians in the following sections of Scripture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在以下经文中定义神使用律法与福音圣洁化基督徒的方式。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“But just as you excel in everything – in faith, in speech, in knowledge, in complete earnestness and in your love for us – see that you also excel in this grace of giving.  I am not commanding you, but I want to test the sincerity of your love by comparing it with the earnestness of others.  For you know the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ,  that though He was rich, yet for your sakes He became poor, so that you through His poverty might become rich.” （2 Corinthians 8:7-9）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;你们既然在信心、口才、知识、热心和待我们的爱心上，都格外显出满足来，就当在这慈惠的事上也格外显出满足来。我说这话，不是吩咐你们，乃是藉着别人的热心试验你们爱心的实在。你们知道我们主耶稣基督的恩典：他本来富足，却为你们成了贫穷，叫你们因他的贫穷，可以成为富足。（哥林多后书8:7-9）

a.     The law 律法：

--------------------------------------------------------------------

b.    The gospel福音：

------------------------------------------------------------------
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Be kind and compassionate to one another, forgiving each other, just as in Christ God forgave you.  Be imitators of God, therefore, as dearly loved children and live a life of love, just as Christ loved us and gave Himself up for us as a fragrant offering and sacrifice to God.” （Ephesians 4:32-5:2）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;并要以恩慈相待，存怜悯的心，彼此饶恕，正如　神在基督里饶恕了你们一样。所以你们该效法　神，好象蒙慈爱的儿女一样。也要凭爱心行事，正如基督爱我们，为我们舍了自己，当作馨香的供物和祭物，献与　神。（以弗所书 4:32-5:2）

a.     The law律法：

--------------------------------------------------------------------

b.    The gospel福音：

------------------------------------------------------------------
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Keep your lives free from the love of money and be content with what you have, because God has said, &amp;lsquo;Never will I leave you; never will I forsake you.&amp;rsquo;  So we say with confidence, &amp;lsquo;The Lord is my helper; I will not be afraid.  What can man do to me?&amp;rsquo; Remember your leaders, who spoke the word of God to you.  Consider the outcome of their way of life and imitate their faith.  Jesus Christ is the same yesterday and today and tomorrow.”（Hebrews 13:5-8）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;你们存心不可贪爱钱财，要以自己所有的为足；因为主曾说：“我总不撇下你，也不丢弃你。” 所以我们可以放胆说：“主是帮助我的，我必不惧怕。人能把我怎么样呢？”从前引导你们、传　神之道给你们的人，你们要想念他们，效法他们的信心，留心看他们为人的结局。耶稣基督昨日今日，一直到永远，是一样的。（希伯来书 13:5-8）

a.     The law律法：

 --------------------------------------------------------------------

b.    The gospel 福音：

---------------------------------------------------------------------
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最后更新于 2012年8月25日 星期六 08:50&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第七课 律法与福音的误用</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/205/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/205/8/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In this lesson, we will begin to examine some of the common ways that the law and gospel are misused and misapplied to harm the spiritual lives of people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;错误地运用律法与福音会严重危害人们的属灵生活。本课我们将审视与辨别某些常见的误用律法与福音的方式。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a----misuse-1-salvation-by-human-works-误用1靠人的行为得救恩&#34;&gt;A.    Misuse 1: Salvation By Human Works 误用1:靠人的行为得救恩&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps the most harmful misuse of law and gospel is the false teaching that people can/must earn their salvation entirely or in part by their own efforts to keep the law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;最为有害的误用方式：人们可以/必须靠着努力遵行律法来赚得自己全部的或部分的救恩。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some examples of salvation by works teaching are:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;某些靠人的行为得救恩的错误教导：

a.     “Live the best life you can and God will save you.”

“尽你所能活出完美的生命，神将救赎你。”

b.    “Jesus&#39; sacrifice is not enough to save you. You must complete your salvation by living a life of obedience to God&#39;s commands.”

“耶稣降世舍命还不足以救赎你，你必须靠着全然服从神的诫命来实现自己的救恩。”

c.    “God will reward those who do good with eternal life.”

“神会以永生来奖赏那些多行善事的人。”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salvation by human works contradicts the biblical teachings that sinners are saved only by God&amp;rsquo;s grace for them through faith in the redeeming work of Jesus Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;因人的行为得救恩与圣经的教导相抵触。

圣经的教导：唯有靠神的恩典、通过对耶稣基督救赎大业的全然信靠，罪人方能得救赎。

“But because of His great love for us, God , who is rich in mercy, made us alive with Christ even when we were dead in transgressions – it is by grace you have been saved.” （Ephesians 2:4-5）

然而　神既有丰富的怜悯，因他爱我们的大爱，当我们死在过犯中的时候，便叫我们与基督一同活过来（你们得救是本乎恩）。（以弗所书2:4-5）

“To the man who does not work but trusts God who justifies the wicked, his faith is credited to him as righteousness.” （Romans 4:5）

惟有不作工的，只信称罪人为义的　神，他的信就算为义。（罗马书 4:5）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b----misuse-2-religious-legalism-误用2宗教律法主义&#34;&gt;B.    Misuse 2: Religious Legalism 误用2:宗教律法主义&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religious legalism is the misguided attempt to produce Christian living （sanctification） by making the law the motivation and power for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;宗教律法主义误导人们试图以律法作为基督徒圣洁生活的动因。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some examples of religious legalism are:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;某些宗教律法主义的实例：

a.     “You must attend worship services at least once a week or God will not bless your life.”

“你每周至少要参加一次崇拜活动，否则神不会祝福你的生活。”

b.    If you do not love other people as much as you love yourself, God will not love you.

“你若非爱人如己，神就不会爱你。”

c.    “It is your duty to witness to your faith.  You must testify to Christ if you expect to be saved.”

“你有责任见证你的信心。若想得救，你必须向基督表明你的信心。”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religious legalism errs by failing to use the gospel to supply the desire and strength to keep the law and live the Christian life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;宗教律法主义的错失在于不懂得福音才是基督徒遵行律法保持圣洁生活的根本力量与动因。

“Therefore, I urge you, brothers, in view of God&#39;s mercy, to offer your bodies as living sacrifices, holy and pleasing to God – this is your spiritual act of worship,” （Romans 12:1）

所以弟兄们，我以　神的慈悲劝你们，将身体献上，当作活祭，是圣洁的，是　神所喜悦的；你们如此事奉乃是理所当然的。（罗马书 12:1）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;c----misuse-3-religious-moralism-误用3宗教道德主义&#34;&gt;C.    Misuse 3: Religious Moralism 误用3:宗教道德主义&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religious moralism is closely related to religious legalism.  It is the mistaken attempt to produce good moral behavior without the motivation and power of the gospel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;宗教道德主义与宗教律法主义相仿，都试图抛开福音这一根本动因，靠自己来向世人“提供”某些良好的道德品行。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Religious moralism is frequently practiced and promoted by people who hold the incorrect view that the main purpose of the church is to transform society and improve the earthly lives of people.  This view is called the Social Gospel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;有一种观点认为，教会的主要目的是转变社会形态，改善世人的生活，即社会福音。持此观点的人不断将宗教道德主义付诸实践并发扬光大。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God has created the Church and has given it the primary mission of proclaiming His Word to save people from sin and make them His disciples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神创建教会并授予它根本的使命——宣扬神的道，救人于罪恶，使他们跟随神。

“Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you.” （Matthew 28:19-20a）

“所以，你们要去使万民作我的门徒，奉父子圣灵的名，给他们施洗（或作”给他们施洗，归于父子圣灵的名。“）。凡我所吩咐你们的，都教训他们遵守。” （马太福音 28:19-20a）

“All this is from God, who reconciled us to Himself through Christ and gave us the ministry of reconciliation. . . We are therefore Christ&#39;s ambassadors, as though God were making His appeal through us.  We implore you on Christ&#39;s behalf: Be reconciled to God.” （2 Corinthians 5:18,20）

一切都是出于　神，他藉着基督使我们与他和好，又将劝人与他和好的职分赐给我们。所以，我们作基督的使者，就好象　神藉我们劝你们一般；我们替基督求你们与　神和好。（哥林多后书 5:18,20）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While Christians are committed to live personally moral lives and to encourage good moral living in society, they recognize that God has given earthly government the job of promoting good morals among its people to produce a good society by using the law to set standards and employ rewards and punishments to gain compliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;当基督徒在日常生活中有良好的社会公德，遵纪守法独善其身时，他们会意识到，是神委派世间的政府在民众当中设立、使用并不断改进各种道德规范、律法标准、奖惩制度，从而营造一个良性和谐的社会氛围。

“The authorities that exist has been established by God. . . Rulers hold no terror for those who do what is right, but for those who do wrong. . . He is God&#39;s servant to do you good.  But if you do wrong, be afraid, for he does not bear the sword for nothing.  He is God&#39;s servant, an agent of wrath to bring punishment on the wrongdoer.”  （Romans 13:1b, 3a, 4）

凡掌权的都是　神所命的。 . . 作官的原不是叫行善的惧怕，乃是叫作恶的惧怕。 . .他是　神的用人，是与你有益的。你若作恶，却当惧怕，因为他不是空空地佩剑。他是　神的用人，是伸冤的，刑罚那作恶的。（罗马书 13:1b, 3a, 4）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some examples of religious moralism are: 某些宗教道德主义的实例：&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;a.     “God&#39;s people must take the lead in fighting drug and alcohol abuse so we can help create a safer, more godly society.”

“基督徒只有成为与吸毒酗酒等社会现象作斗争的先锋，才能建造一个更加安全、虔诚的社会。”

b.    “It is our calling as God&#39;s people to end injustice in the world.”

“作为基督徒，我们受呼召去终止世间一切的不义。”

c.    “One of our major goals as a Christian congregation should be to aggressively protest the evils of gambling because it is hurting the economic welfare of so many in our community.”

“作为基督教会，我们的主要目标之一应该是强烈反对赌博这一丑恶的社会现象，因为它会危害我们团体中许多人的经济利益。”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The major failing of religious moralism is the same as that of religious legalism.  It tries to change human behavior with law and not gospel motivation and power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;宗教道德主义的主要失误与宗教律法相同——试图以律法而非福音为内在力量与动因去改变人类的行为。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;d----misuse-4-antinomianism-误用4反律法主义&#34;&gt;D.    Misuse 4: Antinomianism 误用4:反律法主义&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Antinomianism is derived from two Greek words （“anti” and “nomos”） that literally mean “against the law.”  Antinomianism is a false religious teaching that views God&amp;rsquo;s law as unnecessary for people.Antinomianism has two major forms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;反律法主义来源于两个希腊词语，义为“反对律法”.这一错误的宗教教导认为，神的律法全无必要。反律法主义有两个主要的形式。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extreme Antinomianism = the law is entirely unnecessary for everyone.  God will work repentance, faith and sanctification in people through the gospel alone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;极端反律法主义=律法对所有的人都完全不必要。神只以福音教人悔改、建立信心，使人圣洁。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moderate Antinomianism = the law is necessary to lead people to contrition, but it is not necessary to guide Christians in sanctified living.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;温和反律法主义=律法在教人认罪悔改层面上是必要的，但在使基督徒过圣洁生活的层面上是不必要的。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some examples of antinomianism are:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;某些反律法主义的实例：

a.     “You do not need to hear the law any more.  You already know what God expects of you.”

“你无需再听从律法，你已经知道神要你做什么。”

b.    “It is Jesus&#39; mercy alone that teaches us how great is our sin and how afraid we must be of God&#39;s  punishment.

”只有耶稣的怜悯让我们明白我们的罪孽有多么深重，我们对神的惩罚惧怕到什么程度。“

c.    ”We preach the positive message of Christ&#39;s love.  People hear enough bad news without the church adding any more to their lives.“

” 我们要传讲积极正面的信息——基督的爱。人们听到的负面信息已经足够多了，教会就不要再给他们的生活添加更多类似的信息了。“
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Antinomianism makes the great mistake of insisting that God uses the gospel, not the law, to work contrition and to give guidance for Christian living.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;反律法主义的重大错误在于极力强调神以福音（非律法）促成罪人的悔改、指导基督徒的生活。

”Through the law we become conscious of sin.“  （Romans 3:20b）

因为律法本是叫人知罪。（罗马书 3:20b）

”Direct me in the path of your commands, for there I find delight. . . I gain understanding from your precepts; therefore I hate every wrong path . . . Direct my footsteps according to Your  word; let no sin rule over me.“  （Psalm 119:35, 104, 133）

求你叫我遵行你的命令，因为这是我所喜乐的。 . . 我藉着你的训词得以明白，所以我恨一切的假道。求你用你的话，使我脚步稳当，不许什么罪孽辖制我。（诗篇119:35, 104, 133）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;e----review-the-lesson-本课回顾&#34;&gt;E.    Review The Lesson 本课回顾&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;agree-and-disagree-statements-判断题&#34;&gt;Agree And Disagree Statements 判断题&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark each statement A （agree） or D （disagree）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;正确的划”V“,错误的划”X“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 1.   The most harmful misuse of the law and gospel is to corrupt the Bible&amp;rsquo;s teaching that we are saved by God&amp;rsquo;s grace through Spirit-worked faith in the redeeming work of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 我们得救是本乎恩（神的恩典），因圣灵的工作而相信耶稣基督的救赎大业。误用律法与福音最大的危害在于败坏了圣经的这一教导。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 2.   The teaching that a person is saved mostly by faith in Jesus and in part by his/her own works is not as bad as the teaching that a person is saved entirely by his/her own works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 教导一：一个人得救全凭自己的努力。教导二：一个人得救基本上因着相信基督，部分地靠自己的努力。两个教导相比较，后者没有前者那么糟糕。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 3.   Religious legalism employs the law to do more than God wants it to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 宗教律法主义试图利用律法去做超出神要律法所做的事。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 4.   Legalism turns God&amp;rsquo;s loved children into God&amp;rsquo;s burdened slaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 律法主义将神所钟爱的儿女变为身负重担的奴隶。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 5.   Much religious moralism flows from a confusion of the mission that God has given to His Church and the mission He has given to earthly government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 宗教道德主义的困惑在于：误将神赐予世俗政府的使命当做神赐予教会的使命。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 6.   Since Christians are in the world, but not of it, they don&amp;rsquo;t have much interest in promoting moral living and improving society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 由于基督徒生活在这个世界却不属于这个世界，所以他们不大关心社会的进步与道德生活的改善。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 7.   The Social Gospel deserves a more prominent place in the ministry of Christ&amp;rsquo;s Church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 在基督教会的事工中，”社会福音“配居更显赫的地位。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 8.   An antinomian is one who insists that the law is not needed for a healthy spiritual life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 反律法主义者执意认为，健康的属灵生活不需要律法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 9.   While antinomianism opposes the law, it has little impact on the ministry of the gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 反律法主义反对律法，与福音事工只有微不足道的冲突而已。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 10.  People who diminish the role of God&amp;rsquo;s law don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are saved from or what they are living for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 贬低神律法的人不知道他们因什么得救、为什么而活。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;evaluate-the-following-teachings-你如何评价以下教导&#34;&gt;Evaluate The Following Teachings 你如何评价以下教导&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;”All men, by the grace of God, have the power to gain eternal life.  This is called salvation by grace coupled with obedience to the laws and ordinances of the gospel.  Salvation in the kingdom of God is available because of the atoning blood of Christ.  But it is received only on condition of faith, repentance, baptism, and enduring to the end in keeping the commandments of God.“&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;”所有的人靠着神的恩典而具有赢得永生的能力。我们靠着遵行律法与遵守福音仪式两相结合的恩典而得救赎。在神的国度里我们因着基督的宝血可得救赎，然而若要得此救恩，只能以信心、悔改、洗礼以及持之以恒地遵行神的诫命为前提。“
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;”The church is here to make this world a better place in which to live.  We must especially focus on meeting the needs of the poor and disadvantaged.  We must remove the inequities we find in the world and build a just society.  This is the “saving” work of the church.“&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;”教会有责任使这个世界成为一个更完美的生活所在。我们必须特别致力于如何满足贫穷者的需求，关注社会的缺失。我们必须铲除世间的罪恶，建设一个公正的社会。这是教会救世济民的工作。“
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最后更新于 2012年8月25日 星期六 08:50&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第八课 律法与福音的误用（续）</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/205/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/205/9/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In this lesson, we will begin to examine some additional ways that the law and gospel are misused and misapplied to harm the spiritual lives of people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;错误地运用律法与福音会严重危害人们的属灵生活。本课我们将继续审视与辨别某些误用律法与福音的方式。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a----misuse-5-universalism-误用5普救论&#34;&gt;A.    Misuse 5: Universalism 误用5:普救论&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universalism is the false teaching that God loves people so much that He will save all people from their sins and give them eternal life apart from Spirit-worked sorrow for sin and faith in Jesus Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;普救论抛开圣灵使人认罪悔改的工作，抛开人们对耶稣基督的信靠，只讲神爱世人，神会救赎普天下所有的人脱离罪恶，并赐他们永生。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some examples of universalism are: 某些普救论的实例：&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;a.     “We all worship the same God and are all going to the same heaven.”

“我们敬拜同一位神，进入同一个天国。”

b.    “God loves sinners so much that He will not send anyone to hell.”

“神爱罪人，他不会让任何一个人下地狱。”

c.    “All religions and philosophies will lead a person to God and eternal life.”

“所有的宗教与哲学都会带人相信神并且得永生。”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universalism opposes the Bible&amp;rsquo;s teaching that God is a just and holy God who will punish sinners.  It also dismisses the gospel of Jesus Christ as the necessary means of salvation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;普救论与圣经的教导——“公义圣洁的神将惩罚罪人”——相背离。普救论同样忽略了耶稣基督的福音才是救恩的根本途径。

“Yet He does not leave the guilty unpunished.” （Exodus 34:7b）

万不以有罪的为无罪。 （出埃及记 34:7b）

“Whoever believes in God&#39;s Son is not condemned, but whoever does not believe stands condemned already because he has not believed in God&#39;s one and only Son.” （John 3:18）

信他的人，不被定罪；不信的人，罪已经定了，因为他不信　神独生子的名。（约翰福音 3:18）

“Jesus answered, &#39;I am the way, the truth and the life.  No one comes to the Father except through Me.‘” （John 14:6）

耶稣说：“我就是道路、真理、生命；若不藉着我，没有人能到父那里去。”（约翰福音 14:6）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b----misuse-6-synergism-误用6协作论&#34;&gt;B.    Misuse 6: Synergism 误用6:协作论&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synergism is derived from two Greek words （“syn” and “ergo”） that literally mean “to work with.” Synergism is the false teaching that a person can and must cooperate with God in his/her coming to saving faith in Jesus Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;协作论源自两个希腊词语，义为“一同工作”.协作论错误地认为，一个人能够且必须与神协同工作来建立在耶稣基督里的信心。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synergism is based on the faulty opinion that a person, is by nature, only spiritually impaired, and possesses the free will to accept or reject Jesus Christ as his/her Savior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;协同论基于一个错误观点，即一个人因着天性只是灵魂受损伤而已，且拥有自由意志或接受或拒绝耶稣基督为他/她的救主。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some examples of synergism are: 某些协作论的实例：&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;a.     “I know I am saved because I made my decision to accept Jesus as my Savior.

”我知道我被救赎，因为我已作出决定，接受耶稣为我的救主。“

b.    ”God has sent Jesus to die for your sins.  Now do your part and invite Jesus into your heart.“

”神已差遣耶稣为你的罪而死。现在，请完成你该做的那部分，邀请耶稣进入你的内心。“

c.    ”God will bring you to faith as long as you do not resist His working in you.“

”只要你不拒绝神在你内心的工作，神就会带领你相信他。“
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synergism contradicts the Bible teaching that all people, by nature are spiritually dead and have no free will to cooperate with God in spiritual matters prior to their conversion.  Synergism also opposes the Bible&amp;rsquo;s teaching that God alone creates saving faith and spiritual life in people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;圣经教导一：人从本质上讲，灵里已死亡，不具备自由意志与神协同工作促成自身属灵的转变。

圣经教导二：唯有神在人的内部建立信心与属灵生命。

协同论与圣经的教导相矛盾。

”As for you, you were dead in your transgressions and sins, . . .  Like the rest, we were by nature objects of wrath.  But because of His great love for us, God, who is rich in mercy, made us alive with Christ even when we were dead in transgressions – it is by grace you have been saved.“  （Ephesians 2:1, 3b-5）

你们死在过犯罪恶之中，他叫你们活过来 . . .本为可怒之子，和别人一样。然而　神既有丰富的怜悯，因他爱我们的大爱，当我们死在过犯中的时候，便叫我们与基督一同活过来（你们得救是本乎恩）。（以弗所书 2:1, 3b-5）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;c----misuse-7-adding-law-conditions-to-the-gospel-误用7为福音附加律法条件&#34;&gt;C.    Misuse 7: Adding Law Conditions To The Gospel 误用7:为福音附加律法条件&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A common misuse of the law and gospel is to add law conditions to the message of the gospel.  This improper mixing of law and gospel leads a person to abandon salvation by God&amp;rsquo;s grace and seek salvation by his/her works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;在福音信息上附加律法前提是一种常见的误用律法与福音的方式。混淆律法与福音会使人放弃依靠神的恩典得救恩，而靠自己的行为寻求救恩。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some examples of adding law conditions to the gospel:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;某些在福音之上附加律法前提的实例：

a.     ”Believe in Jesus and live a life of good works so that you can be saved.“

”相信耶稣且在生活中多行善事即可得救。“

b.    ”You will go to heaven if you have faith in Christ and follow God&#39;s orders to worship regularly, respect the church leaders and give 10% of your income to the church.

“如果你相信基督，遵循神的指示定期崇拜，尊重教会领袖，将收入的十分之一捐给教会（十一奉献），你就可以进天堂。”

c.    “God forgives people who are sorry for their sins, look to Jesus for forgiveness and do not repeat their past mistakes.”

“神宽恕这样的人：认罪悔改，寻求耶稣的宽恕，不再重犯以往的错误。”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding law conditions to the gospel opposes the Bible&amp;rsquo;s teaching that salvation is a free gift of God apart from our good works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;圣经教导：救恩是神无偿的礼物，而非靠我们的善行来赢取。

在福音之上附加律法条件与圣经的教导相违背。

“For we maintain that a man is justified by faith apart from observing the law.” （Romans 3:28）

 所以（有古卷作“因为”）我们看定了：人称义是因着信，不在乎遵行律法。（罗马书 3:28）

“For by grace are you saved, through faith – and this not from yourselves, it is the gift of God, not by works, so that no one can boast.” （Ephesians 2:8-9）

 你们得救是本乎恩，也因着信，这并不是出于自己，乃是　神所赐的；也不是出于行为，免得有人自夸。（以弗所书 2:8-9）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;d----misuse-8-faulty-descriptions-of-the-christian-误用8错误地描述基督徒&#34;&gt;D.    Misuse 8: Faulty Descriptions Of The Christian 误用8:错误地描述基督徒&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another common misuse of the law and gospel is to portray the Christian incorrectly.  One error is to describe the Christian as an unconverted sinner who has only a sinful nature.  A second error is to describe the Christian as a perfected saint who has only a believing nature.  Still another error is to make sweeping generalizations that apply to some Christians, but not to all. Such errors confuse and trouble believers and can lead them to doubt or lose their salvation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;另一种常见的误用律法与福音的方式是错误地描述基督徒。其一是将基督徒描述成未曾转变（没有信仰）只有罪性的罪人。其二是将基督徒描述成全无罪性的完美的圣徒。还有就是以偏概全（将只适用于某些基督徒的情况扩大化普遍化）。诸如此类的误用会迷惑与困扰基督徒，使他们对信仰产生怀疑，失去救恩。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some examples of faulty descriptions of the Christian as an unconverted sinner are:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;某些误将基督徒描述成没有信仰的罪人的实例：

“A Christian can not resist temptation.”

“一个基督徒无法抗拒诱惑。”

“A Christian cannot be sure of going to heaven.

”一个基督徒不能确定自己是否会进天国。“

”A Christian is not able to truly love God.“

”一个基督徒无法真正地爱神。“
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some examples of faulty descriptions of the Christian as a perfected saint are:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;某些误将基督徒描述成完美的圣徒的实例：

”A Christian tells the truth at all times.“

”一个基督徒永远讲真话。“

”A Christian never desires revenge.“

”一个基督徒绝不想去报复别人。“

”A Christian never questions or doubts God&#39;s Word.“

”一个基督徒绝不会对神的话语有任何疑问。“
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some examples of sweeping generalizations made about all Christians are:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;某些以偏概全的实例：

”No one in this church listens carefully to the preaching of God&#39;s Word.“

”这间教会里没有一个人专心听牧师传讲神的话语。“

”True Christians always take time to welcome the visitors to our church.“

”真正的基督徒总是花时间邀请人们来我们教会。“

”The members of this congregation are extremely lazy.“

”这个教会的成员极其懒惰。“
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When people make false descriptions of Christians, they either fail to recognize that Christians have both a sinful and a believing nature, that Christians are both sinful and sanctified at the same time or they mistakenly ascribe the behaviors of some believers to all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;有人错误地描述基督徒，是因为没有认识到基督徒既有罪性也有信仰，基督徒有罪恶同时也靠着神得圣洁。有人错误地将某些基督徒的不良行为归咎于所有基督徒。

”The sinful nature desires what is contrary to the spiritual, and the spiritual what is contrary to the sinful nature.  They are in conflict with each other, so that you do not do what you want.“ （Galatians 5:17）

因为情欲和圣灵相争，圣灵和情欲相争，这两个是彼此相敌，使你们不能作所愿意作的。（加拉太书 5:17）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;e----review-the-lesson-本课回顾&#34;&gt;E.    Review The Lesson 本课回顾&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;agree-and-disagree-statements-判断题&#34;&gt;Agree And Disagree Statements 判断题&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark each statement A （agree） or D （disagree）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;正确的划”V“,错误的划”X“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 1.   The teaching of universalism has little need for either the law or the gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 普救论只需要一点点律法或福音而已。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 2.   Since God loves all people and sent Jesus to die for the sins all people, surely He will bring all people safely to heaven in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 神爱世上所有的人并差遣耶稣为世人的罪而死。所以毫无疑问，在末日来临之时，神会将所有的人安全地带入天堂。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 3.   Unbelievers do have some ability to cooperate with God in the matter of their coming to faith in Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 非基督徒具有一定的能力与神协作共事，一同建立在耶稣基督里的信心。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 4.   Synergism denies the Bible&amp;rsquo;s teaching of salvation by God&amp;rsquo;s grace when it insists that a person is saved by a combination of  the redeeming work of Jesus Christ and that person&amp;rsquo;s own decision to believe in Jesus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 我们是靠着神的恩典而得救赎。协作论否认圣经的这一教导，认为某人得救是靠耶稣基督的救赎与此人的决定（决定相信耶稣）两方面联合作用。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 5.   Synergism robs God of His glory as the One who saves people all by Himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 协作论抹煞神的荣耀，否认惟有神救赎世人的真理。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 6.   If you add the law conditions to the gospel promise, you always end up with a law result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 如果你在福音的应许之上加入律法（的条件），你将得到律法的结果。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;（注：律法的结果不能让人得救，得救是福音的结果。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 7.   If a person tries to be saved by a combination of Christ&amp;rsquo;s works and his/her own works, he/she will not be saved at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 如果一个人试图靠基督的救赎大业与自身的努力共同作用而得救赎，他/她便得不到救赎。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 8.   Our salvation depends about 99.99% on God and about .01% on us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 我们得救，大约百分之九十九点九九靠神，百分之零点零一靠我们自己。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 9.   Christians produce works pleasing to God, and they also commit sins displeasing to God  every day of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 在日常生活中，基督徒会做蒙神喜悦的事，他们同样会犯罪，不蒙神喜悦。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 10.  Speaking to Christians as if they were still unbelieving sinners or as if they were already perfected saints can cause them great spiritual harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;- 把基督徒当作没有信仰的罪人或完美的圣徒看待，会给他们造成巨大的属灵伤害。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;evaluate-the-following-teachings-你如何评价以下教导&#34;&gt;Evaluate The Following Teachings 你如何评价以下教导&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;”Every human soul will progress through the ages to heights that are sublime and glorious, where God is Love and Love is God.“&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;”每个人的灵魂会随着时间的推移不断成长，达到崇高荣耀的神爱合一的高度。“
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;”All who because of their faith in Jehovah God and in Christ Jesus dedicate themselves to do God&amp;rsquo;s will and then faithfully carry out their dedication will be rewarded with everlasting life.“&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;”凡相信耶和华神与基督耶稣，忠实执行神的旨意，甘心奉献的人，神必赐予他们永生作为奖赏。“
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最后更新于 2012年8月25日 星期六 08:50&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第九课 律法与福音的实际应用原则</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/205/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/205/10/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;a----law-and-gospel-principles-律法与福音的原则&#34;&gt;A.    Law And Gospel Principles 律法与福音的原则&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the major principles to keep in mind as you use the two precious truths of law and gospel and apply them to people&amp;rsquo;s lives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当你运用律法与福音两大宝贵真理的时候，务必牢记以下主要原则。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seek diligently a true, clear and deep knowledge of God&amp;rsquo;s teachings of the law and gospel, which is essential to a correct understanding of the Bible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;努力寻求神的律法与福音教导真实、明晰、深刻的内涵，此为正确理解圣经的本质所在。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look to God the Holy Spirit for help in the important and challenging task of properly applying the law and gospel to the lives of people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;寻求圣灵的帮助来完成恰当地应用律法与福音这一重大的具有挑战性的功课。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let the law be the law （proclaim the law as the very hard news it is for people） and let the gospel be the gospel （proclaim the gospel as the very good news it is for people）。  Do not mix gospel elements with the law and do not mix law elements with the gospel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;律法就是律法（宣讲律法严酷的信息），福音就是福音（传讲福音好消息）。不可将福音要素与律法相混淆，也不可将律法要素与福音相混淆。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply the law to create in people a genuine sorrow for sin （contrition）， to restrain sinful behavior, and to provide guidance to Christians in how to please God.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;应用律法使人真诚悔罪、约束恶行，指导基督徒做蒙神喜悦的事。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply the gospel to create faith in Jesus Christ, to provide assurance of salvation and to supply spiritual desire and strength to live a Christian life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;应用福音建立在耶稣基督里的信心，使人对救恩确信无疑，具有属灵的力量与渴望活出基督徒圣洁的生命。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proclaim the law to those who are comfortable and secure in their sins and proclaim the gospel to those who are in terror and despair over their sins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;向那些心安理得的罪人宣讲律法，向那些因自己的罪而过度惊恐与绝望的人传讲福音。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In general, proclaim the law first and then the gospel to help people in their salvation and sanctification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;通常是讲律法在先，讲福音在后，帮助人们懂得救恩与基督徒圣洁的生命。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The greatest misuse of the law and the gospel is to confuse the two teachings so that the gospel with its message of free grace and forgiveness in Jesus Christ is turned into a message that requires sinners to earn their salvation in part or entirely by their own works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;最大的误用是混淆两大教导：将福音信息——在耶稣基督里神无偿的恩典与救赎——变成要求罪人靠自己的全部或部分努力赚取神的救赎。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct those who are terrified by the law to find comfort in the gospel promises and what Jesus had done to save them.  Do not direct them to try to find comfort in their works, in their intentions, in their feelings, or in their prayers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;指导那些因律法而恐惧战兢的人知晓耶稣已完成救赎人类的伟业，让他们在福音应许中寻得安慰而非凭着自身的行为、意向、感觉或祷告得安慰。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach that saving faith in Jesus Christ is not just the mind&amp;rsquo;s acceptance of certain truths about Jesus.  Rather teach that saving faith is the heart&amp;rsquo;s reliance on Jesus and His redeeming work for deliverance from the sins that condemn a person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;建立在耶稣基督里的信心不是仅仅在理性上接受关于耶稣的真理，而是全心全意地信靠耶稣，相信他的救赎大业。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;11&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach that faith in Jesus Christ is “saving” faith because it is God-created reliance on the Savior and not because it produces love and other positive changes in one&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;对主耶稣基督的信心是让人得拯救的信心，因为它是由神在人内心建立的对救主耶稣的完全信靠，而不是因为它会产生爱和改变人生命的积极作用。

（附：这些副产品只是信心的一种体现。）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;12&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach that contrition and faith are the Spirit-created means by which a person is ready and able to receive God&amp;rsquo;s gifts of pardon and salvation and not the reason or basis on which God decides to forgive a person their sins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;悔过和信心是由圣灵产生的并借以让人预备好能够去接受神赦免和拯救的恩典的途径，而不是神决定赦免人罪行的原因或基础。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;13&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach that saving faith is something God creates in a person&amp;rsquo;s heart through the gospel and not something a person creates or helps to create for himself/herself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;信心是神通过福音在人的内心建立起来的，而非靠人自我建立。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;14&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach that saving faith is a necessary Spirit-created means by which we receive and possess the forgiveness of sins and not a meriting condition by which we earn or deserve forgiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;信心是圣灵的工作，是我们罪得赦免所不可缺少的。信心的建立绝非我们的功劳，免得我们认为自己可以赚得或配得神的宽恕。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;15&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not equate saving faith in Jesus Christ with progress a person makes in improving his/her outward behavior such as getting rid of certain vices or doing good things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;不可把在耶稣基督里的信心等同于一个人外在行为的改善（如除掉恶习、做善事等）。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proclaim all sins to be serious violations of God&amp;rsquo;s will and deserving of His eternal punishment and not just minor offenses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;所有的罪都严重违背神的意愿（绝非微不足道的冒犯而已），应得神永恒的惩罚。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;17&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treat believers in Christ as people who are ruled by a believing, spiritual nature that trusts God and loves to do His will and who are also burdened with a defiant, sinful nature that fights against God and the holy beliefs and desires of the spiritual nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;要如此看待基督徒：他们受信靠主的、属灵本性的支配，他们信赖神，乐意遵循神的旨意；他们同样背负着叛逆的罪性，这又使他们对抗神，对抗神圣的信念与属灵的渴求。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;18&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach that good works are the expected, proper fruit of a true faith in Jesus Christ and are not optional and unnecessary for Christians.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;一切善行都是对耶稣基督的信靠所结出的预期的适当的果实，而非多余或可有可无的。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;19&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be careful to distinguish between critical spiritual conditions such as the difference between a person with weak faith in Christ and a person with no faith in Christ, between the good works of a Christian and the outward morality of a non-Christian, between godly sorrow for sins （contrition） and worldly sorrow for sins （unbelieving regret）。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;谨慎区分不同的关键性的属灵状况，比如：信心软弱与没有信心，基督徒的善行与非基督徒的外在道德行为，属灵的虔诚悔罪与属世的懊悔（与信心无关的后悔）。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;20&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regard and administer the sacraments of Holy Baptism and Holy Communion as forms of the gospel that God uses to create and preserve saving faith in Christ and to strengthen Christians to live a sanctified life.  Do not rob them of their gospel content and turn them into mere empty symbols or acts of obedience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;尊重与实施圣洗礼与圣餐礼，将其视为神用来建立与保守我们在耶稣基督里的信心、坚固基督徒过圣洁生活的福音盛典。不可抽掉圣礼中福音的内涵，而将它们仅仅当作空泛的象征或顺服的行为。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;21&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember that Christians, because of their sinful natures, still need the law applied to their lives so they can continue to repent of their sins, be warned against falling away from faith in Christ and receive guidance to know how to live a God-pleasing life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;由于罪性尚存，基督徒仍然需要在生活中应用律法来认罪悔过，警钟长鸣以免丧失在耶稣基督里的信心，应用律法来指导他们过蒙神喜悦的生活。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;22&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach that a person&amp;rsquo;s salvation depends entirely on the perfect sacrifice and merits of Jesus Christ and does not depend in any way on a person&amp;rsquo;s own efforts and works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;一个人得救恩全然仰靠耶稣基督，而非凭任何个人的努力与行为。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;23&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the gospel to provide Christians with the spiritual desire and strength to keep the law and produce the good works God desires of them in their sanctified live.  Avoid religious legalism and religious moralism, which use the law as motivation for good works for Christians.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;运用福音为基督徒提供属灵的力量与渴望去遵行律法，在他们圣洁的生活中多做神希望他们去做的善事。避免像宗教律法主义、宗教道德主义那样以律法作为基督徒善行的动因。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;24&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not turn the gospel of God&amp;rsquo;s saving love in Christ for all into the false teaching of universalism, which asserts that God will save everyone apart from contrition and faith in Jesus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;不可将福音——神在耶稣基督里泽及万民的救赎之爱——变成普救论。（普救论认为神会救赎任何一个不认罪悔改、不相信耶稣的人。）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;25&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that the gospel is the prominent teaching in your ministry to people&amp;rsquo;s souls.  Use the law properly as God intends in service of the gospel.   Preach both of these precious teachings in a spirit of love.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;明确福音是你服事人灵魂的主体教导，在福音事工中依照神的心意恰当运用律法。以爱心传扬律法与福音两大真理。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最后更新于 2012年8月25日 星期六 08:50&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 第十课 律法与福音在讲道与教学中的应用</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/205/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/205/11/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;a-knowing-and-using-the-law-and-gospel-properly-is-essential-for-those-who-want-to-be-faithful-messengers-of-gods-true-word&#34;&gt;A. Knowing And Using The Law And Gospel Properly Is Essential For Those Who Want To Be Faithful Messengers Of God&amp;rsquo;s True Word&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;正确理解恰当运用律法与福音，对于神的真道之忠实的传扬者来说至关重要&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proper distinguishing and application of the two great truths of the law and the gospel is of primary importance in the ministry of God&amp;rsquo;s Word to people&amp;rsquo;s lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;恰当区分与应用律法与福音两大真理是福音事工的关键&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The distinction between law and gospel is the supreme art in Christianity, which all who glory in and bear the Christian name may and should understand.  If this ability is lacking, one cannot tell a Christian from a non-Christian; of such importance is this matter.  Place the person who is able properly to distinguish the law from the gospel at the head of the list and call him a Doctor of Holy Scripture.”  （Dr. Martin Luther）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“在基督信仰中，正确区分律法与福音是最高超的艺术，是所有享有基督徒名分并以此为荣的人都可以而且应该领会的。缺少这项技能，便无法将基督徒从非基督徒中区分出来，其重要性正是如此。要尊能恰当地从福音中区分出律法的人为大，并称其为圣经博士。”（马丁路德  博士）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The distinction between the law and the gospel is &amp;lsquo;a special brilliant light, which serves to accomplish the goal that God&amp;rsquo;s Word may be correctly handled and the Scriptures of the holy prophets and apostles may be properly explained and understood.”  （Formula of Concord, Thorough Declaration: Article V, Section 1）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“正确区分律法与福音就象一种特殊的亮光，照耀我们正确理解神的话语、恰当解释和领会先知们和使徒们（所写）的圣经。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Carelessly throwing law and gospel together in a sermon is like throwing building supplies in a pile and calling it a house.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在一篇布道讲章中将律法与福音随意丢在一起，就如同将一堆杂乱无章的建筑材料称作房屋。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b----a-method-for-preparing-a-scriptural-sermon-that-is-sound-in-doctrine&#34;&gt;B.    A Method For Preparing A Scriptural Sermon That Is Sound In Doctrine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;预备一篇符合教义的布道讲章的方法&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translation 翻译&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text Notes 经文注解&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preaching Values 讲道意义&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text Analysis 经文分析&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thematic Statement 主题陈述&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sermon Goal 讲道目的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific Law （To convince of sin） 特定的律法（确认罪）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific Law （To lead to godly action） 特定的律法（引导虔诚的行为）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific Gospel （To pardon and assure of salvation） 特定的福音（宽恕、确信救恩）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific Gospel （To supply spiritual desire and strength） 特定的福音（赐予属灵的力量与渴望）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic Sermon Outline 讲章大纲&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sermon Building Material 讲章基本素材&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expanded Sermon Outline 讲章大纲引申&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;c----preparing-a-scriptural-message-with-law-and-gospel-准备一篇律法与福音的信息&#34;&gt;C.    Preparing A Scriptural Message With Law And Gospel 准备一篇律法与福音的信息&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work through the following Scripture texts to identify law and gospel points as you prepare for delivering a message to a group of people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当你准备向人们传达一个信息时，你如何根据以下经文确认律法与福音重点？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luke 18:9-14  The Parable Of The Pharisee And The Tax Collector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;路加福音18:9-14  法利赛人与税吏的比喻

9） To some who were confident of their own righteousness and looked down on everybody else, Jesus told this parable: 10） “Two men went up to the temple to pray, one a Pharisee and the other a tax collector.  11） The Pharisee stood up and prayed about himself: &#39;God, I thank You that I am not like other men – robbers, evildoers, adulterers – or even like this tax collector.  12） I fast twice a week and give a tenth of all I get.&#39;  13）  But the tax collector stood at a distance.  He would not even look up to heaven, but beat his breast and said, &#39;God, have mercy on me, a sinner.&#39;  14） I tell you that this man, rather than the other, went home justified before God.  For everyone who exalts himself will be humbled, and he who humbles himself will be exalted.

9）耶稣向那些仗着自己是义人，藐视别人的，设一个比喻，10） ”有两个人上殿里去祷告；一个是法利赛人，一个是税吏。11）法利赛人站着，自言自语地祷告说：‘　神啊，我感谢你，我不象别人勒索、不义、奸淫，也不象这个税吏。12）我一个礼拜禁食两次，凡我所得的，都捐上十分之一。&#39;13）那税吏远远地站着，连举目望天也不敢，只捶着胸说：&#39;　神啊，开恩可怜我这个罪人！&#39;14）我告诉你们，这人回家去，比那人倒算为义了；因为凡自高的，必降为卑；自卑的，必升为高。“

a.     Specific Law （To convince of sin） 特定的律法（确认罪）

b.    Specific Law （To lead to godly action） 特定的律法（引导虔诚的行为）

c.    Specific Gospel （To pardon and assure of salvation） 特定的福音（宽恕、确信救恩）

d.    Specific Gospel （To supply spiritual desire and strength） 特定的福音（赐予属灵的力量与渴望）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galatians 3:10-14  The Curse Of The Law And Redemption By Christ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;加拉太书3:10-14   律法的咒诅与基督的救赎

10） All who rely on observing the law are under a curse, for it is written: &#39;Cursed is everyone who does not continue to do everything written in the Book of the Law. 11） Clearly no one is justified before God by observing the law, because, &#39;The righteous will live by faith.&#39;  12） The law is not based on faith; on the contrary, &#39;The man who does these things will live by them.&#39;  13） Christ redeemed us from the curse of the law by becoming a curse for us, for it is written: &#39;Cursed is everyone who is hung on a tree.&#39;  14） He redeemed us in order that the blessing given to Abraham might come to the Gentiles through Christ Jesus, so that by faith we might receive the promise of the Spirit.

10）凡以行律法为本的，都是被咒诅的；因为经上记着：”凡不常照律法书上所记一切之事去行的，就被咒诅。“11）没有一个人靠着律法在　神面前称义，这是明显的；因为经上说：”义人必因信得生。“ 12） 律法原不本乎信，只说：”行这些事的，就必因此活着。“13）基督既为我们受了咒诅（”受“原文作”成“），就赎出我们脱离律法的咒诅；因为经上记着：”凡挂在木头上都是被咒诅的。“ 14） 这便叫亚伯拉罕的福，因基督耶稣可以临到外邦人，使我们因信得着所应许的圣灵。

a.     Specific Law （To convince of sin） 特定的律法（确认罪）

b.    Specific Law （To lead to godly action） 特定的律法（引导虔诚的行为）

c.    Specific Gospel （To pardon and assure of salvation） 特定的福音（宽恕、确信救恩）

d.    Specific Gospel （To supply spiritual desire and strength） 特定的福音（赐予属灵的力量与渴望）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luke 17;11-19  ”The Healing Of The Ten Lepers“&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;路加福音17;11-19  ”治好十个麻风病人“

11） Now on His way to Jerusalem, Jesus traveled along the border between Samaria and Galilee.  12） As He was going into a village, ten men who had leprosy met him.  They stood at a distance 13） and called out in a loud voice, ”Jesus, Master, have pity on us!“  14） When He saw them, He said, ”Go, show yourselves to the priests.“  And as they went, they were cleansed.  15） One of them, when he saw he was healed, came back, praising God in a loud voice.  16） He threw himself at Jesus&#39; feet and thanked Him – and He was a Samaritan.  17） Jesus asked, ”Were not all ten cleansed?  Where are the other nine?  18） Was no one found to return and give praise to God except this foreigner?“  19） Then He said to him, ”Rise and go; your  faith has make you well.“

11）耶稣往耶路撒冷去，经过撒玛利亚和加利利。12）进入一个村子，有十个长大麻风的，迎面而来，远远地站着，13） 高声说：”耶稣，夫子，可怜我们吧！“ 14） 耶稣看见，就对他们说：”你们去，把身体给祭司察看。“他们去的时候就洁净了。15）内中有一个见自己已经好了，就回来大声归荣耀与　神。16） 又俯伏在耶稣脚前感谢他。这人是撒玛利亚人。17）耶稣说：”洁净了的不是十个人吗？那九个在哪里呢？18） 除了这外族人，再没有别人回来归荣耀与　神吗？“19）就对那人说：”起来，走吧！你的信救了你了。“

a.     Specific Law （To convince of sin） 特定的律法（确认罪）

b.    Specific Law （To lead to godly action） 特定的律法（引导虔诚的行为）

c.    Specific Gospel （To pardon and assure of salvation） 特定的福音（宽恕、确信救恩）

d.    Specific Gospel （To supply spiritual desire and strength） 特定的福音（赐予属灵的力量与渴望）
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;d----recognizing-errors-people-make-about-law-and-gospel-辨别题&#34;&gt;D.    Recognizing Errors People Make About Law And Gospel 辨别题&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Briefly indicate what is wrong about each of the following statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;简要指出下列说法的错误&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 10 Commandments are the most important teaching in the Bible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;十诫是圣经中最重要的教导
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is satisfied that we keep His commandments the best we can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神会满足于我们尽力遵行十诫
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God will save you through faith in Jesus Christ as long as you do your part and do not reject Him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;只要你努力做好你该做的部分且不拒绝神，神就会通过你在耶稣基督里的信心而救赎你。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The message of the gospel is that Jesus lived a wonderful life in order to show us how to live and to inspire us to live like Him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;福音信息是为了向我们展示并激励我们效法耶稣基督圣洁完美的生活榜样。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faith in Jesus Christ is both God&amp;rsquo;s gift and a person&amp;rsquo;s own decision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;在耶稣基督里的信心既是神的礼物也是个人的决定。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good works are necessary for a person to be saved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;人若想得救，必须行善事。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By nature there is some spiritual good and some spiritual bad in everyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;从本质上讲，每个人的灵里有好的部分也有坏的部分。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By making salvation a free gift, God is encouraging people to live irresponsible, sinful lives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;神将救恩作为无偿的礼物赐予人类，其实是在鼓励人类随意犯罪。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The church&amp;rsquo;s primary mission is to provide moral training to its members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;教会的根本任务是对会员进行道德培训。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Christians get to the point where they no longer sin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;基督徒中的先进分子可达到不再犯罪的境界。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;closing-thought-结束语&#34;&gt;Closing Thought 结束语&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May God bless us all as we seek to better know and apply His teachings of law and gospel for the salvation and sanctification of those we serve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;愿神祝福我们，为了我们所服事的人的救恩与圣洁，让我们更好地理解与应用律法与福音的教导。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最后更新于 2012年8月25日 星期六 08:50&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
