<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grace Bible Institute – ROMANS 1-8</title>
    <link>/en/courses/110/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ROMANS 1-8 on Grace Bible Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:46:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/en/courses/110/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 1</title>
      <link>/en/courses/110/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/110/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD&#39;S GOSPEL IS THE POWER OF GOD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 1:1 – 17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WELCOME&lt;/strong&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a great opportunity we will have to study together this great teaching book of the Bible. I look forward to getting to know you, together learning God&#39;s Word and growing stronger and closer to Jesus by his grace. Dr. Martin Luther said about Romans, &amp;quot;This epistle is really the chief part of the New Testament and is truly the purest gospel. It is worthy not only that every Christian should know it word for word, by heart, but also that he should occupy himself with it every day, as the daily bread of the soul. We can never read it or ponder over it too much; for the more we deal with it, the more precious it becomes and the better it tastes.&amp;quot; (LW 35:380)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Romans 1:1-7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no question about whom God inspired to write this letter. 1:1____________&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is normal for Greek letters that the writer is identified first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The people written to is equally clear. 1:7_______________________&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is obvious that Paul has planned to come to Rome but hasn&#39;t been able to get there 1:13. He is writing to a gathering of believers that he hasn&#39;t visited before. Most of them seem to be Gentiles. He is writing this letter to teach the basics of Christianity but also to do it with some depth of truth. He does plan to visit them in the future (Ro.15:24). First he must go to Jerusalem to deliver a special offering collected for the poor believers there (Ro.15:25). Many Bible scholars believe Paul was in Corinth (southern Greece) on his third missionary trip when he wrote this letter. The date of the writing is probably in the spring of 57 AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice in verse 1 the three things that Paul brings out about himself. He is (1) a servant – someone who serves his master completely. This particular servant, Paul, was called by Jesus to be (2) an apostle – someone sent out on a mission. The particular mission was (3) to proclaim the gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does being a servant impact our thinking and actions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Matthew 28:19 help us understand to whom point three applies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do these three points influence our view of the purpose of our life here on earth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What two truths are to be proclaimed about Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One truth from verse 3 –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One truth from verse 4 –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is a true human being who had an ancestry that could be traced back to David and even further back in time. He had every human quality that we have with one exception, he had no sin (Hebrews 4:15). Jesus became a human being, took on a human nature, at the time of his conception inside of Mary, his mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus is the true Son of God and always had every quality of God. Notice how it says in vs. 4 that he was declared to be the Son of God by his resurrection. He didn&#39;t become God&#39;s Son at that point, the reality of Jesus being true God was clearly and forcefully proclaimed at the resurrection. He had to be true man so that he was under God&#39;s law just as we are and also could suffer and die for us. He also had to be true God so that he could give a perfect obedience to God&#39;s law and his suffering and death were valuable enough to pay for the sins of all people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What could the &amp;quot;obedience that comes from faith&amp;quot; (vs5) be referring to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does verse six apply to you? Can you be included in the &amp;quot;you&amp;quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does that make you feel?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Romans 1:8-16&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul&#39;s prayer life is also shared in these verses? What do you notice about his prayers for the Romans?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vs 8 –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vs 9-10 –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vs 11 –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of your prayer life for your fellowship group. How are you copying Paul in your prayers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what ways might you grow in your prayers for your group?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 14 – Paul was called to be a servant of Christ (a God given obligation) to proclaim the Gospel. (verse 1) It didn&#39;t make any difference if people were cultured (Greeks) or uncultured (non-Greeks), educated or people with very little mental capabilities. They all needed to hear the Gospel. We are reminded again that it isn&#39;t our mental abilities or social standing that helps us before God. We are all saved only by grace through faith in Jesus and so everyone needs to hear the Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 15 – Paul was eager. He couldn&#39;t wait for God to answer his prayer so that he could bring God&#39;s Word to them to strengthen and renew them in their faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verses 16-17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;12&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why isn&#39;t Paul ashamed of the Gospel?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice it is &amp;quot;the Gospel&amp;quot;. This isn&#39;t just any good news. This is a specific message of good news. It is the good news announced by the angels outside of Bethlehem. The Savior has come to pay for all sin before God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The citizens of Rome understood power. Military power – the greatest in the world, political power – influenced people&#39;s lives far and wide, intellectual power – ideas frequently flowed from this city – yet the Gospel is a greater power. It is the power of God. Through the Gospel God worked to create faith in Jesus and then grow a small faith into a stronger faith through that same word. Paul had seen it happen time and time again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEYWORD: GOSPEL&lt;/strong&gt; – Good News – God&#39;s message of a Savior from sin sent into the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;13&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the result of the power at work in the Gospel? (verse 16)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salvation means a rescue from impending danger, in this case an inescapable danger. God&#39;s judgment over our disobedience. A message that results in people being lifted from the threats of hell to a relationship of peace with God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;14&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who receives the benefit of this rescue?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This message was given to the Jews in Old Testament times, although it wasn&#39;t even then limited to them. During Jesus ministry he primarily spoke God&#39;s Word to the Jewish people but also did share it occasionally with the Gentiles. After his resurrection Jesus told his disciples to go to all nations with the Gospel. It was not that God preferred one over the other. It was the same powerful gospel that was at work in each heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vs 17 – Righteousness - the word has the idea of a judge declaring a person not guilty. A person&#39;s legal status is cleared of all wrong doing. It is a statement by God that one is innocent of wrong doing. This was accomplished by God. He did it. We didn&#39;t do anything. This has been revealed. Literally the word means to uncover something that was hidden. What a wonderful message God has uncovered for us through the Gospel! This message is the power to create faith in Christ and it is only by faith that we receive the blessings of the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul quotes Habakkuk 2:4 The context of this Old Testament passage is: Habakkuk asked God to do something about all of the evil he sees around him. God replies that he is sending the Babylonians to bring judgment on Israel. Habakkuk then questioned how God could use the Babylonians for this task since they were even more wicked than Israel. God acknowledges the Babylonisn rebellion but in the verses after Hab. 2:4 says he will bring ultimate judgment on them also. In verse four he says but the one who believes God&#39;s statement that they are forgiven will live with the Lord forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;15&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe a situation where someone might be ashamed of the Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can someone overcome that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can the assurance that the Gospel is the power of God help us in sharing Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparing for next week&#39;s class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read Romans 1:18 – 2:16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read Romans – the People&#39;s Bible Pages 23-39&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read Romans 1:18 – 2:16 a second time but this time out loud. (Hearing God&#39;s Word can prompt us to realize additional truths we didn&#39;t grasp with a silent reading.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be prepared to answer: Someone is talking with you and is convinced they haven&#39;t done enough to continue to receive God&#39;s forgiveness. How might you use words from this section to help them see the truth?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 2</title>
      <link>/en/courses/110/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/110/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD&amp;rsquo;S JUDGMENT IS DESERVED UPON ALL GENTILES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 1:18-2:16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to answer: Someone is talking with you and is convinced
they haven&amp;rsquo;t done enough to continue to receive God&amp;rsquo;s forgiveness. How
might you use words from this section to help them see the truth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes the gospel so powerful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 1:18-20&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s wrath, his anger, isn&amp;rsquo;t to defend his wounded pride, it is a
reaction to the evil sinfulness he sees in people. It will be revealed
in all of its terror at the end of time but what Paul is speaking
about here occurs now. He uses the present tense, &amp;ldquo;is being revealed.&amp;rdquo;
The first word, godlessness, refers more to attitudes. Disregarding
God &amp;ndash; he isn&amp;rsquo;t important. Ignoring anything he commands and so I have
no responsibility toward him. The second word, wickedness, points to
actions that are opposed to God&amp;rsquo;s will. God sees every thought and
action of each one of us, nothing will escape his notice and anger.
Humans then try to suppress the truth about God so they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t feel
guilty. People will go to great lengths to keep down the knowledge of
God so that they don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with guilt and their need of
Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has clearly revealed aspects of himself in creation. Evolution
tries to replace God with theories of our origin. As more complex
scientific discoveries are made &amp;ndash; the more we are reminded of the
power and wisdom of God in creation. With each new complex discovery
of our world, the more fantastic the explanation has to become for
those rejecting God. We shake our heads in amazement at what has to be
believed in order to keep God from getting the glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 1:21-25&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how Paul describes the unbelievers as determined not to glorify
God or give thanks to him. God certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t forcing them to rebel
against him. The unbeliever is doing it on their own. Notice also the
beginning of verse 24, the word &amp;ldquo;Therefore.&amp;rdquo; As a result of the
previous actions and attitudes now this follows, &amp;ldquo;God gave them over&amp;rdquo;
even now he doesn&amp;rsquo;t force them to rebel but allows the rebellion to
takes its natural course. As we think about this, don&amp;rsquo;t assume if
somebody fails to glorify God once or twice then suddenly God will
give them over. We have plenty of examples of the patience and mercy
of God to give people multiple chances to repent. There is however a
point, when God says OK &amp;ndash; pursue your rebellion and refusal to
glorify and thank me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They exchange the glory of the creator for lie of created things.
Whether those are objects to represent various created animals or
humans or simply created things like wealth, power or earthly fame. It
is all a lie and isn&amp;rsquo;t the answer to a life with God or to existence
here on earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 1:26-32&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three times we read, &amp;ldquo;God gave them over&amp;rdquo; (24,26,28). Each time it is
another step downward. They have &amp;ldquo;suppressed the truth&amp;rdquo; (18). They
have rejected the natural knowledge of God, his power and his glorious
being evident in the world and decided to live their life in total
disregard of the Lord. They turn to false gods of all kinds, then to
depraved sexual activity and then minds totally corrupted. Twenty-one
different sins are reported. Each one has a negative impact on the
person, discord in the family, and turmoil in a society. Worst of all
it is evidence of people separated from God. Sin never leads to
greater satisfaction or ultimate fulfillment in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What other qualities of God can we learn from nature in addition to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the two listed by Paul?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is every human being without excuse before God? (20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe godlessness and wickedness and then how is it evident in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;our world? (18)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As people repeatedly deny God or any accountability to God for their&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;thoughts and actions what happens to their thinking? (21-22)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What evidence do you see of that in the world around you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People can not only be depraved in their own thinking and actions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but what further step can they take? (32)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it possible for someone on this downward spiral to be turned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;around and brought to faith in Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 2:1-4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who is the person addressed in verse 1 and following? Suddenly Paul
turns to &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rdquo;. In verse 17 he refers to the Jews and he may well be
talking about them at this point already. He could also be talking
about a Gentile, who thinks, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t live a crass immoral life like
the people Paul described in chapter 1. &amp;ldquo;I live a respectable life.&amp;rdquo;
Paul could be addressing a person who is living a more moral life. For
the more moral person it can be easy to pass judgment on the defiant
sinners. The Bible says God&amp;rsquo;s judgment (at the end of time) will be
based on truth (2), the facts as they are before God. The judgment
wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be done based on comparing what we have done to others but on
what we did in comparison to God&amp;rsquo;s perfect will. Yet, God hasn&amp;rsquo;t
struck us with his judgment but has shown kindness, tolerance (the
original word has the idea of holding back judgment) and patience
(giving time for the person to realize their sin). In all of this God
is wanting to lead us to repentance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repentance means to have a change of mind or heart. Our self-righteous
attitude has been crushed as we see our sin and trust only Jesus for
our forgiveness. The unbelievable kindness of God expressed to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEYWORD: REPENTANCE &amp;ndash;&lt;/strong&gt; A change of mind or heart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 2:5-11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul continues his thought, the morally superior person in
self-righteousness judging the crass sinner is storing up anger from
God that will be unleashed on Judgment Day. There is no favoritism by
God he will judge according to what each person has done. Each person
will need to persist in doing good. Not just doing something good
occasionally but always &amp;ndash; persistence. God&amp;rsquo;s standard is perfection.
We all, every single one of us is guilty and fall short. God will give
eternal life to anyone who keeps the law perfectly. The problem is we
can&amp;rsquo;t persist in keeping the law perfectly. In today&amp;rsquo;s entire lesson,
there isn&amp;rsquo;t any gospel, only law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 2:12-16&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verse 13 we have a very important Greek word. Translated, declared
righteous. What is the meaning of that word? Some suggest that it
means make righteous, to reform the sinner, to make a good person out
of a bad person. Look at the context here. The Bible says, that the
person who obeys the law, consistently and completely, that person
will be declared righteous by God. If the person has obeyed the law
perfectly, they aren&amp;rsquo;t a bad person they are already good. They don&amp;rsquo;t
need to be made righteous, they already are, after all they kept the
law perfectly. The word means to declare righteous. There isn&amp;rsquo;t any
other way to understand it here. The one who &amp;ldquo;obeys the law&amp;rdquo; did the
right things and in the final judgment God will declare that the
person is right in his sight. We are talking about the definition of
the Greek word, declare not guilty. This passage is one that clearly
identifies the meaning of the word. That meaning, consistent in the
Bible, is important as we look at passages later in the book of
Romans. Just a quick word about the context here, the point of this
section is that no one is perfectly obedient to the law, therefore no
one will be declared righteous in his sight because we haven&amp;rsquo;t kept
the law. We are all sinners before God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 16 says that &amp;ldquo;God will judge men&amp;rsquo;s secrets.&amp;rdquo; Secrets can be
things we did that most people don&amp;rsquo;t know (maybe no one). Secrets can
be the motives we had for doing what we did, even good things we did.
Secrets can be thoughts we cultivated or had that just went through
our mind in a flash and never returned, if fact we don&amp;rsquo;t even remember
them. Everything will be exposed and nothing hidden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word gospel in verse 16 is used in a broader sense. God can not
overlook sin, judgment is real. We can&amp;rsquo;t save ourselves. God sent
Jesus to save us from our sin. The law and the fact that we are all
sinners along with the good news that Jesus was sent for us was Paul&amp;rsquo;s
message for people. It was the good news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you understand the words, &amp;ldquo;God judgment&amp;hellip;is based on truth&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2:2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can God shown &amp;ldquo;his kindness, tolerance and patience&amp;rdquo; with a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;person to lead him (her) to realize sin in life resulting in
repentance? 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why isn&amp;rsquo;t vs 7, &amp;ldquo;To those who by persistence in doing good&amp;hellip;he will&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;give eternal life&amp;rdquo; a contradiction of Ro.1:17, &amp;ldquo;The righteous will
live by faith&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give evidence in your culture of the natural knowledge of God&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would we also want to refer to other passages, like Romans&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3:21-24, as we share the Word of God from chapter 2?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Preparing for next week&amp;rsquo;s class]{.ul}&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 2:17 &amp;ndash; 3:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans &amp;ndash; the People&amp;rsquo;s Bible Pages 39-56&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 2:17 &amp;ndash; 3:20 a second time but this time out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Hearing God&amp;rsquo;s Word can prompt us to realize additional truths we
didn&amp;rsquo;t grasp with a silent reading.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to answer: Every person you ever meet in your life has a
conscience. A conscience that in part is telling them they have done
somethings that are wrong. How can that be helpful as we share our faith
with someone?&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 3</title>
      <link>/en/courses/110/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/110/3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD&amp;rsquo;S JUDGMENT IS DESERVED UPON ALL JEWISH PEOPLE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 2:17-3:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to answer: Every person you ever meet in your life has a
conscience. A conscience that in part is telling them they have done
some things that are wrong. How can that be helpful as we share our
faith with someone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the meaning and thought of the word &amp;ldquo;declare righteous?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 2:17-24&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous section (Romans 2:1-16) Paul spoke about people who
lived very moral lives. They could have been Gentiles or Jews, but
their lives were marked with far better morals than those described
and convicted of guilt in Romans 1. They are however, still guilty
because they haven&amp;rsquo;t consistently kept the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Paul turns his attention to the Jews in particular. He begins with
a series of clauses. Each starts with the word &amp;ldquo;if&amp;rdquo;. The thought of
each clause is a common held perception the Jews had of themselves.
They would have quickly agreed with the points. I am glad I am a Jew,
I have the law of God and I am in a relationship with God. I know his
will because we are the nation that received the revelations from God.
I have tested the law and approve of what really matters in life. I am
constantly taught by the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul makes a turn in the thought in verse 19. He portrayed their
privileged position as a Jew. Now he describes the attitude of the Jew
toward others. The Jews felt they were in a position to help the
spiritually blind, to teach those in the dark about knowing the true
God, to instruct those who didn&amp;rsquo;t have a clue (foolish) about God, to
help the helpless (infants) to understand the living Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jews were in a unique position but now Paul suddenly starts
raising some questions. Were they learning and applying God&amp;rsquo;s law to
themselves? With each question the initial answer might be, &amp;ldquo;No, I
don&amp;rsquo;t do those things.&amp;rdquo; After a closer examination, they would have to
confess, &amp;ldquo;Yes, I have.&amp;rdquo; Their hypocrisy was obvious to the Gentiles
and they weren&amp;rsquo;t attracted to the Lord but rather spoke against the
God of Israel. They couldn&amp;rsquo;t claim salvation on the basis of the law
and obedience. They were sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We like the Jews also are privileged to have and learn from God&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Word. Why do we need to apply God&amp;rsquo;s law to our lives as Paul is
doing here to the Jews?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can God&amp;rsquo;s name be blasphemed (dishonored) in the eyes of people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;around us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember there is no gospel in these early chapters of Romans, as we&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;apply these words to ourselves why do we need to flee to Jesus for
comfort and strength?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 2:25-29&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jew could still think, but I have been circumcised. That will
count before God. Paul demolishes that thought! Paul&amp;rsquo;s first point is
that circumcision only has value if the law is still kept perfectly.
If one breaks the law, circumcision wouldn&amp;rsquo;t help, the person is like
an uncircumcised individual (vs 25). If the Jew is like an
uncircumcised person, they aren&amp;rsquo;t part of God&amp;rsquo;s people. In verse 26,
Paul reverses it. If an uncircumcised person keeps God&amp;rsquo;s law
consistently (in theory &amp;ndash; this isn&amp;rsquo;t possible because we are all
sinners) they will be regarded as a child of God (circumcised).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul continues by saying the Gentile (uncircumcised) will condemn the
Jew who hasn&amp;rsquo;t kept God&amp;rsquo;s law perfectly. Is that what Jesus was saying
in Matthew 12:41-42? The Gentiles who heard God&amp;rsquo;s call to repentance
will stand in judgment over the Jews who rejected the Savior. The
Jewish trust in their family background, their partial obedience to
God&amp;rsquo;s will and that they were outwardly circumcised has been blown
apart by these words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul isn&amp;rsquo;t done. In verse 28-29, he makes the point that circumcision
is something inward worked by the Spirt in someone&amp;rsquo;s heart and has an
outward action to remind the person they are a child of God. A Jew
before God is first someone whose heart has been changed by the
Spirit. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a new thought in Scripture. Remember Old Testament
passages where God spoke of Israel&amp;rsquo;s uncircumcised hearts (Leviticus
26:41)? God called upon Israel to circumcise their hearts (Deuteronomy
10:16, 30:6). Circumcision was always spiritual with an outward sign
to remind each person. Circumcision was always a cutting of the heart
(cutting away sin &amp;ndash; repentance) and a trust in the compassionate and
gracious God who forgave their sin through the promised Messiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that the identity of God&amp;rsquo;s people isn&amp;rsquo;t based on family or
obedience but on the Spirit working in the heart of a person. The
Bible says, &amp;ldquo;If you belong to Christ, then you are Abraham&amp;rsquo;s seed, and
heirs according to the promise&amp;rdquo; (Galatians 3:29). The believer in
Jesus is Abraham&amp;rsquo;s seed &amp;ndash; a descendant of Abraham &amp;ndash; not by a
physical connection but by a faith like Abraham trusting God&amp;rsquo;s word
and promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can be some dangerous thoughts or attitudes (similar to the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jews) that could give us a false sense of security that we are
God&amp;rsquo;s children?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what way could it be said that every believer, no matter what&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;their ethnic background, is a Jew? 28-29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 3:1-4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul has made the strong point that simply being a circumcised Jew
doesn&amp;rsquo;t result in the person being a child of God and an heir of
eternal life. An inward circumcision of the heart, a belief in God&amp;rsquo;s
Word was critical. This was jarring for most Jews because they
believed the most important things were outward. Anticipating their
object he asks their question, What is the advantage of being a Jew?
He answers quickly you have the inspired Word of God. If someone
doesn&amp;rsquo;t believe the Word of God that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make God&amp;rsquo;s Word a lie.
God&amp;rsquo;s Word remains true and will never be proved false.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the difficulty of this section is that Paul moves quickly from
one question to an answer to another logical question that might be
raised and then a quick answer again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What important reminder for us is found in vs. 1-2?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does God&amp;rsquo;s absolute faithfulness even when we are unfaithful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;give us encouragement and strength?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 3:5-8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Paul continues his rapid fire questions and answers, we get the
impression these were actual human arguments that he has heard people
raise. People do try to challenge the Christian faith by using human
not G odly logic. The questions raised end up trying to ridicule
Christianity by setting up some false logical conclusions that end up
saying, &amp;ldquo;Do evil so that God looks holier and more just!&amp;rdquo; The
accusation has even been made that was Paul&amp;rsquo;s teaching. Paul destroys
each question. He finally simply says, &amp;ldquo;Their condemnation is
deserved.&amp;rdquo; (Romans 3:8) Remember the ongoing point unbelieving Jews
are also guilty before God and every attempt to say anything different
will only end in judgment of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone might argue, &amp;ldquo;If you tell someone their sins are completely,
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fully paid for by Jesus and you simply invite them to believe it.
They will then sin all the more because they think they have
forgiveness.&amp;rdquo; How would you respond?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 3:9-18&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jews are not in a better position nor a worse position before God.
Paul gives the reason in the second half of verse 9 &amp;ldquo;all under sin.&amp;rdquo;
We are all under the continuing condition of sin&amp;rsquo;s domination. Paul
uses seven Old Testament quotations to support his point of the
universal nature of sin among humans. He says twice - all have gone
their own way; four times &amp;ndash; no one is righteous; two times &amp;ndash; not
even one. There are no exceptions &amp;ndash; God can&amp;rsquo;t find anyone who has
kept his will perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He then portrays the terrible results of sin in the world. As an open
grave with a body decaying in it has a strong odor, so are our sinful
throats whose words are foul smelling before God. Mouths that speak
deceitful words, hurtful words (poison), cursing or bitter words.
Bitter words are rebellion against God as we are angry or frustrated
with a difficulty that God has allowed into our life. The actions of
humans reflect sin as well (vs. 15-16). As people live in this
rebellion there is no respect for God but only refusal to listen to
him and a lifting up of self before God. The evidence of the
universality of sin is seen in every single human being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to be &amp;ldquo;under sin&amp;rdquo; (vs 9)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul says, &amp;ldquo;There is no fear of God before their eyes.&amp;rdquo; (18) How is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that the root sin of all others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 3:19-20&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last word of this section is &amp;ldquo;sin.&amp;rdquo; Literally the Greek word means
to miss the mark. It is used in the context of archery and an arrow
missing the bull&amp;rsquo;s eye. This obviously is an important word in the
Bible. God&amp;rsquo;s law identifies the target we are to hit with a perfect
obedience but we miss the mark. We fail to keep it perfectly and so we
fall short of hitting the center of the target. Because of the law we
are aware, conscious, of the fact that we are sinful. The law only
brings us a knowledge of our sin, not the forgiveness of sins. Since
we cannot find the perfection inside of us, we will only find it
outside of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEYWORD: SIN&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Miss the mark, failing to hit the bull&amp;rsquo;s eye of
perfection to the law&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;11&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the word &amp;ldquo;accountable to God&amp;rdquo; communicate to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we have to keep teaching the law over and over again to God&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[PREPARING FOR NEXT WEEK&amp;rsquo;S CLASS]{.ul}&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 3:21 &amp;ndash; 3:31&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans &amp;ndash; the People&amp;rsquo;s Bible Pages 57-67&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 3:21 &amp;ndash; 3:31 a second time but this time out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to answer: Why do we need to continually apply the law to
our own heart?&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 4</title>
      <link>/en/courses/110/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/110/4/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD&amp;rsquo;S DECLARATION OF NOT GUILTY IS FOR ALL PEOPLE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 3:21 &amp;ndash; 3:31&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we need to continually apply the law to our own heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Romans 3:21-24&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul stated the dreadful predicament every human being faces before
God in the previous chapters. Every single person, no matter what
race, Jew or Gentile, moral or immoral, religious or irreligious, is
guilty and without excuse before God. Suddenly in vs 21, he begins,
&amp;ldquo;But now.&amp;rdquo; There is a righteousness (see Greek word below), a
declaration of innocence that has its source in God. It has nothing to
do with obedience to the law. God has revealed it. He has put it out
into the open for all to see. The Law and the prophets (Old Testament
writers) spoke of free forgiveness through faith not only for the Jews
but also for the Gentiles. Twice (vs 21,22) Paul emphasized this
righteousness comes from God. How does this righteousness come to an
individual person? Through faith in Jesus, we simply believe what God
has said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again he states that there is no difference between Jew and
Gentile &amp;ndash; every single human being has sinned. Those same people,
every single human being, were declared not guilty by the payment
Christ made for the world. God repeatedly says that the whole world
was declared not guilty through Jesus sacrifice. God recorded John the
Baptists words for us, &amp;ldquo;Look the Lamb of God who takes away the sin of
[the world]{.ul}.&amp;rdquo; (Jn 1:29) God&amp;rsquo;s Word says, &amp;ldquo;God was reconciling
[the world]{.ul} to himself in Christ, not counting men&amp;rsquo;s sins against
them&amp;rdquo; (2 Cor. 5:19). The Bible says, &amp;ldquo;For there is one God and one
mediator between God and men, the man Christ Jesus, who gave himself
as a ransom for [all men]{.ul}.&amp;rdquo; (1 Tim. 2:5) Of course we could
simply recall Jesus words, &amp;ldquo;For God so loved [the world]{.ul} that he
gave his one and only Son&amp;rdquo; (Jn 3:16). Jesus didn&amp;rsquo;t give himself for
some percentage of the world&amp;rsquo;s population. He gave himself for the
world &amp;ndash; yes all human beings. Every single human being has been
declared not guilty before God through Jesus. That declaration is
given freely. We can&amp;rsquo;t in any way earn it or somehow pay for it. It is
a gift from God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEYWORD: RIGHTEOUSNESS&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Declare not guilty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A word that comes from the courtroom of the Romans. It means that a
judge has declared a person cleared of the charge that was brought
against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does this section of Romans and all of Scripture bring out the
teaching that the whole world has been declared not guilty before
God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does God&amp;rsquo;s world-wide declaration of innocence become the
possession of an individual person? (22)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the whole world has been declared innocent, why doesn&amp;rsquo;t
everybody go to heaven?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why can you walk up to any person anywhere and confidently say to
them, &amp;ldquo;Jesus has paid for your sins. You are forgiven before God&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 3:25-26&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul continues to describe how God had all people declared not guilty
before him without compromising his holy justice to punish wrongdoing.
In vs 25 the word translated, &amp;ldquo;God presented him&amp;rdquo; has the idea of
something or someone set out in front of people, doing a public
display. God did something very public with his Son. He calls it &amp;ldquo;a
sacrifice of atonement.&amp;rdquo; That is an interesting word. It means &amp;ldquo;to
satisfy someone so his anger is gone.&amp;rdquo; The word is also connected to
the Old Testament Great Day of Atonement, celebrated every year.
Professor Panning explained one aspect of that festival in the
People&amp;rsquo;s Bible. There is another aspect to it. The high priest took
the blood of an animal into the Holy of Holies and sprinkled it on the
cover of the Ark of the Covenant. Atonement was made for sin. God was
satisfied so his anger over sin was gone. Everybody knew an animal
didn&amp;rsquo;t take away sin before God, but this symbolized what would take
place when Messiah came. Jesus blood was offered in the Holy of Holies
in heaven (Heb 9:11-14). The cover of the ark was where God&amp;rsquo;s justice
and his mercy meet. With Christ&amp;rsquo;s sacrifice God&amp;rsquo;s justice and mercy
met. The sin of the world was not forgotten but was punished through
Jesus blood. Paul emphasizes that God had left the sins of Old
Testament people unpunished. He was patient, waiting until Jesus came.
So God is just &amp;ndash; he punishes wrong doing and also the one who
justifies. Jesus payment for the sin of the world becomes ours simply
through faith as we believe what Jesus did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEYWORD: SACRIFICE OF ATONEMENT&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Satisfy someone so his anger is
gone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What comes first God&amp;rsquo;s declaration of not guilty because of Jesus or
faith in Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus paid for the sins of everybody. That means even the people
that end up in hell had their sins paid for. Why did they end up in
hell if Jesus paid for their sins?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 3:27-31&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boasting is a part of our self-centered sinful nature. Some cultures
may express it more forcefully in words and other cultures or people
may keep boasting confined to their thoughts. But all boasting is
excluded in the Christian faith because we do nothing to get acquitted
before God. Jesus did it all with his life and death for all people.
God gives us a right standing before him simply through faith in Jesus
blood. The word translated, &amp;ldquo;we maintain&amp;rdquo; vs. 28 has the idea of
thinking something through very carefully and then the word can
include what one realizes after thinking it through carefully. After
thinking through carefully what God&amp;rsquo;s Word says, it is obvious we are
acquitted before God through faith in Jesus and not by anything we
might do. Jew and Gentile alike are not guilty before God through
faith in Jesus. I suspect you noticed in vs 30 the words, &amp;ldquo;will
justify&amp;rdquo;. How does that fit in with everything Paul has been saying?
Remember the first point &amp;ndash; Jesus came to take away the sin of the
world. His life and death for all humans produced the Father&amp;rsquo;s verdict
of not guilty for all humans. The second point made: that universal
acquittal becomes the possession of an individual person through trust
in Jesus. Faith being created in people will continue into the future
and they will receive the benefit of what Christ did for them. Faith
doesn&amp;rsquo;t contribute anything to our acquittal before God. It receives
that acquittal through believing what God has said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul doesn&amp;rsquo;t want a wrong impression to be given. He isn&amp;rsquo;t saying in
all of this that the law is useless. It has a very important purpose.
The law still reveals our sin and the very just anger God has with us.
If we don&amp;rsquo;t understand the anger of God over our rebellion against
him, we can&amp;rsquo;t understand it being satisfied at the cross through Jesus
death for us. God&amp;rsquo;s law and gospel are vital in the Christian faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is boasting about ourselves and how we live contrary to the
Christian faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are law and gospel both important to be shared with people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[PREPARING FOR NEXT WEEK&amp;rsquo;S CLASS]{.ul}&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 4:1 &amp;ndash; 15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans &amp;ndash; the People&amp;rsquo;s Bible Pages 67-74&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 4:1 &amp;ndash; 15 a second time but this time out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review Scripture and be prepared to talk about how Jesus life, death
and resurrection resulted in God declaring everybody not guilty before
him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 5</title>
      <link>/en/courses/110/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/110/5/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD SAVES THROUGH FAITH IN JESUS,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TWO OLD TESTAMENT EXAMPLES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 4:1 &amp;ndash; 15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review Scripture and be prepared to talk about how Jesus life, death
and resurrection resulted in God declaring everybody not guilty before
him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 4:1 - 8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul previously said that the Old Testament, the law and the prophets
(3:21) testified that we are acquitted before God through faith. Now
he gives two examples. Abraham, the father of the nation and David,
the great king of the nation are used to emphasize the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Abraham Paul says he had nothing to brag about before
God. If he had done even just a small part to earn his acquittal, he
would have something to brag about. That isn&amp;rsquo;t how Abraham was cleared
of all wrong doing before God. In the context of Genesis 15, God told
Abraham a child would come from his own body and a nation so numerous
would follow that they would be like the stars in the sky. Previously
God had promised that the Savior would come from his family line (Gen.
12:3). Abraham simply believed what God said. Paul quotes word for
word the passage from Gen. 15:6. The word translated &amp;ldquo;credited&amp;rdquo; (vs 3)
is used frequently in business transactions. It involves putting
something on a person&amp;rsquo;s account as a credit. Notice God put it on
Abraham&amp;rsquo;s account, Abraham didn&amp;rsquo;t put it on his account. God put on
Abraham&amp;rsquo;s account, &amp;ldquo;acquitted, cleared of all sin, not guilty&amp;rdquo;. What
did Abraham do? Nothing &amp;ndash; he just believed what God said to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to get a credit on your account. One can work for
it or it can be given. God acquitted the non-worker (vs 5). It was a
gift given to the one who trusts God. Notice it describes God as the
one &amp;ldquo;who justifies the wicked.&amp;rdquo; It doesn&amp;rsquo;t say the believer but the
wicked. We are all wicked before God by nature aren&amp;rsquo;t we? The wicked,
the entire mass of humanity, were acquitted, declared not guilty. The
one who believes God&amp;rsquo;s statement receives that forgiveness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David provides the same lesson. This is a quote from Psalm 32:1-2.
David starts with a generalization and then in the following verses
explains how he tried to hide his sin, but then confessed it and the
forgiveness God was proclaimed to him. In the quote David is simply
saying how happy a person is who knows their transgressions and sins
are forgiven. He speaks of &amp;ldquo;transgressions&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; many lawless acts a
person has done in their life. He speaks of &amp;ldquo;sins&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; many failures to
fall short of what God demands. God forgave, covered them. Any sin in
the future, God will not count against them. All of this happens
simply through faith in God&amp;rsquo;s word of acquittal. Both are held up as
examples of Old Testament believers, none more prominent that Abraham
and David, who were declared not guilty before God simply through
faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEYWORD: CREDITED &amp;ndash;&lt;/strong&gt; Putting something on a person&amp;rsquo;s account as a
credit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How are wages and a gift different and how does that apply to our
spiritual life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does Scripture teach about how Abraham became righteous before
God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Paul stress that righteousness is a pure gift from God? Vs
5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the difference in meaning of the words &amp;ldquo;transgressions&amp;rdquo; and
&amp;ldquo;sins&amp;rdquo;? Vs 7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do verses 7-8 support the truth that God credits righteousness
apart from works?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 4:9 - 12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul made the point that Abraham and David were both cleared of all
wrongdoing before God simply through faith in the Messiah. Since both
of them were Jews, he wants to be sure that a wrong impression isn&amp;rsquo;t
given. He refers to Abraham. He was credited with being acquitted of
all wrongdoing long before he was ever circumcised. Circumcision came
nearly 20 years later. Circumcision was a sign, a seal, that in an
outward way reminded Abraham that he was credited with forgiveness
earlier in time. Circumcision was a sign that identified a person as
belonging to God&amp;rsquo;s family through faith. Abraham was an uncircumcised
believer and thus is a spiritual father of all uncircumcised
believers. Abraham was also a circumcised believer and thus a
spiritual father of all circumcised believers. All who believe as
Abraham believed God&amp;rsquo;s Word are spiritual children of Abraham. Every
believer can claim Abraham as a spiritual father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it important to see that Abraham was acquitted of all sin
before he was circumcised?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can Abraham bear the name &amp;ldquo;father of all who believe &amp;ndash; whether
circumcised or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes you a child of Abraham?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 4:13-15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abraham wasn&amp;rsquo;t declared not guilty because of circumcision (9-12) nor
was it because of any law that he was given and kept (13-15). Paul was
very methodically removing every thought which someone might have to
still believe I have to obey God in order to receive his promise. Law
only produces anger &amp;ndash; some say God&amp;rsquo;s anger over disobedience, others
argue man&amp;rsquo;s anger because it is an impossible demand to keep law.
Either way it results in anger. A right standing before God comes only
through believing what he has promised and done in Jesus (13b).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do efforts to live by the law make faith and God&amp;rsquo;s gospel
promise worthless?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give two examples of religious beliefs and practices that express a
&amp;ldquo;live by law&amp;rdquo; teaching and mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[PREPARING FOR NEXT WEEK&amp;rsquo;S CLASS]{.ul}&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 4:16 &amp;ndash; 25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans &amp;ndash; the People&amp;rsquo;s Bible Pages 74-78&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 4:16 &amp;ndash; 25 a second time but this time out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you say that an Old Testament person got to be innocent before God
and thus got to heaven in the same way or a different way from a New
Testament believer?&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 6</title>
      <link>/en/courses/110/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/110/6/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD PORTRAYS ABRAHAM AS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE FATHER OF ALL BELIEVERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 4:16 &amp;ndash;25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you say that an Old Testament person got to be innocent before
God and thus got to heaven in the same way or a different way from a
New Testament believer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 4:16-17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In last week&amp;rsquo;s reading, Paul said that law, any kind of law, will
bring transgression which will result in God&amp;rsquo;s anger. The law always
demands, &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t do&amp;rdquo; but we always fail to be perfect. Notice
the first word of vs 16, &amp;ldquo;therefore&amp;rdquo;, Paul is now making a conclusion.
The promise of being a forgiven child of God comes by faith. It is by
grace. It is a free gift given by God. Since it is given by God, it
can be guaranteed (16). Paul makes the same point that this guaranteed
promise is for Jew and Gentile alike. Abraham is the father of us all
(16). Notice an important point &amp;ndash; a believer in God&amp;rsquo;s promise of a
Savior is a child of Abraham, a member of his family. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t make
any difference if we are Jewish, or northern European, from the far
east, Africa or the western world. Whoever has the same faith as
Abraham is part of his family and thus a part of God&amp;rsquo;s family. Faith
in what Jesus has done for humanity unites us all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many guarantees that we experience from companies have limits and
exceptions. How is God&amp;rsquo;s guarantee different?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the thought that you are a child of Abraham a new thought for
you? Why is it an important point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 4:17b-25&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God had spoken what may seem to be impossible promises. Abraham and
Sarah were going to have a child. There were two major obstacles, both
Abraham and Sarah were beyond the age of having children. From the
perspective of child-bearing, they were both as good as dead. In spite
of that, God still, &amp;ldquo;calls things that are not as though they
were.&amp;quot;(17) The eventual child, Isaac, didn&amp;rsquo;t exist yet God spoke as
though he did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word translated, &amp;ldquo;he faced the fact&amp;rdquo; (19) has the idea of someone
thinking deeply about something. Abraham realized reality, he and
Sarah were well beyond the age of becoming parents. He wasn&amp;rsquo;t blind to
reality. He wasn&amp;rsquo;t a simpleton. He just believed God had the power and
the will to do what he said, no matter what the physical circumstances
were (21). He trusted what God promised, &amp;ldquo;This is why &amp;lsquo;it was credited
to him as righteousness.&amp;rdquo; (22) Those words were written for your
assurance as well, God does the same through faith in his promise of
forgiveness through Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vs.24 &amp;ndash; Why did the Father hand over his son to death? He did it for
our sins, because of our sin. Why did the Father raise Jesus to life?
He did it for our justification. We were declared not guilty when
Jesus was still on the cross. He had paid for the sin of the world.
Because we were declared not guilty already on Good Friday, God raised
Jesus to life. He was raised to life to proclaim the victory, here was
real life evidence that sin had been paid for by Jesus. He is risen!!
Alleluia! Our forgiveness is assured &amp;ndash; believe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What comfort can we take in the fact that God gives life to the dead
and calls things into existence that did not exist before? (v.17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the basis for Abraham&amp;rsquo;s hope for the future? (v.18)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List some promises of God that are the basis for our hope in the
future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give an example of times when God leads us to &amp;ldquo;hope&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; believe in
the face of human hopelessness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Abraham&amp;rsquo;s experience with God in the matter of receiving
righteousness benefit us? Vs 23-24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to vs 25, what was the purpose of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus death?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus being raised to life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[PREPARING FOR NEXT WEEK&amp;rsquo;S CLASS]{.ul}&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 5:1 - 21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans &amp;ndash; the People&amp;rsquo;s Bible Pages 78-93&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 5:1 &amp;ndash; 21 a second time but this time out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does our faith get strengthen in God&amp;rsquo;s promises as Abraham&amp;rsquo;s was
strengthened? Vs. 20&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 7</title>
      <link>/en/courses/110/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/110/7/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD GIVES US PEACE AND A NEW LIFE THROUGH JESUS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 5:1 &amp;ndash;21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does our faith get strengthen in God&amp;rsquo;s promises as Abraham&amp;rsquo;s was
strengthened? Vs. 20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 5:1-2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul begins with the word, &amp;ldquo;therefore.&amp;rdquo; That points us back to
probably all of Romans 3:21-4:21. The whole world was declared not
guilty, acquitted before God, of any wrongdoing because of the blood
of Jesus. We personally received the benefit of that fact through
trusting what God had said (not guilty). A result is peace. There is
no peace for the wicked (Is. 48:22). Humans try to run away from God
because of guilt. For the believer in Jesus we live in peace. The idea
of the word translated &amp;ldquo;gained access&amp;rdquo; is getting into a restricted
place to meet someone of great importance. We have gained access into
God&amp;rsquo;s room of grace. We don&amp;rsquo;t just visit it on occasion, we live in
it! He also says that we rejoice in hope. Hope always points to the
future &amp;ndash; we don&amp;rsquo;t have it now but we are totally confident we will be
in the glory of God in the future. We rejoice in that hope. We can&amp;rsquo;t
stop talking about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What blessings does Paul list because we are justified through faith
in Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does the picture of always standing (living) in God&amp;rsquo;s room of
grace impact how we perceive our life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is wrong with this comment made by a believer, &amp;ldquo;I hope I am not
sinning when I die&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their understanding of sin in their life &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their understanding of God&amp;rsquo;s grace &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why can we be so confident in our Christian hope?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 5: 3-5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believers have an amazing hope for the future that nothing can
diminish or destroy. We praise God for this hope. Hope always points
to the future, a future that we have through Christ Jesus. Now Paul
says we can also praise God for our sufferings. The word suffering
means literally to be pressed down. Situations can press down on us or
squeeze us. During those pressing situations, we can know (ongoing,
clear understanding) that suffering can result in perseverance. A
patience, a determination to continue on because we know that a loving
God is watching over us. This joy that we have in sufferings is not a
simple strong resolve nor is it finding some strange pleasure in
misery but an awareness that God has a divine plan and purpose in
Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This joy in sufferings produces character. The word has the idea of
acquiring good traits as a result of a test. God is developing good
traits in us through these difficulties. Paul then brings us back to
our hope. God has poured out his love into our hearts by the Holy
Spirit. A love already demonstrated by sending Jesus to be our Savior.
The hope that we have because of Jesus will never disappoint us or be
some kind of illusion. On Judgment Day our hope will be fulfilled and
proved true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are Christians able to rejoice in suffering?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can God use suffering to develop our Christian character?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 5:6 &amp;ndash; 11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coming of Jesus wasn&amp;rsquo;t random nor was it prompted by humanity, it
was the right time set by God. When he came we were powerless, ungodly
and sinners. Humanity, individually or collectively, could offer no
valid reason why Jesus should come and redeem us. The sacrifice of the
blood of Jesus is an amazing act of love. There is no comparison to
any human act of love. Notice it says, &amp;ldquo;God demonstrates his own love
for us.&amp;rdquo; Everyday his love is demonstrated to us in Christ. Verses 9
and 10 use two different words to communicate what Jesus has done for
us, justified and reconciled. The word justified puts it in a legal
context, we are acquitted of all wrongdoing before God. Reconciled
puts it in a personal context, we are no longer enemies of God but
friends with him through Christ. As forgiven children of God we have a
joy in life. A joy in the Lord himself. A joy in God and what he has
done for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEWORD: RECONCILED&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; No longer an enemy but a friend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does Paul stress that Jesus&amp;rsquo; sacrifice was one of undeserved and
unexpected love for us and others in vs. 6-8?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you say to a person who claims that Jesus died for us
because people were worth saving?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over what things does the God who justified sinners teach us to
rejoice in this section? (vs1-11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 5: 12 - 17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam&amp;rsquo;s one sin impacted every one of his descendants. Adam lost the
image of God with his sin and now had a sinful nature. That sinful
nature was present in every person that followed him. All future
people would be sinners. With sin entering the human race death also
came, the wages of sin. Think of death as the idea of separation.
Physical death result from sin &amp;ndash; separating of the soul from the
body. Spiritual death occurred with Adam&amp;rsquo;s sin &amp;ndash; separating of people
from a relationship with God. Eternal death occurred as people were
eternally separated from God. Death of all kinds entered the world
through Adam&amp;rsquo;s one sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus brings life to this wretched human situation. Think of life as
connecting. Physical life means body and soul are connected, spiritual
life means a person is connected to God in a relationship, eternal
life means that connected relationship with God extends into eternity.
Jesus provides the answer to our human need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What terrible things did Adam bring into the world? (12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theologians have called the sin described in vs 12 as &amp;ldquo;original sin&amp;rdquo;
or &amp;ldquo;inherited sin&amp;rdquo;. What do these terms explain about sin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are &amp;ldquo;the many&amp;rdquo; of vs. 19?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 5:18 &amp;ndash; 21&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verse 18 expresses again what has been said many times before by Paul.
The result of Adam&amp;rsquo;s sin was the condemnation of all people throughout
the world. The result of Christ&amp;rsquo;s action is the declaration by God
that all the people of the world are acquitted of all wrongdoing. The
declaration of innocence by God brings life to people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mosaic law was added to increase sin. God&amp;rsquo;s purpose wasn&amp;rsquo;t so that
people would sin more but that they would be aware of the magnitude of
their sin before God. Now there were specific commands and as people
failed to keep them perfectly in thought, word and deed, they would
realize how numerous their sins were. With God&amp;rsquo;s total forgiveness for
all sin, they realized even more the magnitude of God&amp;rsquo;s grace. We not
only live in that grace God wants &amp;ldquo;grace to reign&amp;rdquo; (21) in human
hearts through Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;13&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does grace &amp;ldquo;increase all the more&amp;rdquo; when an awareness of sin and
its consequences increases? (20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give some ways that &amp;ldquo;grace&amp;rdquo; rules or reigns over &amp;ldquo;sin&amp;rdquo; in believers,
hearts and lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[PREPARING FOR NEXT WEEK&amp;rsquo;S CLASS]{.ul}&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 6:1-14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans &amp;ndash; the People&amp;rsquo;s Bible Pages 95 - 103&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 6:1&amp;ndash;14 a second time but this time out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the two main points that Paul brings out in 5:12&amp;ndash;21?&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 8</title>
      <link>/en/courses/110/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/110/8/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD MAKES US ALIVE IN CHRIST JESUS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 6:1 &amp;ndash;14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the two main points that Paul brings out in 5:12&amp;ndash;21?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 6:1&amp;ndash;4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul stated previously, &amp;ldquo;Where sin increased, grace increased all the
more.&amp;rdquo; (5:20) Paul&amp;rsquo;s point was that with the giving of the law of
Moses, human beings became more aware of all the commands they
disobeyed. They have a growing understanding of the depth and darkness
of their guilt and a greater understanding of the depth and height of
God&amp;rsquo;s grace. When some people heard that, they reasoned then lets
continue to sin so that God&amp;rsquo;s grace can shine more and more. Paul
rejected that line of thought in the strongest of terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He discusses what happens when a person is baptized. Baptized in
Christ, connects us to the acquittal that Christ already accomplished
and it becomes ours through faith. As a result of Spirit implanted
faith a new attitude is instilled in us. Because of our new
relationship with Jesus, we no longer have the same relationship with
sin. We don&amp;rsquo;t love sinning any more. In Paul&amp;rsquo;s words, &amp;ldquo;We died to sin&amp;rdquo;
(2). That loving relationship with sin is over. So his question, &amp;ldquo;How
can we live in it (sin) any longer?&amp;rdquo; (2) Baptism connected us to
Jesus, his death and his resurrection. With the death of Christ, he
carried our sin, once for all. Jesus would never have anything to do
with sin again. All the world&amp;rsquo;s sin was paid by Jesus. He died to sin
(10). In our baptism we are connected to Jesus and his payment for sin
and like Jesus died to the mastery of sin. (14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our baptism we were also connected to the resurrection of Jesus. In
Paul&amp;rsquo;s words that &amp;ldquo;we too may live a new life&amp;rdquo; (4). In this new
relationship with Jesus, we have a new attitude in life. In thankful
love for his grace filled forgiveness, we want to serve our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEYWORD: GRACE&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; God&amp;rsquo;s undeserved love for all people expressed by
Jesus coming to pay for all sin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What powerful work and blessing does baptism bring to a person?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the parallel in these verses between Christ and us in his
death and in his resurrection?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 6:5 &amp;ndash; 11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul begins this section stating that &amp;ldquo;We have been united with him in
his death&amp;hellip;in his resurrection&amp;rdquo; (5). With the completed payment for
sin by Christ, he was done with sin. He didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything to do
with it anymore. He was dead to it. We in our baptism are united to
his death, we no longer want anything to do with sin. It no longer has
total dominance over us &amp;ndash; we are no longer slaves to it (6). In
baptism we are united to his resurrection &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;we will also live with
him.&amp;rdquo; (8) We live this new life now and on into the future. A new life
because we are &amp;ldquo;alive to God in Christ Jesus.&amp;rdquo; (11) The believer has a
new identity, dead to sin &amp;ndash; no longer wants to sin (although we
obviously still have sins of weakness that Paul will address later)
and a new desire to live to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the risen Christ&amp;rsquo;s relationship with death? (9-10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the positive result of our old sinful nature being crucified
with Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it mean, &amp;ldquo;Jesus lives to God&amp;rdquo;? (10)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 6:12&amp;ndash;14&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul has stressed the new attitude that we have because of Jesus in
the previous sections. Now he begins to outline how that attitude
works out into the actions of life. While we have a new identity in
Christ, the battle with sin continues throughout our life. He
emphasizes both the negative, &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t let sin reign&amp;rdquo; and the positive,
&amp;ldquo;offer yourselves to God&amp;rdquo;. Our sinful nature will raise its ugly head
to present evil desires that can be expressed through our eyes, ears,
hands, feet and every part of our body. We don&amp;rsquo;t let sin rule by
defeating those desires but also by repentance. We come before our
Savior God with sorrow over our failures, hear his wonderous assurance
of forgiveness and a desire to live a new life in Christ. We offer the
same parts of our body to serve our God in the actions of our daily
life. Our motivation isn&amp;rsquo;t the demands of the law or a compulsion to
keep the law to satisfy God. We are forgiven through Christ. We live
under grace. His love demonstrated toward us through Christ motivates
us. His pure love freely given prompts and grows our thankful love.
Our motivation is the Gospel. God&amp;rsquo;s gracious good news powers our
life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As people who are alive in Christ and dead to sin, what will
believers:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A) refuse to do? 12-13a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B) strive to do? 13b&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give some examples of how we can use our bodies in either&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The service of sin]{.ul} [The service of God]{.ul}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify some differences between law being our master and grace
being our master.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[PREPARING FOR NEXT WEEK&amp;rsquo;S CLASS]{.ul}&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 6:15&amp;ndash;7:6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans &amp;ndash; the People&amp;rsquo;s Bible Pages 103-112&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 6:15&amp;ndash;7:6 a second time but this time out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does being &amp;ldquo;under grace&amp;rdquo; change everything in life?&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 9</title>
      <link>/en/courses/110/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/110/9/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD ENABLES US TO LIVE FOR HIM UNDER GRACE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 6:15 &amp;ndash; 7:6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does being &amp;ldquo;under grace&amp;rdquo; change everything in life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 6:15 &amp;ndash; 6:18&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a slave doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a worthy goal of life. The Bible says
we will be a slave, someone or something will control of our will and
thoughts. Either we are controlled by our sinful nature or we are
controlled by Jesus. The result of serving sin is death (physical and
spiritual &amp;ndash; separation from God). The result of serving Jesus is
doing God pleasing things (righteousness). The believer in the payment
for sin that Christ made has been moved by the Spirit to be under
Jesus&amp;rsquo; control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What great transformation has God worked in the life of a believer?
(17-18)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does Paul say, &amp;ldquo;Thanks be to God&amp;rdquo;? (17)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 6: 19 &amp;ndash; 23&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice in verses 21-22 that Paul uses similar words to set up the
contrast between the two slaveries. The benefit of serving sin is a
sense of shame because of our previous attitudes and actions finally
resulting in eternal separation from God (death). The believer has
been set free from our sin and guilt through the payment of Christ. We
willingly became slaves of God which prompted us to strive to do and
think things that are God pleasing (holiness) and the final result is
eternal life. Obviously our living a holy life doesn&amp;rsquo;t earn the final
result &amp;ndash; eternal life, that would contradict everything that
Scripture says. Eternal life is the final benefit we receive through
Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEYWORD: DEATH&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Separation 1) physical death -soul separated from
body, 2) spiritual death &amp;ndash; person separated from God (no relationship),
3) eternal death &amp;ndash; separated eternally from God&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEYWORD:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;LIFE&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Connected 2) physical life &amp;ndash; soul and body
connected, 2) spiritual life &amp;ndash; person connected to God (a
relationship), 3) eternal life &amp;ndash; eternally connected to God&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the huge disadvantages of being a slave to sin? (19-21,23)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the huge advantages of being a slave to God? (19,22-23)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some of the contrasts between the first half of verse 23
and the second half?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 7: 1 &amp;ndash; 6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul uses an illustration to make the point that we are free from our
old relationship with the law. A woman is bound to her husband as long
as he is alive. If he dies, she is freed from that binding
relationship to start a new marriage relationship with another. The
spiritual point is that we are bound to the law, to trying to keep it
perfectly to earn our favor with God and eternal life. Death broke
that relationship, not our death but the death of Jesus (vs.4). His
death payment on the cross for us frees us to a new binding
relationship. In this new relationship with God, &amp;ldquo;we serve in a new
way&amp;rdquo; (6). The Spirit leads us to serve the Lord. We no longer have an
attitude, &amp;ldquo;I have to serve&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;I must serve&amp;rdquo;. Our new way in the
Spirit is, &amp;ldquo;I want to serve&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;I gladly and willingly serve&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens to a believer&amp;rsquo;s relationship to the law and to God
because of saving work of Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to vs 5 what moral and spiritual conditions exist when
people are controlled by their sinful natures?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what sense are believers &amp;ldquo;released from the law&amp;rdquo; (6)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[PREPARING FOR NEXT WEEK&amp;rsquo;S CLASS]{.ul}&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 7:7 &amp;ndash; 25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans &amp;ndash; the People&amp;rsquo;s Bible Pages 112 - 123&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 7:7 &amp;ndash; 25 a second time but this time out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe how we serve the Lord in the new way of the Spirit (6)?&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 10</title>
      <link>/en/courses/110/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/110/10/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;G&lt;strong&gt;OD GIVES US ULTIMATE VICTORY EVEN AS WE STRUGGLE WITH SIN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 7:7 &amp;ndash; 25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe how we serve the Lord in the new way of the Spirit. (6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 7: 7 &amp;ndash; 12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul said, &amp;ldquo;the sinful passions aroused by the law were at work in our
bodies&amp;rdquo; (7:5). The perverse natural mind of a human might conclude
that the problem is with the law of God. Since it is God&amp;rsquo;s law, God is
the problem. I certainly am not to blame! Paul exposed this whole line
of thought as totally wrong. Paul said &amp;ldquo;sin&amp;rdquo; is the problem. Later in
vs 18, he calls it our sinful nature. In Ephesians 4:22 he calls it
our old self. The sinful nature we all inherited from our parents is
what is leading us astray. It rebels against God&amp;rsquo;s holy law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul uses himself as an example. He refers back to an earlier time of
his life when he was an active Pharisee. He believed God&amp;rsquo;s law only
spoke about outward actions. He honestly thought he wasn&amp;rsquo;t in any
danger before God (vs 9). He even summarized his attitude then, &amp;ldquo;as
for legalistic righteousness, faultless&amp;rdquo; (Philippians 3:6). Then he
became aware that even desires and thoughts can be sinful. Suddenly
his sinful nature was prompting all kinds of sinful thoughts and
desires. His point &amp;ndash; the law doesn&amp;rsquo;t create sin and death, our sinful
nature is the culprit. The law is good. It only intends to benefit a
person. He will teach us more about our sinful nature in the next
section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What important purpose does the law fulfill? (vs7-11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does the sinful nature respond to this helpful purpose the law
of God offers us? (vs.8,11)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some of the deceptive rationalizations sin proposes to
trick us into violating God&amp;rsquo;s law?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 7: 13 - 20&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section my English Bible (NIV84) has the word &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; twenty-one
times. There isn&amp;rsquo;t any reason from the text to assume anything but the
obvious, Paul is speaking about himself. In this section Paul uses the
present tense completely. He is describing himself as he is: a
converted and we can certainly say mature believer. Yet he knows there
is a dark power at work within him. His sinful nature (vs 18) is still
very powerful and active in his heart and life. Living &amp;ldquo;in this new
way of the Spirit&amp;rdquo; (6) doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that the sinful nature is
eliminated from the believer. Paul&amp;rsquo;s personal experience is the same
that the Roman Christians were experiencing, there is a daily struggle
with the sinful nature in a believer. While Paul takes personal
responsibility for his continued imperfections (notice the &amp;ldquo;I&amp;quot;s), he
also says that the culprit is the sinful nature within him. Every
believer, no matter how mature we are or new to the faith that we are,
will have that conflict within us. Our sinful nature will continue to
resist the Spirit and its leading of our life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEYWORD &amp;ndash; SINFUL NATURE&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; A mind and heart incline only toward
evil, inherited from Adam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;NEW MAN, INNER BEING &amp;ndash;&lt;/strong&gt; New heart and mind created by the Holy
Spirit by faith in Jesus, Delights in doing God&amp;rsquo;s will and fights
against the sinful nature&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain what it means for a person to recognize sin as &amp;ldquo;utterly
sinful.&amp;rdquo; (vs.13)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What great conflict does Paul portray in vs. 14-20?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What insights about a believer&amp;rsquo;s sinful nature do we gain in vs.
14-20?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What insights about a believer&amp;rsquo;s spiritual nature do we gain in vs.
14-20?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 7: 21 &amp;ndash; 25&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every moment of everyday, a believer in Jesus has two competing
principles at work within him or her. Our inner being and the sinful
nature are not at all compatible. Paul portrays it as a war being
waged within each of us. It is a war of control over our heart and
life. Battles that are too frequently won by the sinful nature. Paul
express a frustration with himself and a despair because he finds
himself violating God&amp;rsquo;s will. He knows what the consequences are &amp;ndash;
death (24). He can&amp;rsquo;t change his sinful nature nor can he live a
perfect life. He pleads for rescue and reminds himself and all
believers that Jesus is the answer. He is our ongoing Rescuer and
Savior. As Martin Luther said, we are saint and sinner simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does Paul&amp;rsquo;s use of the present tense throughout today&amp;rsquo;s study
emphasize to us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t the believer be surprised that he or she still
struggles with sin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does a Christian find spiritual relief from the struggle with
our sinful nature? 25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What benefits are there in having a good understanding of the
struggle that goes on between the sinful and believing nature of a
Christian?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[PREPARING FOR NEXT WEEK&amp;rsquo;S CLASS]{.ul}&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 8:1&amp;ndash;17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans &amp;ndash; the People&amp;rsquo;s Bible Pages 123 - 133&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 8:1&amp;ndash;17 a second time but this time out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is Paul&amp;rsquo;s teaching about the sinful nature and the new inner being
in the believer confirmed in your own life?&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 11</title>
      <link>/en/courses/110/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/110/11/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD GIVES US THE HOLY SPIRIT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHICH EXERTS CONTROL OVER US&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 8:1&amp;ndash;17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is Paul&amp;rsquo;s teaching about the sinful nature and the new inner being
in the believer confirmed in your own life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 8: 1 &amp;ndash; 8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul said in chapter 7 that living the Christian life will not be
easy. We have a sinful nature that is constantly with us and
frequently leading us into sin. It is an ongoing battle. Now, he
emphasized the Spirit and its mighty influence in the believer&amp;rsquo;s life.
Anyone who is in Christ Jesus, think of it as in the sphere of Christ
Jesus, there is no condemnation. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a single judgment that
can be raised against a believer. The reason, &amp;ldquo;because&amp;rdquo; (vs 2), is
Jesus set me free from the control of sin and death. Sin and its
condemnation resulting in eternal separation from God is gone. The law
itself could never accomplish this. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t produce a single
acquittal before God. The law was powerless to do that, not because of
a problem with the law, but the sinful nature only rebelled against
God&amp;rsquo;s will. God went into action and solved the problem. Here is a
listing of what God did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sent his own Son - Jesus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sent him in human likeness &amp;ndash; had a true humanity and real flesh and
blood. Phil 2:7 &amp;ldquo;human likeness&amp;rdquo; however he had no sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to be a sin offering &amp;ndash; he offered himself as the sacrifice for the
sin of the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;condemned sin &amp;ndash; instead of sin condemning us, Sin was condemned, it
was paid for, it couldn&amp;rsquo;t threaten us with eternal judgment anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;righteous requirements of the law &amp;ndash; Jesus lived a life that fully
and perfectly kept the law. His perfection is credited to believers
and is now &amp;ldquo;in us&amp;rdquo; (4).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sinful nature of an unbeliever prompts a mindset, a way of
thinking, that only reflects who they are. There whole being and
existence conforms to the sinful nature. There whole thought process
flows from the sinful nature. The contrast is equally true for the
person who believes and thus has received the Holy Spirit. According
to their new man, in the new way of the Spirit (7:6) the believers
thought process flows from that Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those controlled by the sinful nature are only hostile to God, they
can&amp;rsquo;t submit to God&amp;rsquo;s will and can&amp;rsquo;t do anything pleasing to God. In
the next verses Paul develops the thought of the Spirit&amp;rsquo;s influence on
believers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. What Christ accomplished blessings does Paul celebrate in vs. 1-2?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. How did God remove the sin that the Law exposed and condemned but
we could not get rid of? (3-4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. What is the spiritual condition of those controlled by the sinful
nature? (5-8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. By contrast, what is the spiritual condition of those who are
controlled by the spiritual nature? (5-6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Why can&amp;rsquo;t those controlled by the sinful nature please God? (8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 8: 9 &amp;ndash; 17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to be a believer and not have the Holy Spirit. The
Holy Spirit creates faith and so whenever the Holy Spirit is in a
person, there faith has already been created by the Spirit and he is
present. Paul said the Spirit of God lives in you &amp;ndash; ongoing action.
It isn&amp;rsquo;t that the Spirit created faith and then moves on to another
person and we are left on our own. The Spirit of God lives in every
believer. Although the Spirit lives in us, our body is still destined
to die (10), but our spiritual nature is alive. It is alive &amp;ldquo;because
of righteousness.&amp;rdquo; (10) The word translated righteousness has two
basic meanings, (1) being declared not guilty before God because of
Jesus, acquitted of all wrong before God (2) doing what is right in
God&amp;rsquo;s eyes. Both options would fit here, but the second fits the
context better. Our spiritual nature under the control of the Holy
Spirit is guiding us to do what is right before God. This isn&amp;rsquo;t
earning our forgiveness but it is the evidence that the Holy Spirit
has created faith in us. Even though our bodies are destined to die,
they will be raised to eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through Christ and the Holy Spirit&amp;rsquo;s work we are the sons of God. The
term sons of God refers to both male and females, through Christ we
are the children of God. We have been adopted into God&amp;rsquo;s family and
can call the Almighty God our Father. The Holy Spirit testifies and
our spiritual nature also testifies that we are God&amp;rsquo;s children and
thus heirs of eternal life. What gracious blessings the Spirit brings
to us in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEYWORD &amp;ndash; SONS OF GOD&lt;/strong&gt;- A term that includes every believer, male or
female, ethnic group or occupation in a society (Galatians 3:26-28)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. Comment &amp;ldquo;You cannot have spiritual life with God without God the
Holy Spirit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7. What are some of the blessings the Holy Spirit brings to us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) vs 9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) vs 10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) vs 11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4) vs 13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5) vs 14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6) vs 15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7) vs 17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8. Paul said, &amp;ldquo;by the Spirit you put to death the misdeeds of the
body&amp;rdquo; (13). &amp;ldquo;Put to death&amp;rdquo; is present tense. What does that mean about
our daily lives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9. How do we put to death the misdeeds of the body? How does that
relate to what Paul said about himself in chapter 7:14-20?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[PREPARING FOR NEXT WEEK&amp;rsquo;S CLASS]{.ul}&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 8:18 &amp;ndash; 39&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans &amp;ndash; the People&amp;rsquo;s Bible Pages 133 - 145&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read Romans 8:18 &amp;ndash; 39 a second time but this time out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we aren&amp;rsquo;t slaves to fear in Christ (15) what kind of attitudes and
confidence can we have in Christ?&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 12</title>
      <link>/en/courses/110/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/110/12/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD WORKS FOR THE GOOD OF EVERY BELIEVER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 8:18 &amp;ndash; 39&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we aren&amp;rsquo;t slaves to fear in Christ (15) what kind of attitudes
and confidence can we have in Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 8: 18 &amp;ndash; 25&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will look at several words and their meanings. Paul uses the word
translated, &amp;ldquo;consider&amp;rdquo; (18). That word has the idea of thinking about
something carefully until one reaches a conclusion. The word
translated, &amp;ldquo;comparing&amp;rdquo; (18) has the picture of an old balance scale,
where weights are put on one side to determine the weight of another
object on the other side. Once both are equal in weight it is
balanced. Paul&amp;rsquo;s point is I thought about this carefully no amount of
present suffering (physical, mental, emotional) will come close to our
eternal glory that will be the believers in heaven. There is no amount
of suffering in this world that we might endure that would make our
eternal inheritance no longer worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of creation was impacted by mankind&amp;rsquo;s fall into sin. As a result
of God&amp;rsquo;s judgment in the Garden of Eden, all of creation was subjected
to &amp;ldquo;frustration&amp;rdquo; (20). Creation cannot accomplish its purpose for
which it was created perfectly. Paul portrays creation as waiting for
Jesus glorious return when creation also will be able to be a perfect
creation again. Like creation we also groan inwardly (23) sin, disease
and catastrophes also deeply impact us. At the same time we have a
hope for the future, we are eagerly waiting for our bodies to be
glorified (23) at Jesus return. God has already given us the Holy
Spirit, which is his guarantee (23) that he will also bring about the
final step, our physical bodies freed from sin. Since this is in the
future, it is a hope. A sure and certain hope because the God who sent
his Son to redeem us will also keep this promise. We eagerly wait with
patience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give three examples to show that the created world has been made
&amp;ldquo;subject to frustration&amp;rdquo; because of sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What future awaits the created world (vs 19-21)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What great expectation do God&amp;rsquo;s children hold on to in the midst of
their present difficulties? (vs 18,23)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 8: 26 &amp;ndash; 30&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At times, we don&amp;rsquo;t know what to pray. We don&amp;rsquo;t know what the will of
God is for us. Paul assures us that the Spirit prays on our behalf.
The Spirit asks for the right solution. The Spirit and the Father have
the same agenda and so the Spirit can pray &amp;ldquo;in accordance with God&amp;rsquo;s
will&amp;rdquo; (27). The &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; is clearly described in vs 17, &amp;ldquo;Now if we are
children, then we are heirs&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul begins vs 28 with the &amp;ldquo;we know&amp;rdquo;. The basis for what we know is
explained in vs 29-30. What we know can be outlined in five points: 1)
God works &amp;ndash; he is ceaselessly involved with each believer. 2) for
good &amp;ndash; not necessarily for our earthly comfort but for our eternal
salvation &amp;ndash; again vs. 29-30 brings out that perspective. 3) All
things &amp;ndash; not occasionally or just things we pray about. 4) those who
love him &amp;ndash; not everyone on earth but the believers. 5) according to
his purpose &amp;ndash; life isn&amp;rsquo;t a series of random events but God has
purpose in them for our spiritual good. How can we know these things
are true? Listen to Paul&amp;rsquo;s list of five aspects of God&amp;rsquo;s grace in each
believer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In verses 29-30 we are told of the eternal good God is working toward.
It started in eternity past in God&amp;rsquo;s foreknowledge and predestination
of believers. It was carried out in time as those predestined were
brought to faith (called) through the Gospel proclaimed. With faith
created each believer now has received the absolute assurance of sin
forgiven already in Jesus. Each believer can anticipate a certain
eternal glory. Each step is rooted in God&amp;rsquo;s grace and flows from him
to us. We contribute nothing in any of this. So we can be totally
certain, even in suffering, that God is at work for our good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What special help does the Holy Spirit provide for sin weakened and
weary believers? (26-27)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it important to remember that God is working all things for
our spiritual good?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s explore God&amp;rsquo;s grace filled works in vs. 29-30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. When God foreknows a person, he &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. When God predestines a person, he &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. When God calls a person, he &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. When God justifies a person, he &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E. When God glorifies a person, he &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can you help a person who wonders whether God has chosen him/her
to be saved?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you help a person who wonders what caused God to choose
him/her to be saved?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROMANS 8: 31 &amp;ndash; 39&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul continues with a series of questions and each one has an obvious
answer. His first question isn&amp;rsquo;t simply, &amp;ldquo;Who can be against us?&amp;rdquo; The
answers could be many. His question starts with a condition, If
(since) God is for us &amp;ndash; whoever may be against us in this world, they
can&amp;rsquo;t stand up to God&amp;rsquo;s love and strength. There isn&amp;rsquo;t any doubt about
God&amp;rsquo;s love for us. He gave his only Son, his greatest treasure for us.
Since he gave up his son for us, we can be sure he will to do anything
for us. Satan may accuse us (Rev.12:10) or our own sinful heart may
condemn us as unable to be forgiven by God, nevertheless we have been
acquitted by God because of Jesus death and resurrection. He also is
at God&amp;rsquo;s right hand pleading for us on the basis of his suffering and
death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at what God has already done for us in Christ. His love for us is
beyond compare. God&amp;rsquo;s love for us will not be overcome or diminished
by anything on earth. With God&amp;rsquo;s fervent love for us we don&amp;rsquo;t just
survive in difficulties we are more than conquers! God&amp;rsquo;s love for us
in Christ Jesus is our strength. His steadfast and abundant love will
remain no matter what the earthly circumstances. Our confidence is
rooted in Christ and his overflowing love demonstrated for us at the
cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KEYWORD &amp;ndash; CHOSEN -&lt;/strong&gt; Literally elect, those God foreknew and
predestined by grace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCUSSION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;9&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In vs 31-35 Paul asks a series of questions with obvious answers to
help us respond to God&amp;rsquo;s wonderful works of love with confident
trust. What assurance does God want us to have in each of these
verses?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Vs. 31&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Vs. 32&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Vs. 33-34&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Vs. 35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;10&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In vs. 33-34 Paul offers four reasons why a believer in Christ
cannot be condemned for his/her sins. What are they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What glorious confidence in God&amp;rsquo;s love does Paul express regarding
the painful trials God&amp;rsquo;s loved ones face? (vs.37-39)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
