<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>恩典圣经学院 – 四个关键的概念</title>
    <link>/zh-cn/courses/101/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 四个关键的概念 on 恩典圣经学院</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/zh-cn/courses/101/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 罪 SIN</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/101/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/101/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In order to understand anything else in the Bible we must first understand sin.  We cannot grasp why there is so much hardship in this world and our life unless we understand sin.  We cannot appreciate our need for a Savior unless we understand sin.  The portions of Scripture used in this Bible study are the ones that deal most directly with this issue.  As we look at these passages, we are going to try to answer the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Where did sin originate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• What exactly is “sin”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Who is guilty of sin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• What does sin do to us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为了能够理解圣经我们必须首先理解罪。除非我们理解罪，否则我们无法领会为什么这个世界上和我们的生命中会有这么多的苦难。除非我们理解罪，否则我们无法感激我们对救主的需求。这个圣经学习里所用的经文是直接针对这个问题的。当我们学习这些段落时，我们将试着回答下列的问题：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 罪是从哪里起源的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• “罪”确切的是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 谁是有罪的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 罪对我们有什么影响？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHERE DID SIN ORIGINATE?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罪是从哪里起源的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请阅读下面的经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:31 – God saw all that he had made, and it was very good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创世记1:31－－神看着一切所造的都甚好。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Peter 2:4 – God did not spare the angels when they sinned, but sent them to hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;彼得后书2:4－－就是天使犯了罪，神也没有宽容，曾把他们丢在地狱。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 3:4-6 – &amp;ldquo;You will not surely die,&amp;rdquo; the serpent said to the woman.  &amp;ldquo;For God knows that when you eat of it your eyes will be opened, and you will be like God, knowing good and evil.&amp;rdquo; When the woman saw that the fruit of the tree was good for food and pleasing to the eye, and also desirable for gaining wisdom, she took some and ate it. She also gave some to her husband, who was with her, and he ate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创世记3:4-6－－蛇对女人说：“你们不一定会死，因为神知道，你们吃的日子眼睛就明亮了，你们便如神能知道善恶。”于是，女人见那棵树的果子好作食物，也悦人眼目，且是可喜爱的，能使人有智慧，就摘下果子来吃了；又给她丈夫，她丈夫也吃了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 3:8 – He who does what is sinful is of the devil, because the devil has been sinning from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书3:8－－犯罪的是属魔鬼的，因为魔鬼从起初就犯罪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 8:44 – [Jesus said,] “You belong to your father, the devil, and you want to carry out your father&amp;rsquo;s desire. He was a murderer from the beginning, not holding to the truth, for there is no truth in him. When he lies, he speaks his native language, for he is a liar and the father of lies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰福音8:44－－【耶稣说，】“你们是出于你们的父魔鬼，你们服的私欲，你们偏要行。他们起初是杀人的，不守真理，因他心里没有真理；他说谎时出于自己，因他本来是说谎的，也是说谎之人的父”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James 1:13 – When tempted, no one should say, &amp;ldquo;God is tempting me.&amp;rdquo; For God cannot be tempted by evil, nor does he tempt anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;雅各书1:13－－人被试探，不可说：“我是被神试探”；因为神不能被恶试探，他也不试探人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the underlined portions of those passages, who is the ultimate author of sin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文中的划线部分，谁是罪最根本的发起者？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satan is the ultimate author of sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the italicized portions of those passages, who else deserves the blame for the presence of sin in the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文中的斜体部分，对于这个世界罪的存在，还有谁应受责备？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam and Eve also deserve blame for the presence of sin in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who IS NOT to blame for sin being in the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;谁不应该对这个世界的罪受责备？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God is not to blame for sin being in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following space, please summarize what you have learned from those passages that help you answer the question, “WHERE DID SIN ORIGINATE?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在下面的空白处，运用你从上述经文中所学的，概括回答该问题，“罪是从哪里起源的?”Sin originated with Satan, the angel who decided on his own to rebel against God.  Satan tempted Eve, who decided to sin against God and invited her husband to join her.  Adam also agreed to sin against God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT EXACTLY IS “SIN”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“罪”确切的是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请阅读下面的经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 51:5 – Surely I have been a sinner from birth, sinful from the time my mother conceived me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇51:5－－我是在罪孽里生的，在我母亲怀胎的时候就有了罪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 8:21 – Every inclination of [man’s] heart is evil from childhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创世记8:21－－人从小时心里怀着恶念。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the underlined portions of those passages, when was I first guilty of sin in God’s eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文中的划线部分，我是从何时在上帝的眼里就是有罪的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was first guilty of sin at the time I was conceived in my mother’s womb .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 5:3 – Adam had a son in his own likeness, in his own image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创世记5:3－－亚当&amp;hellip;生了一个儿子，形像样式和自己相似。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 3:6 – Flesh gives birth to flesh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰福音3:6－－从肉身生的就是肉身。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After looking at John 3:6 and Genesis 5:3, can you explain how this is possible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;阅读约翰福音3:6和创世记5:3后，你能解释为何这是可能的吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sinful condition was passed on from parents to children throughout the history of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 7:18 – I know that nothing good lives in me, that is, in my sinful nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书7:18－－我也知道在我里头，就是我肉体之中，没有良善。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 8:7 – The sinful mind is hostile to God, it does not submit to God’s law, nor can it do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书8:7－－原来体贴肉体的，就是与神为仇；因为不服神的律法，也是不能服。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 2:3 – Like the rest, we were by nature objects of wrath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以弗所书2:3－－本为可怒之子，和别人一样。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Romans 7:18, what could you call this sin that we are born with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据罗马书7:18，你如何称呼这个我们生来就有的罪？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sin is a hostile, rebellious, unwilling mindset against God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the italicized portions of those passages, what does this do to me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文中的斜体部分，这个对我有什么影响？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This inherited sinful condition is part of my nature.  It makes me a target for God’s just, punishing anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That “sinful nature” that we inherit from our parents impacts our life in a negative way.  Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们从父母那里继承的“有罪的本性”消极地影响我们的生活。请阅读下面经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 15:19 – Out of the heart come evil thoughts, murder, adultery, sexual immorality, theft, false testimony, slander.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音15:19－－因为从心里发出来的，有恶念、凶杀、奸淫、苟合、偷盗、妄证、谤讟。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 6:5 – The LORD saw how great man&amp;rsquo;s wickedness on the earth had become, and that every inclination of the thoughts of his heart was only evil all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创世记6:5－－耶和华见人在地上罪恶很大，终日所思想的尽都是恶。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 5:28 – But I tell you that anyone who looks at a woman lustfully has already committed adultery with her in his heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音5:28－－只是我告诉你们，凡看见妇女就动淫念的，这人心里已经与他犯奸淫了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 3:15 – Anyone who hates his brother is a murderer, and you know that no murderer has eternal life in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书3:15－－凡恨他弟兄的，就是杀人的；你们晓得凡杀人的，没有永生存在他里面。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the italicized portions of those passages, where do my sins originate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据经文中斜体的部分，我的罪是从哪里起源的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sins originate in my sinful heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to those passages, does God judge us on just our actions, or does he also judge the thoughts behind those actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据这些经文，上帝仅仅审判我们的行为吗？还是他也审判这些行为背后的思想？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God not only judges our actions, He also judges the thoughts and motives behind those actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 5:3 – This is love for God: to obey his commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书5:3－－我们遵守神的诫命，这就是爱他了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 3:4 – Everyone who sins breaks the law; in fact, sin is lawlessness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书3:4－－凡犯罪的，就是违背律法；违背律法就是罪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leviticus 5:17 – &amp;ldquo;If a person sins and does what is forbidden in any of the LORD&amp;rsquo;s commands, even though he does not know it, he is guilty and will be held responsible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;利未记5:17－－“若有人犯罪，行了耶和华所吩咐不可行的什么事，他虽然不知道，还是有了罪，就要担当他的罪孽.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to those passages, what is the way we show love for God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文，我们向上帝表示爱的方式是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We show our love for God by obeying His commandments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, how is sin defined?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因此，罪是如何定义的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We commit sin when we break God’s &lt;strong&gt;Law&lt;/strong&gt;___________, whether that be by committing sinful actions or by thinking sinful thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当我们违背了上帝的__________________，无论是通过犯下有罪的行为还是通过有罪的思想，我们就犯罪了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We generally speak of two different categories of sin and give them the following definitions. These definitions can serve as the answer to our question, “WHAT IS ‘SIN’?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们一般所说的是两种不同的罪，它们的定义如下。这些定义可以作为问题“什么是罪？”的答案。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“ORIGINAL SIN” –  The sinfulness that is handed down from parents to children.  (This is therefore sometimes also referred to as “inherited sin.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“原罪”－－ 从父母到孩子传下来的罪。（因此有时这个也指“继承罪”）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“ACTUAL SIN” –  The sins in thought, word, and action that an individual commits on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“本罪”－－ 个体在思想，言语和行为上所犯下的他们自己的罪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both types of sin are deserving of God’s punishment.  We’ll look at that in more depth later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这两种罪都应受到上帝的惩罚。我们将在接下来的学习中更深入地学习。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO IS GUILTY OF SIN?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;谁是有罪的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who is guilty of sin?  If you’re speaking about “original sin,” you obviously have to answer “everyone.”  Original sin is handed down from parents to children at the moment of conception.  So let’s focus in on “actual sin.”  Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;谁是有罪的？如果你谈到“原罪”，很明显的答案是“每一个人”。原罪是父母从受孕那一刻就传给其孩子的。所以，我们集中学习“本罪”。请阅读下面的经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leviticus 19:2 – Be holy because I, the LORD your God, am holy. (“Holy” can be defined as “perfect” or “righteous” or “without sin.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;利未记19:2－－你们要圣洁，因为我耶和华你们的神是圣洁的。(“圣洁”可以定义为“完美的”或者“正义的”或者“无罪的”。)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 5:48 – Be perfect, therefore, as your heavenly Father is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音5:48－－所以，你们要完全，像你们的天父完全一样。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James 2:10 – Whoever keeps the whole law and yet stumbles at just one point is guilty of breaking all of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;雅各书2:10－－因为凡遵守全律法的，只在一条上跌倒，他就是犯了众条。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to those passages, how does God want us to keep his law in our thoughts, in our speech, and in our actions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文，上帝是如何想让我们在思想中，在言语中，以及在行为中遵守他的律法的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God wants us to keep His law perfectly in our thoughts, speech and actions without ever committing even one sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about just one slip? Wouldn’t God let that slide?  (Look at James 2:10.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;那么如果只跌倒一次呢？上帝应该不会施加惩罚吧？（参看雅各书2:10）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God expects 100% obedience to His law.  Just one sin makes us a sinner.  He will not ignore even one sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of those passages, what would you guess is the answer to the question, “WHO IS GUILTY OF SIN?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基于上述经文，你如何回答“谁是有罪的”这个问题？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All people are guilty of both original sin and actual sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 3:23 – All have sinned and fall short of the glory of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书3:23－－因为世人都犯了罪，亏缺了神的荣耀。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 53:3 –  Everyone has turned away, they have together become corrupt; there is no one who does good, not even one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇53:3－－他们各人都退后，一同变为污秽；并没有行善的，连一个也没有。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do these passages support what you wrote in the box above?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上两段经文支持你在上面方框中所写的内容吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wanted to diagram this, you could do it in the following way.  What God demands in his Law is that we live a holy, perfect life… a life that has NO sin. However, what he sees is a life that is tainted by sin, and therefore falls short of the perfection he demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果你想用图解来表示，可以按照下面的方式。上帝的律法要求我们有一个圣洁，完美的生命…一个没有罪的生命。但是，上帝看到的却是一个被罪玷污了的生命，因此亏欠了他完美的要求。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/course-file/101/image/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;WHO IS GUILTY OF SIN&#34; title=&#34;WHO IS GUILTY OF SIN&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see how in that diagram one adds up to life and the other to death.  Let’s look at this more closely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你可以看到在这个图解中一个加起来是生命而另一个则是死亡。让我们更进一步地学习。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT DOES SIN DO TO US?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罪对我们有什么影响？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 2:16-17 – And the LORD God commanded the man, &amp;ldquo;You are free to eat from any tree in the garden; but you must not eat from the tree of the knowledge of good and evil, for when you eat of it you will surely die.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创世记2:16-17－－耶和华  神吩咐他说：“园中各样树上的果子，你可以随意吃，只是分别善恶树上的果子，你不可吃，因为你吃的日子必定死！”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezekiel 18:4 – The soul who sins is the one who will die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以西结书18:4－－犯罪的，他必死亡。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 6:23 – The wages of sin is death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书6:23－－罪的工价乃是死。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 5:12 – …sin entered the world through one man, and death through sin, and in this way death came to all men…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书5:12－－…这就如罪是从一人入了世界，死又是从罪来的；于是死就临到众人，因为众人都犯了罪…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to those passages, what is one consequence of sin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文，罪的一个结果是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sin brings death, separation from God and His blessings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can you understand that “death came to all men” as the result of Adam and Eve’s sin in the Garden of Eden?  (Hint – Think about what we said concerning original sin.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如何理解“死就临到众人”是亚当和夏娃在伊甸园犯罪的结果？（提示――回想我们所提到的原罪。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death is the consequence of  sin.   Our inherited condition of original sin has us starting life in a position of being dead to God (separated from Him).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 59:2 – But your iniquities have separated you from your God; your sins have hidden his face from you, so that he will not hear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以赛亚书59:2－－但你们的罪孽使你们与神隔绝；你们的罪恶使他掩面不听你们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Peter 2:4 – God did not spare angels when they sinned, but sent them to hell, putting them in the gloomy dungeons to be held for judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;彼得后书2:4－－就是天使犯了罪，神也没有宽容，曾把他们丢在地狱，交在黑暗坑中，等候审判。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 10:28 – …be afraid of the One who can destroy both soul and body in hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音10:28－－…惟有能把身体和灵魂都灭在地狱里的，正要怕他。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the ultimate consequence of sin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罪的最终结果是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultimate consequence of sin is eternal separation from God  and eternal torments in hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 2:1 – As for you, you were dead in your transgressions and sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以弗所书2:1－－你们死在过犯罪恶之中。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What power do we have to take care of sin on our own?  (Hint – Think of how much power a corpse has to take care of itself.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们有什么样的力量来处理我们自己的罪？（提示――想象一下尸体有多大力量来处理他自己。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have no power to overcome of problem of sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基于以上经文，如何回答问题“我的罪对我有什么影响？”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sin ruins me.  It brings me death and separation from God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every single person is lost in their sin.  But does that mean that we will experience the punishment of hell?  That’s the main focus of the second key concept – GRACE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;每一个人都在他的罪里迷失。但是这意味着我们将在地狱里亲身接受惩罚吗？那便是第二个关键概念的主要关注点――恩典。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 2:4-5 –  But because of his great love for us, God, who is rich in mercy, made us alive with Christ even when we were dead in transgressions – IT IS BY GRACE YOU HAVE BEEN SAVED.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以弗所书2:4-5－－然而，神既有丰富的怜悯，因他爱我们的大爱，当我们死在过犯中的时候，便叫我们与基督一同活过来――你们得救是本乎恩。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TAKING IT DEEPER…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;深入思考…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Agree or Disagree – God is not angry if we sin accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－如果我们意外地犯罪，上帝不会生气。

Disagree.  Sin is still sin.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Agree or Disagree – Although children learn bad habits from others, basically they are good and want to do right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－尽管孩子们从别人哪里学到了不好的习惯，但是基本上他们是良善的而且想做好。

Disagree.   Children are born with original sin and sin on their own initiative.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree or Disagree – God must not hold infants and young children accountable for their sins, because they are too young to know what they are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－上帝必不会要求婴儿和小孩子对他们的罪负责，因为他们太小了不知道他们在做什么。

Disagree.   God does not make exceptions to His law demands.  Ignorance is not innocence.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Agree or Disagree - Some people are able to live a life that conforms perfectly to God’s Law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－有些人活着能完美地遵守上帝的律法。

Disagree.   All are sinful and all commit sins.  Some people are outwardly better morally than others, but all sin.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E. Agree or Disagree – The Bible tells us that God is loving.  Therefore God wouldn’t actually send anyone to hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－圣经告诉我们上帝是慈爱的。因此上帝事实上不会让任何人下地狱。

Disagree.   God is loving and wants to help and deliver people from sin.  However, God is also just and must punish sin.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F. Agree or Disagree – Sinful actions (such as killing someone or stealing) are worse than sinful speech (such as lying or cursing).  And sinful speech is worse than sinful thoughts (such as lust or hatred).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－有罪的行为（比如杀人或者偷窃）比有罪的言语（比如说谎或者诅咒）要坏。有罪的言语比有罪的思想（比如性欲或者憎恨）要坏。

Agree.  In human thinking some sins are more damaging than others and should be punished accordingly.  Disagree.  Sin is sin.  Every sin is an offense against the infinite love and justice of God and deserving of death.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G. Agree or Disagree – No one has ever lived their entire life without committing a sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－没有人活了一辈子没有犯罪的。

Disagree.   Jesus Christ has.   We might also say that a baby that dies before birth has not committed an actual sin, but that baby still has original, inherited sin with its hostile, rebellious attitude toward God and His law.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H. What do you think?  If people are basically good, is it fair that God still punishes them for the very few sins that they do commit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;你怎么认为？如果人基本上是良善的，上帝仍然惩罚他们所犯下很少的罪，这是公平的吗？

Yes, it is fair for God to punish a person for their sins.  He will punish people justly in accordance with their guilt.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 恩典 GRACE</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/101/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/101/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;In the last lesson, we looked at the utter hopelessness of mankind and the inability of anyone to save themselves from the guilt of their sin.  In this lesson, we’re going to look at God’s response to that hopelessness – grace.  Here are the questions we hope to answer in this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• What is God’s “grace”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• What was God’s gracious plan of salvation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• What is the result of God showing his grace to us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在上一课，我们看到人类全然的绝望，以及其从罪责中无法解救自己的无能。在这一课，我们将看到上帝是如何对这绝望回复的－－恩典。下面是这课中我们希望回答的问题：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 什么是上帝的“恩典“？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 上帝恩慈的拯救计划是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 上帝向我们显明他的恩典的结果是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT IS GOD’S GRACE?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;什么是上帝的恩典？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请阅读下面的经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Timothy 2:3-4 – This is good, and pleases God our Savior, who wants all men to be saved and to come to a knowledge of the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;提摩太前书2:3-4－－这是好的，在神我们救主面前可蒙悦纳。他愿意万人得救，明白真道。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezekiel 33:11 – “As surely as I live,” declares the Sovereign LORD, “I take no pleasure in the death of the wicked, but rather that they turn from their ways and live.”  (Note: “Death” here means eternal death in hell.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以西结书 33:11－－主耶和华说：“我指着我的永生起誓，我断不喜悦恶人死亡，惟喜悦恶人转离所行的道而活。”（注：“死亡”这里的意思是地狱中永远的死亡。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Peter 3:9 – He is patient with you, not wanting anyone to perish, but everyone to come to repentance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;彼得后书3:9－－乃是宽容你们，不愿有一人沉沦，乃愿人人都悔改。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deuteronomy 23:5 – “&amp;hellip;the LORD your God loves you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;申命记 23:5－－“&amp;hellip;耶和华你的神爱你。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 136:1-3 – Give thanks to the LORD, for he is good.  His love endures forever.  Give thanks to the God of gods.  His love endures forever.  Give thanks to the Lord of lords: His love endures forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇136:1-3－－你们要称谢耶和华，因他本为善。他的慈爱永远长存。你们要称谢万神之神，因他的慈爱永远长存。你们要称谢万主之主，因他的慈爱永远长存。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 2:4-5 – But because of his great love for us, God, who is rich in mercy, made us alive with Christ even when we were dead in transgressions – it is by grace you have been saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以弗所书 2:4-5－－然而，神既有丰富的怜悯，因他爱我们的大爱，当我们死在过犯中的时候，便叫我们与基督一同活过来――你们得救是本乎恩。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does God want anyone to go to hell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝希望任何人下地狱吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, God does not want anyone to go to hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the underlined portions of those passages, what does God want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文划线部分，上帝确实想要什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God wants all people to be saved, to turn away from their sin toward Him and enjoy life with Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the italicized portions of those passages, why doesn’t God want anyone to go to hell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文斜体部分，为什么上帝不想让任何人下地狱？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God is loves people very much and so desires to spare them from eternal death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titus 3:4-5 – But when the kindness and love of God our Savior appeared, he saved us, not because of righteous things we had done, but because of his mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;提多书 3:4-5－－但到了神我们救主的恩慈和他向人所施的慈爱显明的时候，他便救了我们，并不是因我们自己所行的义，乃是照他的怜悯。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 2:8 – For it is by grace you have been saved, through faith – and this not from yourselves, it is the gift of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以弗所书2:8－－你们得救是本乎恩，也因着信；这并不是出于自己，乃是神所赐的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this love something that we earned or deserved?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这个爱是我们赚来的或者应得的吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, this love is a free gift of God, given apart from our deserving it and in spite of our not deserving it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Ephesians 2:8, what does the Bible call the loving way God treated humanity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据以弗所书2:8，圣经是如何称呼上帝对待人类的慈爱方式的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible calls this loving way of God “grace.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of the passages we have looked at, which one of the following would you say is the best answer to the question, “WHAT IS GOD’S ‘GRACE’?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基于上述经文，下面哪一个是问题“什么是上帝的‘恩典’？”的最佳答案？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____ God’s grace is the love that we earn when we keep his law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____ God’s grace is the justice he shows by punishing the wicked and rewarding the good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt;_ God’s grace is the undeserved love that he gives to all people as a gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____ God’s grace is the love that he shows people when they first love others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____ 上帝的恩典是当我们遵守上帝的律法时可以赚来的爱。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____ 上帝的恩典是他惩罚邪恶以及奖赏良善的公义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____ 上帝的恩典是他给所有人的不应该得的爱。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____ 上帝的恩典是当他显明人们先去爱别人的爱。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT WAS GOD’S GRACIOUS PLAN OF SALVATION?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝恩慈的拯救计划是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请阅读下面的经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 3:16 – &amp;ldquo;For God so loved the world that he gave his one and only Son, that whoever believes in him shall not perish but have eternal life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰福音3:16－－“神爱世人，甚至将他的独生子赐给他们，叫一切信他的，不至灭亡，反得永生。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 1:6 – …to the praise of his glorious grace, which he has freely given us in the One he loves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以弗所书1:6－－…使他荣耀的恩典得着称赞；这恩典是他在爱子里所赐给我们的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 4:9-10 – This is how God showed his love among us: He sent his one and only Son into the world that we might live through him. This is love: not that we loved God, but that he loved us and sent his Son as an atoning sacrifice for our sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书 4:9-10－－神差他独生子到世间来，使我们藉着他得生，神爱我们的心在此就显明了。不是我们爱神，乃是神爱我们，差他的儿子为我们的罪作了挽回祭，这就是爱了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galatians 4:4-5 – But when the time had fully come, God sent his Son, born of a woman, born under law, to redeem those under law, that we might receive the full rights of sons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;加拉太书 4:4-5－－及至时候满足，神就差遣他的儿子，为女子所生，且生在律法以下，要把律法以下的人赎出来，叫我们得着儿子的名分。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the italicized portions of those passages, what did God do, in his love, to save us from our sins?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文斜体部分，上帝在他的爱中做了什么来把我们从罪中拯救出来？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In His love, God sent His Son into the world to save us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the underlined portions of those passages, what was God’s Son going to be for us, in order that we might be saved from our sins?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文划线部分，为了把我们从罪中拯救出来，上帝的儿子将成为我们的什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God’s Son was going to be the sacrifice offered for us so that we might be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God’s grace – the undeserved love he has for humankind – is seen most clearly when we look at the way he sent his Son to pay for sins.  Let’s look more closely at God’s Son, Jesus, and at how Jesus paid for our sins.  Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝的恩典――他给人类的不应得的爱――当我们看到他是如何派他儿子去赎我们的罪时是最清楚的。让我们更进一步地去看上帝的儿子，耶稣，以及耶稣是如何替我们赎罪的。请阅读下列经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebrews 4:15 – For we do not have a high priest who is unable to sympathize with our weaknesses, but we have one who has been tempted in every way, just as we are – yet was without sin.  (The “high priest” here is a reference to Jesus.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;希伯来书4:15－－因我们的大祭司并非不能体恤我们的软弱。他也曾凡事受过试探，与我们一样，只是他没有犯罪。  （“大祭司”这里指的是耶稣。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Peter 2:22 – &amp;ldquo;He (Christ) committed no sin, and no deceit was found in his mouth.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;彼得前书2:22－－ “他（基督）并没有犯罪，口里也没有诡诈。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 3:5 – But you know that he appeared so that he might take away our sins. And in him (Jesus Christ) is no sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书3:5－－你们知道主曾显现，是要除掉人的罪；在他（耶稣基督）并没有罪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 7:14 – Therefore the Lord himself will give you a sign: The virgin will be with child and will give birth to a son, and will call him Immanuel.  (Immanuel means “God with us.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以赛亚书7:14－－因此，主自己要给你们一个兆头，必有童女怀孕生子，给他起名叫以马内利（就是“神与我们同在”的意思）。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 5:5 –  Who is it that overcomes the world? Only he who believes that Jesus is the Son of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书5:5－－胜过世界的是谁呢？不是那信耶稣是神儿子的吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colossians 2:9 – In Christ all the fullness of the Deity lives in bodily form.  (“Deity” means “God.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;歌罗西书2:9－－因为神本性一切的丰盛都有形有体的居住在基督里面。（“神本性”的意思是上帝。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the italicized portions of those verses, what was special about Jesus’ life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文斜体部分，耶稣的生命有什么特别之处？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus lived a perfect life in which He never committed a sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is that possible?  How was Jesus able to go his entire life without committing even one sin?  (Look at the underlined portions of those passages.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;那怎么可能？耶稣如何能够活了一辈子却没有犯过一次罪呢？(参看上述经文划线部分。)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus was able to live His entire life without sinning because He was the holy God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Jesus died on the cross then, something remarkable happened.  God performed an exchange.   Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;所以当耶稣死在十字架上的时候，不平常的事发生了。上帝做了一个交换。请阅读下列经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 5:21 – God made him who had no sin to be sin for us, so that in him we might become the righteousness of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;哥林多后书5:21－－神使那无罪的，替我们成为罪，好叫我们在他里面成为神的义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 53:5-6 – But he was pierced for our transgressions, he was crushed for our iniquities; the punishment that brought us peace was upon him, and by his wounds we are healed.    We all, like sheep, have gone astray, each of us has turned to his own way; and the LORD has laid on him the iniquity of us all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以赛亚书53:5-6－－哪知他为我们的过犯受害，为我们的罪孽压伤。因他受的刑罚，我们得平安；因他受的鞭伤，我们得医治。 我们都如羊走迷；各人偏行己路；耶和华使我们众人的罪孽都归在他身上。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Peter 3:18 – For Christ died for sins once for all, the righteous for the unrighteous, to bring you to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;彼得前书3:18－－因基督也曾一次为罪受苦，就是义的代替不义的，为要引我们到神面前。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 1:7 – In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins, in accordance with the riches of God&amp;rsquo;s grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以弗所书1:7－－我们藉这爱子的血得蒙救赎，过犯得以赦免，乃是照他丰富的恩典。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We said that on the cross, God performed an exchange.  He took something away from us and gave it to Christ.  What is it he took away from us?  (Look at the italicized portions of those passages.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们说在十字架上上帝做了一个交换。他把某物从我们身上拿走，并且把它给了基督。他把什么东西从我们身上拿走了？（参照上述经文中斜体部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God took all our sins from us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second half of this exchange, God took something from Christ and gave it to humankind.  What?  (Look at the underlined portions of those passages.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在这个交换的第二部分，上帝吧某物从基督身上拿走，并把它给了我们。是什么？（参看上述经文划线部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God gave us the righteousness or holiness of Jesus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why was God willing to do this?  (Look at the end of Ephesians 1:7.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么上帝愿意做这样的事呢？（参看以弗所书1:7最后部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God was willing to do this because of His grace, His love for sinners who have given up every right to be loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember in the last lesson we diagrammed what God demands in our lives and what he sees in our lives.  It looked like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上节课我们用如下图解说明了上帝要求我们生命中的什么以及上帝看到我们生命中的什么。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/course-file/101/image/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;WHO IS GUILTY OF SIN&#34; title=&#34;WHO IS GUILTY OF SIN&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now we’ve seen that Christ’s life met those demands of God’s Law.  He never sinned in thought, speech, or action.  In this gracious exchange, God gives us credit for Christ’s holy life.  And he gives Christ credit for our sinful life.  Therefore, on the cross, we see Christ getting punished for our sins.  You could diagram this gracious exchange like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但是现在我们看到基督的生命满足了上帝律法的要求。他从未在思想上，言语上或者行为上犯罪。在这个恩慈的交换里，上帝吧基督圣洁生命的记录给了我们，把我们有罪生命的记录给了基督。因此，在十字架上，我们看到基督因我们的罪受到惩罚。你可以如下图解这个恩慈的交换。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/course-file/101/image/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;WHAT WAS GOD’S GRACIOUS PLAN OF SALVATION&#34; title=&#34;WHAT WAS GOD’S GRACIOUS PLAN OF SALVATION&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should look at one more thing about God’s gracious plan of salvation.  We need to know why it is we can be certain that Jesus paid for ALL sin.  Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们应该看到另一件关于上帝恩慈的拯救计划的事。我们需要知道为什么我们能够肯定耶稣偿还了所有的罪。请阅读下列经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 6:23 – The wages of sin is death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书6:23－－因为罪的工价乃是死。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 28:5-6 – The angel said to the women, &amp;ldquo;Do not be afraid, for I know that you are looking for Jesus, who was crucified.  He is not here; he has risen, just as he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音28:5-6－－天使对妇女说：“不要害怕！我知道你们是寻找那钉十字架的耶稣。他不在这里，照他所说的，已经复活了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke 24:37-39 – (After Jesus’ death and resurrection) – [The disciples] were startled and frightened, thinking they saw a ghost.  [Jesus] said to them, &amp;ldquo;Why are you troubled, and why do doubts rise in your minds?  Look at my hands and my feet. It is I myself! Touch me and see; a ghost does not have flesh and bones, as you see I have.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;路加福音24:37-39－－（在耶稣死亡和复活之后）－【门徒】却惊慌害怕，以为所看见的是魂。耶稣说：“你们为什么愁烦？为什么心里起疑念呢？你们看我的手，我的脚，就知道实在是我了。摸我看看！魂无骨无肉，你们看，我是有的。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 4:25 – He was delivered over to death for our sins and was raised to life for our justification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书4:25－－耶稣被交给人，是为我们的过犯；复活，是为叫我们称义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 15:17 – If Christ has not been raised, your faith is futile; you are still in your sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;哥林多前书15:17－－基督若没有复活，你们的信便是徒然，你们仍在罪里。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think back to the previous lesson.  What did we say was one of the major consequences of sin? (Look at Romans 6:23 above.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;回想上节课，我们说罪的主要结果之一是什么？（参看上面罗马书6:23。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the major consequences of sin is death, separation from God, His love and His blessings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then proves that Jesus defeated sin?  (Look at the italicized portions of those verses.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;什么证明了耶稣战胜了罪？（参看上述经文斜体部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus’ resurrection from death proves that Jesus defeated sin for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to 1 Corinthians 15:17, is this an important doctrine of the Bible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据哥林多前书15:17，这是圣经中的一条重要的教义吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the resurrection of Jesus is a vital teaching.  If Jesus had not been raised from the dead, then we would not know that He has fully paid for our sin.   We would have no Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of all the passages we have looked at in this section of our Bible study, how would you answer that question, “WHAT WAS GOD’S GRACIOUS PLAN OF SALVATION?”  (Please include the exchange that was made on the cross and the proof that our sins are completely paid for.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基于上述我们所学经文，如何回答问题“什么是上帝恩慈的拯救计划？”（请包括在十字架上所完成的交换以及我们的罪已经完全被偿还的证明。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God’s gracious plan of salvation was to have His Son, Jesus, enter the world and become the substitute for all sinners.  Jesus lived a holy, perfect life for us, died as the acceptable sacrifice to God for our sins and rose from the dead to assure us that He had won forgiveness and eternal life for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT IS THE RESULT OF GOD SHOWING HIS GRACE TO US?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝向我们显明他的恩典的结果是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请阅读下面的经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 8:1 – Therefore, there is now no condemnation for those who are in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书8:1－－如今，那些在基督耶稣里的就不定罪了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Timothy 1:9-10 – This grace was given us in Christ Jesus before the beginning of time, but it has now been revealed through the appearing of our Savior, Christ Jesus, who has destroyed death and has brought life and immortality to light through the gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;提摩太后书1:9-10－－这恩典是万古之先，在基督耶稣里赐给我们的，但如今藉着我们救主基督耶稣的显现才表明出来了。他已经把死废去，藉着福音，将不能坏的生命彰显出来。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebrews 2:14-15 – Since the children have flesh and blood, he too shared in their humanity so that by his death he might destroy him who holds the power of death &amp;ndash; that is, the devil &amp;ndash;  and free those who all their lives were held in slavery by their fear of death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;希伯来书 2:14-15－－儿女既同有血肉之体，他也照样亲自成了血肉之体，特要藉着死败坏那掌死权的，就是魔鬼， 并要释放那些一生因怕死而为奴仆的人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titus 3:5-7 – [God] saved us through the washing of rebirth and renewal by the Holy Spirit, whom he poured out on us generously through Jesus Christ our Savior, so that, having been justified by his grace, we might become heirs having the hope of eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;提多书3:5-7－－【上帝】便救了我们，并不是因我们自己所行的义，乃是照他的怜悯，藉着重生的洗和圣灵的更新。圣灵就是神藉着耶稣基督我们救主厚厚浇灌在我们身上的，好叫我们因他的恩得称为义，可以凭着永生的盼望成为后嗣。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 5:17 – For if, by the trespass of the one man, death reigned through that one man, how much more will those who receive God&amp;rsquo;s abundant provision of grace and of the gift of righteousness reign in life through the one man, Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书5:17－－若因一人的过犯，死就因这一人作了王，何况那些受洪恩又蒙所赐之义的，岂不更要因耶稣基督一人在生命中作王吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 11:6 – And if by grace, then it is no longer by works; if it were, grace would no longer be grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书11:6－－既是出于恩典，就不在乎行为；不然，恩典就不是恩典了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the italicized portions of those verses, can you name three things we no longer need to fear?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文斜体部分，你能否命名我们不需要再害怕的三件事？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Jesus has won our salvation, we no longer need to fear 1) being condemned by God for our sins, 2) the devil having power over us, and 3) eternal death in hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through God’s grace, what do we get to look forward to?  (Look at the underlined portions of those passages.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上帝的恩典，我们期盼得到什么？（参看上述经文划线部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through God’s grace, we look forward to eternal life with God in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do our good works play any part in our salvation?  (Look at Romans 11:6.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们的好行为在我们的拯救中起任何作用吗？（参看罗马书11:6。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our good works have no role in our salvation.  Salvation is entirely a gift of God to us because of what Jesus did to save us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of these passages, how would you answer that question, “WHAT IS THE RESULT OF GOD SHOWING HIS GRACE TO US?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文，如何回答问题“上帝向我们显明他的恩典的结果是什么？”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of God showing His grace to us is that we have been saved from our great enemies of sin, Satan and death and that we now have forgiveness, acceptance by God and eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God’s grace is that undeserved love he showed to all humankind.  It moved him to send his Son Jesus to pay for all the sins of all people.  But, unfortunately, not all people receive the benefits of Christ’s death and resurrection.  Why do some receive eternal life and not others?  That is the focus of our next key concept – FAITH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝的恩典是他向人类所显明的不应得的爱。这让他把他儿子耶稣派来赎所有人的罪。但是，可惜地是，不是所有的人都接受了耶稣死亡和复活的恩惠。为什么有些人接受了永生但是其他人没有呢？那就是下一个关键概念的聚焦－－信心。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TAKING IT DEEPER…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;深入思考&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Agree or Disagree – God loves all good people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－上帝爱所有的好人。

Agree.  God loves everyone.  He has provided a Savior who paid for the sins of all people and has won eternal life for all people.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Agree or Disagree – Some people are more deserving of God’s grace than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－有些人比其他人更应受到上帝的恩典。

Disagree.   We all sin and possess nothing deserving of God’s love and favor to give Him.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree or Disagree – Jesus loved us by living a sinless life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－通过没有罪的生活，耶稣爱我们。

Agree.  Jesus’ keeping of God’s commands was done for us as part of what He had to do to save us.  We owe God a perfect life.   Jesus had fulfilled that obligation as our Substitute.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Agree or Disagree – Jesus’ main job was to show us how to live a God-pleasing life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－耶稣的主要工作是教我们如何过上帝喜悦的生活。

Disagree.   Jesus is a wonderful example for us on how to live.  But His main job was to be our Savior and deliver us from sin and death.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E. Agree or Disagree – Jesus could have saved himself by coming down from the cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－耶稣可以从十字架上走下来以拯救自己。

Disagree.   Jesus offered and decided to become our Savior from eternity.  Once He made that commitment there was no turning back from it.   It He had come down from the cross, He would have broken His commitment and failed in His mission.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F. Agree or Disagree – The virgin birth proves Jesus was the Son of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－生于童贞女证明了耶稣是上帝的儿子。

Agree.  The Virgin Birth along with the conception of Jesus in Mary by the Holy Spirit

Is the miracle that allowed the eternal Son of God to also become a true human being

while still being the Son of God.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G. Agree or Disagree – Our Savior had to be both true man and true God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－我们的救主必须既是真人也是真神。

Agree.   Jesus had to be a true man to take our obligation under God’s law and to obey and suffer and die in our place.  He also had to be true God so that He could multiply His obedience and sacrifice to cover the obligations of all people.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H. Agree or Disagree – God shows love and offers forgiveness to those in whom he sees some merit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;同意与否－－上帝向他看到有优点的人显明爱并施以原谅。

Disagree.   God’s love and forgiveness are free gifts of His grace in Jesus.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I. What do you think?  When Jesus was on the cross, did he deserve to die?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;你如何认为？当耶稣在十字架上的时候，他应该受死吗？

Yes and No.   Jesus personally had no sins for which He deserved any punishment.  However, Jesus was serving as our Substitute and was bearing our sins and our curse and punishment for those sins.  In that sense, Jesus “deserved” to die.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. What do you think?  If Jesus paid for all sins, do I have free license to go out and commit whatever sins I want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;你如何认为？如何耶稣赎了所有的罪，那么我有免费执照可以去犯我所想的罪吗？

No, we do not have a license to sin.  God has not abolished His law.  We are still obligated to live a life of perfect love toward God and all people.  Because of the salvation Jesus has given us, this is what we want to do to show our thanks and love for God.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K. What do you think?  Wouldn’t Jesus’ death only pay for the sins that had been committed before his death?  Are all the sins that were committed AFTER Jesus’ death still paid for? What about the sins I will likely commit tomorrow, and the next day, and 25 years from now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;你如何认为？耶稣的死不是仅仅赎了那些在他死之前的罪吗？在耶稣死之后的罪也被赎了吗？那么我明天可能将犯下的罪呢？后天呢？25年以后呢？

In the Bible, God says that Jesus paid for all the sins of all people of all time.  That covers all our present and future sins.  When God transferred the sins of people to Jesus, it is just as easy for Him to gather up all future sins as well as all past sins and

put them on Jesus’ soul.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L. What do you think?  The Bible calls our salvation by grace “a gift.”  Imagine you were given a birthday present, but then the person who gave it to you told you that if you wanted to keep it, you had to wash their car.  Would that really be a gift?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;你如何认为？圣经称我们通过恩典的拯救为“礼物”。想象一下你得到了一个生日礼物，但是给你礼物那人又告诉你如果你想要拥有这个礼物，你必须洗他的车。那是一个真的礼物吗？

No, having to wash a car as a condition for getting the car makes the car no longer a gift.   However, God’s gift of salvation is so wonderful that it moves us to want to do good things to serve, honor and thank God.  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 信心 FAITH</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/101/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/101/3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;So far we’ve looked at how everyone is guilty of sin, and therefore deserving of the punishment of hell.  But we also saw how God responded to humankind’s hopelessness by graciously sending his Son Jesus to pay for sin.  But that raises the question, “If Jesus paid for everyone’s sins, isn’t everyone going to be saved?”  The answer revolves around the third key concept – faith.  In this lesson, we hope to answer the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• What is the difference between those who are saved and those who aren’t?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• What is “faith”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Does faith save us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• How does someone come to faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;目前为止，我们看到每个人都是有罪的，因此都应该受到地狱的惩罚。但是我们也看到上帝是如何回应人类的无望的，他恩慈地差他儿子耶稣来赎罪。这便提出了一个问题，“如果耶稣为每个人赎罪，是不是每个人都会得救呢？”该问题的回答围绕着第三个关键的概念――信心。在这一课，我们希望回答下列问题：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 那些得救的和没得救的有什么区别？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 什么是“信心”？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 信心拯救我们吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 某人是如何开始相信的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT’S THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THOSE WHO ARE SAVED AND THOSE WHO AREN’T?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;那些得救的和没得救的有什么区别？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请阅读下面的经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 3:16 – “For God so loved the world that he gave his one and only Son…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰福音3:16－－“神爱世人，甚至将他的独生子赐给他们…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 5:19 – God was reconciling the world to himself in Christ, not counting men’s sins against them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;哥林多后书5:19－－这就是神在基督里，叫世人与自己和好，不将他们的过犯归到他们身上。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 2:2 – He is the atoning sacrifice for our sins, and not only for ours but also for the sins of the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书2:2－－他为我们的罪作了挽回祭，不是单为我们的罪，也是为普天下人的罪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Thessalonians 1:8-9 – He will punish those who do not know God and do not obey the gospel of our Lord Jesus. They will be punished with everlasting destruction and shut out from the presence of the Lord and from the majesty of his power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;贴撒罗尼迦后书1:8-9－－要报应那不认识神和那不听从我主耶稣福音的人。他们要受刑罚，就是永远沉沦，离开主的面和他权能的荣光。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 25:46 – “Then they will go away to eternal punishment, but the righteous to eternal life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音25:46－－“这些人要往永刑里去；那些义人要往永生里去。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the underlined portions of those passages, whose sins did Jesus pay for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文划线部分，耶稣赎了谁的罪？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus paid for the sins of the whole world, that is, all people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the italicized portions of those passages, does the Bible teach that everyone is saved?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文斜体部分，圣经教导我们每个人都会得救吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, it does not say that everyone will go to heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus while the Bible teaches that Jesus paid for everyone’s sins, it also teaches that not everyone will be saved.  Rather, some will be punished for their sins.  Let’s look at the reason for the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经教导我们耶稣为每个人赎罪，也教导我们不是每个人都会得救。更确切地说，有些人将会因他们的罪而受到惩罚。让我们一起来看看产生这个区别的原因。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 3:16 – “For God so loved the world that he gave his one and only Son, that whoever believes in him shall not perish but have eternal life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰福音3:16－－“神爱世人，甚至将他的独生子赐给他们，叫一切信他的，不至灭亡，反得永生。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark 16:16 – “Whoever believes and is baptized will be saved, but whoever does not believe will be condemned.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马可福音16:16－－“信而受洗的，必然得救；不信的，必被定罪。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 3:18 – Whoever believes in him is not condemned, but whoever does not believe stands condemned already because he has not believed in the name of God’s one and only Son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰福音3:18－－信他的人，不被定罪；不信的人，罪已经定了，因为他不信神独生子的名。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the italicized portions of those passages, whom does the Bible teach will be saved?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文斜体部分，圣经教导我们谁会得救？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;he Bible teaches that those people who believe in Jesus Christ will be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And according to the underlined portions of those passages, who will not be saved?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文划线部分，谁不会得救？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who do not believe in Jesus Christ will not be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 4:13 – It is written: “I believed; therefore I have spoken.” With that same spirit of faith we also believe and therefore speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;哥林多后书4:13－－但我们既有信心，正如经上记着说：“我因信，所以如此说话。”我们也信，所以也说话。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 3:22 – This righteousness from God comes through faith in Jesus Christ to all who believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书3:22－－就是神的义，因信耶稣基督加给一切相信的人，并没有分别。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Peter 1:21 – Through him you believe in God, who raised him from the dead and glorified him, and so your faith and hope are in God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;彼得一书1:21－－你们也因着他，信那叫他从死里复活、又给他荣耀的神，叫你们的信心和盼望都在于神。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to those passages, what is another word for “believing”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文，“相信”的另一种说法是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another word for believing is having faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of the passages we have looked at, how would you then answer the question, “WHAT’S THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THOSE WHO ARE SAVED AND THOSE WHO AREN’T?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述我们所学的经文，如何回答问题“那些得救的和没得救的有什么区别？”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between those who are saved and those who are not is faith in Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT IS “FAITH”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;什么是“信心”？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James 2:19 – You believe that there is one God. Good! Even the demons believe that – and shudder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;雅各书2:19－－你信神只有一位，你信的不错；鬼魔也信，却是战惊。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 8:28 – When he arrived at the other side in the region of the Gadarenes, two demon-possessed men coming from the tombs met him. They were so violent that no one could pass that way.  “What do you want with us, Son of God?” they shouted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音8:28－－耶稣既渡到那边去，来到加大拉人的地方，就有两个被鬼附的人从坟茔里出来迎着他，极其凶猛，甚至没有人能从那条路上经过。他们喊着说：“神的儿子，我们与你有什么相干？时候还没有到，你就上这里来叫我们受苦吗？”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demons know that Jesus is the Son of God.  Therefore, faith is more than just simple head-knowledge about who Jesus is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;魔鬼知道耶稣是上帝的儿子。因此信心胜过头脑里简单的知识，比如耶稣是谁。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 10:10 – For it is with your heart that you believe…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书10:10－－因为人心里相信 …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebrews 10:22 – Let us draw near to God with a sincere heart in full assurance of faith, having our hearts sprinkled to cleanse us from a guilty conscience and having our bodies washed with pure water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;希伯来书10:22－－并我们心中天良的亏欠已经洒去，身体用清水洗净了，就当存着诚心和充足的信心来到神面前。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 78:22 – They did not believe in God or trust in his deliverance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇78:22－－因为他们不信服神，不倚赖他的救恩。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 14:1 – Jesus said, &amp;ldquo;Do not let your hearts be troubled. Trust in God; trust also in me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰福音14:1－－耶稣说：“你们心里不要忧愁；你们信神，也当信我。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebrews 11:1 – Now faith is being sure of what we hope for and certain of what we do not see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;希伯来书11:1－－信就是所望之事的实底，是未见之事的确据。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faith affects more than the head.  It also affects the…?  (Look at the italicized portions of those passages.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;信心不仅影响头脑。它也影响…？（参看上述经文斜体部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faith also affects the human heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is another word you could use to describe this “heart-knowledge”?  (Look at the underlined portions of those verses.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“心灵知识”还可以用哪个词来描述？（参看上述经文划线部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another word to describe heart-knowledge is “trust”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Hebrews 11:1, what does faith enable people to trust in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据希伯来书11:1，信心能够使人们信任什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saving faith in Jesus enables people to trust in God for the invisible, future things that God gives us by promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 8:38-39 – For I am convinced that neither death nor life, neither angels nor demons, neither the present nor the future, nor any powers, neither height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God that is in Christ Jesus our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书8:38-39－－因为我深信无论是死，是生，是天使，是掌权的，是有能的，是现在的事，是将来的事，是高处的，是低处的，是别的受造之物，都不能叫我们与神的爱隔绝；这爱是在我们的主基督耶稣里的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 12:2 – Surely God is my salvation; I will trust and not be afraid. The LORD, the LORD, is my strength and my song; he has become my salvation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以赛亚书12:2－－看哪！神是我的拯救；我要倚靠他，并不惧怕。因为主耶和华是我的力量，是我的诗歌，他也成了我的拯救。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galatians 2:20 – The life I live in the body, I live by faith in the Son of God, who loved me and gave himself for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;加拉太书2:20－－并且我如今在肉身活着，是因信神的儿子而活；他是爱我，为我舍己。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 3:22 – This righteousness from God comes through faith in Jesus Christ to all who believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书3:22－－就是神的义，因信耶稣基督加给一切相信的人，并没有分别。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 2:8 – It is by grace you have been saved, through faith…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以弗所书2:8－－你们得救是本乎恩，也因着信…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the italicized portions of these passages, what exactly is the object of our faith?  What do we put our trust in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文斜体部分，我们信心的对象确切地是什么？我们信任什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The object of our faith and trust  is Jesus Christ and what He has done to save us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does our faith trust that God did?  (Look at the underlined portions of those passages.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们的信心相信上帝做了什么？（参看上述经文划线部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our faith trusts that God  has loved us and saved us through Jesus Christ and His redeeming work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of the passages we have looked at, then, could you please answer the question, “WHAT DO WE MEAN WHEN WE SAY ‘FAITH’?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基于上述我们所学经文，请回答问题“我们说‘信心’时意味着什么？”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By faith we mean our heart’s confidence and trust in God’s love for us in Jesus Christ and what He has done to save us from our sin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DOES FAITH SAVE US?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;信心拯救我们吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请阅读下面的经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acts 16:30-31 – [The jailer said], “Sirs, what must I do to be saved?”  They replied, “Believe in the Lord Jesus, and you will be saved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;使徒行传16:30-31－－【禁卒说】，“二位先生，我当怎样行才可以得救？” 他们说：“当信主耶稣，你和你一家都必得救。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 10:4 – Christ is the end of the law so that there may be righteousness for everyone who believes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书10:4－－律法的总结就是基督，使凡信他的都得着义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 15:6 – Abram believed (that is, had faith in) the LORD, and God credited it to him as righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;创世纪15:6－－亚伯兰信（意思是信任）耶和华，耶和华就以此为他的义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 4:3 – What does the Scripture say? &amp;ldquo;Abraham believed God, and it was credited to him as righteousness.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书4:3－－经上说什么呢？说：“亚伯拉罕信神，这就算为他的义。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 4:23-24 – The words &amp;ldquo;it was credited to him&amp;rdquo; were written not for him alone,  but also for us, to whom God will credit righteousness – for us who believe in him who raised Jesus our Lord from the dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书 4:23-24－－“算为他义”的这句话不是单为他写的，也是为我们将来得算为义之人写的，就是我们这信神使我们的主耶稣从死里复活的人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philippians 3:8-9 – What is more, I consider everything a loss compared to the surpassing greatness of knowing Christ Jesus my Lord, for whose sake I have lost all things. I consider them rubbish, that I may gain Christ and be found in him, not having a righteousness of my own that comes from the law, but that which is through faith in Christ – the righteousness that comes from God and is by faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;腓立比书 3:8-9－－不但如此，我也将万事当作有损的，因我以认识我主基督耶稣为至宝。我为他已经丢弃万事，看作粪土，为要得着基督；并且得以在他里面，不是有自己因律法而得的义，乃是有信基督的义，就是因信神而来的义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 2:1 – If anybody does sin, we have one who speaks to the Father in our defense – Jesus Christ, the Righteous One.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书2:1－－若有人犯罪，在父那里我们有一位中保，就是那义者耶稣基督。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the Bible teach that it is necessary for someone to have faith if they are going to be saved?  (Look especially at the first two passages.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经教导我们如果某人将会得救，信心是必要的吗？（尤其参看前两段经文。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the Bible teaches that it is necessary to have faith in order to be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the italicized portions of those passages, what does God do for people who put their faith in Jesus as their Savior?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文斜体部分，上帝为那些相信耶稣为其救主的人们做些什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God ends the accusations of His law against people and credits the righteousness of Jesus to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whose righteousness do we receive as “credit” through faith?  (Look especially at the underlined portions of those verses.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;通过信心我们得到谁的义而算为我们的义？（尤其看上述经文划线部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We receive the righteousness of Jesus Christ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of the passages we have looked at, how would you answer the question, “DOES FAITH SAVE US?”  Or perhaps if we wanted to ask the question more specifically, “DOES FAITH IN AND OF ITSELF SAVE US, OR DOES THE OBJECT OF OUR FAITH (JESUS CHRIST AND HIS RIGHTEOUSNESS) SAVE US?”  (circle one below)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基于我们所学经文，如何回答问题“信心拯救我们吗？”？或者如果我们想要回答地更具体一些，“信心它自己拯救我们吗？还是我们信心的对象（耶稣和他的义）拯救我们？”（从下面两个陈述中选一个划圈）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WE ARE SAVED BECAUSE OF OUR FAITH.  我们得救是因为我们的信。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WE ARE SAVED BECAUSE OF THE OBJECT OF OUR FAITH – JESUS CHRIST.  我们得救是因为我们信心的对象――耶稣基督。
We are saved because of Jesus Christ, the object of our faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship between faith and salvation can be illustrated in the following way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;信心和拯救的关系可以用下列方式来说明。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you received the injection of that antidote and your life was saved, you probably wouldn’t sing the praises of that wonderful hypodermic needle.  You’d sing the praises of the antidote.  The hypodermic needle had to be there, or you wouldn’t have received the antidote. But you know that the needle isn’t what saved you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当你注射了那解毒剂后，你的生命就得救了。你大概不会去赞扬那个奇妙的皮下注射器针头，但是你会去赞扬解毒剂。皮下注射器针头必须存在，否则你将无法获得该解毒剂。但是你知道不是那个针头救了你。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, faith has to be there if someone is going to be saved (cf. John 3:16 or Acts 16:30-31).  However, we know faith isn’t the cause of salvation.  Salvation is the result of the object of our faith, Jesus Christ.  Through faith we receive the benefits of his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同样地，如果某人要被拯救，信心必须存在 （参看约翰福音3:16 或使徒行传16:30-31）。但是，我们知道信心不是拯救的原因。拯救是因为我们信心的对象――耶稣基督。通过信心，我们获得了他行为的益处。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOW DOES SOMEONE COME TO FAITH?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;某人是如何开始相信的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请阅读下面的经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 2:8 – For it is by grace you have been saved, through faith &amp;ndash; and this not from yourselves, it is the gift of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以弗所书2:8－－你们得救是本乎恩，也因着信；这并不是出于自己，乃是神所赐的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 12:3 – For by the grace given me I say to every one of you: Do not think of yourself more highly than you ought, but rather think of yourself with sober judgment, in accordance with the measure of faith God has given you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书12:3－－我凭着所赐我的恩对你们各人说：不要看自己过于所当看的，要照着神所分给各人信心的大小，看得合乎中道。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 15:16 – [Jesus said], “You did not choose me, but I chose you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰福音15:16－－【耶稣说】，“不是你们拣选了我，是我拣选了你们。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 12:3 – No one can say, &amp;ldquo;Jesus is Lord,&amp;rdquo; except by the Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;哥林多前书12:3－－若不是被圣灵感动的，也没有能说“耶稣是主”的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is faith something we accomplished on our own?  Did we choose to have faith? (Look at the italicized portions of those passages.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;信心是我们自己完成的吗？我们自己选择去相信吗？（参看上述经文斜体部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, saving faith in Jesus is not something we create for ourselves or choose to ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we didn’t choose to have faith, how did we get it?  (Look at the underlined portions of those passages.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果我们没有自己选择去相信，我们是如何开始相信的？（参看上述经文划线部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We received faith as God’s free gift to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 10:17 – Faith comes from hearing the message, and the message is heard through the word of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书10:17－－可见信道是从听道来的，听道是从基督的话来的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Timothy 3:15 – From infancy you have known the holy Scriptures, which are able to make you wise for salvation through faith in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;提摩太后书3:15－－并且知道你是从小明白圣经，这圣经能使你因信基督耶稣，有得救的智慧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Thessalonians 2:13-14 – But we ought always to thank God for you, brothers loved by the Lord, because from the beginning God chose you to be saved through the sanctifying work of the Spirit and through belief in the truth.  He called you to this through our gospel, that you might share in the glory of our Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;贴撒罗尼迦后书2:13-14－－主所爱的弟兄们哪，我们本该常为你们感谢神；因为他从起初拣选了你们，叫你们因信真道，又被圣灵感动，成为圣洁，能以得救。神藉我们所传的福音召你们到这地步，好得着我们主耶稣基督的荣光。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the italicized portions of those verses, what does God use in order to create saving faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据上述经文斜体部分，为了创造拯救的信心，上帝使用了什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God uses the Gospel in God’s Word to create saving faith in us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 2:8 – But for those who are self-seeking and who reject the truth and follow evil, there will be wrath and anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书2:8－－惟有结党、不顺从真理、反顺从不义的，就以忿怒、恼恨报应他们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 3:16-17 – I pray that out of his glorious riches he may strengthen you with power through his Spirit in your inner being, so that Christ may dwell in your hearts through faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以弗所书 3:16-17－－求他按着他丰盛的荣耀，藉着他的灵，叫你们心里的力量刚强起来， 使基督因你们的信，住在你们心里。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Bible teaches that we don’t have the power to come to faith, we do have one awesome power.  According to Romans 2:8, what is that power?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;圣经教导说我们没有开始相信的力量，但是我们确实有一个令人惊叹的力量。根据罗马书2:8，那个力量是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do have the awesome power to reject God’s Word and follow evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why God’s Word is so important in our lives.  According to Ephesians 3:16-17, what does the Holy Spirit do for our faith through God’s Word?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这就是为什么上帝的话在我们的生命中很重要。根据以弗所书3:16-17，通过上帝的话，圣灵为我们的信心做了什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through God’s Word, the Holy Spirit strengthens our faith and gives us power to remain in faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of the passages we have looked at, how would you answer that question, “HOW DOES SOMEONE COME TO FAITH?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基于上述我们所学的经文，如何回答问题，“某人是如何开始相信的？”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person comes to faith by the Holy Spirit creating faith in Christ in a person’s heart through the use of the Gospel in God’s Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is the sacrifice Christ made for us a gift from God, our faith is also a gift from God!  Our salvation, then, is entirely God’s doing.  This raises the logical question, “What about our good works?  How do they fit in?”  That is the focus of our final key concept – WORKS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝的礼物不仅是耶稣为我们所做的牺牲，我们的信心也是上帝的礼物！我们的拯救，则是上帝作为的完全。这就提出了一个逻辑问题，“我们的好行为呢？它们如何协调的？”那便是我们最后一个关键概念的聚焦――行为。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TAKING IT DEEPER…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;深入思考…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Agree or Disagree – Jesus paid for the sins of those people who are in hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  同意与否――耶稣赎了那些在地狱里的人的罪。

  Agree.  Jesus did pay for those sins of the people who go to hell and He deeply desires that they would go to heaven instead.  However, these people go to hell because they refuse to let God save them through the Gospel.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Agree or Disagree – The devil knows that Jesus died on the cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  同意与否――魔鬼知道耶稣死在十字架上。

  Agree.  The devil knows the historical facts that Jesus died.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree or Disagree – The devil has faith in Jesus’ death on the cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  同意与否――魔鬼相信耶稣在十字架上的死。

  Disagree.  The devil has no faith that Jesus died on the cross for him.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Agree or Disagree – We will go to heaven if we believe in Jesus and try to live according to our faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  同意与否――如果我们相耶稣并且试着按照我们的信心去生活，那么我们将会去天堂。

  Disagree.  The reason we will go to heaven in through believing in Jesus as our Savior.   Our trying to live according to our faith is a fruit or result of having saving faith.  Neither our good works nor our faith is a meriting condition for our salvation.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E. Agree or Disagree – Faith comes to those who pray for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  同意与否――那些祷告的人得信心。

  Disagree.   Faith does not come through faith.  Faith comes from the Holy Spirit who creates it through our exposure to God’s Word.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F. Agree or Disagree – We have the power to keep our faith strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  同意与否――我们有能坚固加强我们信心的力量。

  Disagree.  We have an obligation to continue to use God’s Word so that the Holy Spirit can strengthen our faith, but it is the Holy Spirit who does the strengthening.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G. Agree or Disagree – A good pastor will bring many people to faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  同意与否――一位好牧师将会使很多人开始相信。

  Disagree.  It is not a human being who can create saving faith.  Only God the Holy Spirit can bring people to faith.   A Christian who faithfully shares the Gospel with people gives the Holy Spirit wonderful opportunities to bring people to faith.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H. What do you think?  A common expression is “Keep the faith!”  Another one is “You just got to have faith.”  In light of what we said saving faith is, can you explain why those expressions are completely meaningless unless further explanation is given?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  你如何认为？“保持信心”是一个很普遍的表达。另一个是“你就需要信心”。根据我们所说的拯救信心的含义，能否解释为什么这些表达是完全无意义的，除非有进一步地解释？

  By our own natural powers, we do not have the ability to come to faith or stay in faith.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I. What do you think?  You can say a Hindu, or a Muslim, or a Buddhist has faith.  You could even say that they have strong faith.  But if you say that, how are you defining faith?  Could you say those people have saving faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  你如何认为？你可以说一个印度教徒，一位穆斯林（伊斯兰教徒）或者一位佛教徒有信心。你甚至可以说他们有很强的信心。但是如果你这么说，你如何来定义信心呢？你可以说这些人有拯救的信心

  Faith is confidence or trust in something.   Everyone has some kind of faith.  Saving faith is trust and confidence in Jesus Christ as one’s Savior from sin.  Only Christians have Jesus Christ as the object of their faith.  Only Jesus can save.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: 行为 WORK</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/101/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/101/4/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;We’ve seen how our salvation is entirely dependent on God.  Jesus Christ is the one who made the complete payment for our sins.  The Holy Spirit is the one who creates saving faith in our hearts.  But where do our good works play into all this?  That is the focus of our final key concept – works.  Here are the questions we need to answer in this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• What part do good works play in our salvation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Why do we do good works?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• How do we do good works?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• What guidance does God give to help us learn what he considers “good”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们已经看到我们的拯救完全依靠上帝。耶稣基督为我们赎了所有的罪。圣灵在我们的心里创造拯救信心。但是我们的好行为在这其中起什么作用呢？这就是最后一个关键概念的聚焦――好行为。如下是我们这课中需要回答的问题：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 好行为在我们的拯救中起什么作用？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 我们为什么行善？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 我们如何行善？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• 上帝给我们什么指引来帮助我们学习什么是上帝所认为的“好”？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT PART DO GOOD WORKS PLAY IN OUR SALVATION?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;好行为在我们的拯救中起什么作用？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请阅读下面的经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 3:28 – We maintain that a man is justified (declared “not guilty”) by faith apart from observing the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书3:28－－人称义（宣称“无罪”）是因着信，不在乎遵行律法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 2:8-9 – For it is by grace you have been saved, through faith – and this not from yourselves, it is the gift of God – not by works, so that no one can boast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以弗所书2:8-9－－你们得救是本乎恩，也因着信；这并不是出于自己，乃是神所赐的；也不是出于行为，免得有人自夸。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 11:5-6 – So too, at the present time there is a remnant chosen by grace.  And if by grace, then it is no longer by works; if it were, grace would no longer be grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书11:5-6－－如今也是这样，照着拣选的恩典，还有所留的余数。既是出于恩典，就不在乎行为；不然，恩典就不是恩典了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 9:30 – The Gentiles, who did not pursue righteousness, have obtained it, a righteousness that is by faith; but Israel, who pursued a law of righteousness, has not attained it.  Why not? Because they pursued it not by faith but as if it were by works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书9:30－－那本来不追求义的外邦人反得了义，就是因信而得的义。但以色列人追求律法的义，反得不着律法的义。这是什么缘故呢？是因为他们不凭着信心求，只凭着行为求。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galatians 5:4 – You who are trying to be justified by law have been alienated from Christ; you have fallen away from grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;加拉太书5:4－－你们这要靠律法称义的，是与基督隔绝，从恩典中坠落了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of these passages, if you were to fill in percentages for how much our salvation is dependant on God’s grace and how much is dependent on our good works, what would those percentages be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基于上述经文，如果让你来填写我们的拯救有多少是基于上帝的恩典，有多少是基于我们的好行为，其比例是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our salvation is &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt;___% God’s grace and &lt;strong&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt;___% our good works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们的拯救是上帝_______%的恩典和我们_______%的好行为。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do those passages say happens if someone tries to earn salvation on their own, by relying on their own good works? (Look at the underlined portions of those passages.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果某人试着靠自己博得拯救，靠着他们自己的好行为，将会发生什么事情？（参看上述经文划线部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person who tries to earn salvation on their own by their good works will never attain salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of those passages, how would you answer that question, “WHAT PART DO GOOD WORKS PLAY IN OUR SALVATION?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基于上述经文，如何回答问题“好行为在我们的拯救中起什么作用？”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our good works play not part in our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have used the word “justification” (or “justify”) a number of times.  It came up above in Romans 3:28 and Galatians 5:4.  We defined this as “a legal term which means to declare someone ‘not guilty’ of sin.”  It’s important to remember that our salvation is just that – a declaration of God that he makes in light of Christ’s death and resurrection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们已经多次使用了“称义”这个词。在上述经文罗马书3:28以及加拉太书5:4又出现了。我们定义这个为“一个法律词汇，其意思是宣称某人是‘无罪’的”。我们的拯救就是上帝因着基督的死亡和复活所做的一个宣言，牢记这一点很重要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHY DO WE DO GOOD WORKS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们为什么行善？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请阅读下面的经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 56:4 – In God I trust; I will not be afraid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇56:4－－我倚靠神，必不惧怕。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 4:19 – We love because he first loved us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书4:19－－我们爱，因为神先爱我们。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 5:14-15 – For Christ&amp;rsquo;s love compels us, because we are convinced that one died for all, and therefore all died.  And he died for all, that those who live should no longer live for themselves but for him who died for them and was raised again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;哥林多后书5:14-15－－原来基督的爱激励我们；因我们想，一人既替众人死，众人就都死了；并且他替众人死，是叫那些活着的人不再为自己活，乃为替他们死而复活的主活。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galatians 2:20 – I have been crucified with Christ and I no longer live, but Christ lives in me. The life I live in the body, I live by faith in the Son of God, who loved me and gave himself for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;加拉太书2:20－－我已经与基督同钉十字架，现在活着的不再是我，乃是基督在我里面活着；并且我如今在肉身活着，是因信神的儿子而活；他是爱我，为我舍己。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 12:1 – Therefore, I urge you, brothers, in view of God’s mercy, to offer your bodies as living sacrifices, holy and pleasing to God – which is your spiritual worship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书12:1 －－所以弟兄们，我以神的慈悲劝你们，将身体献上，当作活祭，是圣洁的，是神所喜悦的；你们如此事奉乃是理所当然的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 56:4 gives one reason for trying to do good works that has been removed from our life.  What motivator to do good works has been removed from the life of the Christian?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇56:4把我们生活里一个试着去行善的原因拿走了。基督徒生活中什么样的行善动机被拿走了？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motivation of fear as a reason to do good works have been removed from our life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians have a different motivation.  On the basis of those passages, how would you answer that question, “WHY DO WE DO GOOD WORKS?”  (Look at the italicized portions of those passages.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒有一个不一样的动机。基于上述经文，如何回答问题“我们为什么行善？”（参看上述经文斜体部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians do good works out of love for the God who loves us and has saved us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOW DO WE DO GOOD WORKS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们如何行善？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 8:7 – The sinful mind is hostile to God. It does not submit to God&amp;rsquo;s law, nor can it do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书8:7－－原来体贴肉体的，就是与神为仇；因为不服神的律法，也是不能服。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galatians 5:17 – The sinful nature desires what is contrary to the Spirit, and the Spirit what is contrary to the sinful nature. They are in conflict with each other, so that you do not do what you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;加拉太书5:17－－因为情欲和圣灵相争，圣灵和情欲相争，这两个是彼此相敌，使你们不能做所愿意做的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 7:18-19 – I know that nothing good lives in me, that is, in my sinful nature. For I have the desire to do what is good, but I cannot carry it out.  For what I do is not the good I want to do; no, the evil I do not want to do – this I keep on doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书7:18-19－－我也知道在我里头，就是我肉体之中，没有良善。因为，立志为善由得我，只是行出来由不得我。故此，我所愿意的善，我反不做；我所不愿意的恶，我倒去做。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we have the power, on our own, to do good works? (Look at the italicized portions of those verses.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们自己有力量来行善吗？（参看上述经文斜体部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not have the natural ability or power to do good works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? (Look at the underlined portions of those verses.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么？（参看上述经文划线部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By nature, all we have is a sinful nature.  Our sinful nature is spiritual unwilling and unable to do the good God requires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 2:10 – For we are God&amp;rsquo;s workmanship, created in Christ Jesus to do good works, which God prepared in advance for us to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以弗所书2:10－－我们原是他的工作，在基督耶稣里造成的，为要叫我们行善，就是神所预备叫我们行的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philippians 2:13 – …for it is God who works in you to will and to act according to his good purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;腓立比书2:13－－…因为你们立志行事都是神在你们心里运行，为要成就他的美意。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 9:8 – And God is able to make all grace abound to you, so that in all things at all times, having all that you need, you will abound in every good work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;哥林多后书9:8－－神能将各样的恩惠多多的加给你们，使你们凡事常常充足，能多行各样善事。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Titus 2:11-12 – For the grace of God that brings salvation has appeared to all men.  It teaches us to say &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo; to ungodliness and worldly passions, and to live self-controlled, upright and godly lives in this present age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;提多书2:11-12－－因为神救众人的恩典已经显明出来，教训我们除去不敬虔的心和世俗的情欲，在今世自守、公义、敬虔度日。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are we able to do good works? (Look at the italicized portions of those verses.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;为什么我们能够行善？（参看上述经文斜体部分。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God gives us the desires and power to do good works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We said that God gets the credit for the forgiveness of sins.  We said that he gets the credit for our faith.  Would you have to say the same thing about our good works?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罪获赦免，我们说上帝得赞扬。相信耶稣，我们也说上帝得赞扬。对我们的好行为，你会有同样的说法吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes.  God also gives us everything we need to do good works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These passages demonstrate the way that we speak about good works.  We don’t speak of good works as something that we should do.  Good works are something that we want to do.  They are something that by the grace of God we can do.  And they are something that a Christian just naturally will do.  (2 Corinthians 9:8 – “…you will abound in every good work.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这些经文证明了我们是如何描述好行为的。我们不说好行为是我们应该做的。好行为是我们想要做的。好行为是通过上帝的恩典我们才能做。好行为是基督徒自然而然就将会做的。（哥林多后书9:8－－“…使你们凡事常常充足，能多行各样善事。”）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can illustrate it this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你可以用如下方式来解释。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about apple trees.  Why is it that they produce apples?  Is it because they’ll feel guilty if they don’t?  Is it because they will be in some sort of trouble if they don’t produce enough fruit?  That’s foolish!  Apple trees produce apples because that’s just what apple trees do.  It’s natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;试想苹果树。为什么它们结果实呢？是因为如果不结果实它们觉得内疚吗？还是因为如果不结足够的果实，它们将会有些麻烦呢？真愚蠢！苹果树结苹果是因为这是它们本来就做的，这是自然的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians produce good works, not because they’ll feel guilty if they don’t, and not because they’re afraid that otherwise they’ll get in trouble with God.  Christians produce God works because Christ gave them the power to do so.  It’s what they naturally do!  Look at the following passages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒行善，不是因为如果他们不做他们会觉得内疚，也不是因为他们害怕如果不行善，上帝将会愤怒。基督徒行善是因为基督给他们这样去做的力量。基督徒行善是自然而然的！参看下列经文。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 15:4-5 – [Jesus said], “Remain in me, and I will remain in you. No branch can bear fruit by itself; it must remain in the vine. Neither can you bear fruit unless you remain in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am the vine; you are the branches. If a man remains in me and I in him, he will bear much fruit; apart from me you can do nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰福音15:4-5－－【耶稣说】，“你们要常在我里面，我也常在你们里面。枝子若不常在葡萄树上，自己就不能结果子；你们若不常在我里面，也是这样。“我是葡萄树，你们是枝子。常在我里面的，我也常在他里面，这人就多结果子；因为离了我，你们就不能做什么。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galatians 2:20 – I have been crucified with Christ and I no longer live, but Christ lives in me. The life I live in the body, I live by faith in the Son of God…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;加拉太书2:20－－我已经与基督同钉十字架，现在活着的不再是我，乃是基督在我里面活着；并且我如今在肉身活着，是因信神的儿子而活&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those passages tell us something about who can do good works.  In order to do what God considers to be “good works,” you need to be connected to Christ.  How is that connection made?  (Look at Galatians 2:20.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上述经文告诉我们谁能行善。为了能够做到上帝所认为的“行善”，你必须跟耶稣连在一起。这个关联是如何形成的？（参看加拉太书2:20。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our connection to Jesus Christ is made through faith in Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore if you didn’t have faith, would you be able to do good works in God’s eyes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因此，如果你没有信心，在上帝的眼里，你能够行善吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. Without faith I cannot do good works in God’s eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of the passages that we have looked at, how would you answer that question, “HOW DO WE DO GOOD WORKS?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基于上述我们所学经文，如何回答问题“我们如何行善？”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do good works as a fruit of our faith.  We do good works because God gives us both the willingness and the ability to please, honor and thank Him with our works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHAT GUIDANCE DOES GOD GIVE TO HELP US LEARN WHAT HE CONSIDERS “GOOD”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;上帝给我们什么指引来帮助我们学习什么是上帝所认为的“好”？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please read the following passages and then answer the corresponding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;请阅读下面的经文然后回答相关问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119:105 – Your word is a lamp to my feet and a light for my path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇119:105－－你的话是我脚前的灯，是我路上的光。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Timothy 3:16-17 – All Scripture is God-breathed and is useful for teaching, rebuking, correcting and training in righteousness, so that the man of God may be thoroughly equipped for every good work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;提摩太后书3:16-17－－圣经都是神所默示的，于教训、督责、使人归正、教导人学义都是有益的，叫属神的人得以完全，预备行各样的善事。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 7:22 – In my inner being I delight in God&amp;rsquo;s law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书7:22－－因为按着我里面的意思，我是喜欢神的律。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119:35 – Direct me in the path of your commands, for there I find delight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇119:35－－求你叫我遵行你的命令，因为这是我所喜乐的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 5:3 – This is love for God: to obey his commands. And his commands are not burdensome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;约翰一书5:3－－我们遵守神的诫命，这就是爱他了，并且他的诫命不是难守的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to those first two passages, where does God give us directions about how to live our lives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;根据前两段经文，上帝给我们关于如何生活的方向在哪？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God teaches us how to live our lives in His Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the unbeliever, God’s laws and commands are terrifying, because they show that every person deserves punishment since no one has kept God’s commands perfectly as he requires. But according to the last three passages printed above, are God’s commands terrifying for the Christian?  Why is this the case?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于不信主的，上帝的律法和命令是很可怕的。它们表露了每个人都应受惩罚，因为没有一个人按照上帝要求的完美地遵守他的命令。但是，根据上述最后三段经文，上帝的命令对于基督徒来说是可怕的吗？为什么是这样呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No.  For the Christian, God’s Word is a joy and delight.  Knowing that our sins against God’s laws have been forgiven by Christ, the Law no longer condemns us and is no longer our enemy.  Now we can joyfully consider the law a blessed gift from God to show us the way to live that pleases Him and fulfills the purpose for which He created and saved us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 22:37-39 – Jesus replied: &amp;quot; `Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind.&amp;rsquo;  This is the first and greatest commandment.  And the second is like it: `Love your neighbor as yourself.&amp;rsquo;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;马太福音22:37-39－－耶稣对他说：“你要尽心、尽性、尽意爱主你的神。这是诫命中的第一，且是最大的。其次也相仿，就是要爱人如己。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119:104 – I gain understanding from your precepts; therefore I hate every wrong path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;诗篇119:104－－我藉着你的训词得以明白，所以我恨一切的假道。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two passages give us a brief summary of God’s commands, and therefore a summary of how we can live a life of good works.  What are the two parts of this summary?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这两段经文对上帝的命令作了一个简短的总结，因此也是我们如何过好行为生活的总结。这个总结的两部分是什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LOVE &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;________________&amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our  neighbor (all people)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HATE &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;everything that is wrong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;____________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;爱 ___________________________ 和 __________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;恨 ________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of the passages we have looked at in this portion of our Bible study, how would you answer that question, “WHAT GUIDANCE DOES GOD GIVE TO HELP US LEARN WHAT HE CONSIDERS ‘GOOD’?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基于上述我们所学经文，如何回答问题“上帝给我们什么指引来帮助我们学习什么是上帝所认为的‘好’？”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God gives us the commands of His Law to teach us to know what He considers to be “good.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technical term we use for the way God enables us to perform good works is “sanctify.”  He “sanctifies us.”  The word’s basic meaning is “to set apart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们所用的上帝使我们能行善的专业词汇是“成圣”。他“使我们成圣”。这个词的基本意思是“使与众不同”。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SANCTIFY – To lead a believer to hate sin and be eager to live a life filled with good works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;成圣－－引领基督徒憎恨罪并渴望过着充满好行为的生活。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore God is the one who justifies us.  He declares us “not guilty of sin.”  God is also the one who sanctifies us.  He “sets apart” believers as his special people who love to do his will.  Our “justification” is a completed action.  Jesus completed it on the cross.  Our “sanctification” is an ongoing action that the Holy Spirit is working inside of us.  It won’t be perfectly complete until we reach heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因此，是上帝使我们称义的。他宣称我们“没有罪”。也是上帝使我们成圣的。他使信徒“与众不同”，愿意按照他的旨意而行事，并作为他特别的子民。我们的“称义”是一个完整的行为。我们的“成圣”则是一个正在进行的行为，圣灵在我们的内心中不停地做工。直到我们到达天堂，否则成圣是不会完美地完成的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians will slip in their sanctified lives.  Because we are still tainted with sin, we will not always see the opportunities to do good works that God places before us.  We will not always want to do them.  Look again at what the Apostle Paul himself wrote to the Romans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;基督徒也在其成圣的生活中跌倒。因为我们仍然被罪玷污着，我们不会总是看到上帝摆在我们面前去行善的机会。我们不会总是想要行善。请参看使徒保罗在罗马书中所写的相关内容。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 7:18-19, 24-25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that nothing good lives in me, that is, in my sinful nature. For I have the desire to do what is good, but I cannot carry it out.  For what I do is not the good I want to do; no, the evil I do not want to do – this I keep on doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a wretched man I am! Who will rescue me from this body of death?  Thanks be to God – through Jesus Christ our Lord!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;罗马书7:18-19, 24-25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我也知道在我里头，就是我肉体之中，没有良善。因为，立志为善由得我，只是行出来由不得我。故此，我所愿意的善，我反不做；我所不愿意的恶，我倒去做。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我真是苦啊！谁能救我脱离这取死的身体呢？感谢神，靠着我们的主耶稣基督就能脱离了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I don’t always do good works, I know I will live forever.  Why can I be certain that I am saved?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;尽管我不总是行善，我知道我一定会得永生。为什么我能够这么肯定我会被得救呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can be certain that we are saved because our salvation depends completely on Jesus Christ, our Savior, and not at all on our behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concludes our study of the four key concepts – SIN, GRACE, FAITH, &amp;amp; WORKS.  A firm grasp on these four concepts will give you a solid foundation upon which to build with further Bible study.  May God bless your study and grant you the full assurance that you are Christ’s and that Christ is yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这就结束了四个关键概念学习――罪，恩典，信心，和行为。牢固的掌握这四个概念将会给你以后的圣经学习打下坚固的基础。愿上帝祝福你的学习并赐给你坚定的信心，坚信你是耶稣的且耶稣是你的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TAKING IT DEEPER…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;深入思考…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Agree or Disagree – You can’t live a perfectly holy life until you become a Christian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意与否――在你成为基督徒以前，你不能过完美圣洁的生活。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disagree.   Even Christians do not live perfectly holy lives until God takes away their sinfulness when they enter heaven.  Yet God considers us holy through our Substitute and Savior, Jesus, who gives us His holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Agree or Disagree – The work of Jesus Christ gives us the chance to win eternal life by following his example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意与否－－通过效仿耶稣，他做工的效果给我们赢得永生的机会。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disagree.  We have eternal life through faith in Jesus as our Savior, not by our insufficient efforts to follow His perfect example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree or Disagree – Christians do not go to heaven because of their good works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意与否――基督徒上天堂不是因为他们的好行为。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agree.   We go to heaven because of the good works of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Agree or Disagree – I deserve some credit for the good works I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意与否――我行善，那么我应得一些赞扬。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disagree.   Our good works done through the power of the Holy Spirit out of faith in Jesus Christ please God, but they are not meritorious.   They contribute nothing to the payment Jesus made for our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E. Agree or Disagree – Christians, who are justified, still continue to commit sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意与否――称义的基督徒仍然犯罪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agree.  Christians still have their sinful natures which still lead them into sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F. Agree or Disagree – When I sin, I lose my salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意与否――我犯罪的时候，便失去了救恩。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disagree.  Sin weakens our faith, but we still retain our faith.   If we are careless and let our faith die, we will lose our salvation, but we do not fall out of faith every time we sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G. Agree or Disagree – Saving faith will always produces good works.  It won’t produce them perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意与否――拯救的信心将会永远产生好行为。但它不会完美地产生。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agree.   True faith produces real good works.  Yet even our best works are still tainted by by.   God considers them “good” for the sake of Jesus who has won pardon for our sins.  His pardoning love forgives the errors in our works, just as a loving parent “forgives” the mistakes in a small child’s art work that has been done to please the parent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H. Agree or Disagree – Because we are justified by grace, through faith, God doesn’t care whether a Christian does good works or not.  He cares whether or not we have faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同意与否――因为我们因恩典称义，通过信心，上帝不在乎基督徒是否行善。他只在乎我们是否有信心。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disagree.  God does care that we obey His law and live lives of love and service toward Him and others.   While our good works do not save us, they are a necessary fruit of saving faith in Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I. What do you think?  Would you agree with the following statement? “The most important thing about our lives is that we do good works.  It’s not so important why we do them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你如何认为？你同意下面的陈述吗？“我们生命中最重要的事情是我们去行善。至于我们为什么行善不是很重要。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would disagree.   The most important thing is to believe in Jesus Christ as our Savior.  After that the most important thing is to keep God’s command that we live lives of love and service toward God and people as a response to God’s saving love for us.   God does care not only about our works but the motivation behind them.  He wants them to flow from faith in Christ and love for Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G. What do you think?  If I am saved entirely by God’s grace and my good works have nothing to do with it, why can’t I go out and commit whatever sins I want and then ask God for forgiveness later?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你如何认为？如果我是完全被上帝的恩典所拯救的，且我的好行为在其中不起任何作用，为什么我不能犯我所想犯的罪，然后&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person who thinks this way does not understand and appreciate what it means to be saved by God from the sin that destroys us and earns us eternal death.  Thinking that it is OK to deliberately sin is an insult to the God of love and goodness and a rejection of His purpose for us that we love and do good as He does.  This attitude is a despising of God’s grace and will destroy a person’s faith and cause them to forfeit heaven and go to hell.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
