<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>恩典圣经学院 – 讲道学概要</title>
    <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 讲道学概要 on 恩典圣经学院</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:43:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/zh-cn/courses/404/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Homiletics Syllabus 讲道学提纲</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Homiletics Syllabus 讲道学提纲
Homiletics Syllabusalt
Professor John Baumann&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God has given the responsibility to call teachers, pastors, and preachers to the congregation, the people of God. If you are one to whom the congregation or her representatives have asked to speak the Word of God to them, you have been given an important trust. As the Lord says, Now it is required that those who have been given a trust must prove faithful (1 Corinthians 4:2).
This class is to help all speakers of the word to “prove faithful” and to give serious consideration to their thought and preparation for proclaiming God’s Word. Always remember, God’s people are precious treasures and anyone who speaks God’s Word wants to be well prepared for the task and must proclaim to them the truth of God’s Word.  Knowing that we are speaking to God’s people, it is trustworthy for us to use the abilities God has given us faithfully. This class will give you some tools to use your abilities to proclaim God’s Word well.
Section 1: The sermon is to have godly characteristics and purpose.
Section 2: The preacher needs to recognize their Biblical hermeneutic and decide what hermeneutic is best. The godly sermon will be based on Scripture, which is the Word of God.
Section 3: Analysis of the Biblical text on which we will preach prepares the speaker to better proclaim the Word and to reflect the Biblical goal of the text.
Section 4: We wish to develop the structure of our sermon to properly proclaim the text and to communicate to the people.
Section 5: There are primarily four “types” of sermons – topical, analytic, synthetic, and homily. Each has strengths and weaknesses. We are to choose the one to best communicate God’s Word.
Section 6:   The proclamation of God’s Word should not be left to the last minute but needs to be planned. After studying the text and letting the text suggest preaching values, we develop a basic outline and expand that outline.
Section 7: The development of the introduction and the conclusion for the sermon.
Section 8: Be aware that our writing and our speaking are two different talents. Work on the written style of the sermon will guide the spoken presentation.
Section 9: We live in an age of communication both written and spoken. We need to consider the talents that God has given us, and what a good presentation means and work to deliver our sermon using the abilities that God has given us.
Section 10: The choice of texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 11: Sermons for special occasions.
Section 12: Preaching based upon the historic church year.alt
Class Procedure
The instruction will work with the English speaking students . The instructor will give the final exam (preaching assignment) at the conclusion of the class.
Text And Notes
The course notes was prepared by Prof. John Baumann.
Course Length
The course will generally be done between 12-14 weeks or 18-24 hours of time.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 1 （第一课）</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Lesson 1 （第一课）
Focus 1 the Nature and purpose of the sermon.
A sermon is the spoken Word of God addressed to the spiritual needs of people, each who is precious to God. First, the modern preacher speaks what God has revealed to people in the Word. Second, the modern preacher speaks to God’s people to address their faith and their life.
·         See 1 Timothy 2:4 What is God’s goal in this verse?
·         See 2 Peter 1:20-21
·         Although we are not Old Testament prophets, what does this verse point out that is applicable to our sermons?
·         What is the difference between a sermon and a class lecture?
·         What is the difference between a sermon and using words to manipulate people?
God uses the foolishness of preaching to proclaim his salvation for us and his power. (1 Corinthians 1:21).
·         What is it about preaching which seems so foolish?
·         Why is the message of this text comforting to the preacher?
Our sermons are always meant to praise God and the son, Jesus, our Savior. As a preacher, the sermon work you do and the sermon that you finally present is a part of your praise of The Lord who saved you through Jesus Christ.
The sermon is one of the most important tasks a pastor can do. Why?
·         In many congregations you have the best opportunity to speak to the greatest number of people during the sermon.
·         The sermon is the main Bible study that many of our members will do.
·         The Word of God, on which the sermon is written, will impact people spiritually. (see Isaiah 55:11).
The preacher (truly all Christians are) is an ambassador for God (see 2 Corinthians 5:20; 1 Peter 4:11; )
The sermon must be scriptural.
The sermon must proclaim the pure word.
The sermon must be Christ centered.
The preacher must restrict his preaching to what the Bible says. We are not to get involved with meaningless talk.
The purposes of the Sermon.
To lead sinners to Jesus.
To help those who believe in Jesus to become more mature in Christ and their faith.
To fulfill the preachers twofold purposes just mentioned we:
Proclaim God’s Word in accord with God’s intent and purpose.
Distinguish properly between law and gospel.
Proclaim the whole council of God.
Relate the Word in specific and meaningful ways to the life of God’s people.
Preach clear, coherent, goal-oriented sermons.
God’s intent and purpose.
2Tim 3:16 (the purpose of the word.) List the purposes …
Distinguish properly between law and gospel.
What is wrong with a sermon that is all or mostly law?
What is the weakness with a sermon that is all or mostly Gospel?
We are to proclaim the whole counsel of God from all of Scripture, not just those parts we like the most. See John 8:31; Revelation 22:18-19; Matthew 28:20.
Do not leave anything out.
Use specific law and specific gospel.
Relate the Word to daily life.
Preach clear, coherent, goal-oriented sermons.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 2（第二课）</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Lesson 2（第二课）
Preaching must be scriptural.
No one can preach the entire Bible at one time. We need to consider smaller portions that we call texts. Over time we will proclaim the “whole will of God.”
The word “text” derives from the Latin texere which means “to weave.”
From where do we get our texts?
•   If we are preaching according to the church year we can obtain our texts for a lectionary also called a pericope series. Many use what is called the ILCW which has three parts A, B, and C. Over three years the pastor uses a lot of major, Biblical texts. Two PDFs are included with the notes which cover two years worth of church texts.
•   If we are preaching on a topic, we will choose a text or texts that allow us to speak about God’s word for that topic.
•   For a special occasion we will chose an appropriate text for that occasion.
Why do we preaching using texts?
Our starting point is a Bible text so that we can concentrate on God’s Word. Even when we speak on a topic, we focus on a text and not any preconceived ideas from our own thinking.
When we have a smaller text we can speak about that text rather than our own interests.
You will divide the theme into logical parts, but work to cover the whole text.
The organization, writing and preaching of the sermon will be guided by the text.
Advantages of using a text for preaching:
A text offers a manageable part of the whole Bible.
Using a text encourages us to study it in a logical way and encourages us to focus our listeners attention on a specific word of God.
Over time, a text series provides a way for presenting more of God’s word rather than a random selection.
A variety of texts helps to insure freshness in preaching.
Begin your sermon work and the study of a text with prayer and meditation.
Sermon writing is not a job, it is an action of devotion to God. Work on a sermon is a type of meditation for the pastor. Samuel was not writing a sermon, but his attitude is appropriate, “Speak, for your servant is listening” (1 Samuel 3:10).
Study the Text
A. A thorough study of the text in its original language (Hebrew or Greek) is highly recommended.
B. Through study of the grammar, word order, and word relationships;
(this is best done in the original language)
C. Through Word studies (this can also be done using a good, modern translations);
D. Through study of similar texts throughout the book and the Bible
E. Through us of commentaries or other books – Bible study guides that use the text, and a catechism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrive at an understanding of what God is saying in the text!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may ask of the text several questions. Notice in these questions we do not ask, “What shall I say about this text?” We always ask, “What does this text mean?”
What did this text mean to the writer and his original readers?
What has this text meant to believers through the ages?
What does this text mean to us today?
When we are studying the text in the original language (a, b, &amp;amp; c) it will be useful to write our own translation of the text.
Studying similar texts throughout the Bible (d above) can be done in several ways.
The study Bible we are using may provide some cross references.
The catechism may offer opportunities and suggestions for study.
Word studies will take us to other parts of the Bible in our study.
Commentaries will makes references to other parts of the Bible.
Bible dictionaries may refer to other parts of the Bible.
Dogmatic texts will make references to other parts of the Bible.
The Book of Concord will provide cross references.
Discover what the text has meant to others.
We may find it useful to study books as the following:
Commentaries will makes references to other parts of the Bible.
Bible dictionaries may refer to other parts of the Bible.
Dogmatic texts will make references to other parts of the Bible.
The Book of Concord will provide cross references.
Some pastors will read the sermons of others to gain ideas. Luther had written a number of sermons that we can read if the text is available.
Information is available on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WARNING:  It is always best to do your own studies and your own thinking before even looking at the work of others. Regular use of someone else’s work will make us lazy.
Find Preaching Values for Today.
Through study we will realize that each text speaks to various personal and congregational situations. We hear this when a person says, “That text really spoke to me.” They are saying that as they read or heard that word of God, things in the text struck them as applicable to their faith and life. Those parts that “speak to us” are called “preaching values.”
When we ask “What does this mean to me and my congregation?” we are thinking about the “reaching values” of this text.
As you are studying the text, if any ideas come to mind, be sure to write them down so that you do not lose them.
Keep in mind:
•  Experiences that members may have had.
•  Temptations that apply to the text.
File Your Text Studies - it is good practice to keep study notes for future reference.
Let’s look at Luke 7:36-50&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                                             Personal Bible Study Hermeneutic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to each of us to know our personal hermeneutic, or put another way, through what process do each of us understand the Bible.
Over time I have seen five basic ways of understanding the Bible. This model may be overly simplistic, but does well in explaining the differing approaches to studying the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people view the Bible and understand the Bible from the vantage point of what do our traditions say? What have our counsels said? What do our commentaries say? What do our past leaders and our current leaders say? If while studying the Bible you first consider the thinking of counsels and traditions and the others just stated, this is your personal Biblical hermeneutic. (The Tradition Approach).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people approach the study of the Bible with the questions, “What do I think about the Bible?” In this hermeneutic the personal thoughts and ideas and logic influence their conclusions about the Bible.   (The Logic Approach).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others are very concerned about the unity of Christians throughout the world. They view the Bible through the desire that all be one. This method regularly asks the questions what is and what is not central to the work of the church. (The community church approach).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this second to last hermeneutic the Bible is considered through the miraculous work of the Holy Spirit. The main question is how is the Spirit active today. (The Pentecostal approach).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This last hermeneutic is the one which I recommend. Since we are convinced that the Bible is the Word of God, we are to let the Bible speak for itself. While Christians are scholarly people, while we have Christian experiences, while we want Christians to get along we are not to place our thoughts upon the Bible in a way that controls what the Bible says. We are to honestly study and consider what the Bible says and LISTEN to what the Bible says for it is the Word of God, the way through which God has chosen to speak to his people. We are to be guided by God’s Word, not traditions, not our own minds, not a shallow Biblical understanding that stays away from the hard questions, nor a focus only on the work of the Holy Spirit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weaknesses of hermeneutic methods 1-4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The “tradition approach” shows its weaknesses when a church or person’s traditions are more important than what the Bible says. Those who hold this hermeneutic will say, “I am following the Bible,” yet their traditions are more important than what the Bible says.   Jesus addressed this way of thinking when he said, ﻿6﻿ He replied, “Isaiah was right when he prophesied about you hypocrites; as it is written: “‘These people honor me with their lips, but their hearts are far from me. 7﻿ They worship me in vain; their teachings are but rules taught by men.’ (see Isaiah 29:13) ﻿8﻿ You have let go of the commands of God and are holding on to the traditions of men.” (Mark 7:6-8). Every church has traditions, yet those must be secondary to good Biblical thought.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the most commonly held hermeneutics in the world is the “logic approach.” Christians certainly do think, and consider, and we are scholarly as we study and the Word of God. Christians also realize that not everything the Bible says makes sense to the mind. The Gospel does not make sense to humans – we think that we must do something to be saved. Baptism does not make sense. How can water wash away sin? Yet, Baptism does forgive sins. The Lord’s Supper does not make sense – how can the body and blood of Christ be in the bread and wine? Yet Jesus said this is my body and this is my blood. The words of the Bible need to be what guides our Biblical thinking, not out thinking that guides what we think the Bible says. Even when Scripture does not seem clear to us, we still need to have the mind that God’s word is trustworthy, and speaks to us, not we are to guide what Scripture says.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The “community church hermeneutic” is attractive to Christians who want the church of Jesus to be one. God wants the church to be one and so should we. Yet, the other four hermeneutics are very different in their attitude and in their results. To simply wish that the church would be one is naïve. What happens among those churches and individuals who have this hermeneutic is that they must ignore those harder teachings for the sake of what becomes a shallow unity. This hermeneutic cannot deal with the full depth and breadth of the Scriptures teachings because someone may disagree. Trust in the Lord with all your heart and lean not on your own understanding; (Proverbs 3:5).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The “Pentecostal hermeneutic” focuses on the miraculous work of the Holy Spirit in our lives. The Scriptures do teach that the Holy Spirit is active. Yet, those who focus on this hermeneutic are seeing the miraculous work of the Holy Spirit in everything, but without the centrality of the Bible. Any church or person who takes the Word of God out of understanding God’s Will and Way or even greatly moves away from the Scriptures is not following a Biblical hermeneutic. The regular focus on the miraculous does not reflect the way that God acts in the world, nor what is said in his Word. In Galatians Paul notes that even if an angel from heaven speaks about another Gospel [that includes any so called message of God that is apart from Scripture] they are to be condemned. Neither will the Holy Spirit change or move away from His own word, which is in the Bible. God is not a liar about what he has given in the word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The best Biblical hermeneutic recognizes that the Bible is the Word of God and let’s God’s Word speak to us, not us controlling the Word of God, (The Word speaks for itself hermeneutic).
Give consideration to the above hermeneutic styles mean to you. Everyone who studies the Bible will hold one of these. What do you hold? You need to realize this, for only then might you be able to understand the other major ways and consider for yourself, how to teach the word in sermons or Bible classes. You may even say, I want the best points of each. While I can appreciate that, understand the temptations that Satan will bring to your life. Satan will always look for ways to discourage good understanding of God and his Word. Styles 1-4 provide Satan the bigger doors for spiritual attack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 3（第三课）</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-4/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Lesson 3（第三课）
Analysis of the text is very important. Thorough analysis will prepare the preacher to write better sermons.
A way to think about a text is to consider the major and subordinate points.
Each text will have major points. As you first read through a text consider which are the major points that this text is bringing out, that the Holy Spirit is here stressing.
Also list the minor points that make up each major point.
Put each thought of the text on a separate line and leave space between each line.
John 3:16 (NIV)
a.  “For God
b.  so loved
c.  the world
d.  that he gave
e.  his one and only Son,
f.  that whoever believes in him
g.  shall not perish
h.  but have eternal life.
Decide which are the important points
We could ask such questions as:
a.Which thoughts are the major thoughts of this text?
b.Are all the truths of this text of equal importance?
The Subordinates
Which points are under which main point. This usually follows along as they are written.
John 3:16 (NIV)
a.  “For God
b.  so loved
c.  the world
d.  that he gave
e.  his one and only Son,
f.  that whoever believes in him
g.  shall not perish
h.  but have eternal life.
Consider, next Mark 2:1-12
One division might be as follows.
Mark 2:1-12
Jesus comes to Capernaum. (v1)
So many gathered that there was no room left in the house. (v2)
He preached the word to the people. (v2)
Four men brought a paralytic (v3)
Since they could not get him in to Jesus, because the crowd was too big.
They made a hole in the roof by digging through it. (4)
They lowered their friend down to Jesus.
When Jesus saw their faith, he said “Son, your sins are forgiven.”
Some teachers of the law thought that Jesus was blaspheming.
“Who can forgive sins but God alone?” (v7)
Jesus knew in his spirit
What they were thinking in their hearts
He said to them
Why are you thinking this way?
Which is easier to say to the paralytic
Your sins are forgiven, or
Get up, take your mat and walk?
But that you may know that the Son of Man has authority on earth to forgiven sins …
Take up your mat and go home.
The man rose and went home healed.
This amazed everyone.
They praised God
We have never seen anything like this before.
Consider Psalm 119:137-144
Psalm 119:137-144
Analysis of this text might be as follows:
The LORD is
Righteous (137)
His laws are right (137
His statutes are righteous 138
His statutes are trustworthy.
[Your Servant is]
My zeal for the LORD wears me out v139
My enemies ignore your words
Your promises have been completely tested.
Your servant loves them.
I am lowly and despised but I do not forget your precepts. (141)
[Summary]
Your righteousness is everlasting and your law is true (142)
Trouble comes to me, but your commands are my delight (143)
Your statutes are right.
Give me understanding that I may live.
The Propositional Statement
The theme is the guiding idea for the whole sermon. The propositional statement provides the goal of the sermon. “Careful formulation of the prepositional statement is of crucial importance.” [25]
“As you formulate the prepositional statement in your mind, the focus of your attention is on those truths which in your analysis you have identified as the major coordinates.” [27]
Guidelines for a propositional statement. [p. 27]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it positive, not negative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it practical, suggesting the main point of the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it a statement rather than a question. [some people will disagree here and will use questions. Prefer to use statements, but if a good question comes to mind, that can be done.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formulate it so that it expresses the uniqueness of the text and identifies with the text. [Sometimes hard to do]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incorporate the unique qualities of the text. [ “Incorporate the color of the text into it.” “Color” is being used in a figurative way.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not attempt to make the propositional statement a theme. The theme follows.
Other factors which will influence your propositional statement.
*The primary focus of any propositional statement is “what does this text say to us?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other factors do influence the statement which are very practical such as:
What do the people of our congregation need to hear from this text. While we can always say, “everything,” as we get to know our people, some points of God’s word will stand out. Such as if we know that some o four people are struggling with feeling hopeless and a text speaks about the hope of God for his people, we of course, will be able to focus on this text.
At times, a current event and the text we are studying will speak to each other. That connection is a very practical one to explore in our sermon and the propositional statement.
Brainstorming
Once you have formulated a propositional statement, an excellent way to proceed is to “brainstorm” with the text as the focus. I use this technique for sermon work a lot.
Brainstorming is to write down every idea and thought that comes to mind as you are studying a text. Those ideas will relate to your major and subordinate points.
Brainstorming may include:
·     Other texts of the Bible that come to mind as your are studying. Recently when studying “hopelessness” the text of the valley of dry bones in Ezekiel came to mind. Israel felt hopeless at that time and God had Ezekiel tell them about the valley of dry bones.
·     Answers to the question – how does this text speak to the people to whom I am addressing God’s Word?
·     How is this text practical?
·     What is going on in the world that shows exactly what God is bringing up in this text?
·     What specific law does this text contain?
·     What specific gospel does this text contain?
·     How does this text speak about justification and sanctification?
·     Does this text guide the believer to do anything for life and faith?
During brainstorming we apply the knowledge, talents, and experiences that God has given us to help proclamation of a text. We apply all that God has given us to help our listeners to better understand what the Lord is proclaiming.
Homework: Analyze these three texts by choosing primary and secondary points.
Please e-mail finished homework to me before the next session so I can look through your work before we talk about it. Thank you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 23:1-4
1）The LORD is my shepherd, I shall not be in want.
2）He makes me lie down in green pastures,
he leads me beside quiet waters,
3 he restores my soul.
He guides me in paths of righteousness
for his name’s sake.
4Even though I walk
through the valley of the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil,
for you are with me;
your rod and your staff,
they comfort me.
Luke 8:22-25
22One day Jesus said to his disciples, “Let’s go over to the other side of the lake.” So they got into a boat and set out. 23As they sailed, he fell asleep. A squall came down on the lake, so that the boat was being swamped, and they were in great danger.
24The disciples went and woke him, saying, “Master, Master, we’re going to drown!”
He got up and rebuked the wind and the raging waters; the storm subsided, and all was calm. 25“Where is your faith?” he asked his disciples.
In fear and amazement they asked one another, “Who is this? He commands even the winds and the water, and they obey him.”
Romans 5:1-8 (NIV)
1Therefore, since we have been justified through faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ, 2through whom we have gained access by faith into this grace in which we now stand. And we rejoice in the hope of the glory of God. 3Not only so, but we also rejoice in our sufferings, because we know that suffering produces perseverance; 4perseverance, character; and character, hope. 5And hope does not disappoint us, because God has poured out his love into our hearts by the Holy Spirit, whom he has given us.
6You see, at just the right time, when we were still powerless, Christ died for the ungodly. 7Very rarely will anyone die for a righteous man, though for a good man someone might possibly dare to die. 8But God demonstrates his own love for us in this: While we were still sinners, Christ died for us.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 4（第四课）</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-5/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Lesson 4（第四课）
The structure of the Sermon
alt
Structure is needed to bind the sermon together.
The basic outline is the skeleton of the sermon. Such as:
“God’s Strategy for Israel’s Warfare”
I. He arms them with a promise.
II.He directs them with his Word.
III.He assures them with his love.
Structure helps us to proclaim the Word more clearly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure helps the preacher be clear to himself and his hearers. If we cannot be clear, we will not communicate to our people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure helps you chose what you want to say. In our text studies and thinking about our sermon text we noted many points. All of the points may not be suitable for our sermon. Our structure will allow us to decide which points we need to use and which points are to be set aside this time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure will remind us that we need to speak about each part. We may be tempted to deal with only the part(s) we like best. Structure reminds us that there are other parts to talk about so that we are communicating the whole text to our people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since structure guides where we are going, the preacher’s outline guides him so that he completes the work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good structure will help us memorize the sermon easier.
Structure for the sake of the hearer:
There are times when God’s word is a mysterious. When finished, our sermons are to be clear not mysterious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good structure encourages good listening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure helps maintain interest. If a listener cannot tell where we are going, they will get bored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A structured sermon allows the listener to listen more easily. An unstructured sermon is confusing and hard to listen to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good structure helps the listener remember what the Word is all about.
Preparations to choose a theme:
a.       Because you have studied the text you know what this text is saying.
b.      Because you have studied the text you have listed the preaching values that the text suggests and contains.
c.       Because you have studied the text you can now divide the text into its major parts and have placed the subordinate parts under each major part.
d.      With those things in mind write a propositional statement which summarizes the meaning of the text and presents the application(s) which arise from the text.
Plan 1 for choosing the theme:
a.       With your propositional statement in mind write a theme for the sermon you wish to present to the people of God.
b.      With the theme in mind state the parts which you wish to speak to God’s people.
c.       Look over the whole of your theme and parts and reword to make it as clear as possible.
alt
Plan 2 for choosing a theme:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Write a brief description of the parts of the text.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Examine the content of the parts and write a theme that summarizes the parts.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Re-examine the theme and parts and rewrite as best.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Theme: is a brief and clear statement of the main idea of the sermon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The theme should never be a mere topic or subject.
A theme should present a point to consider.
a. “Riches” is a topic.
b. “The Character of Jesus Christ” is a subject.
c. “The Spirit of Thanksgiving” is a subject.
d. “God’s kingdom grows” is a theme
e. Using a question as a theme is not recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The theme should be textual, have to do with the Bible text you are presenting. It is best if the theme is unique to the text you are working on.
A good theme expresses the unity of the sermon and governs each part. Such as:
“God’s Strategy for Israel’s Warfare”
a.       He arms them with a promise.
b.      He directs them with his Word.
c.       He assures them with his love.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good themes are practical themes. This theme suggests an application.
2 Corinthians 5:18-21
Theme: The Gospel of Jesus Reconciles People to the LORD.
a.       Given by God to us.
b.      Communicated by God through us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Reconciliation is the practical application for this text.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 4:1-5,13-17
a.   The Cross made Grace Possible
b. “Grace” is the practical application of this text.
5. Luke 12:29-32
a.   The Faith that Conquers Fear
b.   The practical aspect is that faith affects our fear in life.
6. A good theme indicates scope as well as direction. Poorer themes promise more than they can do.
a. “Our Sin” would be too broad because “sin” is a huge part of scripture. It would be better to be more specific.
b. This theme is not very good (The Sins against the 5th Commandment), but is better in scope the “Our Sin”
7. A good theme is a short theme. Some say that a theme should only be nine words or less.
A theme that is too short will not be clear.
a. We try to write memorable themes, but try not to be “cute.”
b. “Let the Greatness of Jesus Show You Why Faith and Unbelief are So Decisive” This theme is too long and wordy.
8. A very good theme will be one that sounds good when you speak it.
a. “The Marks of Maturity in Christians” is a good theme. A better wording might be
b. “The Marks of a Mature Christian.”
9. A theme is not place for undignified words. Always speak in a noble way.
a. “A Hullabaloo About Pigs” is not a good thing. The “hullabaloo” is not a bad word, but it is not a sophisticated term either.
b. Never use words that will turn people’s minds from the Lord to sinful thoughts, such as with “The Sex Life of Samson”
10. A good theme is capable of being divided. Such as:
Jesus Nurtures Weak Faith
a. He tests it in a storm.
b. He strengthens it with a miracle. Or
A Revelation in a Storm at Sea.
c. Of the disciples’ weak faith.
d. Of the Lord’s Saving power.
11. A theme should contain only one proposition, never more. A sermon that leaves itself open
to two points will confuse the people. We can never deal with everything in a text. There will be other times to speak God’s Word.
a. “The Effectiveness and Necessity of Prayer”
b. “The Causes and Cure of Gossip.”
c. Neither of the above is a good theme for each of them state the parts of the sermon, rather than the theme.
If possible, reflect the uniqueness of the text in the theme. There are many texts that speak about justification. Each of those texts is the same for they speak about being declared innocent of sin. Each of the texts is unique for the context and the presentation is different. As we develop our theme, try to incorporate the uniqueness of the text into the theme. In some literature this is expressed as “incorporating text color.”
The Parts
The theme inform the listener what you intend to preach about. The major divisions of the theme indicate how you intend to cover the subject. The major divisions are the parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good parts express the related thoughts of the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parts should be brief and clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Compassionate Christ – Concerned
a.       About the fallen.
b.      About the faithful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parts must actually divide the theme.  – 2 Corinthians 3:4-5
a. God Directs Christian Lives
·         Our competence comes from God.
·         This competence makes us capable gospel ministers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parts should allow or imply applications that we can make to our lives.
a.   Joshua 1:1-9 God’s Plan for Israel’s Warfare
·         He strengthens them with His Promise
·         He directs them with His Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parts should relate to each other (be logical). The parts should encourage the listeners to want to listen.
Avoid these
a. Parts that repeat the theme.
b. Parts that are questions.
c. A first part that is positive and then a 2nd that is negative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people do not Understand the Scriptures.
a.       Not because they are not clear (the negative proposition)
b.      But because they let preconceived ideas hinder them (the positive proposition).
c.       Do not have a first part that is the explanation of the text and a second part that is all application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God Saves for a Purpose
a.       The Lord has saved you for service.
b.      Serve the Lord with a single mind.
c.       To have a first part that is declaratory and a second part that is imperative.
Assignment once we have gone over this lesson –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look over the 1-8 of theme development. Which of those have you found to be easier to pursue? Which have you found more challenging?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you noted anything in Chinese preaching that should be brought out in the development of a theme?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love over the 1-6 developing the parts. Which of those have you found to be easier to pursue? Which have you found more challenging?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you noted anything in Chinese preaching that should be brought out in the development of the parts for your sermons?
alt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since preaching in China is over a longer time (one to two hours), how does the longer time frame affect the development of sermon themes and parts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Study Luke 7:36-50 and develop a theme and parts for this text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select a text of your choosing – such as one that you might be preaching on three weeks from now – and develop a theme and parts so that we can discuss it before the time when you will preach it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 5（第五课）</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-6/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Lesson 5（第五课）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Topical Sermon&lt;br&gt;
There are different types of sermons. Preachers of homiletics (the study of preaching) differ in their terminology. The following are distinctions we typically use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topical sermons can require less study of the text. Yet, to do a topical sermon well requires good thought and organization. The preacher must study the topic throughout all of Scripture and present the truths of God’s Word to the people. Often, there is no one text, but a series texts that allow the topic to be explored. Topics include:
o      alt Repentance
o       Law and Gospel
o       Justification
o       Sanctification
o       Marriage
o       Love of God
o       Love of Neighbor
o       Living the Christian life.
o       Stewardship of money, talents.
o       Overcoming Fear
o       The Role of Emotions in our Christian Lives
Agree or disagree with the following statement:   A topical sermon is more practical than an expository sermon.
What are the strengths and weaknesses of topical preaching?
Textual or Expository
The text is central to the sermon
The work we have done so far in our study is focused on the analytic sermon.
·         Analytic sermons: The text is analyzed and a theme and parts are developed so that the preacher can tell his congregation about the text. This is the type of sermon that we have been speaking about most. This is spoken of as a “horizontal sermon” for the theme tells the hearer where the sermon is going and the parts unfold the sermon in a linear way.
·         Synthetic sermons: When a text has been analyzed, but its parts do not follow one after another, in a linear fashion, the parts must then be rearranged to make sense to the listener. A sermon that has had the parts rearranged to make sense is a “synthetic sermon.”
(see 2 Corinthians 5:18-21 and Jeremiah 31:31-34.)
2 Corinthians 5:18-21
The Ministry of Reconciliation
·         Given by God to us.
·         Communicated by God to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeremiah 31:31-34
The Superior Blessings of God’s New Covenant.
·         The knowledge it provides
·         The Pardon it provides
·         The New Life if provides.
Jeremiah 31:31-34
The Superior Blessings of God’s New Covenant.
·         Forgiveness for condemned souls.
·         Enlightenment for darkened minds
·         Direction for renewed hearts.
The Homily
A homily is a short sermon on the text.
It is considered the easiest of the sermon styles.
·         Less study of the text is carried out.
·         Less preparation time is done on the sermon.
“A homily is in a sense a kind of running commentary on a text with application added at appropriate points along the way.”
[pg 62, “Preach the Gospel”]. A homily may seem to be easy to do, but it is considered one of the hardest sermons to present. A homily can easily decay into a talk without a point or an emotional appeal without a Biblical focus.&lt;br&gt;
Never allow this style of reaching to become an excuse for doing insufficient study of the text or preparing the sermon.
Other Types of sermons – these may be prepared as either topical, analytical, synthetic or as a homily.
Festival or special occasion Sermons
·         New Year
·         Christmas
·         Easter
·         Pentecost
·         Ascension
·         Funeral
·         Marriage
·         Baptism
Doctrinal Sermons
·         The 10 Commandments
·         Justification / Sanctification
·         Baptism
·         Lord’s Supper
·         God is Triune
·         Jesus is both true God and true Man.
·         The end Times
Narrative sermons (a sermon in which the pastor speaks as if they are the speaker, such as when the pastor presents the message as if he/she is Peter.
·         Noah telling the story of the flood
·         Abraham telling the account of the “sacrifice” of his son Isaac.
·         Joshua telling the account of the walls of Jericho.
·         Peter telling the account of the Transfiguration.
·         Important Notes
·         Stay in Character
·         Don’t over play the role.
·         Be careful which characters you use.
·         Express the emotions of the character.
·         Beware of speculation about what he or she thought and felt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beware, this type of sermon can begin to sound humorous, rather than on God’s Word.
·         A sermon based upon Christian Music.
·         Interactive sermons (This type of sermon is suitable for smaller congregations because it is a mixture of sermon and Bible Study. Beware, some members would feel very uncomfortable speaking in church, during the service.)&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 6（第六课）</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Lesson 6（第六课）
alt
Remember, every way that we expand the sermon comes from the text. Even other Biblical or extra-biblical material is to be included only because of something rising from the text.
Concern for Unity of the Sermon
The theme and parts summarize and focus the direction of the sermon.
The sermon is not
•  An essay;
•  A devotional meditation; or
•  A commentary on the verses.
“Rather it is an oral communication which develops a single thought which has been stated in the theme.” [65]
A theme or proposition is a summary statement of the text, of the text’s central thought. Later the preacher may bring out a different point in the text, but each time he will have a single thought.
Concern for Relevance
After you have studied the text and written down various preaching points, your list (and thoughts) will contain items that you will want to use in the sermon and items that do not fit your theme. We cannot say everything about a text in each sermon. Be willing to exclude things that do not help you develop your theme.
Purpose of Expansion
The sermon writing we do is not just to fill up time. Everything we write for the sermon is to communicate the truth of the Gospel. We do not want to say too much and so clutter the word, nor do we want to say too little so that we do not explain the Word.
Remember, the sermon parts must be logical divisions of the theme and text.
Importance of Good Mechanics
We are not writing a sermon to look good. We are writing to communicate the truth. “Remember, the sermon is intended to crush the sinner and show him the Savior, to edify the saints and motivate the sluggish, to comfort the sorrowing and persuade the reluctant.” [67]
Dialog with the Text
All of our study of a text and our “brain storming” on a text, and finding preaching points are a “dialog with the text.” We are letting God’s word speak to us. Generally we are asking such questions in our “dialogue” as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does this text mean?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What truths about God and Jesus are being taught?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does this text apply to me and my people today?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What truths for life are being taught?
As we think about what we are going to write, we continue the dialog with questions like this, “How can I communicate these things to God’s people.”
“Through out the process he is more than a professional looking for material with which to carry out a professional assignment successfully. He is first of all God’s little child, a trusting learner. He is killed by the law, made alive by the gospel, instructed by the Word. Thus, his sermon becomes a testimony to the great things God has done for him. Meanwhile, he is confident that the Gospel not only offers the gifts of God but also works the faith to accept them.” [69]
Proper Use of Suitable Material
One task of preaching is to help our listeners “appropriate” what God is saying. “Appropriate” is a term to mean understand, gain knowledge about, and take that knowledge to heart. This is also called “appropriation.”
Then, we also encourage “application” of the text, the use of the text today.
In our sermon we are to use only those materials that help us communicate the text so that our listeners can appropriate what God is saying and apply what God is saying in this text. This takes into account the proper use of literal and figurative language and explanations of parables.
Material from Other Biblical Sources
Your study may have led you to other parts of the Bible that apply to this text and help with appropriation and application.
Use only what helps explain and communicate.
Materials from Extra-Biblical Sources
During study you may find materials from other books, commentaries, Bible dictionaries, and others, that help with the sermon. If you have concluded that the material is Biblically accurate and trustworthy, then you may consider using it in the sermon. Again, use only what helps to communicate the text and proclaim the Word of God for appropriation and application.
Expanding the Outline More Fully
With all the points you have found in study, expand your parts.
Under each part list those points that apply to that part.
Organize all the points under the part in a way that you think will communicate the truth of the text in a logical fashion that your people will understand.
At times you will move something to another part.
At times you will discard a thought as not helping the development of the text.
At times something new will come to mind, an illustration, and application, something in the Word of God you want to check more.
When you are done this is your expanded outline.
Some pastors will write very long expanded outlines. The more inexperienced we are in writing sermons the more useful it is to more fully expand the outline.
Some pastors write very short expanded outline. [I usually have four or five points under each part of my basic theme and parts.]
When you are finished your expanded outline, start writing.
Writing your sermon out completely is a good habit. Complete writing will allow you to memorize your sermon more easily and will allow you to speak more effectively. I strongly recommend that the less experienced preacher write out his sermon fully. While it is true that we do not speak the same way that we write, writing does allow us to be more focused.
As we become more experienced we may not write our sermon out fully. Yet, also be aware that you may start saying things in similar fashions and get into bad preaching habits without writing. Each of us will find that we have certain phrases that we use regularly.  Writing the sermon out fully will allow us to be aware of what we are saying. One pastor regularly used the phrase, “picture this on the screen of your mind.” He would say that about five times a sermon. His regular use of that phrase actually became quite annoying. Be aware, we all have pet phrases that we use.
Another problem that can arise if we do not write out our sermon is that we can ramble as we try to think of a good way to make a point. If we had written out our point, we would have had a chance to think through how we want to express that truth of God’s Word.
Sometimes because of the way our schedule develops we do not have time to write the sermon out completely and so must use an outline. Under those circumstances we apply what God has given us and we pray that the Lord will guide our presentation of his word, even though we may wish that we had more time to prepare.
As you write, develop each point so that it communicates to your people and reflects the truth of God’s Word. You may directly quote a portion of Scripture or a commentary. You may reference something that has happened in our lives. Communicate with your people about the text. As Paul wrote in 2 Timothy (3:16) God’s word is good for teaching, rebuking, correcting, and training in righteousness. Our sermons do all four of those things.
While writing, beware of communicating in abstract ways that our listeners may not understand.   The more we know our people and the more they know us, the better we can communicate.   Keep this in mind especially with unbelievers, for they may not understand the Biblical references that we make. To a seeker many things about the Bible and the Christian faith seem abstract. Jesus regularly taught using stories and parables because people could more easily understand those than they could the abstractions. Our writing and talking should be clear and understandable not confusing and unclear.
Remember to connect the parts of your sermon so that your listeners know where you are going.
Remember, to emphasize the law and gospel, sin and grace in all of our preaching.
Planning Applications
A good sermon will include application of the text.
At times application may come during each part of the sermon and throughout the sermon. At times application may be a few paragraphs at the end of the entire sermon before the conclusion. The preacher needs to decide how best to present the importance of this text for his people for today.
The best applications come right from the text. An application that does not flow from the text study will sound out of place and not encourage our listeners to action. s
To decide on which application to use we might ask such questions as:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What actions does this text encourage my listeners to do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is this text pointing out about modern life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does Jesus’ work in this text affect life today?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the members of our congregation taking out of the doors of church that they can use in their daily life?
Sometimes a text may express a condemnation of a certain action. Such as, “You shall not murder.” Most or all of our members are not guilty of murder, so we do not want to speak as if they are. Yet, the 5th commandment also applies to hate and anger, sins our people are guilty of. When expressing a Biblical condemnation be aware how this is expressed so that we show the sins of our people accurately.
Be careful about expressing a condemnation that affects people who are not at church.  We should not focus on those people in the world who are big sinners. Our focus should be to help our people to realize their sin, to repent, and to turn to Jesus and Christian life. Occasionally a member may get the idea that we in the church are better than those who are not at church. In reality we are just as sinful as everyone else, just in more subtle ways. Yet, do not be shy about discouraging a sin that is in the world, because our people will be tempted to commit the same sins.
Remember, preaching is to affect the “old man” and the “new man.” Each believer is a sinner who has been redeemed by Christ. The “old man” in every Christian needs to hear that sin is condemned. Our “new man” needs to hear the good news of Jesus and what God wants us to do.
In Applications:
Be careful that you do not make something a command of God that is not. The widow was commended for giving all she had (Mark 12:41-44) but we cannot apply that text to mean that we are to give all we have to the work of the kingdom.
When an application is negative do not apply it to your congregation as if they are unbelievers. If your application is for unbelievers, say so. Better is that you apply applications to Christians who are believers with sinful natures.
Many applications are based upon the law. Remember to apply gospel motivation and beware of making applications sound legalistic. Be sensitive to the possibility that Satan might encourage Christians to act like Pharisees. Be aware of this temptation an communicate so that we act with the Gospel in mind.
Do not give either of these impressions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not imply that we do good works to be saved. Good works are not necessary for salvation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not give the impression that good works are optional. Good works are necessary in life.
Motivation
“Since all applications are intended to encourage the new man, it must be presented in an evangelical manner. The Christian needs help against his flesh and encouragement in the difficult battle with temptation.” As Paul wrote to the Ephesians, chapter 6, ﻿12﻿ For our struggle is not against flesh and blood, but against the rulers, against the authorities, against the powers of this dark world and against the spiritual forces of evil in the heavenly realms. ﻿13﻿ Therefore put on the full armor of God, so that when the day of evil comes, you may be able to stand your ground, and after you have done everything, to stand.”
“Only the gospel can renew and equip and motivate him.” [76]
Be cautious in the use of terms like “must” and “should” and “ought to.”   When speaking about Christian actions using such phrases as “we want to…” is a much more gospel emphasis appealing to the new man.  “We want to persuade but we will not confuse that with applying pressure [of the law].” [76]
To persuade the Christian to action cannot be best accomplished with the law. We encourage people to act because they are believers – loved by God and who love God.
“We are preaching sanctification properly when we help our hearers grieve over their sinful inclinations and their failures because they have displeased the Savior whom they love, and when we help them take delight in doing good because it pleases their Savior. We can encourage them with the promise that it is God who works in them both to will and to do of his good pleasure.” [77]
Final Checking of the Outline
Now that it is written review what you have before you. [In my preaching, I have found this to be a very important part of my sermon preparation.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do all the paragraphs follow in a way that the people will understand? You may discover that you need to move or even exclude a paragraph or two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have you used illustrations and words that encourage understanding?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does all of your writing fit under the theme and under the correct parts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you notice something that needs more explanation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you notice a part that is explained too much?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have you noticed a part of the sermon that does not help with understanding? Then that paragraph or section needs to be excluded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the sermon as you have developed it fit the time frame that it needs to for the service?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 7（第七课）</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-8/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Lesson 7（第七课）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For what two reasons do we include an introduction to a sermon?
a. To gain the attention of the hearer.
b.To make the connection of the theme to the text. To make the connection of life to the text in a way that encourages the hearers interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider the pros and cons of the following statement: An introduction is intended to enlist the attention and the good will of the hearer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This chapter lists seven faults to avoid in introductions. In general, which of these do you think is the most common?
(1)     Beginning far afield, that is with an introduction that does not help communicate the text.
(2) “Digressing.” This is similar to “beginning far afield.” This type of introduction may begin with a totally unrelated area.
(3) Anticipating the sermon proper. Information about the text as well as explanation of the text belongs in the sermon, not the introduction.
(4) Treating a separate subject. This introduction talks about another topic in the text that is not in the sermon.
(5) Developing a stereotyped form. Be aware of the sermons that you do and be aware of the way that you present texts. If something you say or do in a sermon introduction is the same almost all the time, that makes a bad introduction.
(6) Engaging in polemics. The introduction should not talk about an argument that is going on. Something controversial may need to be dealt with in the sermon, but it is best not to do so in the introduction.
(7) Sharing one’s study thoughts. People are not interested in everything you learned about the text or the process you used to write the sermon. Those types of comments should not be used anywhere in the sermon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the four sources of introductory material for sermons?
Life situations and experiences are some of the best for introductions. Use situations in the life of the synod, congregation, religious world, in the community, and in the nation. The situation must actually apply to the text.
The church year will offer material for the introduction.
If the connection between the theme and the text is not obvious, the introduction can be used to show the connection.   The introduction may also underscore the importance of the theme for the faith and life of the congregation.
The text may offer a fourth source, but be careful about covering things that should be in the sermon. An introduction from the text may speak about the history of the text, a person in the text or a situation.
An interesting word or phrase in the text may make a good introduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What, above all else, determines the need for a conclusion?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A conclusion is to recapitulate the sermon. Recapitulation means to weave things from the sermon together to complete the sermon, for clarity.
A conclusion “helps to fix the chief thoughts of the sermon in the hearer’s mind.”
6. List the essential qualities of a good conclusion in the order of importance you attach to them. Briefly explain your reasons for ranking them in the order you did.
(1) Make the conclusion fit. It cannot be contrived. A good conclusion “brings it all together, rounds it out and properly completes it.
(2) Make it brief.
(3) Give it appeal. Appeals help to persuade. It touches the emotion. The conclusion is an apt place for a forceful appeal.
(4) Make it direct. Speak to God’s people, not about them.
7.    What should the conclusion accomplish for the hearer?&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 8（第八课）</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-9/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Lesson 8（第八课）
To gain and hold the attention of the hearer:alt
•  Use precise language – use words that allow you to say what you mean so that the listener understands. In every language there are words that are confusing. Stay away from words that confuse your listener.
• Use concise language – do not use too many words.
• Use interesting language – People want to listen to what is interesting. If our sermons are written in a boring way, their minds will wander.
• Use fluent language – know what you want to say.
• Very important – put your energy and enthusiasm into your presentation. If you generally are a very calm person, fine. Yet, with your “calmness” be sure that your enthusiasm for the Gospel and Word come out in your speaking.
Our language cannot add to the power of the Word, for it is God’s word. Our language can bore and confuse the listener so that the “full” power of the Word does not take place.
Our primary goal is the proclamation of the Word and moving people to focus on Jesus, NOT how well we can present a sermon. Goal 1, present God’s Word truthfully and accurately. God 2, present the sermon as well as possible.
As we preach more we will develop a “personal style of preaching.” Never speak in a way that is not normal for you, because your listeners will know and may “tune you out.” Speak in a normal enthusiastic way. Become aware of problems with your personal style, and for the sake of the Gospel, and the people of God, adjust your style. Never hold stubbornly to a preaching style that gets in the way of the message. (The pulpit voice and other issues – actions, voice tone, gestures, which can cause issues even while being very Biblical)
Oral and Written styles will differ.
It is excellent practice to write out the sermon. Writing encourages us to be precise, concise, interesting and fluent. Also realize that we do not talk in the same fashion as we write. After you have written the sermon, you still need to speak it in a normal way. It is likely that your speaking and written style will differ.
Oral style employs:
• More repetition for emphasis.
• A more obvious outline.
• Simpler vocabulary.
• Shorter and simpler sentences.
• It uses restatement of thought rather then relying on a single word or sentence to carry the thought.
• It relies on strong nouns and verbs rather than clever language.
Trying to talk in the same way that you write will make your sermon hard to follow for the listener.
We Address Intellect, Emotions and Will
In the sermon we address the whole person. Each has an intellect, emotions, and their own will. If we talk to only one “part” of a person, we are not addressing the whole person as well as we can.
Speak to the intellect (what the listener does or does not know in a thinking, logical fashion).
Address the emotions. A sermon is not just a scholarly pursuit, but affects lives and souls.
God’s word is meant to affect action, so we encourage the person’s Will to act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Need for Clarity
“We must take care, not that it shall be possible for the hearer to understand, but that it shall be utterly impossible for him not to understand.” (Quintilian)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safeguard Logical Order
Speak to communicate well in a way that our listeners can understand.alt
Stay away from
• Digressions – talking about a different but related subject than the one you are supposed to speak about.
• Diversions – getting away from the main point into areas that do not even relate to the text.
• Nonsequiturs – words and phrases that do not fit in the discussion of the topic.
• Abrupt transitions – changing to a new area without doing helping your listeners to realize the change.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 9（第九课）</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-10/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Lesson 9（第九课）
alt
The way that the preacher speaks the sermon, his delivery, makes a big difference regarding whether people listen or not. Become aware of your style of speaking the sermon. Videotaping yourself can be interesting. Try to see yourself through the eyes of the congregation. Change your delivery for the sake of the Word if you must.
Free Delivery
“Pulpit communication must always be heart to heart communication.” [112]
“Free delivery means that the preacher is thinking the thoughts he is expressing at the moment he is expressing them. … He is sharing ideas in a manner that suggests spontaneity not mechanically mouthing words” he has previously written. [112]
Do not read the sermon. Most preachers read their sermon when they have not taken time to learn it properly.
Eye contact with your listeners is important. Repeatedly looking at your notes or manuscript breaks eye contact. Do not look constantly at one area of the church, such as at a corner.
“Free delivery requires careful memorization of the sermon.” It is good to memorize the sermons line of thought, not word for word.
One method of memorization:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As you are reading through your written sermon, underline chief points. Fix these chief points in your mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not memorize one paragraph and then another. Memorize an entire part at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For some people practicing the sermon out loud is very helpful for memorization. Some pastors will even go to the church and stand in the pulpit while they memorize the sermon.
Pastor Baumann’s memorization method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After I have written the sermon, I outline what I have. This allows me to see if what I have written flows. I work on memorizing that outline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I remove most of the words from the outline, so that I have only a small outline of the key points. I work on my memory now relying upon the key points it I forget the line of thought.
As you memorize you find that a section is hard to memorize, think about why it is hard to memorize. You may want to rewrite that section to make it easier to memorize.
A KEY thing to remember, in your preaching you want to talk to the people as if you are having a friendly conversation. Each of us can do better at that as we practice.
What to take into the pulpit with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not take the whole manuscript.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use only an outline. The shorter the outline, the better. I print out the Biblical verses that I will refer to when I’m preaching.
Regardless of what you take with you into the pulpit, do not become tied to what you have written. Memorize and speak to the people.
Getting a good nights sleep is important in sermon presentations.
The Role of the Voice
When preaching speak with the same voice you do when you are talking with others. Do not try to make your voice different from what it normally is. Some pastors have developed a pulpit voice – they try to sound like some professional speaker or another pastor they know, when that is not their voice.
Speak calmly. Some speakers voice gets higher in pitch when they speak publicly or get excited. A high pitched voice can sound as if someone is complaining. A high pitched voice can be hard to listen to. Some speakers [myself included] can talk to fast when they get excited. Be conscious of your speed of talking and slow down.
Evaluate your way of speaking and honestly ask, does my normal way of speaking help the message of God come to the people? Practice so that it does.
Yet, do not be overly concerned about your voice. If you are speaking as you normally do, you will be fine.
If you get nervous about your preaching, you are normal. All of us do get nervous.
Practical Considerations
Speak clearly and understandably. This is enunciation.
Speak with proper volume. Never speak so softly that people cannot hear you. Never speak so loudly that you sound as if you are shouting or angry. Change your volume of speaking according to the words.
Speak naturally.
Typically we will not use slang terms for preaching. Do not mispronounce words.
Good speaking will be fast at some times, and slow at other times. The speed at which we speak is the tempo. Do not always speak fast or slow. Vary the tempo according to what you are saying.
Good speaking will emphasize important words, phrases and sentences. Most of the time, our speaking will have an average emphasis.
Pausing before continuing speaking can be a good way to emphasize what you have just said or what you are about to say.
The Role of the Body
The preacher is not to stand like a statue and be unmoving. In normal conversation we move our hands and our bodies. That normal movement is what we want to do while preaching.
Our faces can express what we are saying. If we are sad, then our face will show it. If we are happy, then our face will show that. Be aware of what your face is showing as you preach.
Remember that preaching is the presentation of God’s Word. Do not use inappropriate gestures while in the pulpit. We are not trying to look cute or be humorous. We are preaching the word of God.
Being a bit dramatic as we preach is appropriate. If done too often, dramatic body movement may become distracting from the message.
Be yourself!!!
Pulpit Procedures - Adjust the following for cultural norms.
Enter the pulpit early enough so that you can prepare to speak before the end of the hymn. (Bible open. Microphone on. Pre-sermon prayer.)alt
Congregation sitting or standing.
Greet the congregation. “Grace and Peace to you from God the Father and our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ.” Or some other greeting.
Read the text or the appropriate section of the text.   Seat the congregation if they have stood.
Present the sermon.
At the end, many congregations rise. May pastors will say “May the peace of God which passes all understanding keep your hearts and minds in Christ Jesus.” Others say something else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 10（第十课）</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-11/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Lesson 10（第十课）
The advantage of using texts as the basis for our sermon work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A text offers a manageable part of the whole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A text injects discipline into the homiletical process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A systematic series of texts provides material for presenting more of God’s instruction and encouragement than random selection according to the preacher’s personal preferences can afford.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A variety of texts helps to insure freshness in preaching.
We are not required to follow a particular order of texts.
The preacher “must exercise his freedom in a way that will help him carry out his responsibility to feed the flock of God.” [133]
We may&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow an order that has been developed. We commonly use the ILCW series, a three year series. Another popular series is the Historical series, a one year series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow an order of our own choosing that focuses on the specific needs of our congregation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select a text each week as we want to.
Advantages of pericopic preaching:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The selections are of a manageable size. They generally contain a complete thought.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You do not need to search for a text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The series follow the church year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The series uses Old Testament and New Testament readings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The series contains opportunities to preach on most of the Christian teachings of Scripture and the history of the Savior.
Disadvantages of pericopic preaching:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The texts may not cover the immediate needs of the congregation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People do not become acquainted with one book all the way through.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the preacher uses all epistles or all gospels for one year, preaching may become tedious. We want to use OT, NT and epistles in our preaching.
Advantages of preaching through an entire book:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The congregation becomes knowledgeable about that book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Historical context and context can be discussed more than in a pericopic text.
Disadvantages to preaching through an entire book:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can becomes difficult to limit texts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specific doctrines of the Bible may be missed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The church year is not being developed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The needs of the congregation may not be met.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A guest will not have the benefit of what has been said on other Sundays.
A topical sermon is one in which the Pastor focuses on a text that allows him to focus on a topic. A topic would be such things as Justification, sanctification, good works, stewardship, how we use our money, the love of parents, etc. For some topics the pastor will focus Scripture on a modern concern, such as war and peace, abortion, being involved in Hmong traditions that may not be Christian, etc.
Advantages to topical preaching:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pastor is focusing on a need of the congregation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timely sermons encourage people to listen, for it is easy for pericopic and going through an entire book to be developed historically.
Disadvantages to topical preaching:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pastor may be tempted not to do his Biblical, study work in preparation for the sermon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The preacher may be tempted not to get too deep into the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The preacher may use the text just to talk about something that is bothering him. We call that a “pretext.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rather than covering the church year or the full teachings of the Scripture, the pastor may cover only what interests him.
Random text selection:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advantage – hopefully the pastor will chose texts that help his people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disadvantage – having no plan each week is a burden on time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disadvantage – it becomes a great temptation to chose texts you like. Soon sermons may begin to sound alike and not be “fresh.”
General guidelines for the Choice of texts:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chose a text that is a complete thought. You do not need to include the prophet’s or apostle’s every inspired thought, but the text length needs to be enough to present a good thought. When we have selected a text we may end up using thoughts from the context to make the text clear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each text should contain sin and grace, law and gospel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not shy away from well-known texts. Our congregation likes to hear those texts.
It is wise to plan your Advent and Lenten series well in advance. Series that others have used are available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 11（第十一课）</title>
      <link>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh-cn/courses/404/preaching-baumann-12/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Lesson 11（第十一课）
The inaugural sermon (your first sermon)
This sermons allows you to make a positive impression.
Some topics that can be covered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being your pastor is a privilege.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will preach you God’s word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will not like one person more than another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hold to the doctrines of the church.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God’s people will be blessed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will cooperate to get the work of the Lord done.
Let the overall tone of the sermon be humble and evangelical.
The Farewell Sermon
End on a positive note.
Review the positive aspects of your ministry.
Do not try to make the congregation feel badly.
If there have been problems, express a forgiving spirit.
The Wedding Sermon
Express the sacredness of marriage and other Biblical teachings about marriage.
Talk about a God centered home.
Remind the Christians about the troubles that come. Encourage trust in Jesus.
Be brief.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Funeral Sermon
This sermon can contain God’s comfort about death and eternal life.
Keep the sermon positive. Do not ignore sin, but do not dwell upon it.
Since the members of the congregation are sad, they will have a hard time concentrating. Use as many illustrations as possible.
Focus on the Lord, not upon the person.
Special cases for funerals:
• The death of an unborn child;
• The death of a young child.
• Suicides create big problems.
Confirmation Sermon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remind the students of how much they still have to learn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage faithfulness to the Lord and his Word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warn against temptations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage responsible participation in the life of the body, the church – church attendance, church tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remind the entire congregation of their confirmation vows and encourage them to keep the young people in their prayers, and encourage them.
Communion Sermons
Stress the Biblical truth and benefits of the Lord’s Supper.
Christian Education sermons
We can stress:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each Christian has a responsibility to give their children a Christian education.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The church will help with Christian education. No do it for parents, but help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christian education has advantages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone, young and old, needs Christian education.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christian faith is for action in life, not just a thing we leave at church.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christian education is good for life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep Christian education in your prayers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need willing teachers.
Children’s Sermons
The Ordination – Installation Sermon
Anniversary Sermons
Other Occasions:
• Mission festivals
• Dedications of buildings or church things;
• Synod occasions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
