<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grace Bible Institute – LUTHER’S SMALL CATECHISM</title>
    <link>/en/courses/207/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LUTHER’S SMALL CATECHISM on Grace Bible Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:48:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/en/courses/207/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 1 Introduction to the Catechism and the Ten Commandments Questions 1-18</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 1-18 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. The Christian religion is primarily a system of belief that teaches people what they must do to achieve their salvation and receive eternal life as their reward from God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. We learn about Christianity from the Bible, which is the collection of 66 sacred books that God directed his chosen human writers to record His words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. The Bible has two major parts: the first is the 39 books of the Old Testament originally written in the Hebrew and Aramaic languages; the second is the 27 books of the New Testament originally written in the Greek language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. When we say that the Bible is “inspired” we mean that God moved the human writers to record every thought and word that He wanted people to know about His will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. When we describe the Bible as “inerrant” we mean that the Bible is incorrect and  not trustworthy in a number of its teachings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. When we describe the Bible as “sufficient” we mean that in the Bible God tells us everything we could possibly want to know about Him and His will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7. In order to properly understand the Bible, we must use our minds to grasp what it says and we depend on God the Holy Spirit to accept its teachings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. It is alright for people to reject a certain teaching of the Bible if that teaching does not seem reasonable or make sense to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. The two main teachings God gives us in the Bible are the Law and the Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10. One of the major differences between the Law and the Gospel if that in the Law God gives us commands to obey and in the Gospel God gives us gifts to receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. The Small Catechism is a book of religious instruction written by Doctor Martin Luther and based entirely on the Bible’s teachings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. In the Small Catechism, ten major parts of the Bible’s teachings are summarized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. God has given us His moral Law in two ways.  He has  written it in people’s hearts and He has also written it in the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. In the 1st of the 10 Commandments, God teaches us to love Him with our whole being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. In the 4th through the 10th Commandments, God teaches us to love ourselves and to not be overly concerned about others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify two benefits of having a clear, orderly, written summary of the Bible’s teachings such as we find in the Small Catechism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your opinion, why it is important that God reveals Himself and His will to people through the medium of the Bible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What things do God’s commands that the people He created live lives of love toward Him and toward other people tell us about the kind of God that He is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 2 Commandments 1-3 Questions 19-44</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 19-44 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. A person’s god is whoever or whatever that person values and serves most in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. Of all the possible gods that people can and do follow, there is only one true God who deserves to be believed and followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 3. The triune nature of the true God, the reality that God is three unique persons, but only one God, is very easy for a person to fully understand with human reason and logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. In the First Commandment, God commands us to put Him first in our hearts and lives and to allow no rivals to Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. If we would just concentrate hard enough, it would be possible for us to consistently give God the complete respect, love and trust of our hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. God’s name is a most wonderful thing.   God’s name is all that God has revealed to us about Himself.  It includes His titles, His qualities, His abilities and His authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7. No one, not even God Himself, has the right to curse someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. It is always a sin to swear by God’s name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. Practicing witchcraft, relying on signs of the zodiac for guidance, and consulting fortune tellers for knowledge about one’s future are harmless and helpful activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10. Pretending to be a Christian is just as sinful as teaching false things in the name of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. Since Jesus Christ has kept all the Old Testament ceremonial laws that God gave the Jewish people to observe, we in the New Testament are obligated to worship God, but we are not required to have our worship services on the Sabbath (Saturday).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. A person who regularly attends Christian worship services is in no danger of despising God’s Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. In our worship of God, we both receive the blessings of God from His Word and we also give Him our adoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. In the Law, God both shows us our sin and He also instructs us how to live to His honor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. In the Gospel, God both shows us our Savior from sin and He also gives us the desire and strength to keep His commandments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give three reasons why God is entitled to the greatest love and loyalty of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your opinion, why is God’s name the most precious gift that we can be given?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List three benefits of participating regularly in Christian worship services with other believers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 3 Commandments 4-8 Questions 45-62</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 45-62 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. By establishing positions of authority in institutions such as the family, the government and the church, God intends that people in those positions will use their authority to serve and bring blessings to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. When we respect and obey those who are in authority over us because we are Christians, we are showing love to them and also to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. If someone in authority over us tells us to do something that is morally wrong, we should do it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. God’s gift of earthly life is not such a valuable thing when we consider how short life is and how difficult and troubled it can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. Every taking of a human life is a sin against God’s command to not murder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. As long as we leave people alone and do not bother them, we will fulfill God’s expectations of us in the Fifth Commandment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7. People should have sexual relations only with people that they truly care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. God gave marriage to people for their happiness.  If a married couple ceases to be happy with each other, they should get divorced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. Homosexuality is a sinful misuse of a person’s sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10. God entrusts us with the use of material possessions, but He always remains the owner of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. A person who steals from others not only harms them, but also insults God by implying that God is failing to give him what he thinks he deserves to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. A Christian should be just as concerned about the condition of another person’s possessions as he is about his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. In the 8th Commandment, God takes special measures to protect people’s reputations because a reputation is a very valuable thing that can very easily be damaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. It is proper to say damaging things about another person as long as we know that those things are true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. Failing to speak up in defense of someone who is being unfairly attacked is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List one positive thing we should do to keep each of the Commandments in this lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4th Commandment:________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5th Commandment: ________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6th Commandment: _______________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7th Commandment: ________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8th Commandment: ________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List one negative thing we should avoid doing to keep each of the Commandments in this lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4th Commandment:________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5th Commandment: ________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6th Commandment: _______________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7th Commandment: ________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8th Commandment: ________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do our efforts to obey God’s commandment help other people know more about the wonderful God that we believe and live for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 4 Commandments 9 – 10, the Law and Sin Questions 63-85</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/4/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 63-85 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. Coveting is the sinful desire for things that we should not want, especially when it would harm another person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. Coveting is not such a harmful sin because it only affects the thoughts of our hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. When God forbids coveting, He is also commanding us to be content with what we have and to have hearts filled with only holy desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. When God describes Himself as a “jealous God”, He is telling us that He has the absolute right to our highest love and loyalty and that He is not willing to share that love and loyalty with anyone or anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. God makes threats to punish sin with both earthly and eternal punishments, but He will only carry out those threats with those who live extremely wicked lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. The primary purpose of God’s threats to punish sinners is to lead people to sincerely repent of their sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7. When God says that He will bless those who revere Him to a thousand generations and curse those who sins against Him to the third and fourth generation, He shows us that He is far more interested in blessing us than  He is in having to punish us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. God demands that we try to keep His Law the best that we can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. No one can be saved by their efforts to keep God’s commandments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10. When God’s Law serves as a curb, it controls the external behavior of sinners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. When God’s Law serves as a mirror, it shows us our sin and our need for a Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. When God’s Law serves as a guide, it points out the ways that we can show our love for God and for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. Original sin is the wicked, rebellious attitude of the heart that we have inherited from our parents since the time that Adam and Eve fell into sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. Actual sins are the evil thoughts, words and deeds that we commit to express our rebellion against God and His commandments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. God’s loving solution to our sin is the Gospel that shows us that we must live the ways Jesus lived so that we can save ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people have offered the opinion that the reason God gave us two commandments that deal with the sin of coveting is that coveting is a sin of the heart and that these invisible sins of the hearts are hard for us to recognize and take seriously.  What do you think of that observation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would you say to help someone who says that while he is not a perfect person, he is also not deserving of going to hell for his sins?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggest something you can do to stay mindful of the Ten Commandments and allow God to carry out His work of curbing your outward sinful behavior, showing you your sins and need for a Savior, and giving you guidance for your Christian living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 5 Creeds and the First Article Questions 86-113</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/5/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 86-113 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. A creed is a statement of what a person or group of people believe about something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. The names of the three main Christian creeds are the Apostles, the Roman, and the Athanasian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. The Apostles Creed got its name because it was written by the 12 Apostles of Jesus shortly before the day of Pentecost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. In the Holy Trinity, the persons of the Father, the Son and the Holy Spirit are all God, but these three persons are not each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. As our Maker, God has a special connection and relationship with human beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. Everything that exists apart from God came into being over a period of 6 billion years through a series of impersonal, random forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7. The holy angels are numerous, powerful, morally perfect, spiritual beings, who willingly and joyfully serve God and people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. The devils are angels who rebelled against God, fell from their perfect state, and are now thoroughly evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. God originally created people in His image.  This means that people were made like God in that they were morally perfect and had an intimate, saving knowledge of God&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10. At the very moment people are spiritually converted and come to faith in Jesus Christ as their Savior, God fully restores His image to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. God uses His almighty Word to preserve His wonderful creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. It is people, not God, who are morally responsible for the sin and evil that have entered and even now exist in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. God does allow sin to occur and bad things to happen to people, but He does not morally approve of sin and evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. God generously provides for our earthly needs because we are deserving of His care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. Because it is God who ultimately preserves and protects us, we have a solemn duty to thank Him, to serve Him, to obey Him and to take good care of His creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you explain the Triune nature of God to someone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List five of God’s attributes/qualities and briefly explain how each one of them has an effect on your life.
a. _______________________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. _________________________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. _______________________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. _______________________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e. _______________________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are three differences between believing that you are a specially created masterpiece of God or that you are the chance, accidental result of impersonal evolutionary forces?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 6 The Second Article - Jesus’ Person, Word and Humiliation Questions 114-132</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/6/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 114-132 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. Jesus is the personal name of our Savior and means “deliverer” or “rescuer”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. Christ (Greek) or Messiah (Hebrew) is a title of a position given to Jesus by God the Father and means “Supreme Commander”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. To believe in Jesus means to intellectually accept that Jesus is a real person who actually lived and died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. In the person of Jesus, God has joined a human nature to the eternal divine nature of the Son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. In His person, Jesus is 50% God and 50% human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. Our Savior had to be a true human being so that He could take our obligation to obey God’s commands perfectly and also take our full punishment for our sins on Himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7. Our Savior had to be true God so that He could multiply the effect of His holy life and sin-removing death and pay for the sins and salvation of all people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. As the Christ, Jesus has faithfully served and even now continues to serve as our Prophet, High Pries and King.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. As the Prophet, Jesus carries out the work of accurately predicting people’s futures and making those futures known to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10.  As the High Priest, Jesus offered Himself as the once-for-all perfect sacrifice for our sins and now continues His work by praying for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. As the King, Jesus plans to take over all earthly governments and rule a united world from His capitol city of Jerusalem for many years..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. When Jesus was in the state of humiliation, He set aside the full use of His divine powers so that He could serve us and save us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. Jesus was conceived in the womb of His mother, Mary, by a miraculous work of the Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. Before Jesus died on the cross, He did not accomplish very much that has significance for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. Jesus’ death on the cross demonstrated just how deeply God loves us and the great lengths to which He will go in order to save us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why was it necessary for Jesus to live an entire life of sinless, selfless obedience to every one of God’s commandments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did the Son of God actually have to become a human being?  Why could He not just have appeared to be human without actually joining the human family?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Jesus is the eternal God, who has always lived and always will live, how was it possible for Him to die?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 7 The Second Article - Jesus’ Redeeming Work and Exaltation Questions 133-152</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/7/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 133-152 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. As our Redeemer, Jesus humbled Himself to the point of suffering the full torments of hell so that He could pay the price that gains our freedom from spiritual and eternal slavery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. By redeeming us from our sins, Jesus took away the power of sin to condemn us to suffer God’s punishment and to control us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. By redeeming us from death, Jesus took away death’s power to terrorize us and to prevent us from enjoying eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. By redeeming us from the devil, Jesus took away Satan’s power to successfully find us guilty of sin and to force us to commit sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. As our Substitute before God, Jesus took all our sins on Himself and credited all His perfection to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. Jesus has redeemed all the people who have or will believe in Him as their Savior, but only them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7. When Jesus entered His state of exaltation, He again made full use of His divine powers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. The exaltation of Jesus will end when He completes His final judgment brings the affairs of this world to a grand conclusion .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. The reason Jesus descended to hell was to give the sinful people who had previously died in unbelief another chance to hear His Word and believe in Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10.  Jesus’ resurrection offers convincing proof that Jesus is God and that all He tells us is absolutely true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. By raising Jesus from the dead, God the Father assures us that He has accepted Jesus’ suffering and death as the full payment for the sins of all people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. By rising from the dead, Jesus assures us that all who believe in Him will also rise from the dead to eternal glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. Jesus’ ascension to the right hand of God the Father means that Jesus is sitting on a throne in heaven right beside the Father’s throne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. When Jesus returns to the world, one of the things He will do is establish a 1,000 year, universal rule of all people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. When Jesus carries out the final judgment, He will only judge those who are alive at that time because those who had died before this time would already have faced God for judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Jesus redeemed us, to whom did He pay the ransom price?  (Explain your answer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When people are redeemed, they are set free from certain things and they are also set free for certain things.  What has Jesus Christ redeemed you for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List three ways that Jesus is able to help us more now that His has entered His state of exaltation than if He had remained in His state of humiliation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 8 The Third Article - The Holy Spirit and Holy Christian Church Questions 153-173</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/8/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 153-173 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. The Holy Spirit is the least known and least powerful member of the Holy Trinity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. When we use the word “sanctification” in its most complete meaning, we are referring to everything that the Holy Spirit does to create, nurture, direct. and preserve our spiritual life as Christians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. Before a person becomes a Christian, he is caught up in a perilous condition of being spiritually blind, spiritually dead and defiantly hostile to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. The Holy Spirit uses a person’s natural abilities and desires to accomplish His sanctifying work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. Conversion and surrender are two of the words commonly used to describe the Holy Spirit’s work of bringing a person to saving faith in Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. When the Holy Spirit brings a person to saving faith, He creates a new believing nature in that person that trusts and loves God and hates and resists sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7.  God judges the goodness of a person’s deeds in the same way that most people in the world judge deeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. Along with the gift of saving faith, the Holy Spirit also gives Christians a variety of spiritual abilities to better serve God and His people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. The Holy Spirit brings people to faith in Christ, but then Christians must rely on their own spiritual abilities to remain in faith for the rest of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10.  God’s greatest desire is that all people would be saved and have eternal life as a gift of His grace through faith in Jesus Christ, the Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. The Holy Christian Church is a magnificent creation of God, whose members are all the people who believe in Jesus Christ as their Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. The Holy Christian Church is described as “invisible” because only God can look into the hearts of its members and know that they truly believe in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. If a person never becomes a member of the Holy Christian Church, it is still possible for him to be saved and go to heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. The Holy Christian Church is called “holy” because all its members stop sinning and become morally perfect before they die and enter heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. The Holy Christian Church is called “Christian” because it is based on the person, redeeming work and teaching of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain why it is impossible for a person to bring himself to saving faith in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What role do good works have in the life of a Christian?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does a person who believes in Christ still have to be concerned about remaining in faith?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 9 The Third Article - The Visible Church, Forgiveness, Resurrection, Eternal Life Questions 173-193</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/9/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 173-193 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. Believers in Christ will be found wherever people gather and make use of the Gospel in the forms of the Word and Sacraments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. We call local gatherings of people around the means of grace “visible churches”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. It is possible that some people who belong to a visible church may not be true believers in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. God wants us to actively participate in a visible church even if that church teaches things that are false and violate the Bible’s teachings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. As long as a person is a member of a visible Christian church, he does not have to attend worship services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. When God forgives sins, He pays 50% of the cost of removing those wrongs and their damage so that it does not interfere with His relationship with the sinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7.  The reason God forgives people is that He sees some potential goodness that He can bring out of that person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. God forgives people mostly on the basis of what Jesus Christ has done to redeem them and partly on what they have done to help themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. When God justifies sinners, He declares them innocent of all their sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10.  A person can enjoy the benefit of God’s verdict of “not guilty of sin” only if he believes God’s promise of pardon through Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. On the Last Day, God will raise to life only believers in Christ who have died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. Because of reincarnation, people live multiple earthly lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. In the Final Judgment, God will give believers glorified bodies and He will give unbelievers horrified bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. Eternal life begins for a person in this world and never ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. Eternal life involves enjoying all the blessings that Jesus Chris has won for us and having most of our earthly sorrows erased from our memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does God want me to do if I discover that my church is not faithfully teaching and practicing God’s Word?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does forgiveness for a sin always have to be a free and freely given gift?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe three ways in which your life in heaven will be better than your life on earth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 10 Prayer and The Lord’s Prayer - Introduction – 2nd Petition Questions 194-214</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/10/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 194-214 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. Prayer is a believer speaking to God from his heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. Prayers should be addressed only to a god that a person believes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. Prayers must be addressed to the true God or they are not actual prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. God wants us to appeal to Him in prayer on the basis of how good and faithful we have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. We should pray to God, even if we do not believe that God will hear or help us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. We should pray with the thinking that God will answer our prayers just the way we want Him to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7.  We must offer our prayers according to God’s will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. When God answers our prayers, He always gives us the answer that is best for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. We should pray for all people including for the souls of people who have already died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10.  We can pray at any place and at any time with the confidence that our God will hear and answer our prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. In the Introduction to the Lord’s Prayer, we are reminded that we are to speak to God in prayer with the confidence and boldness that a deeply loved child would have in talking to his loving father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. God’s Word revealed to us in the Bible is a very big part of God’s name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. We keep God’s name holy by the way we regard and respond to God’s Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. God’s kingdom is His rule over people with His power, His grace and His glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. Our request for God’s kingdom to come is, in part, a mission prayer for the conversion of unbelievers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a written prayer list that includes the people and matters that you would like to pray for this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compose a prayer that includes requests to God for both you and other people and that also offers thanks to God for specific blessings that you have recently received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do you think that God sometimes gives us a “no” answer to our prayers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 11 The Lord’s Prayer - 3rd Petition - Conclusion Questions 215-235</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/11/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 215-235 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. When we pray for God’s will to be done, we are asking that God would help us believe, accept and do many of the things that God wants to happen in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. Along with Satan and other worldly opposition to God, there is a part of every Christian that is an enemy of God and His will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. When we pray for daily bread, we are asking God for only enough food on which to live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. Our prayer for daily bread is a declaration of our dependence on God and an expression of thankfulness to Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. Since a generous, merciful God provides for our needs, we do not need to be concerned about having a job that produces income or about taking good care of our possessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. We can confidently ask God to forgive our sins because morally good people like us deserve to be forgiven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7.  If I am unwilling to forgive those who sin against me, I am telling God that He should not deal with my sins in pardoning love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. Forgiveness is free to the one who is forgiven, but it is extremely costly to the one who forgives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. In the Lord’s Prayer, we use the word “temptation” to mean “anything good or bad that a person may desire”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10.  God will not tempt us to sin, but He will test our faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. Evil includes all the bad, harmful, wicked things that have come into the world as a result of human sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. At times, God answers our request to be delivered from evil by allowing evil to afflict us, but giving us the strength to handle it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. Sadly, we will have to continue to deal with evil forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. The Greek word “Amen” means “this prayer is over”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. The closing words of the Lord’s Prayer are a statement of praise that acknowledges God’s ability to hear and answer our prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a list of at least ten important things God wants that involve you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a prayer of thanksgiving to God that includes at least twenty earthly blessings that He gives you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Briefly explain what helps you be strong to resist temptation to sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 12 The Sacrament of Holy Baptism Questions 236-260</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/12/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 236-260 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. A sacrament is a sacred action, instituted by Jesus Christ, in which He attaches His all-powerful Word to an earthly element and pledges to give people the forgiveness of sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. The two Sacraments of Holy Baptism and Holy Communion are forms of the Law that require our obedience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. The word “baptize” means “to apply water”.  Pouring water on a person’s head is the only valid way that water can be applied in Christian baptism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. Jesus instituted Christian baptism at the time He was baptized by John at the Jordan River.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. When a person is baptized in the name of God the Father, Son and Holy Spirit, the members of the Trinity spiritually adopt that person into the Christian family and give that person God’s love and blessings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. God has given all Christians the authority to perform baptisms, but we usually have our spiritual leaders perform them in normal, non-emergency situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7.  It is proper to teach people who can be taught the basic teachings of the Bible before they are baptized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. There are no clear biblical reasons to baptize infants and small children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. In Holy Baptism, God gives great blessings such as forgiveness of sins, freedom from the control of Satan, deliverance from eternal death, and the assurance of eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10.  A person who comes to faith through hearing and believing God’s Word will also want to be baptized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. God has no way of saving people apart from them being baptized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. Holy Baptism receives its power from the Word of God and not from the water or the way the water was applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. We are to daily suppress the wicked intentions of our sinful nature through ongoing repentance for our sins and continued trust in God’s forgiveness through our Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. We are to have our believing nature express itself by confessing our faith in  God and by living a life of good works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. Our baptism, through which God gave us spiritual life, also gives us daily comfort, strength and willingness to live our lives in joyful thanks to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we consider Baptism a sacrament, but do not consider marriage a sacrament since both were instituted by God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give four reasons why we should baptize infants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you perform a Baptism in an emergency situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 13 Confession And The Keys Questions 261-284</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/13/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 261-284 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. In the section called Confession, God reminds us that sin is our greatest problem and that forgiveness of sins is our greatest need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. Refusing to admit our sins to God and to others is a foolish, dishonest, attempt to avoid responsibility for the wrongs we have done, especially since God already knows all about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. We need to confess to people only the sins that we have committed against them or that trouble our consciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. We need to confess to God only the sins we can remember doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. Absolution is the assurance of God’s forgiveness that is spoken or verbally expressed by one of God’s people to a repentant person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. If someone comes to us to confess a sin that is troubling him, we should do our best to assure them of God’s forgiveness and not tell anyone about the sin or sins confessed to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7.  The Office or Ministry of the Keys is a special authority God has given His Christians to forgive sins to those who are contrite and to withhold forgiveness from those who are not contrite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. All people should be assured that God forgives them even if they are not sorry for their sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. Only people who are sincerely repentant can enjoy God’s forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10.  The pastor or other called spiritual leader of the congregation publicly uses the authority of the Keys publicly on behalf of Christ and the believers in the church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. According to God’s requirements in the Bible, only men who are personally and spiritually qualified are eligible to be Christian pastors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. When dealing with an unrepentant sinner, God teaches us to apply His Word faithfully to that person with great love and patience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. A Christian congregation will take the action of declaring a person to be a non-Christian (excommunication) only when it is clear that they are persistently unrepentant for their sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. The purpose of excommunication is to remove people with difficulty personalities from the church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. If a person who has been removed from the congregation for unrepentant sin later does repent, they are to be forgiven and welcomed again as a believing member of the congregation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a prayer of personal confession to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select and share three Bible verses you would use to assure a repentant person that God forgives him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List three sins that people may commit that might specially trouble their consciences and would be helped by personal confession to a pastor or fellow Christian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 14 The Sacrament of the Altar – Holy Communion Questions 285-306</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/14/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about Questions 285-306 in the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. The Lord’s Supper and Holy Communion are other more common names that we use to refer to the Sacrament of the Altar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. Both Holy Communion and Holy Baptism are forms of the Gospel, but Communion is intended to be observed many times by a Christian to preserve faith while Baptism is to be done only once in order to begin faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. According to the clear words of Jesus, who instituted Holy Communion, God gives each communicant the earthly elements of bread and wine and the spiritual elements of Christ’s body and blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. When we celebrate the Lord’s Supper, we are only imagining that we are receiving Jesus’ body and blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. When we celebrate the Lord’s Supper, we are actually re-sacrificing Jesus’ body and blood in order to make further payment for our sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. In the Sacrament of Holy Communion, God gives us His solemn vow that He forgives all our sins, saves us from hell, and grants us eternal life now and in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7.  It is the special bread and wine we use that gives Holy Communion its great power and ability to give us such great blessings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. If a person takes Holy Communion, but does not truly believe that he is a sinner or that Jesus is his Savior or that God gives His Gospel blessings in Communion, he does not receive God’s blessings, but invites God’s judgment on himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. In order to receive Holy Communion to our benefit, we must prove to God by our good lives that we deserve His favor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10.  Since receiving Holy Communion is such a serious matter, we should take time to think about it and to spiritually examine ourselves before we partake of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. A person with weak faith should wait until their faith is strong before he takes the Lord’s Supper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. Since we want all people to enjoy God’s grace, we should invite anyone who wants to commune to come to Holy Communion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. Only ordained pastors are allowed to administer Holy Communion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. Our church should celebrate Communion only about 4 times a year so that the members do not disregard its importance and benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. The practice of confirming people as communicant members of the church after they have been carefully instructed in the teachings of the Bible is a wise, helpful practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Reflection Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is so wrong about teaching people that the body and blood of Jesus are only symbolized and not actually present in Holy Communion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What things should a person examine about their faith in order to prepare to receive Holy Communion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is practicing a policy of communing only those who hold to a common faith in God and His Word important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. God: _____________________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. those who do not hold to the Bible’s teaching:____________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. those who do hold to the Bible’s teaching: _______________________________________&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 15 The Appendix</title>
      <link>/en/courses/207/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/207/15/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A. Carefully read and think about the Appendix at the back of the Small Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Write down at least 5 Important Things that you discovered in your reading
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Agree-Disagree Questions: Read and think about each of the following Agree-Disagree statements.  Answer each statement and write a brief reason to support the answer you gave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luther’s Preface&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 1. In Martin Luther’s time, the level of biblical knowledge among the people of Germany was very good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 2. In Martin Luther’s time, the religious leaders of Germany were generally well trained in the teachings of the Bible and were very dedicated to the spiritual instruction of the members of their churches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 3. In the Preface to the Small Catechism, Luther appealed to the spiritual leaders to give careful, intensive instruction in the basic doctrines of the Bible to their members, especially to children and those who were not well educated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 4. Once people had learned the basic truths of the Bible, Luther encouraged the spiritual leaders to train their members to understand the deeper meaning of those truths to their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;____ 5. Luther also encouraged community leaders and parents to take a strong interest in the religious education of their children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 6. Toward the end of his preface, Luther made a strong appeal to teach people the value and benefits of participating in Bible study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creeds and Confessions of the Lutheran Church&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 7. Along with the three main Christian Creeds, the Lutheran Church accepts six other Bible-based confessional writings that are contained in the Book of Beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luther’s Seal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 8. Martin Luther designed a special seal with a number of different symbols and colors for the purpose of summarizing his personal spiritual struggles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salvation Outline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 9. The seven part salvation outline with its Bible verses is useful to help lead a person to saving faith in Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Church Year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 10.  The Christian Church year is an interesting arrangement of the year into two major parts: the festival half that focuses on the life of Jesus Christ and the non-festival half that focuses on the life of the Church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Time Between The Testaments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 11. In the 400 year period between the Old Testament and the New Testament, the Jewish people, who carried the promise of the coming Savior, were ruled by three great world powers: the Persians, the Germans and the Romans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 12. One of the significant religious projects in the time between the Testaments was the Septuagint, the translation of the 39 Old Testament books from the original Hebrew into the French language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 13. During the time between the Testaments, two influential religious sects developed in Israel: the Pharisees and the Sadducees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 14. Local houses of religious instruction and worship called synagogues came into existence during the time between the Testaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___ 15. Throughout the centuries up until the time of the New Testament, God was at work to get the world ready for the coming of the Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Instructions For The Examination&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
