<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grace Bible Institute – THE SAVIOR AND THOSE HE SAVES</title>
    <link>/en/courses/202/</link>
    <description>Recent content in THE SAVIOR AND THOSE HE SAVES on Grace Bible Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:47:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/en/courses/202/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 13</title>
      <link>/en/courses/202/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/202/1/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;ANTHROPOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Study of Man, the Object of Salvation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 6 – Creation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALS bilingual pdf file:  Chapter 6, pages 1-21  [NPH: pages 149-161]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In lesson 12 we concluded Unit B, Theology (Lessons 9-12).  In Unit C (Lessons 13-20) we will cover the subject of Anthropology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthropology is the study of humankind.  In this unit we will see who we are: Created in the image of God, but now through the Fall into sin, we are ruined and corrupt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next 8 lessons are critical because they lead us toward Christology.  As we get to know ourselves as we really are, we will be ready, all the more, to appreciate Jesus because of who he is:  Jesus is God the Son; Jesus is the Savior we need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We begin this unit with a lesson on the creation of the universe and of the first man and woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;athe-triune-god-created-the-world&#34;&gt;A.	The Triune God Created the World.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;agod-the-father-created-all-things&#34;&gt;a.	God the Father created all things.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:1
1In the beginning God created the heavens and the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malachi 2:10a
10 Do we not all have one Father? Did not one God create us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bgod-the-spirit-created-all-things&#34;&gt;b.	God the Spirit created all things.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 2:2
2 Now the earth was formless and empty, darkness was over the surface of the deep, and the Spirit of God was hovering over the waters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 104:30
30 When you send your Spirit,
they are created,
and you renew the face of the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cgod-the-son-created-all-things&#34;&gt;c.	God the Son created all things.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:3
3 And God said, “Let there be light,” and there was light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 1:1-3
1In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. 2 He was with God in the beginning. 3 Through him all things were made; without him nothing was made that has been made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 1:1-3
That which was from the beginning, which we have heard, which we have seen with our eyes, which we have looked at and our hands have touched—this we proclaim concerning the Word of life. 2 The life appeared; we have seen it and testify to it, and we proclaim to you the eternal life, which was with the Father and has appeared to us. 3 We proclaim to you what we have seen and heard, so that you also may have fellowship with us. And our fellowship is with the Father and with his Son, Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colossians 1:15-16
15 The Son is the image of the invisible God, the firstborn over all creation. 16 For in him all things were created: things in heaven and on earth, visible and invisible, whether thrones or powers or rulers or authorities; all things have been created through him and for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bthe-triune-god-made-the-world-in-six-6-ordinary-days&#34;&gt;B.	The triune God made the world in six (6) ordinary days.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;agod-does-all-things-in-an-orderly-peaceful-way&#34;&gt;a.	God does all things in an orderly, peaceful way.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 14:33a
33 For God is not a God of disorder but of peace….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bgod-created-the-universe-in-an-orderly-fashion&#34;&gt;b.	God created the universe in an orderly fashion.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;iday-1--time-matter-light-day--night&#34;&gt;i.	Day 1:  Time, matter, light; day &amp;amp; night.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:1-5
In the beginning God created the heavens and the earth. 2 Now the earth was formless and empty, darkness was over the surface of the deep, and the Spirit of God was hovering over the waters.
3 And God said, “Let there be light,” and there was light. 4 God saw that the light was good, and he separated the light from the darkness. 5 God called the light “day,” and the darkness he called “night.” And there was evening, and there was morning—the first day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;iiday-2-sky-separation-of-the-waters&#34;&gt;ii.	Day 2: sky; separation of the waters&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:6-8
6 And God said, “Let there be a vault between the waters to separate water from water.” 7 So God made the vault and separated the water under the vault from the water above it. And it was so. 8 God called the vault “sky.” And there was evening, and there was morning—the second day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;iiiday-3-dry-ground--seas-vegetation&#34;&gt;iii.	Day 3: dry ground &amp;amp; seas; vegetation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:9-13
9 And God said, “Let the water under the sky be gathered to one place, and let dry ground appear.” And it was so. 10 God called the dry ground “land,” and the gathered waters he called “seas.” And God saw that it was good.
11 Then God said, “Let the land produce vegetation: seed-bearing plants and trees on the land that bear fruit with seed in it, according to their various kinds.” And it was so. 12 The land produced vegetation: plants bearing seed according to their kinds and trees bearing fruit with seed in it according to their kinds. And God saw that it was good. 13 And there was evening, and there was morning—the third day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ivday-4--sun-moon-and-stars-times-and-seasons&#34;&gt;iv.	Day 4:  Sun, moon and stars; times and seasons&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:14-19
14 And God said, “Let there be lights in the vault of the sky to separate the day from the night, and let them serve as signs to mark sacred times, and days and years, 15 and let them be lights in the vault of the sky to give light on the earth.” And it was so. 16 God made two great lights—the greater light to govern the day and the lesser light to govern the night. He also made the stars. 17 God set them in the vault of the sky to give light on the earth, 18 to govern the day and the night, and to separate light from darkness. And God saw that it was good. 19 And there was evening, and there was morning—the fourth day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;vday-5-sea-creatures--winged-birds&#34;&gt;v.	Day 5: sea creatures &amp;amp; winged birds&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:20-23
20 And God said, “Let the water teem with living creatures, and let birds fly above the earth across the vault of the sky.” 21 So God created the great creatures of the sea and every living thing with which the water teems and that moves about in it, according to their kinds, and every winged bird according to its kind. And God saw that it was good. 22 God blessed them and said, “Be fruitful and increase in number and fill the water in the seas, and let the birds increase on the earth.” 23 And there was evening, and there was morning—the fifth day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;viday-6--land-animals-man-and-woman&#34;&gt;vi.	Day 6:  land animals; man and woman&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:24-31
24 And God said, “Let the land produce living creatures according to their kinds: the livestock, the creatures that move along the ground, and the wild animals, each according to its kind.” And it was so. 25 God made the wild animals according to their kinds, the livestock according to their kinds, and all the creatures that move along the ground according to their kinds. And God saw that it was good.
26 Then God said, “Let us make mankind in our image, in our likeness, so that they may rule over the fish in the sea and the birds in the sky, over the livestock and all the wild animals, and over all the creatures that move along the ground.”
27 So God created mankind in his own image,
in the image of God he created them;
male and female he created them.
28 God blessed them and said to them, “Be fruitful and increase in number; fill the earth and subdue it. Rule over the fish in the sea and the birds in the sky and over every living creature that moves on the ground.”
29 Then God said, “I give you every seed-bearing plant on the face of the whole earth and every tree that has fruit with seed in it. They will be yours for food. 30 And to all the beasts of the earth and all the birds in the sky and all the creatures that move along the ground—everything that has the breath of life in it—I give every green plant for food.” And it was so.
31 God saw all that he had made, and it was very good. And there was evening, and there was morning—the sixth day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;con-the-seventh-day-god-rested&#34;&gt;c.	On the seventh day, God rested.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 2:1-3
Thus the heavens and the earth were completed in all their vast array.
2 By the seventh day God had finished the work he had been doing; so on the seventh day he rested from all his work. 3 Then God blessed the seventh day and made it holy, because on it he rested from all the work of creating that he had done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dgenesis-is-an-orderly-book-with-10-clearly-marked-sections&#34;&gt;d.	Genesis is an orderly book with 10 clearly marked sections.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 2:4 
4 This is the account of the heavens and the earth when they were created, when the LORD God made the earth and the heavens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ctoledoth-1-genesis-25-25-gives-more-details-about-6th-day-of-creation&#34;&gt;C.	“Toledoth” #1 (Genesis 2:5-25) gives more details about 6th day of creation.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;athe-lord-god-created-the-first-man-and-a-special-home-for-humankind&#34;&gt;a.	The LORD God created the first man and a special home for humankind.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 2:5-7
5 Now no shrub had yet appeared on the earth and no plant had yet sprung up, for the LORD God had not sent rain on the earth and there was no one to work the ground, 6 but streams came up from the earth and watered the whole surface of the ground.  7 Then the LORD God formed a man from the dust of the ground and breathed into his nostrils the breath of life, and the man became a living being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 2:8-14
8 Now the LORD God had planted a garden in the east, in Eden; and there he put the man he had formed. 9 The LORD God made all kinds of trees grow out of the ground—trees that were pleasing to the eye and good for food. In the middle of the garden were the tree of life and the tree of the knowledge of good and evil.
10 A river watering the garden flowed from Eden; from there it was separated into four headwaters. 11 The name of the first is the Pishon; it winds through the entire land of Havilah, where there is gold. 12 (The gold of that land is good; aromatic resin and onyx are also there.) 13 The name of the second river is the Gihon; it winds through the entire land of Cush. 14 The name of the third river is the Tigris; it runs along the east side of Ashur. And the fourth river is the Euphrates. 15 The LORD God took the man and put him in the Garden of Eden to work it and take care of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bthe-lord-god-gave-mankind-his-life-giving-word&#34;&gt;b.	The LORD God gave mankind his life-giving Word.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16 And the LORD God commanded the man, “You are free to eat from any tree in the garden; 17 but you must not eat from the tree of the knowledge of good and evil, for when you eat from it you will certainly die.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cthe-lord-god-created-the-first-woman-from-the-first-man&#34;&gt;c.	The LORD God created the first woman from the first man.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18 The LORD God said, “It is not good for the man to be alone. I will make a helper suitable for him.”
19 Now the LORD God had formed out of the ground all the wild animals and all the birds in the sky. He brought them to the man to see what he would name them; and whatever the man called each living creature, that was its name. 20 So the man gave names to all the livestock, the birds in the sky and all the wild animals.
But for Adam no suitable helper was found. 21 So the LORD God caused the man to fall into a deep sleep; and while he was sleeping, he took one of the man’s ribs and then closed up the place with flesh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dthe-lord-god-created-the-first-marriage&#34;&gt;d.	The LORD God created the first marriage.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 Then the LORD God made a woman from the rib he had taken out of the man, and he brought her to the man.
23 The man said,
“This is now bone of my bones
and flesh of my flesh;
she shall be called ‘woman,’
for she was taken out of man.”
24 That is why a man leaves his father and mother and is united to his wife, and they become one flesh.
25 Adam and his wife were both naked, and they felt no shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dthe-theory-of-evolution-must-be-rejected&#34;&gt;D.	The Theory of Evolution must be rejected&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aevolution-denies-the-biblical-account-of-creation&#34;&gt;a.	Evolution denies the biblical account of creation.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Peter 3:3-5
3 Above all, you must understand that in the last days scoffers will come, scoffing and following their own evil desires. 4 They will say, “Where is this ‘coming’ he promised? Ever since our ancestors died, everything goes on as it has since the beginning of creation.” 5 But they deliberately forget that long ago by God’s word the heavens came into being and the earth was formed out of water and by water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bevolution-rejects-the-fall-into-sin&#34;&gt;b.	Evolution rejects the fall into sin.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 11:1-4
Now the whole world had one language and a common speech. 2 As people moved eastward, they found a plain in Shinar and settled there.
3 They said to each other, “Come, let’s make bricks and bake them thoroughly.” They used brick instead of stone, and tar for mortar. 4 Then they said, “Come, let us build ourselves a city, with a tower that reaches to the heavens, so that we may make a name for ourselves; otherwise we will be scattered over the face of the whole earth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cevolution-rejects-original-sin&#34;&gt;c.	Evolution rejects original sin.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colossians 2:6-8
6 So then, just as you received Christ Jesus as Lord, continue to live your lives in him, 7 rooted and built up in him, strengthened in the faith as you were taught, and overflowing with thankfulness.
8 See to it that no one takes you captive through hollow and deceptive philosophy, which depends on human tradition and the elemental spiritual forces of this world rather than on Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;devolution-rejects-actual-sin&#34;&gt;d.	Evolution rejects actual sin.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Timothy 3:1-5
But mark this: There will be terrible times in the last days. 2 People will be lovers of themselves, lovers of money, boastful, proud, abusive, disobedient to their parents, ungrateful, unholy, 3 without love, unforgiving, slanderous, without self-control, brutal, not lovers of the good, 4 treacherous, rash, conceited, lovers of pleasure rather than lovers of God— 5 having a form of godliness but denying its power. Have nothing to do with such people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eevolution-sees-death-as-a-natural-tool-in-the-evolutionary-process&#34;&gt;e.	Evolution sees death as a natural tool in the evolutionary process.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Timothy 1:9b-10
This grace was given us in Christ Jesus before the beginning of time, 10 but it has now been revealed through the appearing of our Savior, Christ Jesus, who has destroyed death and has brought life and immortality to light through the gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson has given us our first look at “anthropology”.  There will be 7 more lessons in this unit.  We must get to know ourselves as we are – created by the triune God and given God’s image.  Now, however, we are corrupted by sin.  This is not a pretty picture.  We would rather think better of ourselves.  And so people have developed evolutionary philosophies and self-help religions.  As we continue a study of “anthropology”, we will all the more appreciate and long for the salvation which is ours in Jesus the Son of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discussion-time&#34;&gt;DISCUSSION TIME&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;students-questions&#34;&gt;STUDENTS’ QUESTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructors-questions&#34;&gt;INSTRUCTOR’S QUESTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;homework&#34;&gt;Homework&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review your notes from this lesson.  Give correct answers to the following questions.  You may also find correct answers to these questions in the book “God So Loved the World” as indicated on page 1 of this lesson.  Be ready to discuss these questions and your answers at the beginning of the next session.&lt;br&gt;
Your next exam will follow lesson 20 of this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the created world tell us about God?  Romans 1:20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it a matter of faith that God made the world?  Hebrews 11:3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that the Triune God made the world.  Genesis 1:1,2, John 1:3; Colossians 1:15,16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that God made the world out of nothing?  Ge 1:1; Heb 11:3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What idea concerning the length of creation did the church father Athanasius have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What idea concerning the days of creation is held by theistic evolutionists?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify the ten historical accounts which comprise the book of Genesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;f.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;g.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;j.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we know that the information given in Genesis is fact and not folklore or myth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did Jesus and the apostles view the account of creation?  Matthew 19:4, Acts 4:24; 14:15-17; 17:22-31; Revelation 4:11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the Hebrew word for day sometimes mean more than a normal day?  Explain.  Isaiah 7:18, 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we believe that God made the world in six normal days?  Genesis 1:5; Exodus 20:9-11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify what God made on each day of creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.	Genesis 1:1-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	1:6-8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.	1:9-13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d.	1:14-19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e.	1:20-23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;f.	1:24-31.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;13&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did God do on day 7?  Genesis 2:1-3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what did the “image of God” not consist? John 4:24.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what did the image of God consist?  Colossians 3:10; Ephesians 4:24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What position did mankind have with regard to the rest of creation?  Genesis 1:28-30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that Genesis 1 and 2 comprise a unified account of creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that God’s command not to eat of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil was based against the background of God’s love.  Genesis 2:16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that Adam was an intelligent man.  Genesis 2:19, 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the significance of the creation of Eve out of Adam?  Romans 5:18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that marriage is “monogamous” and “heterosexual.”  Genesis 2:22-25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify three purposes for marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;g.	Genesis 2:24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h.	Genesis 1:28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i.	1 Corinthians 7:2  (since the fall into sin)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;23&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we know that God did not create evil (Genesis 1:31).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Show how evolution affects the following doctrines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.  creation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.  the fall into sin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.  original sin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d.  actual sin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e.  death&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;j.	Jesus’ redemption of the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;25&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why can we not harmonize evolution with creation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 14</title>
      <link>/en/courses/202/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/202/2/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;ANTHROPOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Study of Man, the Object of Salvation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 7 – Providence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALS bilingual pdf file:  Chapter 7, pages 1-9 [NPH: pages 163-169]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In lesson 13 our study of anthropology began with the creation of the world.  The Triune God created all things.  Then, on the 6th and final day of his creating activity, God made humankind as the crown of creation.
On the 7th day, God rested from his creating activity.  However, this does not mean that God stopped being involved in the world which he created.  In this lesson we begin a study of divine “providence”.  Divine providence has to do with the fact that the Triune God remains directly involved in the world which he created: God preserves, protects and provides for the world which he created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may speak about divine providence in both a broader and a narrow sense.  We will focus on the narrow aspect of providence.  This focus will give us mysteries to ponder as we learn how God takes care of us and everyone else and everything which he created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aby-his-providence-the-lord-god-preserves-all-that-he-has-created&#34;&gt;A.	By his providence, the LORD God preserves all that he has created.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ait-was-by-gods-will-or-desire-that-all-things-came-into-existence&#34;&gt;a.	It was by God’s will [or desire] that all things came into existence.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ithe-bible-tells-us-that-god-spoke-the-universe-into-existence-by-means-of-his-creative-word&#34;&gt;i.	The Bible tells us that God “spoke” the universe into existence by means of his “creative word”.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 33:6-9 (EHV)
By the word of the LORD the heavens were made.
By the breath of his mouth he made the whole army of stars.
7 He gathers the water of the sea into a heap.
He puts the depths into storehouses.
8 Let all the earth fear the LORD.
Let all the inhabitants of the world revere him.
9 For he said, “Let it be,” and it was!
He gave a command, and there it stood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;iithe-bible-explains-that-gods-creative-word-is-an-expression-of-his-will-or-desire&#34;&gt;ii.	The Bible explains that God’s creative word is an expression of his will (or desire).&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revelation 4:11 (EHV)
Worthy are you, our Lord and God,
to receive the glory and the honor and the power,
for you have created all things,
and because of your will they existed and were created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bit-is-by-his-will-that-the-triune-god-preserves-all-things&#34;&gt;b.	It is by his will that the Triune God preserves all things.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;igod-preserves-all-things-through-his-presence-within-everything-and-everyone&#34;&gt;i.	God preserves all things through his presence within everything and everyone.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job 38:4; 8-10
4 “Where were you when I laid the earth’s foundation?
Tell me, if you understand.
8 “Who shut up the sea behind doors
when it burst forth from the womb,
9when I made the clouds its garment
and wrapped it in thick darkness,
10 when I fixed limits for it
and set its doors and bars in place,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 90:1-2 (EHV)
Lord, you have been our dwelling place throughout all generations.
2 Before the mountains were born,
before you gave birth to the earth and the world,
from eternity to eternity you are God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 125:2 
As the mountains surround Jerusalem, so the LORD surrounds his people both now and forevermore.
Acts 17:28a (EHV)
28 ‘For in him we live and move and have our being.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;iigod-preserves-all-things-through-the-natural-laws-he-created-in-the-beginning&#34;&gt;ii.	God preserves all things through the natural laws he created in the beginning.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:29-30 
Then God said, “I give you every seed-bearing plant on the face of the whole earth and every tree that has fruit with seed in it. They will be yours for food. And to all the beasts of the earth and all the birds of the air and all the creatures that move on the ground—everything that has the breath of life in it—I give every green plant for food.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 104:27-29 (EHV)
27 All of them wait hopefully for you to give them their food in its time.
28 You give it to them. They gather it up.
You open your hand. They are satisfied with good things.
29 You hide your face. They are terrified.
You take away their breath.
They breathe their last and return to their dust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 5:45b (EHV)
For he makes his sun to rise on the evil and the good and sends rain on the righteous and the unrighteous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bgod-provides-for-and-protects-his-world-by-his-concurrent-working-in-us&#34;&gt;B.	God provides for and protects his world by his concurrent working in us.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 127:1-2 (EHV)
1 If the LORD does not build the house,
it is useless for the builders to work hard over it.
If the LORD does not watch over the city,
it is useless for the watchman to stand guard.
2 It is useless for you to get up early and to work late,
worrying about bread to eat,
because God grants sleep to the one he loves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proverbs 3:5-6
5 Trust in the LORD with all your heart
and lean not on your own understanding;
6 in all your ways submit to him,
and he will make your paths straight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proverbs 6:6-8
6 Go to the ant, you sluggard;
consider its ways and be wise!
7 It has no commander,
no overseer or ruler,
8 yet it stores its provisions in summer
and gathers its food at harvest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Thessalonians 3:10 (EHV)
0 In fact, when we were with you, this was our command to you: If anyone does not want to work, he should not eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Pray for potatoes with a hoe in your hand.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cgod-guards-and-guides-everything-by-his-governance-of-all-things&#34;&gt;C.	God guards and guides everything by his governance of all things.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aeverything-in-the-universe-is-governed-by-his-providence&#34;&gt;a.	Everything in the universe is governed by his providence&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ithe-stars&#34;&gt;i.	The stars&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 40:25-26
25 “To whom will you compare me?
Or who is my equal?” says the Holy One.
26 Lift up your eyes and look to the heavens:
Who created all these?
He who brings out the starry host one by one
and calls forth each of them by name.
Because of his great power and mighty strength,
not one of them is missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;iithe-seas&#34;&gt;ii.	The seas&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 104:6-9 (EHV)
6 You covered it with the deep as a garment.
The waters stood above the mountains.
7 At your rebuke they fled.
At the sound of your thunder they hurried away.
8 The waters surged up the mountains.
They went down into the valleys,
to the place that you prepared for them.
9 You set a boundary that they cannot cross.
They will not return to cover the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;iiiall-that-exists--large-and-small&#34;&gt;iii.	All that exists – large and small.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colossians 1:17 (EHV)
17 He is before all things, and all things hold together in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;beverything-is-governed-by-his-providence-for-the-good-of-his-church&#34;&gt;b.	Everything is governed by his providence for the good of his church&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genesis 50:20
20 You intended to harm me, but God intended it for good to accomplish what is now being done, the saving of many lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeremiah 29:11
11 For I know the plans I have for you,” declares the LORD, “plans to prosper you and not to harm you, plans to give you hope and a future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 8:28 (EHV)
28 We know that all things work together for the good of those who love God, for those who are called according to his purpose….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 1:22 (EHV)
22 God also placed all things under his feet and made him head over everything for the church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All of creation in general, the church in particular, and a believer in specific are all under the providence of God.  This is a great comfort.” (Lyle W. Lange, God So Loved the World, NPH, 2005, page 165; ALS bilingual version, chapter 7, page 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dwe-are-responsible-for-how-we-use-the-abilities-god-gives-to-us&#34;&gt;D.	We are responsible for how we use the abilities God gives to us.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;agod-is-not-at-fault-when-people-using-the-powers-god-has-given-to-them-the-material-portion-of-an-action-do-what-is-evil-the-formal-portion-of-a-human-action&#34;&gt;a.	God is not at fault when people, using the powers God has given to them (the “material” portion of an action), do what is evil (the “formal” portion of a human action).&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deuteronomy 32:4 
He is the Rock, his works are perfect, and all his ways are just. A faithful God who does no wrong, upright and just is he.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 92:15 (EHV)
15 Yes, they can proclaim, “The LORD is upright.
He is my Rock, and he does no wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 3:3-4 (NIV)
3 Now what if some did not believe? Their unbelief[a] will not nullify God’s faithfulness, will it? 4 Absolutely not! God must be true, even though everyone is found to be a liar, just as it is written:
So that you would be justified whenever you speak,
and win the case when you judge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The scriptural way of speaking is that God goes along (concurs) with every action insofar as it is an act but not insofar as it is evil. Or, we might say that God goes along with the effect but not the defect of evil actions.” (Mark J. Lenz, God’s Providence ~ A Bible Study Course for Adults – NPH, 1997)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bgod-is-to-be-praised-and-thanked-for-the-good-things-his-believing-people-do-through-their-god-given-faith-in-jesus&#34;&gt;b.	God is to be praised and thanked for the good things his believing people do through their God-given faith in Jesus.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 2:8-10 (NIV)
8 Indeed, it is by grace you have been saved, through faith—and this is not from yourselves, it is the gift of God— 9 not by works, so that no one can boast. 10 For we are God’s workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works, which God prepared in advance so that we would walk in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philippians 2:13
13 In fact, it is God who is working in you, both to will and to work, for the sake of his good pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson has given us a brief glimpse into the topic of divine providence.  These are the basics.  Much more could be said.  This mystery can be explored more fully.
However, we must do as Job learned to do (put our hand over our mouth; repent of our sinful pride {40:4; 42:6}). We do not want to say too littler nor do we want to say too much about these things.  Faith – i.e., trust in the goodness and love of our Triune God – as revealed on the pages of his Word, the Bible – faith must remain in us also when we fail to perceive the guiding, guarding, protecting and providing which God is working in all the events of our lives.  We walk by faith, not by sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discussion-time&#34;&gt;DISCUSSION TIME&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;students-questions&#34;&gt;STUDENTS’ QUESTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructors-questions&#34;&gt;INSTRUCTOR’S QUESTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;homework&#34;&gt;Homework&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review your notes from this lesson.  Give correct answers to the following questions.  You may also find correct answers to these questions in the book “God So Loved the World” as indicated on page 1 of this lesson.  Be ready to discuss these questions and your answers at the beginning of the next session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your next exam will follow lesson 20 of this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify the three parts of providence in the wide sense.
a.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Define providence in the narrow sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify the three acts which comprise God’s execution of His decree of providence in time.
a.	Psalm 104:27,28; Matthew 6:26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	Acts 17:28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.	Jeremiah 10:23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the objects of God’s providence?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.	Psalm 147:4; Job 38:11; Mark 4:41; Job 38:28-30; Hebrews 1:3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	Matthew 10:29; 16:18, 10:30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that creation depends on God’s sustaining it.  Psalm 104:29,30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we say that preservation is immediate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that God uses means to preserve His creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.	Genesis 1:29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	Genesis 9:3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.	Matthew 5:45, Isaiah 55:10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that God can sustain life without means.  Deuteronomy 9:9, 18;  Matthew 4:2-4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does God not want us to neglect his means of preservation?  Deuteronomy 6:16;  Matthew 4:7; Matthew 6:26-34.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is divine concurrence?  Matthew 10:29; Acts 17:28.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain:  though distinct from His creation, God is present throughout creation, Enabling His creatures to carry out the functions He gave them..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regard to the evil that people do, demonstrate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.	that God can prevent it from happening.  Genesis 20:6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.  that God may permit it but will direct it so it works out for the believer’s good. Genesis 50:20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;13&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate that God’s permission of evil is not:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.  a weakness in God, as though he could not prevent evil.  Exodus 14:19, 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	an apathy on God’s part toward evil.  2 Thessalonians 1:6; Romans 6:23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.	an abrogation of God’s will.  Exodus 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;14&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that by nature we have no free will in spiritual matters.  1 Corinthians 2:14, Ephesians 2:1; Romans 8:7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that we are responsible for the evil we do but that God gets all the credit for the good which we do.  Psalm 5:4-6; Ephesians 2:10; Philippians 2:13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain:  God supplies the capability of action, but we bear the blame for our evil actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 15</title>
      <link>/en/courses/202/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/202/3/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;ANTHROPOLOGY
A Study of Man, the Object of Salvation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 7 – Providence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lesson 15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALS bilingual pdf file:  Chapter 7, pages 9-19
[NPH: pages 169-176]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction
In lesson 14 we began a two-part study of divine providence.  This doctrine has to do with the mysterious yet very real way by which the LORD God takes care of the world which he created.
In conclusion, we noted that “much more can be said” than was said in lesson 14.  In this lesson we will say some of the “more” which can be said.  Once again, we want to say what we can say; we want to say no more and no less than the Bible teaches us.&lt;br&gt;
The human mind – the sinfully hindered and corrupt human mind – strives to make sense of events and of life itself.  We must walk by faith and not by sight.  One day we will know as we are now known.  Until then, we walk by faith.&lt;br&gt;
Our Christian faith extends only to those things we learn in God’s Word, the Bible.  Let us strive once again to understand the word of our Lord on the matter of divine providence – and to keep our faith based on the clear words of God while we strive to avoid empty speculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already covered by lesson 14:
A.	By his providence, the LORD God preserves all that he has created. 
a.	It was by God’s will [or desire] that all things came into existence.
b.	It is by his will that the Triune God preserves all things. 
B.	God provides for and protects his world by his concurrent working in us.
C.	God guards and guides everything by his governance of all things.
a.	Everything in the universe is governed by his providence
b.	Everything is governed by his providence for the good of his church
D.	We are responsible for how we use the abilities God gives to us. 
a.	God is not at fault when people, using the powers God has given to them (the “material” portion of an action), do what is evil (the “formal” portion of a human action).
b.	God is to be praised and thanked for the good things his believing people do through their God-given faith in Jesus.
.
We conclude what we can say here about divine providence:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E.	Both of the following statements are true [although they seem to contradict each other].
I	Things must happen as they do.
II	Things could happen differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.	Philosophers of the world accept one or the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i.	Those who agree with statement “I” include&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Stoics among the ancient Greeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determinists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fatalists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The adherents of Hinduism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ii.	Those who agree with statement “II” include&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Epicureans among the ancient Greeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Sadducees of Jesus’ day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Deist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Atheist of our own day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	Christian doctrine compels us to agree with both of these statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i.	[From our view of divine providence] Things must happen as they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acts 4:27-28
27 Indeed Herod and Pontius Pilate met together with the Gentiles and the people of Israel in this city to conspire against your holy servant Jesus, whom you anointed. 28 They did what your power and will had decided beforehand should happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acts 2:23
23 This man was handed over to you by God’s deliberate plan and foreknowledge; and you, with the help of wicked men, put him to death by nailing him to the cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 26:24; 54
24 The Son of Man will go just as it is written about him. But woe to that man who betrays the Son of Man! It would be better for him if he had not been born.”
54 But how then would the Scriptures be fulfilled that say it must happen in this way?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ii.	[From our view of human accountability] Things could happen differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we noted in the previous lesson (#14), God’s foreknowledge and providential governing of all things does not remove from people their responsibility (culpability) for the wrong they do.  E.g., Judas Iscariot was not forced to betray Jesus. Judas chose to commit this sin. It was Judas who was at fault for his sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The believer’s prayer changes things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 38:1-5
In those days Hezekiah became ill and was at the point of death. The prophet Isaiah son of Amoz went to him and said, “This is what the LORD says: Put your house in order, because you are going to die; you will not recover.”
2 Hezekiah turned his face to the wall and prayed to the LORD, 3 “Remember, LORD, how I have walked before you faithfully and with wholehearted devotion and have done what is good in your eyes.” And Hezekiah wept bitterly.
4 Then the word of the LORD came to Isaiah: 5 “Go and tell Hezekiah, ‘This is what the LORD, the God of your father David, says: I have heard your prayer and seen your tears; I will add fifteen years to your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James 5:16b-18
The prayer of a righteous person is powerful and effective.
17 Elijah was a human being, even as we are. He prayed earnestly that it would not rain, and it did not rain on the land for three and a half years. 18 Again he prayed, and the heavens gave rain, and the earth produced its crops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human behavior changes things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.	Life is extended or made short by behavior&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 20:12
12 “Honor your father and your mother, so that you may live long in the land the LORD your God is giving you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 34:11-16
11 Come, my children, listen to me;
I will teach you the fear of the LORD.
12 Whoever of you loves life
and desires to see many good days,
13 keep your tongue from evil
and your lips from telling lies.
14 Turn from evil and do good;
seek peace and pursue it.
15 The eyes of the LORD are on the righteous,
and his ears are attentive to their cry;
16 but the face of the LORD is against those who do evil,
to blot out their name from the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	Life is extended by nourishing the body&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acts 27:33-34
33 Just before dawn Paul urged them all to eat. “For the last fourteen days,” he said, “you have been in constant suspense and have gone without food—you haven’t eaten anything. 34 Now I urge you to take some food. You need it to survive. Not one of you will lose a single hair from his head.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.	Life is made brief by harming the body&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Samuel 17:23
23 When Ahithophel saw that his advice had not been followed, he saddled his donkey and set out for his house in his hometown. He put his house in order and then hanged himself. So he died and was buried in his father’s tomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord can overrule our “plans” to live long through good food and exercise. As a result, we die “young” because of his providence.&lt;br&gt;
The Lord may overrule people’s desire to end their life by suicide.  As a result, they live on for many more years because of his providence.&lt;br&gt;
On the other hand, another suicide victim dies by his/her own hand and physically fit individuals live to celebrate their 101st birthday.  Human behavior seems to be the reason these things turned out as they did.
Nevertheless, in all these examples, whether or not we perceive that divine providence was at work – divine providence was indeed at work.  At the same time, human behavior made a difference in the events that took place.&lt;br&gt;
These statements seem to contradict each other.  Both are true.  We reject all human philosophies.  “We live by faith, not by sight” (2 Corinthians 5:7).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
The author of God So Loved the World concludes this chapter with a section titled The Bible and Bioethics.  Because of the truth we have affirmed in this lesson, Christians want to adhere to right behavior in the matter of bioethics.&lt;br&gt;
Life is precious and protected by God.  The commandment says “You shall not murder”.  This will of God does not change by circumstances or situations.&lt;br&gt;
Our Lord wants us to regard life in the way he regards life: his precious gift to us.  By faith in Jesus, we will thank Jesus for our life and do all we can to preserve physical life in ourselves and in others. 
At the same time, we yield to the Lord’s will regarding the length of our life. We recognize that by divine providence life is ours only until the moment God determines that our life here on earth is over (Matthew 6:27; Psalm 90:3; Hebrews 9:27).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DISCUSSION TIME&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STUDENTS’ QUESTIONS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INSTRUCTOR’S QUESTIONS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homework
Review your notes from this lesson.  Give correct answers to the following questions.  You may also find correct answers to these questions in the book “God So Loved the World” as indicated on page 1 of this lesson.  Be ready to discuss these questions and your answers at the beginning of the next session.&lt;br&gt;
Your next exam will follow lesson 20 of this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relate how the following deny God’s governance of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.  atheism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.  Epicureanism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.  Deism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relate how the following deny human accountability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.  Stoicism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.  Determinism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.  dogmatic

2.  fatalistic

3.  pantheistic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that things must happen as they do.  Acts 4:27, 28; 2:23; Matthew 26:24, 
54.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How far does God’s governance of the world extend?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;a.  Job 38:31

b.  Job 38:22-30

c.  Job 38:8-11

d.  Acts 17:26; Daniel 2:20-22.

e.  Matthew 10:29.

f.   Jeremiah 10:23

g.  Romans 8:28
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what way may we speak of chance? 1 Samuel 6:9.  Yet, why can we say there is no chance when it comes to things happening in this world?   Isaiah 45:7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a miracle?  Psalm 78:12, 13, 19, 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify miracles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.  of grace—Ephesians 2:4,5; Romans 7:22.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.  in nature—Mark 4:39; Daniel 3:26, 27; 6:22, John 5:8; Romans 4:18-21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who alone can do miracles?  Psalm 72:18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How were God’s messengers able to do miracles?  Exodus 4:21; Matthew                  &lt;br&gt;
10:8; Acts 19:11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does God permit or enable unbelievers to do miracles?  Explain.  Exodus 7:22;
Deuteronomy 13:1-3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer the claim that the world is a closed system and that this makes miracles impossible.
Genesis 18:14.  Identify David Hume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comment:  All of God’s prophecies must be fulfilled.  Isaiah 44:26; Matthew 26:54.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate that people are responsible for their own actions.  Matthew 26:24; John&lt;br&gt;
19:12;  cf. FC Ep 11:7,8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does prayer change things?   Isaiah 38:1-5; James 5:16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain:  The end of life is fixed—Job 14:5 Psalm 90:3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain:  People can lengthen or shorten their lives.  Isaiah 38:1-5;  Genesis 38:7, 10;
Acts 27:33,34; 2 Samuel 17:23; 18:14; Genesis 9:6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify and explain two major bioethical systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;a.

b.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;18&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evaluate these two systems in the light of the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain  and evaluate the following ethical systems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;a.  Emotivism

b.  voluntarism

c.  autonomism

d.  Positivism

e.  religious legalism

f.  natural law ethics

g.  proportionalism

h.  consequentialism

i.  situation ethics
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;20&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define and comment on active and passive euthanasia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses: Lesson 20</title>
      <link>/en/courses/202/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/courses/202/8/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;ANTHROPOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Study of Man, the Object of Salvation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 9 – Mankind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lesson 20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALS bilingual pdf file:  Chapter 9, pages 51-66&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[NPH: pages 218-226]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In lesson 19 we continued a 4-lesson unit on “Mankind”.  Here is an outline of what we learned about mankind in lessons 17-19:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A.	God created Adam and Eve in his own image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B.	We were not born with God’s image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C.	Every human being has a body and a soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D.	The characteristics of the soul/spirit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E.	All humans have descended from one man (Adam).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F.	God creates all people through the descendants of Adam and Eve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G.	The History of the Fall&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H.	The Law of God reveals our sin in order to bring us to repentance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I.	What sin is and what sin does&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J.	Original Sin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K.	Actual Sins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson is the conclusion of our study of Mankind.  We will now take a look at specific “actual sins”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L.	Giving Offense is a sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.	Jesus warns us concerning the sin of “giving offense”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 18:6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 “If anyone causes one of these little ones—those who believe in me—to stumble, it would be better for them to have a large millstone hung around their neck and to be drowned in the depths of the sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	It is a sin of giving offense when someone keeps people from the blessings of the gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark 10:13-14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 People were bringing little children to Jesus for him to place his hands on them, but the disciples rebuked them. 14 When Jesus saw this, he was indignant. He said to them, “Let the little children come to me, and do not hinder them, for the kingdom of God belongs to such as these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke 18:15-17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 People were also bringing babies to Jesus for him to place his hands on them. When the disciples saw this, they rebuked them. 16 But Jesus called the children to him and said, “Let the little children come to me, and do not hinder them, for the kingdom of God belongs to such as these. 17 Truly I tell you, anyone who will not receive the kingdom of God like a little child will never enter it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.	It is a sin of giving offense when someone harms the faith of those who believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 6:29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 Jesus answered, “The work of God is this: to believe in the one he has sent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 14:20-21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 Do not destroy the work of God for the sake of food. All food is clean, but it is wrong for a person to eat anything that causes someone else to stumble. 21 It is better not to eat meat or drink wine or to do anything else that will cause your brother or sister to fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d.	False teachers are committing a sin of giving offense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 16:17-18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 I urge you, brothers and sisters, to watch out for those who cause divisions and put obstacles in your way that are contrary to the teaching you have learned. Keep away from them. 18 For such people are not serving our Lord Christ, but their own appetites. By smooth talk and flattery they deceive the minds of naive people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note:  For more on the subjects of giving offense and the sinful use of Christian freedom, read:  Matthew 18:1-9; Mark 9:33-37; Luke 9:46-50; Luke 17:1-3; Romans 14:1-15:3; 1 Corinthians 8; 1 Corinthians 9:22-23; Galatians 2:11-21; Galatians 5:1-15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M.	God disciplines; Satan tempts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.	Our Lord does not tempt us to sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James 1:13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 When tempted, no one should say, “God is tempting me.” For God cannot be tempted by evil, nor does he tempt anyone….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	Our Lord promises to use our difficulties to bless us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebrews 12:7-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 Endure hardship as discipline; God is treating you as his children. For what children are not disciplined by their father? 8 If you are not disciplined—and everyone undergoes discipline—then you are not legitimate, not true sons and daughters at all. 9 Moreover, we have all had human fathers who disciplined us and we respected them for it. How much more should we submit to the Father of spirits and live! 10 They disciplined us for a little while as they thought best; but God disciplines us for our good, in order that we may share in his holiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 8:28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28 And we know that in all things God works for the good of those who love him, who have been called according to his purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.	Satan (together with the sinful nature in us, and the world around us) works to lead us into sinning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I Peter 5:8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 Be alert and of sober mind. Your enemy the devil prowls around like a roaring lion looking for someone to devour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James 1:14-15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 but each person is tempted when they are dragged away by their own evil desire and enticed. 15 Then, after desire has conceived, it gives birth to sin; and sin, when it is full-grown, gives birth to death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 2:15-16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 Do not love the world or anything in the world. If anyone loves the world, love for the Father is not in them. 16 For everything in the world—the lust of the flesh, the lust of the eyes, and the pride of life—comes not from the Father but from the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N.	The sin of hardening one’s heart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.	Egypt’s Pharaoh and his officials committed this sin against the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 9:7, 34&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 Pharaoh sent men to investigate and found that not even one of the animals of the Israelites had died. Yet his heart was unyielding and he would not let the people go. 34 When Pharaoh saw that the rain and hail and thunder had stopped, he sinned again: He and his officials hardened their hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	The LORD warns us not to commit this sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i.	God warns us with his words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proverbs 28:14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed is the man who always fears the LORD, but he who hardens his heart falls into trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 95:8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not harden your hearts as you did at Meribah, as you did that day at Massah in the desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebrews 3:8, 13, 15; 4:7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8 Do not harden your hearts as you did in the rebellion, during the time of testing in the desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 But encourage one another daily, as long as it is called Today, so that none of you may be hardened by sin’s deceitfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 As has just been said: “Today, if you hear his voice, do not harden your hearts as you did in the rebellion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 Therefore God again set a certain day, calling it Today, when a long time later he spoke through David, as was said before: “Today, if you hear his voice, do not harden your hearts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 4:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 And do not grieve the Holy Spirit of God, with whom you were sealed for the day of redemption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ii.	God warns us with examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 10:6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 Now these things occurred as examples to keep us from setting our hearts on evil things as they did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pharaoh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.	Egypt’s Pharaoh repeatedly hardened his heart against the Word of God spoken by Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 7:13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 Yet Pharaoh’s heart became hard and he would not listen to them, just as the LORDhad said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 7:22&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 But the Egyptian magicians did the same things by their secret arts, and Pharaoh’s heart became hard; he would not listen to Moses and Aaron, just as the LORD had said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 8:15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 But when Pharaoh saw that there was relief, he hardened his heart and would not listen to Moses and Aaron, just as the LORD had said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 8:19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 the magicians said to Pharaoh, “This is the finger of God.” But Pharaoh’s heart was hard and he would not listen, just as the LORD had said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 8:32&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;32 But this time also Pharaoh hardened his heart and would not let the people go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 9:7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 Pharaoh investigated and found that not even one of the animals of the Israelites had died. Yet his heart was unyielding and he would not let the people go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	The LORD hardened the pharaoh’s heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 9:12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 But the LORD hardened Pharaoh’s heart and he would not listen to Moses and Aaron, just as the LORD had said to Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 10:1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the LORD said to Moses, “Go to Pharaoh, for I have hardened his heartand the hearts of his officials so that I may perform these signs of mine among them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 10:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 But the LORD hardened Pharaoh’s heart, and he would not let the Israelites go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 10:27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;27 But the LORD hardened Pharaoh’s heart, and he was not willing to let them go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exodus 11:10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 Moses and Aaron performed all these wonders before Pharaoh, but the LORD hardened Pharaoh’s heart, and he would not let the Israelites go out of his country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ananias and Sapphira&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acts 5:1-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now a man named Ananias, together with his wife Sapphira, also sold a piece of property. 2 With his wife’s full knowledge he kept back part of the money for himself, but brought the rest and put it at the apostles’ feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Then Peter said, “Ananias, how is it that Satan has so filled your heart that you have lied to the Holy Spirit and have kept for yourself some of the money you received for the land? 4 Didn’t it belong to you before it was sold? And after it was sold, wasn’t the money at your disposal? What made you think of doing such a thing? You have not lied just to human beings but to God.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 When Ananias heard this, he fell down and died. And great fear seized all who heard what had happened. 6 Then some young men came forward, wrapped up his body, and carried him out and buried him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 About three hours later his wife came in, not knowing what had happened.8 Peter asked her, “Tell me, is this the price you and Ananias got for the land?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes,” she said, “that is the price.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 Peter said to her, “How could you conspire to test the Spirit of the Lord? Listen! The feet of the men who buried your husband are at the door, and they will carry you out also.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 At that moment she fell down at his feet and died. Then the young men came in and, finding her dead, carried her out and buried her beside her husband. 11 Great fear seized the whole church and all who heard about these events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O.	Sins of weakness vs. willful sinning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.	Sins of weakness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i.	Christians sin all the time because of the sinful nature in us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 26:41&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch and pray so that you will not fall into temptation. The spirit is willing, but the flesh is weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 7:15-17,19,20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not understand what I do. For what I want to do I do not do, but what I hate I do. 16 And if I do what I do not want to do, I agree that the law is good. 17 As it is, it is no longer I myself who do it, but it is sin living in me. 19 For what I do is not the good I want to do; no, the evil I do not want to do—this I keep on doing. 20 Now if I do what I do not want to do, it is no longer I who do it, but it is sin living in me that does it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ii.	Sins of weakness are forgiven through faith in Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 19:12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 But who can discern their own errors?
Forgive my hidden faults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 1:7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 But if we walk in the light, as he is in the light, we have fellowship with one another, and the blood of Jesus, his Son, purifies us from all sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Thessalonians 5:9-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 For God did not appoint us to suffer wrath but to receive salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ. 10 He died for us so that, whether we are awake or asleep, we may live together with him. 11 Therefore encourage one another and build each other up, just as in fact you are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	Willful sinning is sin accompanied by unbelief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psalm 19:13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 Keep your servant also from willful sins;
may they not rule over me.
Then I will be blameless,
innocent of great transgression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebrews 10:26   If we deliberately keep on sinning after we have received the knowledge of the truth, no sacrifice for sins is left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John 3:18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18 Whoever believes in him is not condemned, but whoever does not believe stands condemned already because they have not believed in the name of God’s one and only Son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.	The Sin against the Holy Spirit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.	This sin cannot be forgiven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew 12:31-32&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I tell you, every sin and blasphemy will be forgiven men, but the blasphemy against the Spirit will not be forgiven. 32 Anyone who speaks a word against the Son of Man will be forgiven, but anyone who speaks against the Holy Spirit will not be forgiven, either in this age or in the age to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark 3:28-30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell you the truth, all the sins and blasphemies of men will be forgiven them. 29 But whoever blasphemes against the Holy Spirit will never be forgiven; he is guilty of an eternal sin.” 30 He said this because they were saying, “He has an evil spirit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke 12:10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And everyone who speaks a word against the Son of Man will be forgiven, but anyone who blasphemes against the Holy Spirit will not be forgiven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.	This sin cannot be forgiven because it is the sin of willfully rejecting the gospel by which sins are forgiven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romans 10:17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 Consequently, faith comes from hearing the message, and the message is heard through the word about Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Thessalonians 2:9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 The coming of the lawless one will be in accordance with how Satan works. He will use all sorts of displays of power through signs and wonders that serve the lie, 10 and all the ways that wickedness deceives those who are perishing. They perish because they refused to love the truth and so be saved. 11 For this reason God sends them a powerful delusion so that they will believe the lie 12 and so that all will be condemned who have not believed the truth but have delighted in wickedness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.	We can examine our own hearts to see that we have faith in Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 13:5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 Examine yourselves to see whether you are in the faith; test yourselves. Do you not realize that Christ Jesus is in you—unless, of course, you fail the test?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d.	The person who has committed the unforgiveable sin is doomed to eternal death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 John 5:16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone sees his brother commit a sin that does not lead to death, he should pray and God will give him life. I refer to those whose sin does not lead to death. There is a sin that leads to death.  I am not saying that he should pray about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A person who is in danger of committing the sin against the Spirit does not care about his condition. A man whose conscience is assailed by fear of having committed it certainly is not guilty of it. Proclaim to such a person the universal and all-powerful gospel of God&amp;rsquo;s grace.” (Dr. John Brug, WLS Dogmatic notes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord loves us very much.  He proved that love for us when he lived, suffered, died and rose again to redeem us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Lord wants us to remain in him through faith in his word.  Therefore our Lord warns us not to grow comfortable with sin but to live continually in repentance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, only the sin of unbelief condemns (Mark 16:16).  Be on guard against every kind of sin, especially the sin of unbelief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continue in the word of Jesus; let his word live in your abundantly (Colossians 3:15-16). In this way you will remain in the faith by which you will be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DISCUSSION TIME&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STUDENTS’ QUESTIONS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INSTRUCTOR’S QUESTIONS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homework&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review your notes from this lesson.  Give correct answers to the following questions.  You may also find correct answers to these questions in the book “God So Loved the World” as indicated on page 1 of this lesson.  Be ready to discuss these questions and your answers at the beginning of the next session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your next exam will follow lesson 20 of this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is “giving offense?” Mt 18:6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can people give offense?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.  Ro 16:17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.  Mt 18:6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.  1 Cor 8:9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is taking offense?  Isa 8:14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does God permit trials to come into the Christian’s life?  Explain.   Ge 50:20; Job 1:6-12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What assurance does the Lord give us concerning the trials he permits to come into our lives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.  Ro 8:28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.  Heb 12:7-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.  1 Co 10:13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d.  2 Ti 4:18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relate what the Bible tells us about the devil’s temptations to sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.  1 Pe 5:8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.  1 Jn 2:15-17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c.  Jas 1:14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is obduration?  1 Ti 4:2, Ex 8:15; Ps 95:8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the causes for hardening of the heart?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.  Eph 2:2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b.  Ex 8:15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is all hardening of the heart terminal?  Ac 3:15, 17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does the Bible warn against hardening our hearts?  Ps 95:7,8; 2 Co 6:2, Ac 5:5; Cf. CW 337:3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is one sin less damning or more damning than another?  Jas 2:10; Eph 2:3, Ro 5:18, Ps 5:5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is meant by sins of weakness?  Ro 7:18-20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why must we also warn people that repeated, willful sinning can destroy faith?  Eph 4:30, Gal 5:19-21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the Bible speak of some sins being more grievous than others?  Explain.  Lk 12:47, 48; Jn 19:11; Ro 2:12-16; Mt 11:20-24.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What false distinction is made by Rome with regard to mortal and venial sins?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the end result of this false distinction?  Cf. SA III III: 19-22&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is any sin so terrible God cannot forgive it? 1 Ti 2:4; Jn 1:29; 3:16, 1 Jn 2:2; 2 Co 5:21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the sin against the Holy Spirit?  Mt 12:31,32; Luke 12:10; He 6:4-6; 10:26, 27; 1 Jn 5:16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distinguish this sin from final impenitence (Mk 16:16), spiritual ignorance (1 Ti 1:13), or a denial of Jesus’ caused by fear (Luke 22:61, 62).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this called the unpardonable sin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this sin committed only by a fallen believer or by unbelievers who have seen and rejected the compelling evidence for Christ’s claims?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What must we tell those who may be committing this sin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will we tell those who think they have committed this sin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
